Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 141 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser. So, how you doing, man?
Better spring break went well. Yeah. Right. Right.
By the time this is out, we'll hopefully know how Brexit went.
And then I'm, I'm going to assume it gets worse.
I,
yes, I, I'm not, I'm not even to think about it. I,
the more I know the, the sadder I get,
I think at this point,
all I can say about Brexit is the problem isn't Brexit anymore.
The problem is that the British government
doesn't work and I don't mean in the sense of like,
the current political parties are like f bar but I mean,
like the whole system doesn't work
like representative democracy in that country is broken.
I'm not even going to start on this one man because there's,
that's a rathole we will never escape from, but we'll just leave it with.
-- Well, and I suspect Canada and the US are not far behind. All
-- right.
So, so let's do this since this is before
April 12th,
which is the new crash out date for Brexit and I'll use
the word crash out because I think that's where I may,
-- oh,
-- regardless of what happens, it's going to be a disaster.
I see three possibilities and let's, let's predict it now and we'll find it later.
So there's either,
-- uh, they revoke Brexit and don't do it,
-- revoke article 50
right. Revoke article 50. They crash out hard or they come up with a compromise.
What do you think is going to happen?
They absolutely can't come up with a
compromise because internally they can't negotiate it.
And also the eu states, one of them will veto it.
So that leaves you with either revoke article 50 or crash out hard.
And
I hate to say it, but
if they were going to revoke article 50 wouldn't they have done it by now?
I tend to agree. So we both, we both agree, crash out hard. That's our prediction.
I'm thinking hard, Brexit and like complete
cluster.
I'm going to stock up on beans because while I don't think it will affect me,
technical
one never knows. And it's always good to have a surplus supply of canned beans.
What really gets me is that they can't even
import enough extra medicine to hold over for shortages
because they don't even have enough refrigerated warehouse space.
It's
like
second order problems, man. I love it anyway.
Anyway, let's, I'm not going to let us rattle on this.
We're going to find out when this publishes, if they crash out and I Lord knows,
I hope we're wrong because
that's the worst possible option. But anyway, all right, that's enough.
That's enough. That's enough. We don't, we don't need to do this.
I hope they survive it.
Yes.
Right. Me.
May God be with you all? That's,
yeah.
So, I guess, well, and this is kind of feeds into that, that whole, like, who knew?
-- This could be so complicated, kind of class of problem. Oh,
-- security is easy, right?
Like everything is easy. It's fine.
I think somebody came up with it last week was
that we just train all the developers to do security.
Why did we think of that before?
I know it's been 50 years and we just, we got this one thing wrong.
-- I, I know. Right.
-- Right. Right. Exactly.
So, so you say that and this is something I've,
I've started doing some research into the history of aviation because this is
like we can't train developers
and at the same time, I've, I've come to realize just
security is on fire so much all the time.
I like,
I never have 10 minutes to just sit down and say what happened and how do we prevent it,
-- you know? Yeah,
-- we never have time for a good post mortem
followed by actually fixing the root causes.
-- And
-- so anyway, I'm,
I'm curious if this is how industries evolve or if we're special and I,
I don't know the answer yet.
-- I'm, I'm trying to find out,
-- typically, industries evolve this way,
but part of it is industries typically get
sort of a, a
comprehensive body of knowledge of engineering.
So for example,
I was at the university bookstore one time and I remember seeing this book,
it was about three inches thick hard cover
and it was a manual for civil engineers specifically on roads. That's it.
And things like, you know, what angle do you make the road to bank it on a curve?
You know, how do you do drainage? How do
you, you know what, what layers of the road do you need,
say in a warm climate versus in a climate like mine where we have lots of frost heave
and just,
but they have this body of knowledge of like, OK, you have problem X.
Well, you can solve it
with, you know,
technique A B and Q or you can do this
other thing that also works and it's known to work.
Whereas in software,
well, let me put it this way. How many web servers can you pick from at this point?
Over 1000?
I,
I would say there's probably 10, you could practically choose.
Well, no, no, no, I'm I'm also talking about like the,
the language specific things like say flask or you know,
Python flask or ruby on rails,
Puma or
just all the, you know, all the different things that basically are like hi
you can talk to me with http
like restful api
how many things provide that?
I, I bet you could.
-- And the answer is thousands.
-- It is thousands.
I bet though the practical answer is 100 which is still ridiculous
-- or
-- something is quote
unquote, simple ruby on rails. What's the asset pipeline?
Well, currently they're moving to a new thing called Web pack.
Away from the old one which I don't even remember the name of.
And so part of the problem is we just,
we don't have established like we don't have a good mix for concrete.
Yeah,
we don't even have a way to measure if our concrete is strong.
I know you've been working on that.
-- I
-- I am and
yeah, but that, that's a good point. I got, you got me thinking now anyway,
so
I ran across this article that I love is, which is
so the eu is getting rid of daylight savings,
which I 100% support like changing the clocks is some bs, sorry folks.
But that whole World War Two thing needs to go away. And so they're getting rid of it.
Great.
How do you store a date and time accurately?
Especially when you have things like time zones and
especially things like time zones that do change,
right.
That's something
I always took for granted as a kid because like I
live in a time zone that actually has been basically the same
for a long time.
Um, but time zones do change.
I lived through this once, I,
I used to live in the State of Indiana in the United States.
And when I moved there, when I was fresh out of college,
they did not,
they did not observe daylight savings time,
which,
when I was there I thought was super annoying because basically the
whole rest of the country was observing it for the most part,
everyone I interacted with.
And it really sucked being
the one place that didn't. And so when they wanted to change the time zone,
I said that's great. Let's totally do that.
And then I hated it. So,
-- and actually there's because you
-- had to fix all your computers.
Well, there's a second problem to that too is
they put us in the eastern time zone when we
were extremely far west in the eastern time zone.
And so it ended up being light out until 10 pm in the summer.
And that kind of sucked rocks too.
I bet the reason they did that simply was for economic reasons.
-- So,
-- here's, here's part of the challenge that came with it is when the,
the then governor, his name was Mitch Daniels.
I remember that
he, he kind of, part of his campaign promise was we're going to
observe daylight savings time and we're going to be in the central time zone. Right.
And we thought, oh, that's neat.
Uh, it turns out the states don't get to choose the, the Federal Trade Commission.
I think it is, tells you what time zone you're in and you can't, you can't like
the
-- States.
-- Right.
No.
Right. Exactly. And there was nothing
we could
-- do.
-- It. Kind of,
it was actually as well.
It was
crazy.
Wow. That, that's kind of bonkers
is sort of, but not really.
I mean,
I guess the issue I could see is they don't want like one state
in the middle of the country deciding we're on the eastern time zone now.
And
you can't just do that. You idiots but whatever, whatever.
Anyway, back to the topic. So
this one came up as really interesting when you,
when you mentioned it because like you said,
it feels like dealing with time should be really easy.
Oh,
-- easy.
-- Right. Just fix
it and, and kind of using the parallel of security here.
It's very similar of,
there's lots of things we do in security that feel like it should be easy,
but it's actually really hard to do.
And I think the time zones are a unique thing
for us to discuss in the context of security because
people generally understand time zones
and they're way harder than people can imagine.
-- People have a superficial understanding of time zones,
-- right?
Just like security, right?
And so the worst thing is they, they think they understand it but they really don't.
And,
and it's also worth mentioning that the planet has literally
hundreds of time zones and we always think of,
-- oh, there's like, uh,
-- thousands,
there, there's 24 of them.
Is it is. It could be thousands. I wouldn't, I wouldn't be surprised at that.
But we always imagine there's 24 but they're totally honest.
Well, there's so there's, obviously there's 24 time zones.
There's also the half hour, 15 minute ones.
But then there's all the different, like, daylight savings
or daylight standard or all that kind of stuff where, you know,
your time changes throughout the year.
And so if you count sort of each jurisdiction
that has its own set of unique kind of
time zone rules laws, whatever, then it's, it's my understanding is it's like
probably close to 1000.
Go look at the time zone file on your UNIX machine that's maintained by that one guy.
Remember?
It's enormous
and, well, so there, there's a reason for that though.
And here's, here's what it comes down to and I'll, I'll,
I'll set the table here because this is something I had
to deal with back when Indiana changed the time zone is.
So
let's say you have a, a time stamp
saved in a file, right?
And you need to say, what is this, let's say, what is this UTC time
in
whatever time zone I want. We'll say at, at the time it was called Indiana.
Us East is what I was in because we had our own time zone because we were a weird place.
So anyway, the thing is
you have to look at the time and then decide where in
history is it from and what was the time zone back then?
Because obviously if I look at the time zone, say from 1990 in Indiana,
there's no daylight savings time.
Right.
So I've got to take that into account, but if I look at a time,
say now they're totally observing it.
And so that makes it really difficult.
And you have to think there are places that change time zones on a
sadly regular basis where they're either adding an hour or subtracting an hour.
They're observing daylight savings or not observing daylight savings.
-- And it's, well,
-- they're skipping a day.
-- Right. Right.
-- That's what Samoa did.
They,
they basically skipped forward a day because so that they were
-- more in line with the people they do business with
-- which,
which makes sense
because
it was, yeah, here we go
in doing business with New Zealand and Australia.
We're losing out on two working days a week. Mr, and I can't pronounce his name.
Tuil, a
apostrophe or no hyphen
or
whatever epa said
while it's Friday here at Saturday, New Zealand, when we're at church on Sunday,
they're already conducting business in Sydney and Brisbane.
So Samoa was just over the Dateline
and they skipped
forwards to be like,
so that they could do business with the people they do business with.
And,
you know, And that totally makes sense. Yeah.
But, and again, like, your Indiana thing,
I'm guessing that's why they picked the ST, because,
you know, being, like, no offense central,
my understanding of the central US is it's a bunch of farmers, right.
Uh, generally speaking,
Chicago is kind of the big city there that you'd often deal with.
And, and again,
when, I mean, I was a remote employee,
generally dealing with people on the east coast.
And so for half the year
I'd be in their time zone in half the year I wouldn't be.
And this was before Google calendar existed.
And so scheduling meetings is a freaking night.
Well,
it's still a nightmare because like dealing with people
in Australia because they have the opposite daylight savings.
So all of a sudden it's not that we're one hour apart, we're two hours.
No, there's a simple solution to this. I've discovered
you schedule the meeting
and you can click a box that says, allow guests to modify event
and in the invite you say, if this time doesn't work for you, please move it
and then it's not your problem.
Well, no, but I mean,
just something that's a regular meeting all of a
sudden for one of you shifts two hours.
-- It does. It
-- does.
And, and I have some standing meetings just like that with Australia, in fact,
and II, I just always tell him like, I've got that box ticked.
I say, look, guys if this doesn't work.
But I don't care, I'll, I'll, I'll show up when the meeting is,
-- this
-- is why in my calendar I'm marked when I'm sleeping.
So that, and vice versa, I tell people I deal with and,
you know, because I was talking with one of my coworkers and, and she's like, oh,
it's getting really
here. And I'm like, what? It's like lunch.
She's like, no, no, it's like eight o'clock at night.
And I'm like, uh, where are you in, in Berlin? 00. Right. Right.
-- We have an office there. I forgot about that.
-- No, I agree. I do the same thing.
I block off
because they all speak really. They speak better English than I do.
I know. It's so funny.
I love it. But, yeah. No, I, I totally do that on my calendar.
I block off all kinds of crazy stuff.
Yeah, I just tell people if, if I have a free slot on my calendar,
I will show up if there is anything else there, I will decline this meeting.
I don't care if you think it's less important than your thing. Like
full stop. That is my policy. Anyway.
-- Anyway, we're talking about time zones, not ranting about meetings.
-- So, yeah.
So you have a time zone. You, well, and here's part of the problem,
you better have that.
I'm hoping that you store the time zone in UTZUTC
because if you don't store it in UTC,
then you've just opened up a whole other can of worms.
-- The time stamp, you don't UTC is a time zone.
-- Sorry.
Uh Yeah, you better store your time stamp in UTC otherwise.
Well, what happens if you don't store your time stamp in UTC?
Uh I mean, look, there's nothing that necessarily makes it wrong.
It just creates some extra pain when you're
trying to process the dates because now you,
you probably have to load the time
and make sure the time zone is correct in whatever library you're using.
And then depending upon what you're doing,
you may have to turn it into UTC and then turn it into something else.
Just,
there's a lot of crazy things that get involved here.
-- U
-- TC is sort of that, that it's the lowest common denominator.
And so that in my mind is why you should always store your time stamps in UTC.
Yeah, I agree completely. It, it just makes life easier.
I've been.
Although, so here's one of the funny things you'll love is when,
when I lived in Indiana
and we were changing our clocks, actually, windows was very,
very late to pick up on this time zone.
Change the open source world, of course, got it right immediately.
And there were no issues but
the people on the news were telling everyone just, yeah,
on this day just change your clocks to Eastern time.
Right. That's your time zone.
-- It's like,
-- no,
that's
no,
wrong.
But I'm not going to argue with you.
In fact, I worked at a company that,
that's what they did to their servers and I'm like, you know what,
this isn't worth arguing with you,
whatever.
Right.
Right. Good enough. Eventually they got it. But,
yeah, whatever
it was, it was very silly.
And,
but again, time
zone
are you gonna do
well and especially if your vendor doesn't support it.
What literally are you going to do?
-- You're
-- going to change your clock to be on the eastern time zone.
That's what you a
calendar reminder.
Pretty much it, it was, it was very silly. But anyway, anyway, so
this is a security podcast.
So, so here's the thing I always think of,
especially in the context of time is time
is one of those fundamentals that as a species
we accept and deal with on a regular basis just because it's like,
it's a truth of the universe as much as I
wish the arrow of time wasn't one direction it is.
So that's the way it goes.
And,
and like this is something
humans understand from birth,
whether we know it or not and we struggle to get it right.
And now we want to talk about security and say, oh,
just teach people security or read this or learn that or something.
And it's like this is so foreign to us as, as mammals that you just, you can't learn it.
-- Oh,
-- and actually you know what you and I got a fundamental thing wrong,
this whole conversation, you and I were wrong about something.
It wouldn't shock me at all.
UTC is not a time zone,
it's a time standard.
It is a standard, it is not a time zone
is a time zone,
for example, but UTC is not a time zone.
IP
Z equals UTC
-- and things happen
-- but it's not technically a time zone. It's the time standard.
It's, it's above the time zone. Essentially.
It, it could be, I mean, it wouldn't shock me at all.
I,
I remember it was so much special also because you
got to remember with leap seconds and you know,
keeping UTC
kind of on, on time, I guess expiring the pun with, you know,
the solar clock like the solar, the earth going around the, the the sun
does vary a bit because, you know, gravitational disturbances from
-- stuff like Saturn and Jupiter
-- and we're slowing down,
right? I mean, someday I believe the earth will become tightly locked.
Yes. Well, that, that's inevitable in, well, not inevitable,
theoretically speaking, that's inevitable in all of these,
all of these orbital systems, right, that you become tidally locked at some point.
Um So yeah, the spin of the earth is slowing down,
which means the days will get longer.
-- And then, yeah, in theory, eventually becomes tightly locked
-- like
the
what is tidally locked mean for people?
So a perfect example is the moon, the moon orbits the earth,
right goes around the earth in a big kind of wonky oval.
And, um,
we only ever see one side of the moon, one face of the moon because it, it's,
it's basically the moon rotates around the earth
in one period of its orbit.
So it's just,
it's like when you're holding your kid in
helicoptering them and you can see their face
and I'm assuming you're holding your kids' hands, not their feet.
If you hold their feet, you're hard.
I like it.
I approve.
Uh, and, and actually mercury is tightly locked to the sun as well.
So, good luck settling it.
Right.
Right. I don't
anyway.
Right. Oh,
but wait, so time zones are hard.
-- Security is hard
-- and time is hard because there's also things
like leap seconds that an extra second or subtract a second.
And my experience,
there's a lot of computer programs that just assume a minute is 60 seconds always.
Uh, didn't, didn't Microsoft's cloud come down because of a leap second.
A couple of years back.
Uh, no, that was a leap
year certificate. Expiration thing
where
-- they had their certificates set to expire after how many days in a
-- year? 365. And
most
of the
time
it's three out of four,
it's close enough.
It'll work.
Yeah.
And so, yeah, they are all their certificates expired on, uh, well,
the certificates, uh, a bunch of certificates expired February 29th
as they should because they were valid until February 28th because February 29th.
Whoops, that happens this year.
God bless time.
Well, it's unfortunate that the earth is close enough to kind of that,
you know, like if it was some wonky
other number then we'd probably pay more attention to it.
But it's close enough that, you know, we have this correction
that mostly works except, well, here's the thing. Right. What was 2000 a leap year?
Well, the answer was, yes. No. Yes. Right. Like every four years, yes.
Every 100 years. No, every 1000 years. Yes. Or is it 2000 years?
We didn't, we don't even know it's too hard.
Well, because the, the, the, the, the length of the year I, it's what,
365.25 something something something.
-- Right. It's just, it's slightly more than a quarter.
-- It's madness anyway.
-- Anyway, this is making
-- my
head.
So, yeah, good luck with your buffers and memory management.
And see, I guess is what the conclusion is
and whatever that's
cross site scripting.
I mean, pick a security issue and the fact is we can't figure out time zones.
How are we going to figure out security?
And
once
you train your developers to do time correctly,
then maybe think about teaching them to do security correctly.
That is fair.
And I,
I want to make sure we don't always just end
on doom and gloom and talk about how doomed.
We are because we are. But I mean that that's another point story.
Uh No, I, I feel like the answer here is
there's I I'm all for developer awareness and
I think it's good people understand this stuff.
But I think we also need to make
the realistic observation that we can't train away some of these problems.
And this is a place where the right answer is who cares about time zones,
Just trust someone else to build a library that will do them correctly.
And in
all seriousness, those libraries are,
are going to figure this out and they'll get it right.
So you,
you don't have to care or worry about it and security
doesn't have that in many cases and we need them,
we need them back.
Well,
it's weird that like in civil engineering or whatever you have these standards,
like I need some rebar with this tensile strength.
OK? Flip through the catalog. OK. I'll buy it from you
or I need screws of this strength and whatever and you just go and get that.
Whereas, but in software it's always like
I need to handle time.
I'm going to write it myself rather than use some like very simple library or,
or God forgive all the people that are like, I need encryption.
-- OK? I can do that.
-- Right. Right.
And,
and you think a screw is infinitely simpler and
we don't think twice about buying them because,
oh, my goodness.
Actually, there's a video I'm gonna put in the show notes. I, I watched this weekend,
there's this guy on youtube called Project Farm
and he's just some weirdo who does these like
crazy things and one of the things he did,
he was, he was testing like the po strength of nails and screws.
It is
insane
how
strong screws are. It's
bonkers.
It came up on my feet and I was going to look at it, but I, I forgot
it
was
fantastic.
I actually did a bunch of research
into this and,
and there's some really interesting patents around nails and screws,
especially modern ones because there's this company that makes these really
fascinating high tech hurricane proof nails
that are almost as strong as screws.
And the way they're designed is actually quite clever.
And what really got me was when I installed my, um, my nest smoke alarms.
They come with a screw
that's designed to work in both wood and drywall.
And so it's got actually two sets of threading on it.
Wow.
It's got like wood screw or it's got like a finer thread
on the tip and then like a chunkier threading on the shank.
So that if you're, you go into a wood, it'll,
the tip of it will go into the wooden hole there.
But if you're just going into straight drywall,
it's got like a nice chunky thread that will hold in the drywall.
And it was interesting because like the nest was so proud of
their engineering and they were talking about how they spent like,
ump Gaji Lion hours
basically over engineering these screws so that they only had to send
one set of screws with the device to plug it in,
like to screw it into the wall so that people
didn't
forgive me for this. They didn't screw it up.
Um
And uh but seriously, right, because like, I've,
I've bought devices where they come with like really terrible, you know,
drywall screws
and then if you have to screw into wood or something, that's like, well,
that's an exercise left to the reader.
-- Good luck with that.
-- Right. Right.
So, so anyway, the other cool video I watched this guy,
uh I won't link it but I'll tell you to find it.
Is he put bacon grease in an engine as the oil and it was,
the results are amazing and I will just let you watch it and find out.
So, so anyway, anyway, let's move on to the second thing we wanted to discuss today.
And that is,
and this is totally related right there.
It's completely related to the time zone problem because
there's a story on Reddit
talking about the fact that U two F which we've discussed in the past numerous times
will now work in Firefox and Safari
and then the Reddit
and, and edge poor edge,
-- even Microsoft gave off.
-- I know, I know, I feel bad
for. OK. Just so real quick.
What is UTU two F
-- Fido? Again, it is
-- basically,
it's a second factor authentication.
And the beauty of it is when I go to a website and it'll say plug in
your key and I plug it in and I have to push a button on the,
on like a UB key is a little tappy thing. But whatever
you,
you have to physically interact with the key
and then something happens and the beauty of it is it uses the URL in the browser
is basically what gets sent to the key. What, what was your description of this?
A magic?
It's a magic elf that sits inside the key signing off on paper. There you
go.
I love that.
That's perfect and only paperwork that he recognizes like so to be clear,
you have to register your key.
So if you want to use a U two F key with Google, you go to google.com/,
it's like two step landing,
just Google Google second two fa and you'll get their
landing page and at the very bottom you click,
let's get started
and then you choose security key at the top and you choose register security key,
you plug your key in, it sends it that little URL bit of data stuff, your key signs,
it sends it back and also gives it like the public key that the key is using
and now your key is registered and,
and you're good to go. It's that simple. You plug it in, you touch it.
Yep,
that's it. There's no second step.
And you basically can't be man in the middle with this where
the like uh the, the, the Google authenticator style apps on your phone,
someone could present you with a fake login page.
Have you enter all the credentials they need and then log in as you.
Whereas in this instance, if you're not on the real website,
the U two F key just doesn't do the right thing.
So there's no way to spoof it.
Yeah.
Well,
the only way to really attack this would be is if your browser had a
flaw that allowed the attacker to like spoof the address bar on an entire website,
which we've gotten really good at preventing that
or I guess
now,
now here's something else I want to point out is there are going to be flaws
similar to this and there are going to be people who find ways to leverage,
we'll say shortcomings in U two F.
But that's not a good enough reason not to use it because it's like 99% good enough.
Whereas nearly every other solution is 80% or less,
it basically moves the attack surface to things that we've
already spent a lot of time fixing and gotten really good at.
And so it basically,
it relies on things like your browser address bar showing the correct address,
which it's like I don't know people that are young here but 1520 years ago,
that was a hard problem.
And there were a lot of flaws
-- but we fix them like we got good at that.
-- Some of them. Not all though.
I mean, there's still,
you can use various unicode characters or
it's still not perfect and there's still ways
actually. No, they, most of those have fixed the unicode thing.
They, they, they don't display the unicode,
they put the hyphen hyphen blah, blah, blah stuff in.
Um Well,
I remember we did that on the show and remember
on the mobile browser it didn't put on the Safari.
Right.
-- Right. Right.
-- But regardless the point is that, yeah. No, you, you the, the,
the bar for proxy and doing an attack is way, way higher and more to the point.
What I love about these keys,
they're epoxy sealed, you can't break them.
They sit on my, like I have a bunch of them on my key ring. They don't, they don't
break there. You plug it into the computer and you tap it,
that's it.
-- And
-- actually
-- unplug it because you need to put your keys back in your pocket.
My other favorite feature
is the UI
-- keys can store P GP and SSH keys in them,
-- some of them,
some of the
keys.
But
here's the purpose of this particular discussion is you look at these
comments on Reddit and there's a lot of misunderstanding about this.
-- Well,
-- and so it's understandable because people have never,
if you've never been exposed to a UB key,
how would you understand or know what it is?
Because quite frankly, it looks like a USB thumb drive.
So you assume it has like storage on it. Well,
it kind of has storage but like secure crypto magic storage, not like
regular file storage.
-- And
-- it's even more confusing for some people because like you plug in a UI
key on, on my Mac
and it always pops up. Oh, you just plugged in a keyboard. Let's configure.
It's like, no, there's no F and keys on this keyboard you moron.
But asking me that
there's nothing I can do to make it go away.
That I thought, well, my solution is to get rid of the Mac.
But that's another story and that that's happening soon. I'm excited.
But
yeah,
and
there's
so here's,
here's what I thought of when you sent me this link and I was reading these
comments and there was a lot of misunderstanding
is if a security person tells someone,
get one of these and just use it,
are they going to listen?
So, no, they're not. They really aren't.
I was going to say like even in my case,
I have trouble convincing people to use these things.
And it's funny because once they start using them, they're like, oh,
this is awesome.
I'm like, yeah.
Right.
But, but at the same time I,
I feel like as an industry I have a suspicion we have tried to scare people for so long.
They look at us
funny anytime we say this is something you should do.
I think it's a combination of the boy who cried wolf
because we've doom and gloom about all sorts of things that,
like, my favorite is the c,
remember Cyber Pearl Harbor.
Yeah. When, when does that happen again?
-- I think we, I think it got rescheduled to next Thursday,
-- next Thursday
maybe.
But so there's the, I think it's a combination of alarm fatigue,
the boy who cried wolf and all that.
And more to the point though,
when we, a lot of security professionals and you and I both used to be guilty of this.
When we do tell people what to do and to fix things,
we give them horrifically terrible.
Hard to follow advice
like, ok, tell the world about how you store your encryption keys.
Oh, wait, you gave up. You just, you, you basically,
I don't think you're going to try and recover them anymore. Right?
We don't have a lot. We don't have long enough left on our podcast.
I need a whole podcast to explain to you how I,
I still protect my encryption keys this way just because it's, it's already done,
the damage is done and there's no reason to undo it. But yeah, it's uh I
bet it would take me more than 20 minutes. To explain everything. I do.
Yeah.
And I just have my,
what few encryption keys I have basically on
my workstations with no passphrase because the,
you know, it's, it's an encrypted laptop to begin with.
-- And, and
-- the number of times we've each been hacked is
the same.
Actually, you know, I got my,
my servers to get hacked once through a known combination
of a wordpress bug and a Linux kernel bug.
-- And this is about 1520 years ago. I
-- mean, having your keys stolen. Right.
The number of times our keys have been stolen is the same number. Even though
I spent,
uh, I bet I lost days of my life putting together my key protection scheme.
Oh, I used to be like you, I'm, I'm not, I don't hold the moral high ground here.
II, I admitted
my problem and, and I, and I, well, and I buried the problem out in the backyard.
Right, right now at the same time, my, my P GP key is very old because changing it.
It's a lot of work. So I just have no incentive to do it.
But someday I will.
Although I don't know, maybe I won't, it doesn't matter. I mean,
-- no, not really.
-- Do you
-- even
-- need your encryption keys?
I use
-- mine
-- to sign git commits. That's all I use them for anymore.
Because encrypted email is a dead donkey.
In fact, when people send me GP G mail, I usually reply back with,
please send it in plain
-- text.
-- Yeah,
un unless, yeah. Anyway, anyway, whatever. So here's,
I, I guess here's the point is
I can relate to these users on Reddit who don't understand what's going on.
And then I think about our industry and, and let's say I want to find out about U two F.
Is there anywhere I can go and get like a nice easy explanation.
And the answer is maybe, I mean, you could probably go read some Yuki materials.
You could probably find some youtube videos that are ok.
-- But
-- the Wikipedia page is not bad.
But I, I guess if I'm in
it's not great.
Oh yeah. No, this is, no, this is not. No, no, no, no, no, no, sorry. Actually, I lied.
The uh the Wikipedia page is not,
it, it has the factual of like when it became a standard and stuff,
but no actual explanation of what it is
and, and this is and at the same time,
no one's no one's going to care because you're talking about screws earlier.
I'm sure there are thousands of pages detailing how to test screws,
how to build screws.
What kind of,
what kind of things we should look for when we make the screws. And
as a consumer of screws,
I don't care, I'm not going to read that crap. Right.
I want to basically show up at the store and buy some screws.
Funny story about screws.
I noticed at Home Depot about a year, maybe two years ago,
the screws went from like, they have, you know, like the, the number, uh, screw,
like how wide the screws, right?
Like number four, number six, number eight, number 1012, 1416, whatever.
And they have the different lengths, obviously,
you know,
because sometimes you need a half inch screws to do whatever and piece of furniture
and sometimes you need like a 3.5 inch
construction screw because you're building a deck.
Right?
But what I noticed is for all the sort of standard steel screws for wood stuff,
they're still all packaged individually by, you know, size and length.
Um, but they're all the same price.
There's just like this giant wall of like,
it's like little boxes of like five or 10 or whatever screws each
and they're all like
five bucks or whatever it is.
Whereas they used to all be different prices in different, you know, like the, like,
you know, the, the number four, like
half inch screws were a different price than the number 41 inch screws.
Now, they're all the same price
and you just get slightly different amounts of screws. So it's kind of
almost like just by buying by weight.
But the point is they, they,
they vastly simplified it for the people that only need like
a few screws for like hanging a picture or doing,
you know, like a small project.
And I guess the professionals, you know,
still you go to the kind of down the aisle a bit more and look down and, you know,
there's like the big scary boxes of like, you know, 20 pounds of,
-- of construction screws or whatever.
-- That's fair.
And
right, I mean,
-- this is the thing I keep thinking of is
-- why can't we do
that offer people a couple of different
security solutions that are all attractively packaged
and they're all relatively easy to use and they, you know, oh, you, for example,
you want a hardware-based token because, you know,
you want to have a high level of security.
Cool.
You know, you want to, you want to go download Google authenticator,
put that on your phone.
Cool. You do you right. That, that's pretty secure.
Especially if your phone is a modern phone.
It has like a fingerprint reader and stuff,
you know, and you have a good pass, uh lock and all that.
But yeah, no, instead we offer them like these
horrifically complicated solutions that
kind of don't work a lot of the time. Like antivirus.
I have no antivirus on any of my systems because it's just,
I don't want to screw them up.
You know what the example I would say is,
imagine if you didn't know what you were buying for screws,
you bought them and then some of the screws when you tried to use them actually,
like destroyed the thing.
You were screwing it. Into instead of actually working, right?
That, that's the comparison.
That's actually a thing that can happen because for example, here in Canada,
we use Robertson's, you know, the square hole right on the top of the,
which is
far superior because a properly made screw sticks to your screwdriver, even
horizontal, vertical, whatever,
right? You don't.
Yeah, it's perfect. But
there's the different sizes, right?
There's like the number six, number eight, number 10, whatever.
And if you like me, um, or sorry, the number two is the most common size for the bit.
And so like me, you have like 50 million numbers, two bits but not the, you know,
the slightly larger one,
you have like three of them and they're lost because
they're like floating around the bottom of your tool bag.
And more annoyingly they're color coded and the ones,
the slightly larger ones are color coded black and of course, my tool bag is black,
so it's
really tricky to find.
Fantastic.
So you can usually, if you're driving into something that's not too hard,
you can use the smaller bit in the larger screw head.
But if you're driving into something that's a little bit harder,
then of course what happens is the bit will rotate
and round the inside of the hole of the screw
and now you have a screw halfway into something.
Well, no, actually, no, the bit, uh, well,
the bits I buy are really good and hard metal So the bit doesn't ruin, it,
ruins the head of the screw.
And then basically you have to go hunting for your vice lock grips,
chomp them onto the screw and manually
pull it like, turn it around to get it back out and it takes about a good 10 minutes.
So the point is by using the wrong screw bit and the wrong screw,
you can actually drive a screw like halfway into something,
Have it sticking out and can't, you maybe not,
can't get it out easily or when you walk the vice grips to it and unscrew it,
it sheers off.
I've had that happen,
which
does
happen. Yeah. And then I just
cut it
off. Yeah,
just take a dremel out and try to get the sparks anywhere.
So the point is with screws, you can make, you can mess up and
ruin something if, but, but you kind of have to try,
you have
to.
Security is the opposite in a lot of instances and, and we're,
we're, we're, we're fresh out of time at this point. But I guess here's,
here's what I would say is my not doom and gloom advice at the end of this,
go buy a
Yike
five
and use it
end of star,
right? And if someone says, what do I do here,
the answers go by.
It only works
at a couple of sites like the support for the thing is nowhere near universal.
But I'll be blunt the sites it works at are kind of the ones that matter, like Google
or
last pass it works on the enterprise and
the premium, but it doesn't work for like the free one.
Right. Because, you know, but if you really want like a strong,
easy and see, here's the thing, right? This is the up is one of those great examples of
the, there's a classic trope of, oh, you know,
you can have security but you have to trade off usability and it's harder to use.
No,
no good. Well designed security
is easy to use.
And the UB key is a perfect example of it.
You plug it in and tap it when the light turns green
-- and,
-- and I would even argue if it's hard to use.
I'm not going to call it good
-- because
-- it's easy to screw up like antivirus.
There we go. I like it.
That makes sense. All right, sweet.
I'm calling
it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up our show notes.
You can use the Pound
and Os S Podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
-- Yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your
-- day. You too, everybody.
Thanks.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.