Hello and welcome to the open source
security podcast where apparently public key cryptography
and using the number nine, which is not prime is fine.
You know, I suppose I could have moved it to number 11, which was prime, but whatever,
I don't care, this was,
this was the only free slot left when I
wanted to add public key cryptography as a topic.
It
just deleted something.
It's December 9th, Kurt, it's almost Christmas. Don't be a Grinch
dude. The Grinch was correct. Everybody else was wrong.
He just wanted to enjoy his life and all those whoville
idiots were like making noise and wrecking his place off.
No, they were there first. It's fine.
OK.
So
public key cryptography, what is it? Why do we care?
Public key cryptography is essentially magic
in the sense of I have
a,
I have a public and private key.
And fundamentally, this allows me to sign things that only I could have signed
and it allows you to encrypt things to me that only I can read,
which gives you two big properties, non
repudiation
and privacy,
non
repudiation, non
-- repudiation means only I could have done that nobody else could have done it
-- well.
So look, the,
the real magic behind public key encryption
is it literally runs the whole internet.
It literally runs all of society at this
-- point.
-- It's true at this point. It really does.
I mean, and,
-- and it's amazing and it basically,
-- have you been paid by your employer recently?
That was public key crypto everything.
Like I bought crap on the internet yesterday and it
was public key cryptography that let me do that.
I paid for a car wash today.
That was public key crypto.
-- Not necessarily, you could use
-- cash,
-- no credit card, swipe machine in the wash
-- base. But yeah. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
Public key cryptography. The idea being there's a public key, private key.
And in the case of the internet, for example, you go to a website,
the website has a private key
and there's how trust is created is complicated. We won't cover that right now.
-- But I mean, fundamentally speaking,
-- trust is created through
and happy little, you know, those kittens with the like big bright eyes.
That's how trust is created.
Look,
we'll just say there's maybe another door in this
house of madness where we'll talk about that.
Right. The point being unless tab
there it is. All right. Cool.
So the point is the magic of public key cryptography is before that
there was no way to share information
with someone securely without both parties essentially
-- over
-- an untrusted channel. That's
true.
That's true because you can share things over a trusted channel,
but fundamentally both sides needed the key, a private key in this instance.
And that obviously doesn't work in something like the
internet because you can't distribute private keys to everybody.
You can't really do trusted channels when there's 8 billion people on the planet.
Because what is 8 billion times 8 billion minus one? It's a big number.
Yeah, exactly.
And,
and also that, that would be one hell of a key signing party.
No, it would be 8 billion factorial.
-- No,
-- it wouldn't be, it would be
8 billion minus one.
Factorial would be the number of private keys you would need to distribute.
It'd be 8 billion times 8 billion minus one. Not factorial.
It would be factorial because you'd have to, every,
every person would have to exchange a key with every other person.
Yeah. So 8 billion times
-- minus one
-- factorial factorial.
So factorials when you're shuffling cards. Yeah.
All right math nerds help me out.
You're
not
factorial is when you shuffle cards,
if you have seven people who need to
sign
-- to
-- distribute every possible combination of keys amongst all of the humans,
whatever doesn't matter.
Private
key,
you solve this problem but private key photography solve
-- this problem as
-- long as you trust somebody,
but you don't have to trust them.
Even you just have to say
here is the private, or here's the public key. I have the private key. Exactly.
Now we can set up a secure communication.
Public key has to be signed so that you know that
it's my public key so that you can trust it.
We're not talking about that right now.
That's another door. It's,
it's another day.
This is how advent calendars work.
You can't talk about the thing behind the next Advent calendar door.
That's just not how it works.
So the point is public crypto is magic because also it's highly inefficient.
So what you do is you use public key
crypto to encrypt a symmetric key which is stupidly efficient.
That's true.
That is,
and that is the magic to me of public key crypto
is that you use something horrifically inefficient because who
cares if it takes five or six seconds to
then encrypt something that is very efficient and bam
and that is where cryptographers did get things right?
Cryptographers have always gotten things right?
Because cryptography is one of the few things in the world that it's all or none.
There's literally nothing in the middle yet. You can't be sort of right?
-- In cryptography,
-- you are surfing a trusted site.
No, the answer is you are now surfing an untrusted site.
Crypto
one.
No, crypto
crypto did win. I agree. I
agree.
And it won in the web browser, which is,
wow, actually, yeah, that's pretty impressive.
I'm ending it.
-- We will see you all.
-- Thanks everybody
on December 10th.