Hello.
And welcome to episode 43 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
What's new Kurt?
-- Well, shadow brokers is at it again. Oh, my
-- goodness. That's,
this is madness. That was. What day was that? Was that Friday or Thursday?
They released a whole bunch of stuff and it's, it's crazy town now because
it's not just that they found a bunch of security issues, it's that this is, well,
they didn't find them, we say they acquired them
but it's all weaponized stuff.
So, pretty much anyone with an internet connection can put these to use,
which is terrifying to pretty much anyone
who does any sort of operational security.
Well, and I mean, some of these vulnerabilities go back.
Uh, I think, what was it? Windows? What version of it was?
It was, it's a version of Windows. It's like more than 10 years old at this point.
-- Yeah, they go back quite a long ways.
-- Yeah.
And, and what gets me is it wasn't always,
it's not just the sort of technical phones which let's face it.
You know, people can do technical phones all day long. Great.
But there's like the operational sort of side of stuff that's apparently in there,
like, um, apparently there's a whole bunch of stuff
about the banking system. And so the,
the thinking is essentially that the NSA has been, you know,
knee deep in the various parts of the world banking system, I guess.
-- Nothing, keeping tabs
-- on
me,
literally nothing.
Well, see, that's what always guts me about crime is like,
and this even goes back to Al Capone, like, follow the money,
right? Because
no fundamentally, you know,
criminals either at some point they have to interact with money,
they need money to buy stuff or to bribe people or to whatever.
Right.
And, you know,
we're not going to be shipping large duffel bags of cash around internationally.
You would be surprised.
True. But, I mean, it's, you know, but these people use the banking system,
you know.
Yes.
And uh, it's at some point they also maybe have to interface with legitimate,
you know, companies and people, you know,
who aren't going to take a duffel bag full of cash for that truck
-- or
-- whatever, you know, for what it's worth.
I'm not even going to speculate on what purpose
it could possibly need
and, and that's ok.
It, it
is what it is,
right? We'll just say that.
-- So
-- what gets me about this though is that there's,
there's no real easy silver bullet good way to deal with, you know,
the the disclosure of these vulnerabilities, right?
Like, and you know, obviously the NSA isn't the only people with this kind of stuff.
Ok. Ok. There,
that's part of the story.
There's,
I can see a couple of things here is, first of all,
every organization on the planet
is
compromised.
Ok.
Let's start there.
Anyone who thinks that,
that the US hasn't infiltrated every other country and every
other country hasn't infiltrated the US is fooling themselves.
And historically speaking, these organizations acquire
stuff, we'll say be it, um, intelligence of some manner and they don't release it
because you don't want to.
And so the shadow brokers obviously are, they're, they're part of some game.
It's not that they're just like some guys who
found some stuff and now they're releasing it.
And so that part is terrifying
in, in many ways.
But then there's also the,
the idea of the exploit and here's the thing that always gets good exploits and,
and you're familiar with this concept as well is
it is very common for an exploit to be found by two people at the same time,
which means
a and these organizations know this, right?
These guys aren't dumb, they know what's up.
So they know their adversaries probably have the same stuff they do.
Well.
And the other thing too is, is I'm,
I'm hesitant to read in like these grand global
conspiracies when it could just be like simple,
you know, somebody screwed up.
Oh, somebody screwed up. They, somebody certainly screwed up.
But there's also a certain amount of
global conspiracy involved here without question.
But, and I mean, here's what really gets me is, is the real
brutal truth of this is, is, this is not hard stuff.
This is not like building a nuclear bomb in 1945.
You know, this is literally one,
you know, one
smart guy who knows how to use the internet and maybe has a couple of $1000 for,
you know,
a, a
reasonably decent laptop. And, um,
honestly, I can only think of like,
there's only maybe one or two software packages that you actually have
to pay money for the rest of it's all open source,
you know, and there's online tutorials, there's, I mean, heck,
there's even books on this for, you know, developing these exploits.
-- I want you to
-- clarify this.
Are you saying exploit development is easy or are you saying
-- I'm
-- saying it's easy in the context of like,
compared to developing a nuclear weapon or, you know, putting a man on the moon,
you know what I mean? Like it's, it's not easy like making a loaf of bread,
right? It's actually, it's harder. Ok. So
you
in your basement
can develop exploits very cheaply,
but a clandestine organization cannot, because they need infrastructure,
they need things in place.
It's actually very, very expensive.
Well, yeah, and at that level, that sort of industrial level.
Yeah, they would have a lot of controls, they'd have, you know,
security to make sure it doesn't walk out the door, stuff like that.
But fundamentally it's still, you know, it's
millions of dollars,
-- maybe tens of millions. It's a
-- lot,
it's a lot of
money.
And in the grand scheme of a major government though, that's not a lot of money.
That's fair.
You know.
Anyway. Anyway, let's
let, let's, let's back this one up because I'd rather not get too deep in the weeds on,
on how all this works.
But I, I think what I would like to talk about are some of the,
the themes that have come out of this.
And my favorite so far has been the people on Twitter saying, oh,
the shadow brokers exploits were patched in,
in one of the previous Microsoft patch.
Tuesdays just upgrade Windows.
And I laugh hysterically at that because that's like saying
just stop being poor, you know, it's easy.
This is one of the reasons I, I actually, I, I am,
I have an M CS E A Microsoft Certified Systems
Engineer uh thing from back in the NT four days
and I did all those exams and I actually almost got my M CS E plus internet,
but I didn't.
And,
and I quickly realized that being on the operational end of windows was a nightmare
back
-- in
-- the
end of anything is a nightmare.
Linux
Linux,
like I, this is one of the reasons I chose. Linux is.
Linux is slightly less nightmarish in the sense
of like getting it up and running and,
you know, so on is kind of a pain in the butt.
But once you get it up and running, it tends to stay
up and running.
That's fair.
You know, whereas windows,
you can actually get it up and running pretty quick and then just something happens
and then you have to,
-- you have to click the mouse 10 million times to solve your problem.
-- Yeah.
And, and it's just totally random stuff like DLL S just
like, literally, I remember like,
like just an important DLL on the server just went missing
just gone. Of course,
it did.
Nobody knows,
you know. And you know, so,
I mean,
yeah, then we enable, you know, auditing and logging and it's, yeah,
we still have no idea why stuff breaks or
we know why it breaks it because this, you know,
third party app that's garbage does it.
But we have to have that third party app
because the accountants need it or whatever anyways.
So I quickly, no, out of that.
Um,
because it was just so so painful.
But, um, yeah, that's the thing like, so you're basically trading.
It's, it's a nonzero chance that you'll get hacked by these bad guys.
But there's also a nonzero chance that in the update you're gonna like,
horribly wreck something.
And quite honestly that non zero chance for the wrecking
stuff is a lot higher than the being hacked.
-- One. Typically,
-- it very well might be. And not just that
a lot of organizations have clearly defined
policies on doing things like updates and doing
an out of band update is nontrivial to say the least not counting the fact
that you could be talking about thousands or tens
of thousands of machines that need to be updated,
which even if you said let's update them all right now,
you can't update them all at the same time because things have to reboot.
Things need passwords typed in it. It's insane how this all works.
And then it,
that's even worse because you might not have a big fleet of machines,
but that fleet of machines might be controlling an oil refinery or a train system.
You know, I mean,
I know for a fact that there are companies out there running railroads
and their policy is we have a yearly update cycle and then we do non,
or we do criticals as needed.
But otherwise we have like a yearly patch cycle and it's like
that it's, it's running a major North American railroad. Like, you can't just
not have that working for four hours.
-- Yeah, mi minor
-- detail. You know,
like, like those airports that, you know,
every time the computers glitch out at the
airport and like the entire airport shut down,
not only does that airport lose a ton of money,
but the airlines and then there's that ripple effect, right?
Like all the, all the incoming and outgoing flights that are, like,
totally messed up.
And I remember somebody, I don't know if you saw it.
They did a really beautiful animated gif
of an incident at Heathrow and like the shock waves as it rippled around the world,
kind of like to all the other airports and stuff and it was,
it was kind of horrifying but also quite pretty
your inability to pronounce GIF correctly has put me,
it's not a GIF, it's AJ,
-- sorry, I'm Canadian. We tend to pronounce it with a hard
-- g, you're wrong.
I accept that just
like
ZNZ.
So, anyway, yes, I, I've seen, actually, I've been affected by this more than once.
Is
o'hare one time had their, I guess their server room lit on fire,
I was
told
and whatever that means, ok.
And
I have visions of actual flames, which I'm sure it was.
Well, the problem is even a small fire but if the water suppression system kicks in
and, right, and that's kind of what I think.
Right is a fire suppression,
fire suppression system probably messed everything up.
But anyway,
this is a place that I think was landing a plane every 30 seconds or something.
Maybe even more than that.
And
the, the
airline people I was talking to because I was talking to the gate agent kind
of about what's going on here because I was waiting for a plane coming from Chicago
and they said that right now
they were doing, I think one plane every three minutes
and you think that's an amazing difference
in terms of takeoff.
It,
it was, it was crazy and in fact,
it screwed up air travel for like three days and I was just
glad that I got out and I got to where I was going
and then I was there for the week and even by the time I was done
it was still like,
the airports were still rough where there were lots of people hanging out and,
and it was just, it was madness.
It was such a pain in the neck. But yeah, I mean, I totally get it and,
and, and these people, they can't update their systems in, at a moment's notice.
I mean, they probably need to plan for months. I don't know how they're going to do it.
So what gets me though about like modern airports is even like my local airport,
you know, Edmonton International,
which is not by any means like a super large airport or even super busy.
Um,
when I was a kid, you know, we'd fly through it and it was like
dead at night.
Like there were, you know,
there were basically there were flights from like eight or nine in the morning until
like five or six in the afternoon or maybe a little bit in the evening,
you know, but even in Edmonton International.
Now that sort of, that dead time is like, maybe four or six hours,
you know, and, and major airports, like, say, Heathrow or, you know, uh, well, yeah,
like those, uh,
like Atlanta or, uh, what is it?
Saint Paul Minneapolis, you know, those, like, hub airport or Denver.
Denver is a great example, you know, those things never have downtime now,
basically.
Or if they do it's like an hour maybe.
And that's what gets me is,
you know, it's, it's like these just in time delivery networks, you know, is, yeah,
they're hyper efficient and it's, you know,
it's great that Chicago is using their runways to maximum capacity, you know,
a plane coming off and on every 30 seconds.
That's great, you know, economically speaking.
But yeah, if anything breaks, you are so up the creek, you know,
and a great example of this is like Atlanta right now,
you know.
Um, they've now had, uh so, uh
they had a fire under the, uh what was it? The I
-- I blank I 20 or I 85 I
-- think it's 85.
So
they had like a lay down yard below the I 85 where they kept like a whole bunch of cable
spools with PV C Conduit or something that caught on
fire and it got hot enough that the concrete,
you know,
uh stressed and cracked and a whole section of the I 85 fell down
and there's actually a really nice, uh,
live cam on it now that you can watch them rebuilding it.
Um, very high quality camera. Very enu anyway,
uh,
then they had
a railroad fire under a bridge and they're
inspecting the bridge to make sure it's ok.
And,
well, I hope it's ok because if not, like, that's another bridge to rebuild.
Uh, then, and this one's shorter.
So they just had a chemical spill on like one of the on ramps or off ramps or something.
So it was shut down for like a day or two.
But then what was it yesterday?
There's like all they would confirm is that like
a contractor was working on a gas line,
like retiring some casing or whatever that means.
So I assume they were just replacing the pipe
and something went wrong and there's like a 2 m
bulge in the road closing two lanes of it,
you know, and this, and this pavement is like a foot thick and it's like just
like tossed up, you know,
and
a
I Yeah, what got me was when they were asking the guy, like, you know,
how bad should we expect traffic to be on Monday or on
Monday or whatever? And he's like, you can expect it to be super, super, super bad.
-- Like the guy used the word super three times.
-- That's
awesome,
you know, and
like, that's the thing, right? Like we can't afford to build an extra set of ropes
just in case,
you know, some of them break.
That's,
that's a good,
well,
that's true because any time you build an extra
highway through an area it's to alleviate congestion,
it's not like a redundant backup.
Exactly.
You know,
I mean, we just kind of have to live with this whole, you know, well, if it breaks,
it breaks and, I mean, in the extreme case of like that
piece that collapsed, it's going to take a few at a minimum, a few weeks,
if not months to replace it.
Um,
I don't know if you remember in California after the big earthquake, uh,
many years ago
they basically went to 24 7 construction
and they had, uh, what I thought was really clever.
They had, the Department of Transport had inspectors on site 24 hours a day
so that there were no delays waiting for inspections.
Right. They just,
they basically what they did is they looked at every single latency loop
and closed, every single one they could,
that makes a lot of sense to me,
you know,
and the thing is, but here's the problem,
the upfront cost is much higher than building it slowly.
But of course,
you know, by building it quickly and getting the economy back up and running,
sort of, you know, like,
I can't even imagine how much time truckers are wasting in Atlanta right now.
You know, it, it, it makes the quality of life terrible and I'm sure it does increase
-- the cost on the city, but I bet the benefits are substantial.
-- Oh, of course.
But the problem is these are all externalized costs, you know,
they don't show up on the, on the
balance sheet directly of the city. You know?
I
mean, and that's always the problem with these.
It's like the pollution problem or, well, again the upgrade problem. Right.
The upgrade cost is upfront and immediate, like, oh, I upgraded it and it broke.
Now I have to spend the weekend fixing it
versus I don't upgrade it and I take a nonzero chance that, you know,
maybe we get hacked,
maybe we don't get hacked fingers crossed. Right.
Right.
And this is in,
this is a discussion that I think is always
very interesting and this is one that I have spent
a fair bit of time
investigating and, and trying to understand is
what is our return on investment for security
and in a lot of instances
it's bad
and, well, ok, generally we don't know. All right. Number one,
but when we, the things we do understand
a
lot of security investment is wasted money
because sometimes it is easier to clean up the mess
on the other side.
That's something that always, you know,
realistically, that's something that people forget is when it comes to risk,
you basically have three major strategies,
you can just avoid the risk entirely. Like we're just not going to do that.
You know,
um,
secondly, you can choose to try and mitigate the risk.
You know, we'll,
we'll put on like antivirus software and we'll install a firewall and we'll hire,
you know, hire a guy with a dog to guard the server room.
And then the third thing you can do is you can like,
uh, essentially accept the risk
and, and optionally do something to offset it, like buy insurance
and say, you know, perfect example, my house is not fireproof.
Uh I could in theory build a fireproof house.
It would be very expensive if it was cheaper just to get a normal house and buy,
you know, standard insurance.
Well, and,
and part of it as well is the odds
of your house burning down are realistically very low
-- and
-- it's low enough that it makes the paper when it happens locally.
Right.
-- Right.
-- That's always my rule of thumb. Right.
If it's, if it's, if it's rare enough to actually end up in the papers,
I don't have to worry about it.
It's the stuff that you don't hear about in the papers that, you know,
that's the stuff that's actually killing people on a regular basis.
Right?
But so you actually have a really good point
when you talk about the house analogy in this context is
sometimes
we plan for things that are ridiculous
and
fire insurance is basically the extent of your
planning for your house burning down or,
or backing up your
it's another one. Yeah. Well, smoke alarms aren't really,
those are about making sure you don't die.
Right.
It's risk alleviation because I'm accepting that it will burn down.
So, what can I do to, you know,
that even less terrible,
it probably won't even,
it's just,
you don't want to not have them because the,
the potential payoff from having them is incredibly high and let's face it.
The upfront investment cost is very, very low.
And, and this is kind of where we fail in security a lot is
we don't understand you, you kind of have to have
a couple of ways to look at it. You can do nothing
and then you're basically backloading all the cost where there
will be an event and then you pay for it,
right?
But that's
the thing, there may not be an event,
-- that's just
-- it right? There might not be,
there might not be,
but you should assume there will be when you're doing this kind of planning, right?
There's you front load all your cost where you build your fireproof house,
which is generally insanely expensive.
But that's also what we try to do in security more often than not is
we try to front load all the costs to prevent the bad thing from happening
and is, well,
you can still build a fireproof house and your house can still burn down, right?
There's gonna be,
there's gonna be things that can burn in the house and if they light on fire,
yes, the structure may be standing,
but all the stuff inside is either gone or it
smells like smoke and you're gonna throw it away.
Ok.
And then there's basically trying to figure out what can I do up front
that will significantly alleviate
the cost after the event.
And like smoke alarms are a great example of that is human life is we'll say, I,
I know it has a value from the insurance companies but, but we'll say it's
yes,
we'll say it's extremely valuable.
And so in our case, like literally spending a couple 100 bucks on smoke detectors can
save that incredibly valuable asset
when there is an event.
You know, if we think about this in the context of security,
what do we do that has minimal upfront cost,
but substantial savings later on.
And, and I bet if I, if I asked 10 people this question,
I would be lucky if I got 10 answers even. Right. And none of them would be the same.
Yeah.
Oh, totally. And I mean, and it even varies.
I mean, there's, you know,
my classic one that I love the most because it's so useless now
-- is don't click links from untrusted sources.
-- That's so.
No,
-- no, no, no. In the
-- modern world. Ok.
Oh, you're saying the advice is terrible. Yes.
That doesn't make any sense.
Advice.
-- Yeah,
-- because for one thing, well, how am I supposed to browse the web,
not only
number
-- two, I mean,
-- a sophisticated attacker is going to send me spam from Kurt
siefried
and right,
like that is what you do. That is how it works.
You know what I remember is, remember the I love you virus
the
20 years
in
the
back.
Well,
I, I remember when it hit because, you know, I, every single,
like very technical person was like, oh God, no, don't open that.
Don't open that.
And of course my favorite was reading this article where this journalist is like,
well,
at first I was suspicious of it but then like 10 more of my acquaintances sent it to me.
So I thought it must be legit and I opened it
like God damn.
But what I love was my mom.
She came home from work and I'm like, oh, please don't tell me you like click the,
I love you thing.
She's like, no, no, no, I didn't. I'm like, ha ha.
She's like everybody else did, but I didn't, I'm like,
I'm OK legitimately why she's like, well, the first one I got was from my boss.
So clearly my boss clearly does not love me. Like, so, you know.
Right.
Right. Obviously.
And then when you see like a whole bunch more of them, it's like, OK, clearly,
this isn't quite right.
That's awesome.
You know, and, and she was like,
literally the only one in the office that didn't click this thing and you know,
of course they spent, well,
the whole world spent weeks cleaning this piece of garbage off the servers.
And
I mean, what really frustrated me is even after that, you know, there were,
it would still kind of pop up once in a while.
Right. Like, somebody would, you know,
open an old one and, like,
it would bounce around the university or something for a while.
But,
yeah, so, I mean, this whole idea of like all this old advice that,
you know, people swear by is like,
-- it doesn't make any sense anymore.
-- It doesn't. And
I have come to the realization
and, and I'm certainly not the only person to do this, but
it, it's obvious that in the way the world has changed with like all this cloud,
all the DEV
ops we've got just the way that everything's distributed.
People are doing work on their telephones, they're using their own tablets,
stuff like that, that
the vast majority of security advice and practices we use today are,
are so comically outdated
and, and we,
we basically have nothing to replace them and we don't
even know where to start in a lot of cases,
which is nuts.
Yeah, I mean, honestly, for me,
one of the biggest things I have encouraged for most people
use
an up to date web browser
as your app, right?
Like, don't, don't use an email app, use a web browser like gmail, you know,
and then right there boom.
That makes life a whole lot more difficult, you know,
because remember we used to laugh about, oh, you know,
it's safe to open up an image because you could never get hacked through an image.
And of course, that changed like 1015 years ago, you know,
with all these buffer overflows.
But, um, I mean, that's, that's honestly, that is about the only,
well,
and the second piece of real world advice I typically offer to people
who are less computer savvy is get a phone or a tablet.
Don't get a computer.
I agree completely.
In
fact that
the neighbor who I helped out, I think it was two episodes ago I talked about,
I brought,
I brought all this, I got it working right as you'd expect
days because there were like millions of updates anyway.
I brought it back to him and I'm like, all right, here we go. I've got all this working.
You know,
I set it up for me his house and I show it to him and then I just looked at him and said,
go buy an ipad
all,
stop using this computer. You don't need it,
just buy a tablet because you will thank me someday.
Yeah. No, I had the same experience this weekend.
I replaced a friend, her parents, you know, they had a wraw RT 54 G
-- router. Like one of those
-- old, oh man, those, those ones could run Linux.
I remember, I bought the, the L model just because it was, it was designed for Linux
and they were awesome little wireless routers like
10 years ago.
But nowadays they're terrible and their range
is terrible and they're just terrible.
Um And it's, you know, 2.4 gigahertz.
So the whole neighborhood is just stomping over each other.
So anyways II,
I gave them like a more up to date router that does five gigahertz and stuff.
And
their desktop computer plugged into the router directly with a cable
was getting slower speeds than like my phone.
Like their desktop is just, and this is after my friend, you know,
she put it through malware bytes and a whole bunch of other stuff
and it's just, this machine is so
I don't, it's just whatever's wrong with it. There's so much wrong with it
that it literally,
you know, it, it's network speed is slower than my phone going over the wireless.
Is it just really old or is it full of garbage? No,
no, it's like a, it's like a, it's like a,
a stand up, you know, integrated windows PC running Windows seven
which tried to upgrade itself to Windows 10 and failed.
Um And I looked at that and I just, I basically had to like, say to myself like, hurt.
No, it's ok. You know,
these are nice people but you don't have to like, you know,
go back into the burning building to save the washer and dryer.
It's just walk away, just walk away,
you know. And luckily, yeah, the, uh, the one,
person does have an ipad so they have at least one reasonably working computer. But,
yeah, you know, it's just like, uh, just,
I literally had to force myself to walk away from it because, yeah,
trying to save that computer would take a dozen hours.
I know the feeling. Well, this is why I had my, uh,
my, my parents' neighbor bring me his computer because then
I would do things and then walk away for the
six hours it took to install windows update and then
later,
well, and this is the thing, right? Like you think this is, you know, this is bad.
Yeah. Try it when you have like a, a corporate network with a 10,000 servers
and three of them are running an accounting app for which we don't have
any support because the person who built this died or went out of business.
-- So, if it dies we're screwed. But,
-- ok, so, so let's latch on to that thought.
And what we end up with though is
in a case like that, they don't even get to pick which option
they want for risk.
Like they have to pick, do nothing
and, and like, prayer,
prayer is their risk management solution.
Yeah, pretty much. I mean, what do you?
I'm glad I'm not in that situation right now. All right, let's just say that.
Yeah.
Well,
and this is one of the reasons I think cloud
is so compelling to a lot of these business people.
It's like,
well from the outside,
it looks like these cloud providers keep everything up to date and running fine and,
and some do and
-- some don't,
-- whatever, man.
You know, it's like a disastrous mess of, like,
on fire sheep running around burning.
What was it, that thing, Amazon was talking about how they don't use,
actually amazon.com, like the, the,
the commerce website stuff apparently doesn't use Aws for their hosting because
it's just not capable enough or something.
There's some articles on this a few weeks ago.
I did not read them,
but I actually know this story and I will not
tell it because the person who told it to me,
I suspect doesn't want it to get out.
But yes, that is true.
And there are many reasons I'll say.
Yeah.
Well, no, I mean, I mean, Amazon, what is it,
over 50% of all online dollars spent on the internet now?
-- Are with Amazon in North America?
-- I would not doubt that because it's so easy to use.
I mean,
whenever I need something that's basically just where I go because it's also,
I click twice and it,
at my door often the next day,
you know, that's, that's what I'm really noticing. Right.
Is all these off like these, uh, what is it?
The Amazon delivery courier bit work piece work now thing that, you know,
where they're delivering packages on the weekend and stuff and it's,
I love it, but again, it scares me where this economy is headed and,
you know, it goes back to that redundancy piece.
You know, Amazon's trying to kind of buy extra capacity and redundancy by, you know,
farming it out to like, essentially sharecroppers who deliver packages.
You know, because, like, Amazon can't afford to build another
separate logistics network. I mean, they are in the process of doing that already.
They're doing that.
Yeah, they're doing that, but I mean, they can't build it large enough, you know.
So they're, they're outsourcing like that last mile as much as possible.
There's nothing wrong with outsourcing and in many instances,
I suspect that that could be part of our,
with security is
we try to do too much in house and you just can't have
that much talent in one place.
And again, that goes back to the whole clown thing of why, you know,
a clown provider can easily get a team of five or 10 security people and, you know,
and really do a good job on their
-- end.
-- Not just that man. I mean, so,
you know, we are security people. I don't have to say,
imagine you're a security person but
like, where would you rather work on Aws doing security or would you rather be at,
you know, like Joe's accounting service in Hamburger shop,
you know?
Yeah, I want to go over with Aws,
you know, I, I know some of the local banks here and they, all the,
when I say small local banks, I mean,
you know, they have less than say, 1000 branches in Canada,
you know, and they generally have one or two captive hackers in house.
I believe that.
And that's it, you know, versus like a major cloud provider.
And, uh,
yeah, I mean, I just,
there are not enough security professionals to go around.
That's part of it too. And it really does frustrate me that we,
you know, think about this.
I remember setting up a DH TP server by hand, way back in the day, you know,
like actually editing the DH p.com file
trying to figure out the,
the various
uh uh
not zones.
What's the scopes, the various scopes, you know,
and attaching them to the right interface and, oh,
just all the black magic
and now you just like turn on the router
and the defaults are like it's on, it works,
right.
You know what I mean? Same thing with secure Webster, right?
I remember setting one of those up and having to
buy a certificate and all that and now it's just
you turn it on it works
and security hasn't really done that.
No, no, we've not
-- like
-- what good security have we, you know,
really the only example I can think of good security by
default that just works is like the fingerprint reader on iphones.
That one, that one's pretty good and well, ok. So here's the deal though is,
yes, the fingerprint readers on, we'll say phones in general
are,
I would say improving security substantially for most people because now a lot of
people I know who just didn't have phone locks because they couldn't be bothered.
I know. I know. Well, that's the thing. We're not supposed to understand it. Right.
We're not those people,
we, we will never understand
how they think or, or why they do the things they do. And that's ok.
But,
but the point is fingerprint readers have these people,
you know, using security now, why?
Because it's easy, it's super easy and they can understand the benefit of that.
Whereas you go to a person and you say, oh,
you just have to do this and this and this and this and this and
you give them this insane laundry list of things they should do to be.
We'll use the word secure in air quotes
and they say this is dumb. I don't care.
And they're not wrong though. They're not wrong.
Well, a great example,
actually coming back to the show notes is the fishing via Scary unicode.
You know, we've known for a long time. So there's unicode characters that look.
Well,
this one's actually special.
If you haven't read this story, I'll, I'll put it in the show notes.
And what's essentially happened is
if you have a certain
glyph character sense, you know, things like Chinese and Japanese and whatnot
there is,
you can't type those on an English speaking keyboard obviously.
And so they, they've set it up in a way so it uses certain, you know,
western character sets
to display
the,
I don't even know if I'd say it. Words is the correct term.
I, I'm not super familiar with the terminology in this, but
basically, so like you can,
if somebody registered what looks like apple.com,
but it's, it's not apple.com, it's a couple of
characters.
It's like
a
Cyrillic.
A
no, no, no, no, no, no, not in this instance.
These are, these are asking characters but they're transformed in a certain way.
Just uh
read the news story. It's
I, I don't understand the terminology around that
these were back to the, just like the standard. So
those are actually mostly solved because now if you do that,
the web browsers in the address bar
color those characters differently in most cases.
So you can understand they are not the same.
And this is just another attack which actually what,
what this really comes down to though is the fact that
it, it, it's a game of can't mouse.
We can't win the browse and, and the browsers are all gonna fix this, right?
They're gonna fix this. It won't be a problem. And then
in, in a couple of weeks or months or years,
someone's gonna find a new way to misrepresent this stuff.
And
that's ok though. Right. I'm not saying we're going to fix it. The trick is fix it fast
because if the scammers only have, you know,
say a two or three week window to work with,
it's not going to be very effective.
Yeah.
No, I mean, this cat and mouse game, that's, that's actually a good point is this,
you know, there will always be new attacks, full stop end of story, right?
And the trick is like, you know, how fast can we
deal with them?
How fast can we say squish them down to like
only being a 1% problem instead of 100 you know,
it reminds me of email spam,
right? I remember when,
like, I remember when I used to have email with no spam filtering
right back in
like the late nineties
and, you know, and then we started this cat and mouse game of like, oh keywords, well,
then they would misspell the keywords or whatever and then, you know, bay
and filtering, which is this, you know, magic of like,
here's a pile of good stuff, here's a pile of bad stuff,
figure out what the differences are and, you know,
classify new stuff and that worked pretty good.
Then they started sending those spams with like,
like randomly written poetry and stuff, you know, kind of whatever,
you know, and, and now I still, what kills me is I still get spam
that you really think would be caught because it's almost always these
like buying database lists of users that have been like verified and
they really want to talk to you about
various technical subjects. So just buy this list and email them.
I don't understand how that
doesn't get caught by the spam folders.
But, you know, the point is basically, I only get like one or two of these a day tops.
I,
I get almost no spam anymore and I don't even
look at my spam folder because my assumption is if,
if you sent me something and it goes in there,
it probably deserves to be in there anyway.
Yeah, I've actually um I've actually had a few false positives, um annoyingly. Um
but I mean, fundamentally spam is not a solved problem,
but we've reduced it enough that it's not a problem problem.
It's an annoyance at best or at worst. You know,
the real challenge becomes if you want to run your own mail servers.
I mean, then you have to jump through all these hoops
to do all the anti spam stuff to be for anybody to listen to you. Right?
Like a great example is I was actually um setting up and testing a new mail server
and so I tried telling to port 25 from my workstation.
Uh and it actually my ISP no longer blocks port 25 outgoing, which is nice for them
to block that.
But
Uh I'm
the IP blocks are registered in the policy blacklist from,
I think it's spam house basically saying like these are
machines that should just never be sending mail directly.
And, and, and honestly, yeah, they're not wrong.
And so the beauty is the remote mail server basically went, you know,
er, something, something you're listed in the policy blacklist, blah, blah, blah,
goodbye, click.
And I was like, ok.
Yeah. No, that, that's,
you know, and, and I'm kind of um
thinking this, you know,
while we were talking about that wordpress
wordpress thing where these guys are building,
you know,
they have a plug in that helps secure your wordpress
site and they were basically classifying bad IP S and,
you know, blocking them
and I'm kind of wondering long term if this like IP reputation thing is,
is going to have to be a thing because, you know, especially with I PV six,
there's just gonna be, you know, these huge blocks of network addresses
with God knows what,
you know, how do we, how do we keep sort of,
how do we stop the bad guys from
constantly hammering on our servers and attacking them?
I
don't know. I mean,
I'm not opposed to blacklist but I see two potential issues is number one,
eventually just every IP will be on the blacklist, right.
Someday
there won't be any,
they have them, you know, they have them bleed off, right? Like the word for
the
word
guys.
So they get booted off after a few hours or a few days or whatever.
Um,
and, you know, and I can see things like, you know, um,
a great example of being ecommerce sites that, you know, give preference to,
you know, um, sessions that are logged in
or sessions that have bought stuff in the past. Right?
Because, like, chances are, if you've, you know,
if you've been to the website and actually purchased stuff in the past,
-- then you're like, chances are you're a legitimate customer and
-- that's,
that's totally fair.
But so here's the other problem I can think of with,
with utilizing blacklist heavily is
with something like I PV six,
we're going to reach a point where you could conceivably have
a significant number of things blacklisted that it could be
a real load on your system in terms of
memory.
Well, I mean, there you would just start blacklisting the networks
that could be
-- realistically,
-- right?
But then you enter problems like, you know, the classic one being,
um whenever I'm on my cell phone on, you know, not on Wi Fi, but on the, you know,
the cell data thing,
you know, I'm coming through a gateway
and there's like a handful of gateway addresses for my cell provider,
you know, so I'll, I'll literally hit sites and like, oh, you're coming from a bad IP.
And I'm like, you know, well,
every single cell phone,
right? So
did something that, you know,
and then that's the other problem.
Right is you can easily, you know,
I could go on the cell network and get that those IP s blacklisted and, you know,
that would be a huge pain in the butt for everybody.
I mean,
probably,
-- yeah,
-- exactly.
And,
but what I see is though is that we're
going to have more of these automated systems where,
you know, um, oh, I saw that IP yesterday and it was behaving reasonably well.
Let's, you know, give it the benefit of the doubt for today,
you know,
versus it's a new IP, I don't know what it's doing. Oh, it's behaving badly. Ok.
Let's try blocking it, you know, for half an hour and see what happens, you know,
things
like that.
That's fair. I, I won't disagree with that and
the trick obviously becomes just having the tools to do this sort of thing.
And I think we're getting really close with a lot of the A I and machine learning
that that's developing and becoming a thing
because I know I, I've talked to a handful of A I and machine learning type folks, uh,
a couple of months ago it was,
and
they were saying that the,
the things they were doing a year ago
are drastically different from the way it works
now because the industry is evolving so quickly.
It's just like
the
web
when you, when you think about where the web went from, like 95 to 2000.
Oh, man. You know,
not, not even just that you got to think the iphone is 10 years old,
11 years ago. We didn't have smartphones. Now.
Can you imagine living your life without a smartphone today? I can't,
that, that would like, yeah, I honestly, like when I lost my wallet I was like, oh,
thank God, I lost my wallet and not my phone.
Like, seriously,
-- you
-- know,
I agree with you completely. I would rather give someone my wallet than my phone
if I had to choose.
Yeah.
Yeah, totally.
Um, yeah. No, the, the world has definitely changed. I mean,
yeah. No, it's, it's a whole different world now.
Oh, you gotta love it.
So
welcome to the future we deserve.
Yeah. Well, and it's
the one thing that really gets me about this
whole machine learning A I stuff is I don't
and I kind of hope we never see like general purpose A I or whatever,
but we're gonna see some hopefully,
like really domain specific A I and machine
learning that will make life a lot better.
Like the biggest thing I could see is, you know,
a combination of self driving cars being centrally directed
could really make traffic better,
you know.
You know,
things like platooning traffic so that you never have to
stop for a stoplight is just kind of meshed,
you know.
Right. And
-- things like that
-- would make a huge difference.
A possibility we'll say.
Yeah.
Anyway, anyway,
or even cars that just know how to merge
cars that aren't driven by people, like literally
anything is better than people.
Yeah, we just had a snowfall uh, this weekend and of course,
100 plus collisions because, you know,
snow in April, that's totally unexpected and people forgot how to drive in
winter already.
Of
course,
the roads have been nice for about a month
and today we've had snow again.
So I'm guessing another whack ton of collisions as people
forget how to drive in the snow because again,
-- it's been like three days since
-- been
snow.
You
know,
I love it.
Well, I'm sure part of it too though.
I bet a lot of people have taken their snow tires off their cars and,
-- and whatnot.
-- A lot of people here run all season because it's just, you know,
it's,
I run all season but man, snow tires, you can't beat snow tires.
True.
I mean, but, uh, in general, I mean, we almost got sideswiped by a guy who just like,
came up way too fast and kind of forgot that it had snow
-- godless
-- people.
Yeah. So he did wave at us and he did look, you know, contrite and apologetic. But
anyway, anyway, let's, uh, we should talk about this,
this siren story from Dallas Texas
because,
well, I can,
I can speak firsthand of that having those stupid n smoke alarms that have failed.
Now,
-- you have been
-- replaced now. Do you still have them or have you given up?
They,
they sent me an updated version of them saying that, yeah,
we know this is a problem with the first version.
That's just great.
Yeah.
So they send me new ones, like a newer model and I put them back up because, well, yeah,
I mean,
I also actually bought old timey smoke alarms and the funniest thing is though,
like, I bought one of the, you know, like the regular 30 $40 ones for the kitchen
and like, yeah, man, like, humidity, the toaster,
everything makes that smoke alarm angry.
Ok. So you have two smoke alarms in each room or just?
-- Well, two in the bedroom, two in the kitchen.
-- Doesn't that seem
unnecessary?
Well, I needed smoke alarms while my other smoke alarms were missing for
a
week.
Welcome to iot everybody.
Yeah, exactly.
So, they haven't false alarmed yet, but it's only been like a week or two.
So I have to say I'm not very impressed
with Nest though because there's been apart from like,
oh, yeah, we know that's a problem.
Here's some new ones.
-- Uh,
-- what else are they gonna do?
Well, just maybe actually offer me some guarantee that these aren't garbage.
I mean, or
what, and part of what me wonders is, uh,
how many other people suffered this,
you certainly aren't the only one.
And I also don't expect them to ever guarantee anything because the
problem being when you start guaranteeing things in the consumer space,
you then have insane liability issues.
But what gets me is, I mean, I had 100% failure rate and it's not like I have some
weird situation,
you know, like I just have a regular house with,
you know, I'm not like,
I, I don't know, like doing whatever it is that makes smoke alarms, malfunction,
whatever it is that
makes
cooking meth in the basement. Maybe, I don't know.
But, um,
you know, that's, that's, that's what gets me right is like,
how many other people suffered this? I, I don't know.
And that's what gets me is,
I really wonder what these iot failure rates are like right now my bathroom scale,
it keeps turning itself on and then runs the battery down.
So my bathroom scale my stupid area.
-- And so
-- now because the battery is dead, you can't weigh yourself.
Yeah.
You know, so,
yeah, I mean, it's just like I, I'm not real impressed with this. Iot
not super impressed.
All right. So this is vaguely related.
So the, the air raid sirens,
not the air
sirens.
And
so for those of you who haven't heard this story,
uh, essentially some, they're blaming hackers, which maybe it was,
maybe it wasn't, doesn't matter,
hackers broke into the warning siren system in Dallas,
Texas apparently and turned them on at like midnight.
And now generally speaking, if warning sirens go off at midnight,
it's because something terrible has happened.
And I'm sure a lot of people woke up and, like, took cover, we'll say,
because this is also kind of tornado season,
which is what you'd expect to be going on.
And they managed to get them turned off after it sounds like
a significant amount of time.
-- But then,
-- but they had to, like, turn them off.
And that's the thing, if you read between the lines,
it sounds like they disabled the entire system in a
manner that it could not be re enabled again.
And
that's, I, I mean, this is kind of like you, with your smoke alarms,
you bought more smoke alarms because
when
that too, right.
But the point being you took them away and sent them off,
you now had zero smoke alarms and that's basically
what happened in da if there was a legitimate
emergency,
what would they have done?
And everybody
that actually works. I, I've gotten text before
with, uh, from, from various things and, and whatever
you could argue that it doesn't cover everybody and, and some people,
-- their phones might be off,
-- whatever it,
it would probably be acceptable as well.
-- Yeah, they, they should have that set up anyway.
-- See what's interesting to me about.
This is we used to live in a world without
911 that's only about 30 years old at this point.
-- That is true, isn't it?
-- I mean,
you think
about it?
The world has become a lot safer things to 911
as a concept, you know?
And I mean,
I, I remember watching those old, uh, you know,
those older films in the fifties and sixties.
Right.
Where somebody would get hurt and it'd be like, you know,
they just load the guy up in a car and drive him to the hospital.
Right.
Right. Well, I mean, ok, let's face it too in the fifties and sixties.
If, if you were hurt badly enough.
I mean, medicine was essentially witchcraft at that point. And,
you know, that's one of the things I love is you look at even 3040 years ago,
medicine was kind of a mess.
And so you think in 30 or 40 more years they're going to look at us and say, you know,
those people were savages.
How did they survive?
And it's fascinating how that works and, and, you know,
hopefully that's how IOT is when in 30 years we look back at IOT and be like,
oh my goodness, those people are banging rocks together.
This is madness.
Well,
and actually this leads to a nice story that Iot bricking
malware that goes around and uses it logs in by its
helmet using known passwords and stuff.
And then like, basically wipes the file system.
Like it basically, I think it was doing like DD,
you know, input files, DEV, random output file is like DEV slash whatever
and it does a bunch of these to basically break the device.
And
part of me wonders, you know, between refresh rates being what they are.
Um, you know, smoke alarms are supposed to be replaced every 10 years.
Um,
you know, things like that bathroom scales,
I don't know what the standard replacement cycle for bathroom scale.
The
standard
cycle is never if you have a normal bathroom scale.
Like,
like my grandmother's bathroom scale who is like
she was like 95 when she passed away.
Like it was the same one I think she bought in, in 1920.
But um I can't help but wonder, you know, people write a couple of these. Um
because by definition,
it's the products with the well known flaws that
are garbage that are going to be well,
relatively easy to wipe off the internet,
you know,
face
to scan the entire internet. Now,
you know, using things like Z scanner mass scan, you can scan the entire I PV for,
-- you can scan the entire I PV for address space in about 10 to 15 minutes. Now.
-- I know.
I know, but it's still, this is, this is vigilante justice and
vigilante justice isn't justice. But I'm also not.
-- No,
-- it isn't a manufacturer
that's got to be illegal.
-- It's completely illegal,
-- but it's certainly not
a
manufacturer
-- because why would they care? Right. They, they already
-- saw
the
refs
or other vendors,
other vendors look bad,
man.
You think somebody wouldn't stoop to that
somewhere on the globe.
See, that's the beauty of this kind of attack.
It only takes one manufacturer to say to one guy, you know, go
get the, go hire somebody to do something deniable.
It's not,
it's not impossible. But I would think the, the cost
in terms of risk, the cost of being caught
far outweighs any potential benefit. I think,
I don't know. Look at the Marae
bot
net.
Have we caught that guy
yet?
But that wasn't a manufacturer.
We don't know,
-- why don't we just blame Richard Nixon. Then you can't prove it wasn't him.
-- So
I'm not saying it was a manufacturer but I'm just
saying like there's a lot of this stuff that where,
or even if they do know who it is, they're in a country where the police don't care.
-- There,
-- there is some of that and, oh, my goodness, this is.
Anyway. Anyway, here's, here's the thing
that
I want to come back to these sirens because I think we've gone to a bad place. But
so
as more and more of these kind of industrial
control systems continue to be attached to the internet.
We,
we often don't have in place. Kind of what happens if,
and, and in this instance it was hackers,
but like
what happens if you have an interconnected warning system
and
somehow something goes wrong and they all go off
and you don't know. You know,
it, it is, it sounds like there, there's no safeguards built into this stuff.
And I think that's true of,
kind of security in general is we often don't have safeguards in place.
I mean, if something terrible happens, what do you do next?
We don't know,
by definition if there's a bug or a glitch, it's,
it's an unanticipated behavior or an UN.
Ok. Yes. You know, I was waiting,
I was waiting for you to say that actually because I'm going to tie this into,
uh,
airline disasters because you keep bringing them up and
now it's my turn to bring them up.
So
when something goes wrong on an airplane,
they have all these processes in checklists to, first of all identify the issue
and then calmly do something about it in
a manner that doesn't instantly crash the plane.
And in computer security,
we basically have like push the self destruct button
and everybody run like that's all we have.
Right.
And,
and I, I,
-- so here's, here's what I wonder that
-- concept. Well, the concept of,
you know, fly the plane first and
troubleshoot the problem second because there's been cases where, yeah,
they literally, uh,
one was a faulty bulb in an instrument and they spent so much time fiddling with it.
They crashed into a swamp,
right. So bad cockpit management, bad, you know,
but
the point being, you know, is that in computing terms, what does, you know,
fly the plane first look like?
And the problem is though,
is a computer system is not something where you can just like,
kind of sort of reset it to a known good state because if you could do that,
you would have done that,
but you can't necessarily reset a plane to a known good state.
I mean, if an engine starts
pulling in some,
in some cases, they do that, like, they literally will just start pulling breakers
and see when the prom goes away.
Like literally,
that's one of the standard troubleshooting tips for
electrical stuff is like literally pull a fuse.
Did the prom go away? No, put the fuse back in, try the next one,
Dan.
You know, although how many times have we done that with,
with security where you just start shutting things off or segmenting networks or,
or whatnot, trying to figure out what's happening.
-- I, I don't think that's out of the question
-- necessarily,
but
we don't, yeah, we don't have a good uh
most networks don't have a good inventory or topology map, let alone, you know,
something where they could clearly,
here's how we're going to do it, you know.
Yeah, I guess where it all ends is I feel like this is a problem
with an immature industry
which we are, we are totally immature
and,
but here, here's the thing I wonder, OK is
how did the airlines become mature?
So from what I've seen in red part of it was forced on them uh
in the form of regulation.
Um,
and some, like some airlines did,
uh, essentially try to have good safety records and good, you know,
to be known for their safety.
Uh, a lot of airlines don't care or, you know, they're, when you,
when they do these investigations it's just like constant, you know,
uh, this one,
airline in Southeast Asia, you know, their,
their training program was found to be totally inadequate.
Like they,
they just didn't train for certain types of situations
which in the industry are generally trained for,
you know,
um, or in one case,
I think it was something like they only got eight
hours of training on a certain type of problem,
you know.
So it, it, the problem is, it still varies and,
and that will always be the problem in computing, right?
Like
internationally, you know, providers in, say America with PC I and stuff, you know,
placed on them might be better than, you know, providers in some,
like eastern European country where, you know, law, what is that?
Right? But I guess the trick then is
in, in the airline industry, if I'm not flying on airplanes in Asia,
I don't have to really care
in
general
Africa is about
if you look at airline disaster stats, basically, if you,
if you take Africa out of the equation that the numbers get much better.
Ok. So regardless. All right, I'm not flying on airplanes in Africa either.
And so
that's great. The problem is your data might be on some,
not even the data you can have nefarious people literally anywhere in the world
that can.
It, it's kind of like actually someone asked me about this this weekend
and I said, imagine if you,
you literally every thief had access to your front door any time they wanted it,
right? How long do you think your house would not be broken into?
And they looked at me in horror for even suggesting that
that's the internet, right?
Like every bad guy on the internet can basically access whatever
they want anywhere at any time because that's how it works.
Well, that's the benefit of this thing,
you know, just like phones,
the benefit of phones is anybody can talk to anybody pretty cheaply.
And now we have tons of phone fraud, you know.
Hi, this is so, and so calling from Microsoft,
you know. Yeah, that's true. That's
true. Or even better. Uh, did you just read this weekend?
The, uh, the IRS will be outsourcing debt collection to private agencies.
I'm sure that won't go horribly wrong.
And I'm just, I mean, ignoring all the, the potential issues for abuse and whatnot.
But
traditionally, you know, it's been very simple.
The IRS does not phone you, they don't, you know what I
mean? Like they send you register. Yeah, they send you registered mail stuff and,
you know,
and now we're going to be having threatening phone calls that are legitimate or,
or maybe not, you know,
um like what gets me in Canada,
like what gets me in Canada revenue? Canada has repeatedly stated.
We will not call you,
we will not email you,
we will send you nasty letters in those little
brown envelopes and if you don't respond to them,
we'll, well, we'll do something
but you know, they repeatedly stated this because,
you know,
they've now got this thing where people are
buying itunes gift cards to pay their taxes.
Supposedly, you know, somebody calls them to threaten them and,
and,
you know, and, and it's gotten to the point now where I know, um,
at least in a lot of Canada now, a lot of retailers will only sell you a certain,
you know, a couple of 100 bucks in gift cards
per day because no, because generally speaking,
somebody comes in and wants to buy $5000 worth of itunes gift cards
are,
yeah, chances are they're getting scammed and they're not just like going nuts,
you know, with $5000 in gifts for their friends or whatever,
you know, and same thing for, um, some of these other sort of cash equivalent things,
you know.
Oh, and a big thing. Oh, I love this.
Magic.
The gathering cards now are being purchased using like fake credit cards and stuff
because basically magic, the gathering cards are cash. They're fungible, right?
You can get, you can make those things on ebay
and I was just reading into them because my, my son is getting into these games. And so
this guy wrote a big long article about how he was
one of the original sort of magic the gathering card counterfeiters.
Like this is 10 years ago.
And he would go to these events, you know, these magic, the gathering tournaments
to sell his fake cards and he never did the expensive cards. Right.
He would do cards that were like 50 100 $200 or whatever. Right.
Because if you're selling like a, you know,
a $30,000 black lotus and it turns out to be fake,
you know,
chances are the police might actually listen to you when you explain it to them,
you know, versus like a $50 card, they're going to be like,
-- you fill out this report and like, please
-- go
away,
we'll never come.
And it's funny to me because I bet if it was trading cards, like baseball cards,
they would maybe understand better and they're like the exact same thing.
But I digress.
So this guy would go to these tournaments and, you know, try and sell these fake cards
and he found that,
you know what his number one method was to deal with people who
-- are a bit suspicious of him for selling these cards
-- sort of cheap.
I bet he
gave them cheaper cards for free.
-- Now what he
-- said they were stolen,
they were stolen,
he said they were stolen.
He's like, oh, well, actually the truth is I just,
I stole this backpack out of a locked car and I just need to move these cards.
That's why I'm selling them so cheap and, and he said,
like the majority of the people would then buy them
and, and on his end, you know, morally and ethically,
he felt a lot better about himself
and, and part of me was wondering morally and ethically, you know,
it's like you're selling a counterfeit good to
people who think they're buying stolen goods cheap.
Uh,
you know, part of me is just like, ok, they're both uh uh reprehensible.
Um, and he actually stopped because he was doing Pokemon cards and he sold, you know,
to adults and then a 12 year old came up to him and he's just like, sorry,
I'm all out and then he
quit or so he says, but
so I recently on Saturday went to the dollar dollar
rama, sorry, it's a dollar store and they had magic, the gathering cards, uh,
packs of 15 for a buck.
So I'm like, sweet,
you know, like,
and so I bought four packs.
I opened up these four packs, uh, 15 cards each.
So 60 cards in total, three of them are printed,
like with the character stuff on both sides.
Totally legit.
Right. So right off the bat there, I'm a little bit suspicious of these cards.
Uh, did the rip test, ripped a bunch of them in half.
They have that blue stuff in the middle. Did the light test? The light
seems to be,
it doesn't seem to be legit.
Uh And then I, my little camera magnifying lens thing finally arrived this morning.
So I took a picture and posted it on my twitter of the, um, what you
call the rosettes,
you know, the, the, the little printing artifacts.
Um
And from what I've seen, they, they seem to be pretty legit.
So you're saying these cards basically check out,
well,
obviously, like the fact that three of them were printed with the characters
of
these are clearly fake cards,
but
they got the blue stuff. They kind of passed the light test and
I'm not an expert but the,
the rosettes look and the print quality is like
these obviously weren't run off on a laser,
you know, or an ink jet printer.
Um, and also judging by the way, the corners are cut, the corners are cut and,
and from what I've read online, they, they do appear to fall into the fake camp,
um, because they're not cut as cleanly as the normal cards.
But here's what gets me,
these are cards that are selling at retail for less
-- than seven cents per card
-- and they're really expensive usually.
Well, and, and so the point is
somebody is counterfeiting these cards
and making money,
like, and they're selling them wholesale to the
dollarama chain
who's buying them for, you know,
probably at most half of what they're selling them for.
Uh,
it's also conceivable that it is one of the legitimate magic printers
that has just erased quality control because they don't need to care.
But, I mean, a 5% failure rate where the cards are printed on both sides with the,
you know, with the character info and they don't have like the magic deck masters
printing on one side. Like that's, that's,
-- that's a 5% failure rate. That's, yeah, but
-- what do they care?
They're selling pirate cards.
I mean, because you have to remember a lot of these organizations, they,
they get this stuff printed
in, we'll say a country that, that is
often times not uh super friendly
to China
maybe.
And,
and it is not uncommon for the actual
market.
But then those cards would, you would think that they would be cut, right?
And they would be using the correct paper and stuff. So
I'm just fascinated because
apparently you can make money counterfeiting cards that like
retail for less than seven cents a card and there's
enough profit margin in there to make it worthwhile doing.
That's what blows me away. Right.
You know, I can certainly see, you know, counterfeiting a $500 card. Sure, easy.
You know, you counterfeit th
oh and that's the other thing is then I was looking on uh what was it?
Alibaba
actually contact wizards of the coast
and
I was actually going
to do
this and it would be really fun to follow this and see if you can chase it.
Well,
actually what I'm going to do today is I'm actually going to go back
to the store and buy a couple more packs of these and leave them sealed
and I wanted to take one.
there's actually a card store, a few blocks away from me like that has, you know,
tournaments on every Saturday afternoon and like legit, you know,
it's a legitimate card store game store, right?
And I want to take them a sealed pack of these things and be like, you know,
what's the deal with this?
Right?
-- Like, are these counterfeit because they sure as hell,
-- yeah,
-- they might know
-- actually, like a 5% failure rate on the printing seems
well, you can't say 5%.
You need to have like,
literally hundreds of thousands of cards before you can even make that assumption.
Well, but three out of four decks so far
-- the
-- lottery
get some more or it could be the batch
that, that was printed, you know, whatever,
I'd buy a handful more and just see what happens before I'd make the argument that
it's 5% because your sample size is still too small to definitively say yes or no.
Well, but statistically if it is unlikely, then I've, I've,
I need to start going to buy lottery tickets or something.
Yes.
That's exactly the takeaway you should hear from this and I think
we can't end the show on a better note than that.
So I'll let you guys know next week. What happens? Hopefully.
Yeah, I can't wait, man. That'll be fascinating.
Maybe you'll get beat up by some magic gathering players.
They, they didn't look real healthy.
Oh, I know. I know. I'm, I'm one of them anyway. Thank you, everybody for listening.
Thank you, Kurt.
Uh If, if you want to see the show notes and any of the crazy topics, as always,
you can go to open source security podcast.com.
You can find links there to Twitter and Facebook and
connect with Kurt and myself and ask us silly questions.
Maybe Kurt will post something on Twitter about his uh magic.
The gathering beat down for his fake cards
and
everybody have a great day. Kurt.
You have a fantastic day and good luck with your magic conquest.
All right. Thanks folks. Enjoy the snow.
Not,
no, just you just, you. All right. Thanks everybody. Bye bye.