Hello and welcome to a special late night edition
of the Open source Security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers.
Oh, we're back to Thought Crime. That's exciting.
I,
I have the coolest thing in that I've ever shared with
you that I'm going to tell you about right now.
So we're recording on, it is a late
for us in the evening. It's just when I would have normally been getting started.
-- My younger days,
-- my bedtime is coming up in a few hours.
But anyway,
so games done quick is coming to an end.
This is literally the last day of it that I'm talking to you.
I'm, I'm putting aside my games done quick time to talk to you this evening.
Just so, you know that
it's, they're all on youtube anyway.
And it's nice.
They're, they're showing up on youtube like two hours after the run,
which is very abnormal.
-- Usually it took like weeks.
-- Are they edited or just raw?
Uh, I mean, they're cut to the correct length. There's no editing to be done.
It's just the live stream. But anyway,
there was a run
done. Maybe Monday or Tuesday. I forget what day
a guy trained his dog to play video games.
It was,
it was so good. And which game?
Uh Gyre?
So Gyra
has the
Kurt's looking it up right now.
No one knows what
Gyre is. Don't feel bad.
It's the one, remember the, the weird robot from Nintendo,
Rob?
-- I wanted that so much.
-- Right. Gyre
was the game the robot played.
Anyway, this guy taught his dog,
he would point at a button on the special controller
and the dog would basically hold down the button.
It was absolutely fantastic. And it's so good. I'll put a link in the show notes.
But it, like, it is the best speed run I have ever seen in my life.
-- Anyway. Anyway,
-- I just, what was that movie where the, uh, with the
-- Nez glove and uh
-- the Wizard?
Yes. Thank you. The Wizard.
-- Uh uh
-- Fred Savage.
It was a commercial for Super Mario Brothers three. That's what the whole
movie
with that.
Yeah, it was, it was good. It was,
well, it's not a good movie at, at all, but when I was a kid,
like I wanted to see it so bad.
I wanted the glove. I wanted the robot.
Oh,
so I, I used to own a power glove.
I don't know if you knew that this is apparently a video game episode now.
But yeah, it's funny because like, and then as an adult,
I also wanted a power glove because then you can, like,
hack them to talk to your computer.
And that's what I did. I, I had one in college and I
made my power glove control a robotic arm.
And apparently I know I've been out of college,
like 20 years at this point and apparently the glove is still in a case
in the
environment,
-- but they're really expensive now. I mean, I literally gave it to the school.
-- Do it.
It's like it's like a Microsoft connect, right?
Those things are impossible to get hold of. Now.
I have one in my basement, I think. Anyway.
-- Ok, we have a real topic, video games, unfortunately
-- today. Yeah.
-- So Pie Torch got hacked. Well, kind of sort
-- of did they?
Yeah, I mean, I would say from an intent point of view they got hacked.
Now, luckily it wasn't like a malicious hacker. It was a classical
I could hack you but I'm not going to hack you kind of thing.
Well, there, there's kind of, I think two stories that,
that I are tied together that,
that you and I have passed around for the last like week or so p torches one.
But then also
there's a story about an N PM rat, a remote access Trojan that was found
and that also ties into some research aqua
security did around deprecated N PM packages.
And I feel like this is just,
I'm gonna say it's a supply chain grab bag of fun.
You know,
the cause of all this is
uh can we, who should we blame?
No, no, no. There's a very
-- simple
-- blame dice that
there's a very simple root
cause for all this failure and it is efficiency.
I know why you said that and you're not wrong but it definitely needs an explanation.
Oh yeah. No, this is like the, the the six levels down of like why did this plane crash?
Because the guy sneezed because he didn't blow his nose.
It's no, a better example would be the Malcolm in the middle.
Change the light bulb to the garage where the guys
he goes,
-- we have to get a light bulb or the door,
-- the sticky drawer,
right.
The door doesn't open. Right. We got to get a screwdriver.
Oh, the screwdriver drawer doesn't work. Right.
And he is changing his oil and his wife's like, can you change this light bulb?
He's like, what do you think I'm doing
anyway? But yes, that is exactly right.
So Pytorch is,
uh,
kind of an important Python library for A I stuff.
It's like the library that runs probably 90% of the A I on the planet.
-- Probably more like 99.
-- Ok.
The bigger stuff.
-- That's fair.
-- Yeah.
So it's just a little important because the thing, this is what I love.
I was like, I'm, I'm a Python used to have been forever and Python comes from big data.
Right. Guido Van Rossen worked at the Italian supercomputer center.
So Python has always been
big data
and
a natural extension of big data obviously is A I, right, those two camps
kind of live next to each other.
And so Python is,
I'm going to say a resurgence, but it really never went away.
It's been, yeah, it's been like top 10 language for probably 20 years or so now,
-- at least
-- like it is dominating
-- A
-- I it's, it's dominated a lot of data.
You got stuff like panda and numpy and fuzzy wuzzy. Like just things.
Yeah, Python does a ton of cool stuff and it's so easy, it's so easy to use.
And what I love is like stuff like fuzzy wuzzy and, and numpty and panda are, you know,
written in sea or whatever and are just super optimized out the wazoo
and super capable libraries that do insanely
complicated stuff with data and language.
-- And so
-- I have, I have a funny story about that actually.
So I remember when I was doing a bunch of work,
when I was doing like some Bitcoin analysis stuff.
I didn't talk about it long ago. I'll see if I can dig it up at some point. But anyway,
there was one point where I had like, I think it was 60 million basically bits of data
that I needed to do something with.
And I was like, I wonder if I can just put these in a Python dictionary.
And, yeah, and it worked perfectly and I, I told a data nerd.
I know that he's like, oh, yeah, you can go way higher than 60 million.
I was like, what? That, that seems like ridiculous to me.
And when you look at Hitler stuff like how panda loads data, it's like,
it's engineered to load a lot of data.
Yeah. I wasn't doing anything.
I was using a literal Python dictionary
and it loaded up 60 million records and
then I was like sorting them and searching them
at ridiculous speeds.
I've done this forever where I use like I just use keyed
dictionaries to like basically sort in unique stuff based on the keys
and just,
I've literally never thought about how big is it
anyway. OK. OK. Python is a great language. Sure. We all know that
-- what happened to Pytorch.
-- So Pytorch lives in github
-- shocker,
-- like everything else does
pretty much all of the open source,
pretty
much.
There's still a little bit of it somehow left in
source horch which I find so bizarre every time I
end up there and I have to download something from
there because it's kind of still very dodgy feeling.
But anyways
and there is some in git lab, but by and large github
is the winner
of this.
Github
wants to make life easier for developers, right?
And so they've done some like some conceptually
simple stuff like we basically will host your
GIT, we will Oh, we have an issues tracker, we have a project thing with Kan
boards
and they've also done some stuff that is
quite complicated,
but
I guess it's intended to probably
reduce developer friction and community friction.
And so things like
there's settings where, you know, oh, if you contribute,
uh if you commit to this project is accepted,
you can be a contributor except it's kind of an automatic
plague setting. Apparently
-- not necessarily. So, this one, what happened?
-- Is it a default or not?
-- See, I wasn't clear on that.
-- It's not a default. No, it's not default.
So what, but what? So what happened here with Pytorch was these researchers?
Basically,
they realized that the
way Pytorch would run C I jobs in non github
hosted environments because there's like different ways to run C I and the github
hosted C I is shockingly secure. Apparently I shouldn't say shockingly
it's better.
Well, it's just, it's, but it's piggybacking on Azure. So it's containers and V MS.
Well, sure. And it's, it's, they, they,
they don't recycle anything like they throw it
all away and start again fresh every time,
-- which is how you should do it.
-- Right. Yes, exactly. Everyone throw everything
away.
Well, not even for security, but just so that your build is clean and not
-- depending on magic from another build.
-- That's complicated.
It's a long story because there anyway, I'm not getting into it today.
So,
what happened with Pytorch was these researchers found
that Pytorch was running what they call it,
like they called, like self hosted.
C I,
I forget the exact terminology they use
but
so they're running like the self hosted C I, and it reused
environments
between certain runs and I don't know exactly if it,
I'm sure it threw things away occasionally.
I don't, I don't know all the details here. But anyway,
that part of it is like environmental variables,
recycling them between runs could be useful.
But again, I would say in anyways. Well,
yeah, anyway,
so what ends up happening is they realize that Pytorch has a configuration setting.
So I I should say, OK,
so the the way this often works is like if I
submit APR a pull request and get hub to a project,
it doesn't just like run the tests, right? The
pull request is, is sent
and then a developer has to look at it.
And the developer from the project would be like, OK, this looks like a good commit.
Let's run the test, click this button, run the test now.
But if you're a member of the project quite often,
the test will just run because the assumption
is that members of projects are trusted.
And so
like the test should run because you want the test
to run and you get your feedback real fast.
All that jazz, right? Like very dev
ops,
all that stuff
now.
So what happened was these folks figured out that
Pytorch had a setting, not just for members of project but
for anyone who had a poll request accepted in
the past being maybe this person is trustworthy.
Right. Maybe, maybe not. I don't know. Now, so what happened was
they,
they submitted a Typo Fix
to Pie Torch because obviously, like
any reasonably sized project has typo somewhere and you can totally fix them
and they're usually pretty quick about accepting these things.
So like, oh, they, they fix like four words, whatever, good enough except, you know,
no big deal.
It's a read me.
Now, once these researchers got that commit accepted,
which they literally did this with this intent, right?
It wasn't like they accidentally did this along the way.
They knew once they got that accepted,
now, they could create a poor request that had malicious content,
right?
And that malicious content was designed to attack the self hosted runners.
I don't recall exactly why you can't attack github
runners.
I think it's because they're thrown away each time, but don't quote me on that.
But anyway, so
they create a poll request.
The thing that makes it brilliant is they made the poll request a draft poll request.
Now, I
know there's a concept called the draft pull request where I could,
let's say I have a poll request I'm working on and I want to be like, hey, developer,
I would like an opinion on like this particular thing I'm doing.
But the purpose of a draft is you
can't like accidentally accept it because goodness knows,
more than once I went to review something for someone and I hit, you know,
merge instead of like something else I meant to click.
So anyway,
that's kind of the purpose of draft this pull request
as drafts also doesn't show up in anyone's like radar.
So no one even knows this thing is running crap on their runners.
And then like the article goes into all the shenanigans they could
do and they basically could have taken over the Pytorch project.
That's the thing with any complex system, there's gonna be
clause
for sure.
That's just how it is.
And so it's like, you know, I keep coming back to the whole thing if,
if you gave me a billion dollars taught at
the Linux kernel and say it's security bug free.
Would you bet your life on it? Of course not. Would you even a $10,000 to review?
I throw a heck of a party,
you know, like given
$10,000 and a lot of effort to review
organizations, github
settings and repo settings and configurations.
Would you bet that there's no way to hack into them with something clever like this?
No, of course not. Like there's,
well github,
I bet, I bet a github
organization has hundreds to thousands of settings
that can be twiddled. Like it's an amazing project.
I used to look through the settings once in a while just
to see what was new stuff there because this is a,
this is a challenge I have with being a cloud.
Ain I literally have had like where somebody's like, Kirk,
can you change this permission setting in Google Drive?
No,
no, I can't. They're like, yes you can. And I'm like, what? And he's like,
I'm like, no, you have to add a, you have to do and he's like, yeah, you can do that now.
And I'm like, what? Right click and like,
oh yeah, you can a perfect example. Somebody at the CS A wanted Zapp year for teams.
And I'm like, oh jeez, I don't know. The last time I looked, it was pretty expensive.
So I looked at it again.
Yeah,
we had to pay an extra $22 for the year prepaid to go upgrade to
teams because it's the same price effectively as
our existing grandfather doesn't exist anymore plans.
And that
-- like, I can't keep up with all this. But
-- anyway, anyway,
now here is the one thing I will say, no,
-- I think
-- that's actually an important thing because these blank is of service
providers are constantly adding new features and they have to pick a default
and quite often they pick a default where they want it to work for people.
-- I
-- mean, for sure, for sure, but that's not the case here.
-- Well,
-- no, no, but I'm just saying in general, but like
-- to for security people to stay on top of this. I don't know how we can, we
-- can't.
That's the reality, I think.
-- And I'm paid to do this. Like the pytorch people are not. Oh, for
-- sure.
Well, some of them might be.
I don't, I don't know exactly what the structure of py torch is.
-- They're
-- probably not paid to go through github
-- repo settings.
-- Uh, probably not.
And look, you, you raise a good point though, of the fact is
there is so much complexity in a lot of
this stuff that securing it is virtually impossible.
Now, here's the one thing I would say though, in most instances,
if there is an attack like this against Pytorch,
like let's say the developers like went
the extra mile and they started actually attacking it.
I think there's a high probability it would have been detected
because Pytorch is widely used by a lot of people.
We're back to the open source thing of it only takes one person to say, hey,
I saw this weird thing and for it to be in github
issue or on hacker news and it goes kaboom real fast.
Yeah, the th this is why I went into open source,
I got into security and I was running both Windows and
Os two and Linux.
And I very quickly realized with Linux, I had documentation,
source code manual pages, all that good stuff.
It was awesome.
And I realized from a security perspective I can take some courses on windows,
which I did,
but I can never really know what's going on and I looked at what
these windows security people were doing and this is back in the late nineties.
Right.
And so, like, the people that could work G DB and actually debug a windows thing and,
like,
you know, understand what's going on.
It was magic versus with Linux,
I just open up a text file in an editor and read
their
source
code. It's much easier
-- and there's mailing lists where they, you
-- don't have to reverse engineer anything
and there's mailing lists where they explain why they did it that way and there's
IRC channels where you can actually poke them.
And so this comes back to this in the open source world, right?
You can file an issue in github if you found this in a commercial product that, well,
how would you notify them or other people?
You can maybe notify the company,
-- maybe
-- solar winds. Yo.
Exactly. Right.
How do you like if, if I find some random problem in like a Chinese device driver?
Like good luck. No, like, right.
And I think that's one of the secrets to open source and why
it has won so heavily is that we don't hide our problems.
And it's not, I'm not saying like, companies intentionally hide their problems,
but they do make it very hard.
Like even just to figure out who to talk to to report it to them.
Like uh the CS A, we're looking at a new vendor for something. I
as far as I can tell,
they do not have a privacy officer or ad po
or a secured team or anything like everything they say,
talks, says talk to customer support.
And I'm like, I hopefully they have a path test like this maybe.
Yeah, I know how that look.
II I want to tie this into the N PM story now about the rat, right?
The remote access Trojan.
So this,
I think lends some credibility and I know what
we're talking about could be misconstrued as Linus's law,
which is with enough eyeballs, all bugs are shallow.
I think that is nonsense. So anyway, this this rat story
from N PM, right? I
think this is a good example of what you're talking
about in the context of open source because this is where
someone
added a backdoor package to N PM
and it looks like it got picked up in about a day,
right?
Like this is where you had security researchers doing this work looking for things
and they found it because they were looking for it. And this is a very unique
angle. Open source brings is
there are security people like they are actively hunting for this kind of stuff.
Well, it's no, no, it's not security people.
It's security companies which is even better because this is, that's
bread and butter is saying like this N PM package.
Good, bad, risky, not risky.
And so, like, yeah, they found a package with one index dot Js file a DLL,
an exe and another binary file.
-- It's,
-- it's a clever attack. Like, if you read the story, I'll put it in the show notes.
-- Like it's cool.
-- But also if you look at that,
like, library
it, like, if a sec,
let me rephrase if a security person looks at that
library at all for more than 10 seconds immediately,
they're going to get the heebie Jeebies.
Oh, yeah. Yeah,
for sure.
And that's the other thing with this stuff is like, it's so
it's easy for somebody to make a claim and publish the claim.
But it's also easy for me to validate
it.
And that I think is one of the strengths of open sources,
not that there's a lot of eyeballs looking at the bugs.
It's, but that when somebody sees the bug,
they can actually get it bubbled up real
quick and dealt with real quick because like,
I love it when people make claims about open source.
And I'm like, cool, like, what line of code is it?
That's
right. That's right.
-- Show
-- me
-- the code and, and the, the other thing that I think is magic here
is like
open source is unique in the context of select this company phylum.
-- I've heard of them before, but I couldn't tell you why
-- they're a security firm. Flam
did this work and everyone benefits from the work of this one company.
Like that's a, that is a big freaking deal. Yeah. Right.
Like when you're a, a closed source company working on your own products and like,
sure Flum
has closed source products. Goodness. So like we do at Anor
as well,
we can make a change to our product and that will benefit our customers.
But now if we make a change to an open source library, now we benefit
everyone using that stuff in open source.
-- Like it is a hugely powerful, powerful concept, you know,
-- OK,
here's a really interesting thing on their website.
They actually list attacks blocked in the last 24 hours,
33,968 new packages analyzed 1.6 million number of file,
scanned 120 malware packages identified
that's
like identified. What just it just says malware packages identified.
So well, the thing is right is, I mean, what gets me is stuff like N PM and Piye there,
there is literally no barrier to becoming a contributor and uploading something.
And so
I also wonder how much of this is like people doing their first like, oh,
I meant taking a virus course and I just want to upload and see what happens, right?
-- Like that's the thing that always blows my mind when I don't, I
-- don't,
I think it's real.
I I suspect this is marketing speak because I
think if they were real honest malware packages,
they make a lot more noise about it. Right.
They, they, for example, like this, this blog post they wrote about a rat.
But that's kind of what's amazing to me is so, like,
it's like every time where some company is like, oh,
we get 6 million cyber attacks an hour and it's like, yeah, somebody ran in map.
That's, let's see, 1000 ports times 100 posts is like 100,000
scan,
you know.
Exactly. But the, the point I was getting at is there is no barrier to entry.
And yet the problem is this
minimally not terrible.
Like, realistically,
if Attackers really want to upload a malware package to a repo, like to not a repo,
sorry, an ecosystem they absolutely can.
And yet we have a shockingly low rate of this happening.
It's, it's rare enough that it makes the news.
I know.
And that's, that's one of the things I think about a lot in,
in this context is when you listen to a lot of security people,
it's like the constant, the world is ending.
Cyber Pearl Harbor. Yeah, everything is terrible.
Like, it's a miracle that we're not all dead.
And at the same time it's like
I pay my bills online and I just ordered
some stuff from Amazon that's getting delivered later today.
Like,
-- I
-- mean, I do
like, I remember when my credit card got hacked and,
or used to buy some food in Singapore.
And I was, like, trying to figure out where,
and I narrowed it down to one of two places this car wash I use, which if they did,
you think they would have done it years ago?
And I did use a specific online retailer to buy a
niche thing that only could be bought at this one,
you know,
probably
store
and they had a really dodgy, like home brew ish looking Ecommerce site. Like it was,
it's, you know, and I was just like, oh, whatever, you know,
I want this thing anyways and
because, you know, if you go through like, shop fire Etsy or ebay or something,
you know, it's gonna be fine.
But it's, you know, when you get to somebody who built this site,
like 20 years ago and it's still running,
-- you know? So, I'm pretty sure that's how I got.
-- Definitely PC I compliant.
Yeah.
No, it's looking at stuff like pytorch and well, on this, this malware rat, like,
every time there's a malware rat, like it tends to get in the news
and
let's be real.
If these security companies were finding a lot more of these, they'd be saying. So,
like, they
trying to press office and that's,
-- and that's how we, no, it's actually not that bad of a problem.
-- It's, there are,
I think there are instances where it is. I'm sure there are organizations that have
solar winds and stuff. There's Absolutely.
Well, not even just solar winds.
I think the,
the Kaspersky thing we were talking about
before we hit record where basically some,
basically, probably a government,
like,
attacked Kaspersky in the most ridiculous way possible with
like undocumented CPU functionality and iphones and it's,
I'll, I'll find the link to the talk and, and it was at CCC.
It's nuts.
It could be a state level actor or it could
-- be a university group with a bunch of
-- spare time.
It's not, it's not at all. It's definitely, anyway, it doesn't matter.
I'm not, I'm not going to dwell on this right now. The point is
that
we can sit here and say if someone attacks open source,
it's gonna get found right away and some of them will.
But
the,
you also cannot deny the point that there are almost certainly
like nation state level Attackers that have infiltrated open source projects
and have inserted malicious code that none of us will ever detect
because it has been done.
So in a manner that is functionally undetectable by a normal person.
Ok. Every off by one bug.
Is it a typo or is it a nation State inserting a back door
-- and,
-- and you, you can't, you will never know.
But there, I guarantee that has happened.
However,
here's my point in that and this comes to
the Mossad versus not Mossad argument where there's this,
this paper that was written,
it's probably been a decade or more now and I will link to it.
But the author basically talks about dealing with threats
as a mossad or not Mossad angle where like
if Massad wants your files,
they will give you like he, what is his comment?
I think he says they will replace your cell phone with a brick of uranium.
Wait for you to die of brain cancer and buy your estate.
That is the type of attack you cannot stop.
And that is the kind of attack that
is I guarantee has infiltrated open source projects.
We will never know
they might get caught someday, but they probably won't.
Well, but no, no, but here's the thing, even if they did get caught, they'd be like,
-- oh, we found an off by one bug in the
-- software, right?
But here's the thing,
we can't defend against those attacks either, right?
This is an attacker with infinite resources and infinite time.
We don't have infinite resources or time on our side.
Now we however can defend against,
we'll say the the low sophistication Attackers and the like spray and pre attacks.
And this is like that rat for example, might be one of those.
See, that's, well, I don't know that we can because for example,
if you look at ransomware,
like my understanding is the vast majority of
ransomware is using stuff that's months old.
No, no, no. In the open
-- source world, Kirk.
-- Oh, in the open
source world, sorry,
-- like
-- attacks against open source. Yes, I agree. Ransomware will never go away.
Like log for Jay.
It's even in the open source world, like it's, it's still floating around.
There's like, what are the stats?
Like,
I think you said some number of 60% of downloads of log
-- for Jay instances are still out of date or whatever it
-- was.
Uh, sonatype had a report a while back.
I don't, I'll see if I can find another copy of it. But anyway,
it's a lot. But here's the thing too with log for
shell
long for shell, I don't think is as bad as we thought it was.
And I think if it was a lot more of these organizations would have been popped
or you'd see more widespread attacks.
I mean, I think that's the reality of it.
-- I
-- mean, it definitely, if it is exploitable they would have exploited it.
It's kind of a pathology. But it's true. Ee,
exactly. I think,
I think anyone running it in a way that could have been exploited probably was.
And like, yeah,
a lot of people are downloading vulnerable versions but I think at the same time the,
the reality we see doesn't match the reality of the data.
And the reality we see is probably the correct one.
Yeah. Well, I mean, I'm still seeing scans for Front Page
that hasn't really existed in 1520 years and yet,
you know, so, like, if you're running a vulnerable front page server.
You are for sure. Paul, it's like,
it's like every time like those
that this week's uh what was it? Some flavor of VPN
server has a flaw that you need to patch
because it's being like widely exploited Juniper stuff.
It's some brand I've never heard of
anyway.
More than what it's literally the flavor of the week, you know,
and, and here's the thing,
like my other example is I remember when I ran an elastic search honey pot for a while,
the ransomware people were like ransoming each other because they just,
it was hilarious. But anyway, the point is now all that said,
I don't want us to end on some like, oh, it's really not that bad.
Everyone like there are systemic problems in this space.
There is a lot of work to do and none of us have a free pass to be like,
-- uh it'll probably be ok
-- and going back to my efficiency thing.
This is one of the worst problems I think in open source is that
open source is so efficient to use that you can generally
get away with as a company grabbing a bunch of it,
shoving it in your light bulb to make the light bulb work
-- and then walking away from it and never supporting
-- it and never touching it again
-- for sure
-- because I'm
sure my Hugh light bulbs have like really not had an OS update in since I bought them.
-- Uh No,
-- they probably do.
Like,
I actually keep an eye on this from time to time because I check my bulbs and they,
every couple of months
there's an update to my Hugh light bulbs.
I think the app will tell you for
updated.
-- It's
-- on automatic updates. Everything is
in the
middle of the night.
Uh, I have no idea what these version numbers mean.
Oh, wow. The version numbers across my light bulbs are all over the place.
So the challenge is people turn their lights off. Sometimes
I know I'm literally seeing that like the whole like
this is why
this is why like a bunch of my basically,
once a year I turn on all of my hue light bulbs and then I manually
update all the firmware for the things that are off like when they normally update.
-- But anyway, it doesn't matter. It's
-- actually not too bad. A couple of them.
Uh There's a couple of lights in here that probably no,
the kitchen light's been turned on or is that?
Oh, is that the anyway, is it?
We
don't need
to do this,
we
need to do.
It's
not as bad as I thought.
Well, but he was a premium brand and like I'm sure those cheaper brands are not so
premium,
I think. Anyway.
Well, and this goes to some of the things we've been looking at is like
part of the challenge is
ok, perfect.
It's like having emergency generator capacity why
would I have emergency generator capacity as
a power provider when I could like have generator capacity that I can sell?
Like, why would I have a capacity that I'm not selling?
And so,
but it goes to this like these efficiency arguments of open source
works so well and it's so good and it's so easy.
Why would I not use it? Especially when I don't have to give back or contribute.
And I, I don't know if there's a solution to these, that these challenges,
you know,
-- some of
-- them, a lot of them don't have, a lot of them don't have solutions.
And look,
here's what it comes down to and this is
exactly where the pie torch stuff lands and I'll,
I'll, I'll just end it on this note.
All of this,
everything we've talked about fundamentally boils down to a risk decision.
Your comment about
I own a generator.
Shouldn't I be running it and selling the excess capacity? For example?
Well, that's a risk decision. Right? If I
think I'm going to need power,
then I have to decide like is the cost of not running for
a period of time versus the cost of buying and maintaining a generator?
Like,
let's do the math and figure out like is my downtime worth more than the generator.
Maybe it is. Maybe it is. It depends
on a more personal level. I live here in Alberta. Right?
And we had last week that emergency alert to,
like, turn off your stove and stuff because, right,
because it was minus a billion degrees.
-- Yeah.
-- Actually the one place hit minus 50.3 or something,
it was only like, minus 40 here plus windshield. But anyway,
but the point that's kind of normal for this area.
In fact, everyone minus 40 is where Celsius and Fahrenheit cross.
So you can just say minus 40
it doesn't matter which scale you use.
-- Alberta
-- was using just over 12 gigawatts of power
and you know what the buffer was?
10 megawatts, that's the only excess capacity they have.
Like, that's not a lot. That's 10, 1 megawatt generators.
Hey, they
above the line. All right
-- above the line.
-- It's
the alert
and power usage dropped 100 and 50 megawatts in five minutes.
I'm impressed. I think in America it would have gone up after such an alert.
I was part of the problem.
I had my car plugged in with the block heater that consumes about a kilowatt.
Wow, that's a lot.
And now I was like, you know,
that is stupid because I only need to heat it for an hour or two before I use the car.
So I have one of those little, you know,
like timer plug things with a 15 minute increment thing, ma jiggers.
And so, yeah, I just have it, it's set. Now,
I do plug it in to run between six and eight in the morning,
which is not, I mean, the power usage time
and you'll save a ton of money too. So,
anyway,
risk, it's all about risk. And this is the Pie Torch project
has to make a risk decision about how much effort are we going to put into?
I'll put security and air quotes versus just like running a project.
And the other problem with this risk thing though is
it assumes that people know that they even have risk,
let alone
even remotely, have quantified it.
Uh, everyone knows they have risk. Most people don't know what to do with it.
And this is true of security people, security people,
I think are some of the worst of all of making up crap.
-- That isn't real
-- true.
And there's also a lot of like, real risks that they ignore and,
or don't even think about,
like, when I talk to people about off fender backups and I'm like,
what if your account gets deleted?
They're like, oh,
-- yeah, it
-- an unknown risk.
I mean, I need to think about that one because it might not matter.
No, I don't mean unknown, unknown, but I mean,
I'm talking about common risk that that person specifically is ignoring.
Oh, yeah. No, that's fine.
-- That's called accepting the risk and if you accept the risk,
-- great.
-- Well, no, but do they even know about it? Uh,
-- do they know they're accepting the risk?
-- Some people might, some people might not.
-- I was going through a backup system.
Then I remembered, oh, we have this other org that I set up.
I don't have backups enabled for it. Oops. And I went in and did that
well, but here's the other part of that, let's say you don't have backups,
let's say you're the, it,
for a company, everything crashes, company goes out of business.
Whose problem is that really, you're just going to go get a new job.
Like the owner of the company is the one who actually
outsourced the risk to an employee who didn't do their job.
And so that's the funny thing is like, when you talk about risk in that context,
you think, oh, it's the, it person's risk.
No, it's the owner's risk.
They outsourced it to the, it person who then dropped it on the floor.
And that's what makes these discussions so difficult and weird.
And this is where something like Pie Torch is in a
situation just like that where the vast majority of these people,
it's not their problem.
-- Pytorch is the Kubernetes of a
-- I, uh, that, that's fair.
Like, it's just a foundational building block now.
No, I know,
-- I know that's irrelevant to my point.
-- But
what gets me is nobody's gonna even remotely help them out or, you know,
give them more than a dollar.
Well, we're gonna find out, aren't we? So,
and, and here's the thing, even if no one helps him out, will it matter? It'll be fine.
Maybe it won't. I think my guess is it'll be fine.
They'll have some incidents, they'll deal with the incidents and then
that's just the way it is. It's like, it's like an episode of Star Trek. Right.
Everything gets crazy for a little while and then it just goes back to normal,
-- then
-- they reverse the polarity.
Yeah.
And then, like, uh, we don't have to change anything, anybody,
no need to do any sort of post mortem on what just happened.
Just go back to doing everything the way we were doing it before.
You know what my favorite thing is, is how they like,
took away Jordy's visor and like they made commander
data more human to explain the actor's aging.
No data. No, no, they can explain that data was programmed by doctor soon to age
-- naturally as part of his like, just experience.
-- Yes, that's Wink Wink.
Even though he would live for hundreds and hundreds of years
and Jordy lost the visor because Levar Burton wasn't going to come back
if they made him wear it again because he hated that thing.
That's why Jordy didn't need a visor anymore.
But anyway, anyway,
-- but they made him wear those wonky contacts.
-- It's,
it must have been better than the visor because he came back.
Well, it's funny to me because one of the original, hang on a sec.
Um because one of the original core like rules from Gene
Roddenberry was you have to be able to see aliens eyes.
You can put as much junk on them as you want,
but actors emote through their eyes a lot. And so you have to be able to see their eyes.
So in the original Star Trek, no matter what,
you could always see the alien's eyes and
mostly true in the later, Star Treks and Jordi was like the one exception to the rule.
But also the uh, I want to say the brain, you know,
-- the way they wear those goofy helmets,
-- like the, the brain wear helmets.
-- I mean, there were a handful of characters with helmets during the show,
-- right.
But, I mean, even the brain took their helmets off once in a while.
-- Poor Jordie was
-- like, I don't think the Breen ever took their helmets off.
Uh, they knocked one out, remember?
And they, like, hid in its uniform.
-- But
-- I don't think we know what a Breen looks like under its uniform.
Well, I mean,
they've probably must because they've killed them and knocked them out and stuff.
I don't think we've ever seen under a Brien's helmet that I know of anyway.
All right, here's, here is a,
to do for the audience because we need to end this episode.
Send us a picture of a Breen.
If, if there is information about what a Breen looks like under their helmet,
let us know because, and, and if you don't know what we're talking about like,
go watch more Star Trek.
All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening.
Go to over
security podcast.com. Hit up the show. Not, it's Easy Pounds
podcast. Hashtag I
asked it
out
-- like Google result, it's whatever.
-- Oh, no,
sorry. This is a meme. Never mind.
Kurt. Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.