Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in reading CV entries, Josh Pressers.
-- I mean,
-- I try not to but it's been,
it's been a week man.
I realized I say that and I, I don't think I've actually read a CV E properly
in
-- months, years.
-- I look at them every day for sure, for, for various reasons.
But like I scan, like, if they show up in the news,
I'll scan one but like I used to read all of them
talking about news.
We're going to discuss
NVD. Well, that's going to be part of the discussion.
I don't know if we can, can I read the announcement?
No,
I'm gonna read you the announcement and I want you
to tell me what you think that would mean.
So for anyone listening, NVD, the National Vulnerability Database,
it's something hosted by Nist in the United States.
Nist is the National Institute of Standards and Technologies.
They do things like they have standards on cybersecurity reference.
Peanut butter. Yeah, they, they $1000 a pound peanut butter. They like
clocks and, and
you know, my favorite is all the people I know who are like, oh,
there's two kinds of countries,
those who use the metric system and those who went to the moon,
except do you know what the definition of an inch is?
-- Yeah, 2.25 0.4 millimeters.
-- That's right. They literally have defined the inch
off of,
off of the metric system.
It's not about 25.4
millimeters that's defined
by.
Anyway, here's what
NVD has put on their website. They put this on the website on February 15th.
-- I use a way back machine to figure out exactly when this went on. I love
-- that.
They went with a very
-- calm yellow.
-- Hold on. We, we'll get to that. All right.
So here's what the notice says.
-- It's in big yellow, a big yellow box, but
-- a very soothing yellow.
And it says Nist is currently working to establish a consortium to
address challenges in the NVD program and develop improved tools and methods.
You will temporarily see delays in analysis efforts during this transition.
We apologize for the inconvenience and ask for your
patience as we work to improve the NVD program.
How would you interpret that statement?
It's
-- no, you know the answer, but that's not the question. It's
-- pining for the fjords.
OK.
Here's what a normal person would think when they read that
they would think.
And
VD has slowed down that they're overwhelmed
and they need to figure something new out. And
I think that would be a reasonable
way to interpret that.
That's not what happened.
-- But
-- then that's ignoring the actual what the growth of CV E
entries is and the growth of the nist work and everything.
We, we'll talk about that in a minute.
-- I want to talk about what NVT is doing first
-- as an outsider with
no domain specific knowledge about this.
It's kind of weird but like, OK, the,
this government program is kind of rejiggering stuff
and it's gonna get their stuff together.
But
I would even knowing nothing about Mr CV E or NVD,
I would point out when is the last time
you saw a government notice like this?
-- And the answer is never, I,
-- yeah, I don't think I've ever seen something like this.
This is not something that I,
I've never seen a government agency in Canada or
the US or basically anywhere on the Planet Post.
This is like a restaurant saying, you know, we're closed for, uh, renovations.
Totally not the health department shutting us down.
Yeah, exactly. Now, here's kind of what happened.
I saw this notice
and
there were a handful of folks and like linkedin and Master on and stuff that, like,
what's going on at NVD.
And I didn't think anything of it.
I just figured, oh, there's, they've slowed down a little bit,
there's gonna be a lag between CV ES being released and CV ES being analyzed like,
whatever that happens.
And I didn't think twice about it. And then
a couple days later,
I was actually doing some data analysis work
uh on the Linux kernel data specifically.
And I have a graph I in
it's saved in my elastic search instance that I used to do this work
that just shows the current CV E data
versus what NVD has enriched.
And I opened that graph
and NVD hasn't slowed down.
They stopped.
And I was like,
oh boy, like what is going on here?
And now I wanna,
I wanna add before we go on because we're probably gonna crap on NVD
a lot and I know we've crapped on them a lot in the past.
Like they have a monumental task.
It's very hard and they actually do a pretty good job, all things considered
like it's a, it's a tough job.
I know Nist as a whole is like chronically underfunded,
I'm sure the NBD program is underfunded and I'm sure all of the people who work on this
are doing vastly more work than they should have to do.
So by all means anyone involved in this program, please do not
like, pick on these people or crap on them or think they're bad people.
They are not bad people, they are like superheroes doing the Lord's work here.
Well, and I would also argue that having the NVD do this, uh How do I phrase this is, oh,
I'm just going to go with is wrong in the sense of number one,
the NVD will only ever enrich data,
the US government cares about because that's who funds this.
-- No, they enrich like everything.
-- Let me finish.
Like, so they will definitely, most definitely
enrich data that the US government cares about and
that the US companies and users care about
-- and then they kind of go to everything else.
-- Sure. That's fair, that's fair
and that's
great that they did that.
But relying on them to do this for something that is
like when people consume CV E data,
there's a 90
I'm gonna make up a number 98% chance they're
pulling from the NVD database and they don't even know
how to get the data from Miter,
like the fact that it lives in a github
-- and there's sort of an API
-- now
they have an API now for C five
people don't even know about.
And so
have like,
like, it's nice that the US government was paying for this.
And I know for a fact way back in the day, like, and N I
didn't actually do the analysis. It was outsourced to a contractor.
-- I suspect it still is.
-- I would assume. So. Actually,
I, yeah,
but the problem is like, this is something that is so, so
widely used and relied upon.
And, and we've,
you and I personally have tried to fix this with the DWF and the GSD and all that stuff
to try and build a con like to try and build a consortium of people to do this.
But the fundamental problem is anybody that can do this work can sell that.
And why would they give it away for free?
And that's one of the core problems here is, is
anybody that is capable of doing this work is like, but or we can charge for this data,
why would we fold it back into a public data source and give it away for free?
I I will answer that question later
because that's exactly what we're going to do at
ANCAR. Exactly.
Here's the other piece to this that not everyone can see.
So like it was, it was funny because like on linkedin,
-- there were people I saw reply to comments that were like,
-- and actually there's
one more thing if this was due to like a US government shutdown or something,
like if there was some sort of external event that like, oh n
just had a massive budget cut or there's a US government shutdown or whatever,
then this notice would kind of have a context and make sense.
But there isn't anything like that
-- as far as I know, I,
-- I know nist is underfunded.
-- I mean, there's some news stories about that,
-- right?
But I'm just saying like,
it's not like they just lost half their funding and they're like, well,
what can we cut?
Not recently that, that I'm aware of
and, and not only that like this notice is
I think
it is
maybe technically correct, but ethically questionable is how I would describe it.
Well, here's the thing,
I'm just going to point something out.
Nist is currently working to establish a current consortium to address challenges
in the NVD program and develop and improve tools and methods.
If this were actually what they were truly doing
-- there, be like a link or a contact or something
-- too. So
I've been informed,
they're going to put a notice on the federal register at some point in the future.
But there's, there's some other pieces to this. I want to get to.
But I, I want to start out first by saying
there are,
there have been people who, who like made jokes and saying, oh if,
if you're relying on the N
data,
you're screwed anyway and stuff like that because like it has some quality issues.
But here's the thing,
I don't think a lot of people understand
in the US, in the federal government,
there are a number of regulations that specifically call out the NVD severity.
Like for example, if you're a fed ramp product or serve service,
it's a fed ramp service.
The fed ramp standard specifically says you have to use the NVD severity
which ironically don't exist now.
But,
but that's kind of a different problem,
-- I guess. Divide by zero, it's fine,
-- it's fine. They're all zero. That's right. Well,
there is a language to say like if an NVD severity doesn't exist,
fall back to the vendors severity.
But fundamentally, you are expected to use the severity NVD is setting.
So this isn't like some data set.
You can just be like whatever, I'm gonna blow this off. It doesn't matter like
it's literally named in these standards.
This is a lot like plumbing and electrical code in the sense of
for the vast majority of us, it just doesn't matter.
But we don't care if you,
if you took the plumbing code or electrical standards away
and let people do kind of whatever they want,
we'd have some problems.
Well,
it would basically be back when all the houses kept burning down for some reason.
Right. Right.
Ok.
Now
-- there's so many moving parts in this story,
-- man.
And I mean, that's part of the problem here is there's so much complexity,
this is part of an ecosystem as a whole.
And I love these people saying that
you shouldn't rely on the NVD data when
they sort of conveniently ignore the fact that,
well, how else do you get the CV,
data with this enriched stuff that everybody wants and uses?
Because like I can speak of authoritatively here.
I worked for I
site partners and I defense where we basically consumed CV,
and a bunch of other stuff and enriched it and sold it for an ungodly amount of money.
Like it started at six figures back in the day
and
now that you can kind of get a lot of that through NVD for free. Well,
yeah,
like, yeah.
And so these people that are, like, oh, this is no big deal or?
Oh, this doesn't matter. Yeah. They're sort of ignoring reality.
-- Oh, for
-- sure. 100%.
And, and I know there's companies that,
that do this sort of work on their own and things like that.
But the reality is
every
private database I have ever interacted with had
very, the, the data quality was not good.
Well,
it's because it's like a bunch of people like me grinding
about these reports trying to do the best we can.
Yeah. And to give you an idea, you're talking like 100 of these a day, give or take
no 2 to 300 a day with NVD and a bunch
-- of other sources because N
-- VD has with other sources.
-- Sure. Yeah,
-- that's fair.
Like they don't, there's like no uh last I checked, I don't uh I want to say like hai
or somebody,
there's a Japanese vendor that does a ton like probably about 100 vols a month.
I forget which one
that are like, just not an NVD or CV at all. Maybe they are now
interesting. I didn't know that back in the day.
So like when you start covering not even and I'm ignoring the open source world,
but when you start covering major vendors,
a couple of them have become CNAs. Like I think Schneider Electric became one.
There's quite a few now. There's, there's a lot of CN A s. Ok.
There's over 1000 skater companies globally,
-- I think. Like two of them are CNAs. Uh,
-- yeah, it's not that many.
And that's, that's what people forget is that like, there's accounting software,
there's
like a jillion of them.
And, and the other thing, I mean,
the thing I always talk about with CN AC N CV E numbering authority, right?
This is an organization that could basically coin their own CV ES
we just talked to Greg Kh about the Linux kernel becoming one.
Not everyone should have to be ac na
I
the reason almost everyone is doing it is to just
deal with the Brokenness of the system.
I mean, this is,
this is one of my pet peeves about like this whole vulnerability universe
is
if you talk to people doing the work,
they basically detest these systems because there's
a lot of systemic problems in them.
But then you go and talk to the insiders
and they spend all their time convincing you you're wrong,
which is like,
that's not OK.
I'm gonna say this as kindly as I can
CV E was created actually 25 years ago, roughly 1999
and it was totally appropriate and applicable back then.
And it has not changed significantly
at
all
in that time.
There's been incremental progress like I got them into github,
but they still use that weird magical backend
that imports and exports data from github.
Github is not the source of truth. Github
is just republishing,
they at least use
-- json instead of XML. So you're welcome to for that world like,
-- well, in the new
JSON format,
the CV E five format is significantly nicer than the CV E four format was.
And you know why the CV four format is so terrible.
It's because I invented it and nobody gave me feedback and I,
the CV four format solved every single problem I had
and nobody else wanted to contribute. So
that's what we got,
right? And that's how it works for sure,
for sure.
It's a classic open source. But the thing is like the CV board is the same people.
There's been no turnover, like there's been no significant renewal in
over two decades. Like that's insane.
Oh, it's, it's for sure.
Now, we, we, we ranted about all this on an episode a while back.
So I don't, I don't want to rehash all that. I want, I
want to talk about NVD in this context.
So now you mentioned about like the consortium aspect of this, right?
I don't know what to think of that piece
because the reality is if you look at how the US Federal government works,
they have a very hard time working with anyone outside of the US federal government.
Well, yeah, if you don't have an office with an address in Maryland or Virginia,
you're not going to be part of this consort.
That's quite likely. And, and that's one of my concerns is
I'm not sure how they can do this in a way that will actually be effective
just because it's, this is not what the US government does.
I mean, this is why Miter runs CV E because the US government can't run CV E.
They had to find someone else to do it
well, and I mean, it does fit with Miters.
One of their main things is cybersecurity and they do a lot of
CV, ecwe and a whole bunch of hardware software. You name it,
blah, blah, blah.
I think fundamentally, this is a classic problem of,
it's like the time zone file guy.
It started out like, ok, we need a time zone file du and ok,
so this one guy seems to be maintaining it cool.
Let's like, let him do it because
that is a lot of work and annoying to coordinate and it's tricky
and
there's a lot of
stuff in society that underpins
everything in that industry.
Like here's a crazy thing. You're gonna hear trick question.
But what's generally the smallest
ridge breaker in North America?
-- And the answer is 15 amps.
-- Well, it was 15 amps.
-- Ah So you heard about the new 10 amp
-- breakers? 10 amp now
-- only for
-- lights. Yes, with 14 gauge wire. So because like all the lights got
stupid efficient.
And now we can, like, run them off of, like, basically cheap toy wire and,
and it's, it's that kind of weird, small,
boring detail oriented stuff that underpins
-- the cybersecurity industry is CV E and NVD.
-- It's very wonky. Right.
It's Wonkish in that regard where it's,
and I mean, this is something that
I, I forget I was talking to someone about this and they were,
they were basically saying, like, why aren't more people talking about this?
And I'm like, well, it's very niche.
This is like a niche of a niche.
I mean, the cybersecurity industry is already kind of niche.
But the vulnerability identifier piece of that industry is
even more niche than an already niche industry.
You've got it, then you've got information security,
then you've got vulnerability management,
then you've got the foreign vulnerability identification.
And a perfect example of this is we tried to do this with GSD and
DWF and failed because there's just so
many weird economic issues and externalities and internal
that. It's just, this is really hard
and there's also like 100 people that really kind of know this and do this
in the world.
Yeah, it's small.
Anor
has an interesting idea
that
we're, we're pushing ahead with. So, so there's,
there's a guy I work with who is involved in the GSD in the past.
His name is Weston Steimel and Weston's like, really bright.
He knows more about vulnerabilities than either you or I do
or probably both of us put together.
That's good because if we know the most, we're, but we're screwed as a species.
We got problems. But anyway,
so one of the things we're, we're going to do and, and
we have
a V vulnerability scanner called Gripe.
Right. And Gripe can work on bombs. You can scan all kinds of stuff with it.
It does a pretty nice job
and we use as many of the, like, upstream ecosystems to match against like github
and redhead and Debbie and ubuntu.
All all those kind of things, you know, the usual suspects whenever we can.
However, there is some vulnerability data
that just doesn't exist anywhere else and we we would fall back to NVD for that data,
right?
And so the idea of being like my example would be Curl, right?
Like curl publishes their own advisories.
But curl is a binary on a disk quite often, right? Busy box, a binary on a disk.
It's not part, it's not there from a package manager.
-- If curls from a package manager from like Debian or red hat
-- curl on an Apple device is
made by Apple in a way that Ashley Curl has some issues with
-- which was to get into in another show.
-- But anyway, so
there is some NVD data we need
because it's like that we call it the matcher of last resort.
We like this data doesn't exist anywhere else.
This is the only place to get it from and now it's gone.
-- No,
-- it's just, it'll be updated later. Where
is, maybe it's, it's delayed temporarily, but it's like, what's the,
the, the gull of French
Arc fleet from Hitchhikers down to the galaxy where they're
there? What is it, the like 100 year temporary delay or something?
Anyway,
we're,
we're going to create a repository to just start capturing the things we need
and we're going to focus very much on the things we need to start.
But ideally,
we would like to try to build some sort of open community to work on some of this
data because there's a bunch of other things you
can enrich a lot of vulnerability data with.
But I think here's the difference because like DWF and GSD,
like those didn't work out.
But I think the reason they didn't work out is there was
isn't like a specific demand for that data. At the time,
we have a demand for that data.
Like we need this data, we're doing it whether people come and help or not.
Here's the classic problem.
But everything trying to replace Bitcoin or Ethereum
or fax or email or the internet has,
which is
how do you build something
that is so much better than the existing solution.
But at the same time, familiar enough and similar enough to
use
that people will actually use it.
And it's a sort of innovation trap of like how do you move forward significantly.
But in a way where it's like
this, but just a little bit better,
but it is so much, significantly better.
And that is another problem that DWF and GST I,
which is we weren't doing anything significantly better.
No.
No,
not at all.
Right. That's just it.
-- And now there's this asteroid extension level event coming for CV E basically.
-- Yes.
And, oh, well, now the dinosaur
-- were a little worried,
-- I mean, you know what this feels like this is like
if you don't schedule downtime, the universe will schedule it for you.
Like the universe just scheduled us some downtime. So we got to deal with it.
-- Now,
-- like imagine if the Linux kernel team just said like, hey,
we're taking a 30 day break.
They had to kind of do that when Linus's power went out.
Yeah.
But I mean, imagine then if, but here's the thing, this isn't,
this notice is not like a 30 or 60 or 90 day thing. It's like, uh you know,
maybe and that's that uncertainty risk.
-- So
-- here's, here's some information I do have about the notice
that uh you can imagine many people have mailed NVD
asking for more, more details and they started replying to people.
But not until after like, basically, the story broke across the, the,
the vulnerability ecosystem which displeases me.
It, it, it basically has been,
it was three weeks essentially until this like
became public knowledge that what was actually going
on, which I think is way too long.
But then they started replying to people and there's
a conference at the end of March called Von,
which is all of the vulnerability insiders going to Raleigh North Carolina. Uh,
you know what? Oh, the Von
conference. Yeah, it's just the CV conference. But rebranded
was there a CV E conference?
There was, well, there was once at that satellite campus because,
oh, ok. I, I don't know.
it's, it's basically, it's probably the same people in the same ideas. But anyway,
so the response
is
exactly that.
But the response NVD is now giving is that, oh, we're going to announce something at B
Khan. By the time B
Khan comes around,
you're talking about basically a month and a half from the time the,
the faucet was turned off which in the vulnerability world,
a month and a half is a really, really, really long time.
-- Also,
-- I feel like they could have just posted a web page.
I mean, this is one of my complaints is I feel like that notice,
it probably went through 600 layers of government lawyers,
but like it doesn't contain usable information.
And I think it's, it's misleading to a degree which I don't approve of it all.
So, so anyway, now we're now we're here.
-- This is
-- actually I'm going to be blunt, this is one of the reason I
left Red Hat is I got tired of
the vulnerability management space being such a cluster.
It's a mess. I mean, it's, it's been difficult forever.
It's the same problems I had, we had 25 years ago.
I mean,
I won't disagree with you on that. Right.
And what I really love every time CV, and quality of CV comes up, you know,
what people propose
should have two levels of CV.
We should have ones that are like,
good and golden and standard and the ones that are like,
maybe so like almost like a candidate
and a CV, which
I'm being facetious here because if you look at it
that they, that's how CV started. They had candidates that then
-- the board as a whole had to vote on.
-- Yeah. Oh, it was. But they were, they were like,
they were like 100 a year back then. Like you could do that.
But even 100 year like anyways.
So it just makes me laugh where they're like,
people are proposing solutions and it's like, no, no, we,
we tried that 25 years ago and it failed 25 years ago to do scale issues.
And, and look, here's one of the things I have to say about that is
this sort of problem is fundamentally an open source problem
is what I would say is the vast majority
of these ideas are applying to open source products.
The things most people actually care about is open source dependencies.
Like there's a lot of open source going on here and this is an open source
-- scale problem that needs an open source solution.
-- Well, it's an open
source scale
solution. And I think that's one thing,
people keep forgetting the law of large numbers here. Like
we're talking tens of thousands of events per year, which means
tens to hundreds of events per day.
So it, it's crazier than that.
I,
I'm giving a talk at Cipher Con the first week of April where I
think the talk is titled Open Source Security is bigger than you can imagine.
And like here's something to think about
we have right now there. I think it was like 28,000 cbes last year, right?
There are literally 8 million open source packages being like not versions,
just the packages like the, the the projects being tracked.
There's, there's a data set called Ecosystems. A guy named Andrew
Nesbitt runs it. It's a very cool data set.
But anyway, Ecosystems is tracking eight. I think it's 8.8 million packages.
And if you break out all the versions you're talking about,
I think it's like 40 or 50 million, I forget the exact number.
But like it is an insane amount
of, of packages in version
being released.
You think there's 28,000 security vulnerabilities
in tens of millions of packages.
No freaking way.
And what's even better is he has no visibility into the closed source world,
which is bigger.
No, I don't think it is. I don't think the closed source world is bigger at all.
There's
a,
well,
there's a lot of badly written stuff that never sees
the light of day but is attached to the internet.
-- Let me put it that way.
-- Oh, for sure there is.
But I, I have a suspicion, open source probably eclipses a closed source
by several magnitudes. At least
-- my
-- code
is probably true.
Now,
I want to tie in the Linux kernel to this conversation because
this has also been a topic that's come up in the vulnerability universe
because
a lot of the people running these like secret private databases
are very upset by what the Linux kernel is doing.
And the reality is,
can I just tell people what the Linux kernel actually did versus what
they think they did because there's what people think the Linux kernel did.
Hold on. Let me, let me explain first. So
there are all of these organizations that, that parse all the vulnerabilities.
You know, we mentioned them a little while ago
and I guarantee they're all running like on the very edge of what they can do.
-- And so if you increase,
-- I worked for two of them, I can confirm that statement.
-- You literally
-- know exactly.
But if you increase the volume of vulnerabilities by let's say 10 or 20%
which is
literally what's happening.
If you look at the, the CV E data in the Linux kernel editions,
they're accounting for around 10% of all CV ES now, which is quite a lot.
-- But basically the Linux kernel, it
-- is kind of used widely
and it is kind of big.
It's one of the most used applications on the planet and off the planet.
So,
is
it on Mars?
Yeah, I'm pretty sure it is. Ok.
We'll just say yes, even if it's not
anyway.
So curls probably be there too
is absolutely on Mars.
Yeah. Yeah.
But, but you get the idea, a lot of these organizations,
they're really angry and they're,
they're complaining a lot to the CBE people as well as the Linux kernel people.
And of course, Greg
doesn't care. So he's gonna just keep doing what he does.
So, and here's the beautiful thing.
A lot of people are complaining saying, oh,
the Linux kernel became a CV numbering authority and
is assigning CV S to things that are not
confirmed as a vulnerability
and going back to Greg's argument, which is,
if
it looks weird enough,
we kind of have to say it's security related because we
cannot guarantee how or what people are using this for.
-- And so we have to err on the side of caution,
-- right?
Like as he pointed out, it's running on literally rockets and milking machines.
Like
-- that's amazing.
-- And what's interesting.
So what's what the Linux kernel actually did
is they're not,
people ignore stuff anymore. They're actually labeling it clearly.
Now in the past, they could have like put a security tag on it
and the reality is at most organizations no CV, E, no harm, no foul.
It is literally that simple.
And the moment you assign a CV for a lot of organizations,
a 30 day clock starts ticking or a 90 day clock or whatever
for sure.
And that's what they're ticking awful about it is
because they have all this process wrapped around CV.
Identifiers, make it real to put it bluntly
100%.
There's that whole argument with people trying to get
CV S to count K to improve their resume.
And my take on this always was, is it a real CV E like,
is it legitimately a vulnerability?
Yes. Then
that's what we're trying. Like we want people to game the system and get these.
That's the point.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And, and look, the world isn't ready for kind of that thing.
But I think the reality is if,
if most projects started kind of doing what the Linux kernel is doing where
they're being a little more generous with
what they're defining as security issues,
I think we wouldn't have 28,000,
we'd probably have
-- 280,000 or 2 million.
-- I've actually run the numbers and done spot checks.
So a great example is quota quota,
a Blockchain project.
They actually very clearly label all their security stuff
as security with all caps security focal and blah,
blah, blah.
And they have, you know, about 10 or 20 a year.
They're not abnormal if you actually look at the data
of just stuff that is actually labeled as security fixes,
like in github.
Like, oh, this fixes a buffer overflow and stuff.
The actual number of CV ES for the English speaking
world should be about 1 to 10 million a year.
I wouldn't, I
not be surprised if that's true. Well, I know like,
uh, what we had a meal from um Debret on the show. It's been several years now. I think
where one of the things he talked about was he basically built the
system to go look at like get commits and try to determine,
is this
pull request or commit or whatever? Is it a is it fixing a security vulnerability?
And he found hundreds of thousands
and when he tried to bring his research to people,
they basically were like get out of here.
-- Now. We do not want to talk about this.
-- I didn't even try anything fancy.
I literally just was spot checking projects
and looking at stuff where the maintainer said
this fixes a security flaw
and
like that low of a bar,
not even a maybe but a confirmed is like I
said 1 to 10 million a year because simple numbers.
Yeah, there are 522,833 PP projects.
-- There are millions of N PM, there are right.
-- Like
they all have
the ecosystems data 8.8 million packages right now and it is going up,
which is nuts.
The problem is historically,
we've been able to ignore the vast majority of security vulnerabilities.
And what's interesting is there's a lot of places
but do actually reasonably update software.
But then there are places and this, I think where
will actually make a difference? And that was posted on Mastodon, where
was it? A car?
Anyway,
somebody pointed out this close this entity that was using
open source and they were using stuff that was 8,
10 years out of date.
Oh,
-- those are the avanti routers,
-- right? Sorry. Yeah, the Avanti routers.
Yeah, which are definitely connected to the internet, right?
Maybe. Yes
and yeah.
And they were pointing out like I think it had a
version of curl that was eight years out of date.
Like it was wild. I feel like they fixed a few flaws
-- since then. Now
-- I want to finish up this conversation
on
an important point is we talk about how
there's probably millions of vulnerabilities per year.
The world is not prepared for that future
at all. No.
And the problem I see right now
is all of the conversations I'm seeing around NVD
and about the Linux kernel putting out all these vulnerable
ideas.
It's not about like maybe we need to rethink some of this. Everyone's screaming.
We have to go back to the way it was and here's the thing
we will never go back to the way it was that is over now
and now we have to think about what is going to come next.
And if we obsess over like individual CV E findings like we've done in the past,
we will be crushed under the weight of those boulders.
Like we have to find new ideas and new ways to deal with all of this.
Well,
a good analogy here would be forestry management which basically
used to boil down to if there's a fire,
put it out right away.
And we've done that for 50 years and now last year, about 5% of my province burnt.
And this year we already basically,
they declared the fire season started early because we
also already had 100 wildfires burning underground under snow.
And
so, for example, here we need to start thinking about
massively rethinking forestry management.
Like we don't even, we're not even at the point where we can really fix forest fires.
Like we, we've hired more firefighters,
we've declared the fire season starts like now,
like a few weeks before it officially starts.
But like, fundamentally,
we need to rethink forestry management and how we
manage our forests and do we let them burn?
Where do we, you know, it's, it's to put it bluntly, it's too late.
We already built cities and towns where they should not have been built.
And that's exactly what's happened here in the open source world is
we've got
not just technical debt but like a like a cultural debt of how we look at software.
So a perfect example of this is I don't
care about vulnerability management as much as for example,
your ability to
ship an update.
Like if you can't ship an update, no amount of vulnerability management matters.
And so for example, with
uh with shipping and update,
you need to have test cases,
so you need to have testing frameworks,
you need to have feedback loops so that if because people will find bugs that are bad,
like if you don't have a way to ingest that and then
ship an update and fix it,
none of this matters. And the vast majority of project
and especially closed source. Yeah, their test cases are weak
if they exist at all
and their ability to ship an update confidently
without breaking stuff like the Linux kernel does.
Like I'm, I will disagree with Greg here. The Linux kernel is special.
They do some magic, they have the discipline
like
I'm sorry, but like at like expecting an N PM to have a full test suite.
I'm I'm not going to hold my breath.
What if it's one person who only has two hours
on Saturdays to work on their N PM project,
right? And 17 N PM projects in total,
there's some of that too.
So the majority of these people don't have just one project.
This is we, we talk, I mean,
what we had to on a couple of times we had the sovereign Texan people.
I'm like,
yeah, we don't know what to do with this.
But what I'm pointing out is until we look at, until we look at this as like this is not,
I'm gonna say this, this is not a vulnerability management problem.
This is a software ecosystem management problem
of which vulnerability management is just a very
uh
noticeable issue that we can no longer ignore.
I, I agree with that.
Like people are breaking like ransomware is still a
thing and they're still using six month old vulnerabilities.
And as I understand it,
the healthcare system in the US is still crippled from
that cyberattack against that one major healthcare provider that,
you know,
-- I know who you mean.
-- Yeah.
And so that's, I think like I'm not saying we don't try to fix CV and NVD and all this.
But what I'm saying is as much as we fix those things,
even if we had magical solutions for them, which we do not,
we would still have a lot of problems. We need to start thinking bigger and better.
And I,
I'm gonna say this, I think open source,
not just the licensing, not just the,
the way of doing open source, but the culture is
really the only way forwards significantly
for a lot of this stuff. I think that's right. I think expecting,
-- it's the only thing that'll scale
-- it. Right. It has to scale to the moon
100%.
And, and the challenge
is going to be how do you bootstrap something like this
because it's not free. I mean, like let me give you an example,
Acor is going to do all this work and we're going to dump it out and,
and hope some people come and help us out
but like it's not free, it's it, we need the data anyway.
I think that's our superpower here because we have to have it. But you know, like
this is one of those things that
the data will be available, but that data has a cost behind it.
And, and when you look at like, and we're only doing a really small sliver of the the
-- system
-- and the data is very temporal in that I
need it as soon as possible because the the the value
of the data
-- drops off a cliff because
-- like, I don't think it drops off a cliff.
-- But
-- if the data is 30 days late, that's 30 days added to my response.
That's what I mean.
That that's, and that's,
that's a subtle thing most people don't realize is
that like especially vulnerability management of scale is all about
like when Microsoft Tuesday comes around, I used to have,
I actually had a written contract with my ex-wife
that she would not speak to me on that
because I was so stressed out and horrible. No, I'm serious.
That's one of the reasons I left that industry is it was in hindsight, it was so gross,
especially Microsoft Tuesdays.
But my point is like this data, I, I people don't need it in a month or a week.
They need it. Now.
Like when Microsoft drops Microsoft Tuesday,
every infosec team on the planet starts scrambling to digest it and give guidance
and to start patching because sometimes there's stuff in there that it's like,
oh, you know, there's this little thing, if you visit a web page,
it just hijacks your kernel at the
like ringing zero level. Oops.
Yeah. Right. OK.
So here's how I want to end this show because we're, we're run ourselves out of time.
Like
I have no doubt the US government is going to think
about and have a lot of meetings about specifically NVD in
this
-- because they need the data, right? They, they don't have a choice
-- one. Comment.
CIA just got a budget increase.
And I always wondered, like I look at NVD doing this and I'm like,
this seems more like a CIA thing.
-- It might
-- be and it wouldn't surprise me if they take it over.
But fundamentally at the end of the day,
I think one of the challenges that the government is going to have and like
I know Anisa in Europe is trying to do some of this as well,
but
we need to do things different
because if we try to keep doing it, the way it's been done,
we're going to have the same problems.
And, and additionally, I mean, this is always one of the challenges for new things
is expecting the same people to do something in a different way,
generally doesn't happen. And so this is where I think
you need like a very open source like model where you have many people
can come and sit at the table and,
and work on this stuff because when you restrict
something like this to a small group of insiders,
it can't change and grow.
There's a good reason why they're doing that is because they don't
want to change and grow the people that consume this data, especially at scale,
do not want to have to make significant changes.
It's very risky and
-- costly. I mean,
-- no one wants to change, right? And we've avoided it for a long time.
But I think like
the asteroid has hit the planet. What happens now?
Well, back to the forestry management thing. We have all this dead wood now
it's gonna burn at some point.
We have all these vulnerabilities that we've ignored successfully.
Yep, at
scale and most people are not keeping their stuff up to date.
No, no. That's the thing.
We can't keep up as it is and how, what would happen if,
if we went from 28,000 CV ES to a million CV ES
like we would crush the world.
I literally looked at just Parson
github for things like thank you.
-- This confirmed fixes a buffer overflow that alone would double the size of CV
-- S.
So I've, I've searched github.
You can type a buffer overflow into the search box, put it in double quotes
and I think it's 9 million issues
like
it's
-- not zero or
-- look for how many people add the html special cares wrapper in a PHP app.
Oh, yeah. Right. Right. Basically every single one of those is
scripting,
cutting us off.
I think
we don't know what's coming next,
but it's going to be a wild ride. That's about all I will say.
I actually have a suspicion
that the
language specific ecosystems will really help within their domain.
But people forget that there's a lot of corporations and
organizations that have to consume all the data because they have
all the systems. No. Like I think people forget like a fortune 100
will have
-- their inventory of it. Basically boils down to. Yes. Every
-- everything ever.
Yeah, for sure.
Yeah, Windows 95 is on the list folks
anyway. All right, I've cut this off.
I'm sure we'll talk about this more in the future.
Hopefully we find out some more in the coming weeks. Goodness knows
it's, it's wild out there. So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to it.
Our security podcast.com hit up the show notes, UZ
Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Find us on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.