Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and appreciating good Shawarma.
Josh Bresser.
I do like good Shawarma.
-- Yeah. And I had bad Shawarma tonight.
-- What does that mean?
I mean, I can think of multiple ways. Shawarma can be bad.
Ok, so Shawarma is supposed to be a pile of meat on a stick roasted
and
normally I like to get the mixed Shawarma plate to go because I, well,
multiple kinds of shawarma is better than one kind of shawarma.
Well, obviously,
so what they gave me though was they gave me
chicken Shawarma yay and like this kind of grit,
like grizzly gritty chunks of beef that were not like
Shawarma beef but like kind of like stir fried,
I guess or something.
And it was grizzly and unpleasant and dried out
and I did not care for it and I was sad because it was bad and it was also not Sharma,
right?
I see.
So
yeah,
it happens. So I ate the chicken, which was good. But
so, well, see, the problem is I tried a new place that had a 4.5 out of five
and does not deserve it.
-- I don't trust ratings on any apps because it's so easy to game that system.
-- Oh,
these places don't bother with that. Like, this place had 80 ratings.
Yeah.
And in general, and the salad was just greens with like one tiny piece of tomato. So,
I think part of the challenge is it's maybe they were good a few months ago but they've
back on food costs or something. I don't know.
But that's kind of the impression I got. So
I'm just going to go back to
-- it
-- could be whoever cooked tonight, you know, like,
well, but here's the thing,
I ordered the mixed Shawarma plate and I got one Shawarma and one not Shawarma.
Why are we still talking anyway?
Because it's the same thing as what I was
thinking about earlier today with the S bomb stuff.
Right. I need you to explain to me everything you were thinking about because I have
an odd collection of incoherent ramblings from you and
signals and I'm not sure what you're talking about.
Ok.
So at a very high level when you build a piece
of software and I'm talking like something you ship on CD.
A game, an operating system, something that's in a car. A to
CD.
Exactly.
A Blu Ray. No DVD. Do we ship software on Blu Rays? I don't know.
I honestly don't know.
I would imagine they'll fit on a DVD anyways.
The point is what at a very conceptual level goes into it.
And I'm thinking bits go into it like like data
libraries, source code, closed source like bits,
I'm thinking the next output or rather the next input would be services.
So for example,
like Mastodon,
you want to use an object store like S3 to host your images or
it uses like some kind of like a remote time service,
right
or whatever.
And thinking further on this,
that there's also services that go into like building the software.
So for example, like it maybe is hosted on
github and which C I CD pipeline,
you know. So because like, well
red hat, for example, right?
We every single build happened in like that
offline container to make sure that we weren't like
grabbing something from an online source that then
one day disappears and the whole bill breaks,
they call that Hermetic builds.
Hermetic builds. OK?
And then the next thing
and I, the more I think about this,
the more I think it fits which is legal obligations, right?
Traditionally in the form of like sort of
licenses around the source code or whatever.
For example, if like somebody might have some insane license that says, you know,
I have to wear a blue shirt while I compile this.
And I know that's a bad example. But
the point is there are legal obligations
both in the traditional software licenses.
And for example, maybe I buy a piece of or I buy a piece of music.
Well, I can't just, like, buy a CD and then use that music in a game and publish it.
Like, I'm gonna get sued.
Like, they're going to want me to license it. Right.
Yeah,
that's right.
So, I think legal
and,
and then the other thing I was thinking was
what does
such a software or something producing it, it basically produces the same things.
Again, it produces data bits,
images, text binaries,
whatever config files,
it produces potentially services and it produces legal obligations.
So it kind of feeds in on itself, right?
The the whole, it's just a whole, you know,
like a wily wobbly mish mash ecosystem rainforest like
doctor who in the it crowd says and so
because I've been thinking about
eal
and at first I was sort of thinking about sort of more the technical side of like, OK,
so currently the idea behind what a lot of people think of EB
is,
is I I have this thing and I shove it through my S bomb X ray and
it says like it contains this and that and peanuts and live weasels and oh my God,
what is this thing that's out of date?
And that's, that's a good start.
But what if, for example,
what if I ship a Mastodon container that relies on an S3 bucket for hosting images?
As I understand most PLM
systems right now are gonna be like whatever man like, they don't see that.
They don't because they don't look for it.
They might see an S3 dependency and say, hey,
this thing has an S3 library but then it's on a human to rec like
a human's gonna have to dig through all these libraries and be like, OK,
which of these actually create like a remote requirement?
Well,
you could use an S3 library with a local
object store that just happens to present as S3,
right?
Because, well, they all do now because that's the default,
-- right?
-- I mean, so I have a good example for this, we have
a product at work
that needs a postscript database,
right?
And so
we have a, we will say we'll put shipping quotes,
we have the postscript container in our container registry that you can use or
most of our customers like to use just like R DS, right? From Amazon.
So it's either or it's we need a database.
We don't really care where it comes from,
but we'll give you one just because we're nice
and I could totally see a different vendor. For example,
what if they
require to use?
And for those of you that maybe don't know R
DS is a relational database service at Amazon web services.
-- I I have no idea what R DS stands for
-- relational database services.
Yeah.
And you basically get your choice of my SQL post
Gra SQL or the Amazon versions of those like Pera
and whatever
anyways.
So, but here's the thing, there's sort of a couple of options here.
One you could ship like you can give them,
you can run it locally in a container and you ship that.
Cool. Thank you two. You make it like a config thing so that we already have a nice Pro
SQL cluster.
We'd prefer to use that because we already have a bunch of DB A S running this. OK?
Cool, do that. But a piece of software could say, for example, you must use R DS
at Amazon or even could say
you have to use one that we run and we charge more for that.
Or maybe that's why you're paying them a monthly subscription.
And here's the thing,
wouldn't it be nice if your s
bomb told you which of these four things was going on or what kind of is happening?
So Espo
isn't that advanced yet? I mean, I can.
So a lot of the things you've talked about are
being worked on CIA has some S PM working groups.
There's for example, you're talking about like builds and you're talking about
post build.
There's like all these stages and there's actually there's a document I'll
link in the show notes that's currently in draft from Cissa.
So don't tell anyone I'm linking it,
but it, it lays out here. I haven't sent this to you.
I'll send it to you in signal while we're chatting.
I just, I love like
I get kind of why people want to keep the draft somewhat private,
but especially drafts of documents that are meant to be widely shared.
And like we're hoping people will actually do this.
It's not
a great deal.
But anyway, they break down.
There's these phases, they've got, I'll just read them out.
There's design source, build, analyzed,
deployed and run time and you can probably figure out what all those are.
And it makes sense because there isn't like one way to do an S bomb,
there isn't one stage that really matters.
I mean, everyone's going to be different. Like a, a great example is
there are a lot of tools that folk like like github
has depend
aot,
for example, right? Like for example, in depend a
bot
has a variant of S
bomb. It has to do
to figure out what you have and how to upgrade it.
And that's obviously in the very source universe versus there's
other tooling that will look at like a container image.
You know, we've got the, the tool sift from
Acor that looks at container images and,
and you can look at stuff on disk for example, but it generally
speaking, it's after the source stage and that's fine. And like github
does a great job with source, we do a great job but not source.
We don't do a great job with source github
doesn't do any of that other stuff, you know, and I think this is we,
we've reached the point where
I, I always, I like to talk about problems in the context of like layers.
And one of my favorite examples is I remember when I started at elastic,
we didn't have single sign on, right?
And all the customers complained about was single sign on.
We got single sign on.
And now all the customers complained about like 10 things instead of the one thing.
And I think that's the same deal with SS bomb where we've been just talking about S
bomb and now that we've kind of peeled that first layer off.
Now there's like five problems under that.
And as we peel each one of those, there's five more under those. And so
-- we're going to see this keep exploding. Yeah.
-- Well, and so OK, two quick things.
One, I never really thought this out loud but yeah, S
bomb can run for example on your source or on the, the things
it can run on how it's shipped. So R PM packages, containers, whatever.
But and then there's also that it needs to run potentially
on the deployed systems because going back to the database example.
Well, if this uses Postgres
QL cool, like is it shipped with it?
Well, then I need to make sure that version's up to date or if it relies on Amazon rds,
for example, as an extreme example, I have seen software which says, hey,
you actually have to run an outdated version because
we don't know how to talk to the newer version
that happens all the time. Absolutely.
Now, let me, let me,
let me cook your noodle for a second here and we'll talk about the build that
bomb.
So here's something to think about. When do you build software?
Like for example, what version of compiler did you use?
I was
about
-- to what was the version of the libraries?
-- Right. That was my second next thought.
There's all this other like tool chain stuff, right? That goes on top of that, that
we don't almost nobody tracks this, right? Like you have no idea.
I mean,
one of my favorite examples always was most people don't know this but you know,
there was uh Red Hat had Red Hat Enterprise Linux and there was sent
os and sent os always lagged Red Hat Enterprise Linux by several months on,
on big releases.
And the reason for that is you have to actually build things in
a certain order because like when when you build a Linux distribution,
you don't just like build all the packages,
you have to build this package first and then build these
other packages and then go back and build some other things again
because like things have dependencies on each other
and people don't realize that.
But like as Red Hat was developing Red Hat Enterprise Linux,
they were building things in a very specific way that they wouldn't tell anyone
So the sento s people had to basically figure out what the order was
and then they had to go and do it again.
And so you don't think about this kind of stuff, but
that is
super important
and we throw away all that metadata today.
Well, and, and that's exactly where I was going with this, which is,
which leads to the fact that there are certain things
that are either
not easily testable or maybe unt testable and it's on
sort of whoever produced that component or shipped that component
to tell you. So a great example of this would be a JPEG.
Like if I download a JPEG online,
I don't know what license it's under,
it may be old enough that it's public domain or it might be, you know, some pa
copy of something that is supposed to cost a million dollars, right?
And so
uh whoever kind of has actually owns that J peg, if they, you know,
sell it to somebody or license it to somebody or whatever,
it's also on them to give them.
Like for example, the legal terms and obligations that come with it, right? Because
I can't like sell you a JPEG
and then come back and say, oh by the way, you're not allowed to do this with it.
Like that has to be in the original contract and
license and whatever and so on a technical level,
a great example, just be,
where was the source code originally hosted. Was it in github
or GIT labs? Because those, or, or
some person's workstation because those are like three very,
very different answers.
Because for example, well, like we've seen several C I CD systems broken into
and it would be nice for like, me as a user to know.
Oh, I, I might be affected because I also use that C I CD system or I use something that,
well, let's throw solar winds under the bus yet again.
Oh, you know,
I use a piece of solar wind software that was
compiled during the time that solar winds was fully compromised.
Fantastic.
Um
And so I'm just, I'm looking at this and I'm thinking essentially
to some degree, we, we'll always have to do archaeological
analysis, you know, that sort of investigative analysis
because there will always be something I buy or use or license
that ships without some metadata that I would like to see probably.
And if I have a system that can do that, then, well,
I have all that metadata potentially.
Whereas, you know, if I rely on, like if I rely on, well,
I mean, there are still open
source projects that don't ship with an actual proper license,
like they don't have a license files
of stuff, you know,
and
so if we can't even get people to include a license file,
I doubt that they're gonna include like
in their tar ball.
Like here's exactly how it was compiled on what system,
with what versions of which flags and everything.
It's like, no, here's just a binary that kind of mostly works on most Linuxes,
-- you know.
-- That's right.
That's right.
So, I mean,
there's a lot to unpack in what you just said and I want to start out with kind of a,
like a PS A announcement for everyone is PS A
that doesn't make sense because E A stands for announcement,
-- public
-- service announcement.
Yeah, I know. But I said PS A announcement because everyone says PS A announcement.
-- Well,
-- you're going to go to the ATM machine later. I do
go to ATM machine. Yes.
So
everything Kurt and I are talking about is basically magic fairy dust land.
And
if, if you read the Twitters or the whatevers,
it feels like everyone else has a lot of this
stuff figured out and I'm going to tell you now,
literally no one has this figured out anyone who pretends they does, they does.
-- I'm doing all right. I
-- would
say
worse than this.
Some people have it figured out in the sense of given enough time and effort.
They can do it manually once a year with something like log for J
and that's,
that's what I'm saying.
That's even worse because we're not at a point where we're saying, wow,
we can't even do this.
We're saying, no, no, no.
Like I can build a rocket once every year and it probably doesn't kill everybody,
maybe sort of,
but that's the thing
when these
capabilities are needed because of something like log for
J where you have to actually track it down everywhere
we end up with these insane.
Like here's like, here's this like 16 bit string,
you can grip everything on your hard disk for or
you know, just all this insane stuff that like we're,
I mean,
I remember the log for JAY, the amount of detection stuff that came out for it,
you know, Yara rules uh Sam Grep, just good old Grep
MD five sons,
Shaw 16
and
OK, great. Now, like, you know, you're assisted men with 100 systems.
Good luck.
I hope you have a lot of coffee. We, we need to,
we definitely have the need for it
and people
right now only do it once or twice a year
because doing it any more than that would kill them.
Well, I mean, look, there is tooling that exists and it's getting better
and
a lot of this is coming along,
but we're a long ways away from, for example,
being able to say like this JPEG image you have has this license on it.
-- We generally can't do that.
-- Well, ironically, reverse image search with TI
I mean,
but yeah, I know what you
mean.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
What we can do easily is like if you're, if you have a No Js project,
we can tell you with pretty much 100% accuracy,
what all your packages are and what the licenses of
those packages are like the tooling can do that.
But that's an easy example.
Well, and so for example, hypothetical question here,
what happens if you see one of those curl blah, blah, blah pipe bash things?
So there isn't generally tooling to the. So OK, actually,
the correct answer to that is this is where the S bomb in stages comes from.
And there's a concept that is known as S bomb drift. So what happened is
I have my source
repo I scan it
right. Then I do my build and we'll put building quotes for no J
and then I scan it
and I'll look at what's different
and then I'll take that and I'll put it
in a container and I'll look at what's different.
And I actually have, I have a blog post on the Inco blog. I'll link to,
-- I guess
-- what dependencies, especially
because, yeah,
you say I want this but something else pulls
in something newer or older or holds it back.
-- And
-- so if you are running a weird curl command, you can say, oh,
between these two steps, something weird happened,
let's go see what it was.
And that's where, then you have to have a human go and you know,
dig in the dirt and stuff.
But
at this point
that's kind of how you could do that.
Well, and this is one of the things I'm thinking where doing S
bomb
will be possible for open source because third parties can choose to do it
and publish it.
Whereas you can't really do that with close sources easily without
like buying a license to it and running it through.
But for example, I mean, somebody could,
somebody could crawl N PM, js.org or you know, whatever, right?
Or all the go binaries, right?
Somebody could crawl all the open source go Binaries on github
and publish the results somewhere, you know,
for me to use and not have to do it myself.
But so there is some things happening here as well.
There's a group actually,
that's part of the open ssf that I I I'm the co-chair of called SBO
everywhere and we're still putting a lot of the pieces together.
So no one's really heard about anything. But like
one of the things we're talking about is
we want every open source project to release an S bomb next to their tar ball, right?
-- Every one of them you want
-- to boil the ocean and have every open source project,
do it themselves or a third party does it.
So we don't want third parties doing it.
We want the project doing it at BUILD, generating an S
bomb at BUILD,
gives you different metadata than generating an S bomb after build.
Now, one of the things we recognize is you can't just say like, oh open source,
you should go do this like that is not, I mean, we, we have the whole episode.
Open source owes you nothing.
-- We can't even get them to put licenses on their software.
-- But who cares?
It's not their problem. They don't care.
So what we actually want to do
is do the work for them
and we're putting together some plans and proposals not to say, oh, open source,
you should do this.
But we want to show up and be like open source. We want to do this for you
and learn lessons along the way. And there will be people who are like, I don't care.
I don't want to do this and that. That's ok. That's fine.
There's no one's gonna make you do anything. But
it's definitely,
and, and it, it's comical though because like
bomb again is one of my favorite things where you
look at what everyone's talking about on social media.
You read these news stories and
there's all these people saying, oh open source needs to generate S bombs and it,
it's like, yeah.
No, no, they don't. I mean, if, if, if you want an S bomb for them, go help the project,
send them a patch. Are you gonna do that? Oh, you're not. Why?
Because it's easier to complain on Twitter. Oh, ok. Good job to you.
You know, and that's just kind of the universe we have today and, and it's tough, man.
It's really tough. So, anyway, back to your original point though.
So third party
having like a clearing house for all this stuff,
the kind of problem I think you run into with that
is.
So let's say
you have a project that's generating an S
bomb.
How are you generating it?
Where are you getting your data from?
How do I know what you're doing is even remotely accurate?
Well, I mean, in theory, I download their Tar Ball, you know, check the shaw 256.
Publish sig. Make sure it's the right Tar Ball.
And then I published an S bomb for that Tar Ball of that
-- cha 256 sig. But
-- how do I, what did you use to do it? How do I know you did make sense?
-- And
-- actually, and, and that was something I was going to say is
part of what doesn't make a lot of sense here is
why would I download third party s bomb data
unless I can know exactly how they generated,
which sort of strongly implies.
I want to see their tools, which means it better be open source like I, I, you know,
and
now in that instance, why don't you just do it yourself
exactly where I was going with this? Right. That's, that's exactly it.
Right.
And, and the one argument would be is it would, you know,
it would save a bit of carbon if you know,
one person did it against that thing and then publish it.
We don't all run, you know, we don't have
like, what if everybody does it on every pull of node?
Like that's gonna be a ton of compute time versus, you know.
Yes,
absolutely. But, yeah, and then essentially that's where I was going with.
This is like, well,
yeah, why don't I just do it myself to put it bluntly,
I think one of the challenges of SS
balm will be
the only way to fully understand what the tool is
doing and to replicate it is of course,
is to have the tool and ideally it be open source.
So again, do it yourself.
And I think that's kind of what's gonna have to happen. And
that's not to say that you can't have a service based on this, right?
Like Red Hat's a great example.
You can go get free Linux or run Sento.
Why would you pay for Red Hat?
Well, because things like support and it's just easier and blah, blah, blah,
there's a bunch of good reasons to actually pay for your Linux or your
word processor or whatever. And you know,
the free ones are, I'm not saying free ones are bad.
I'm just saying sometimes there are good reasons to pay for stuff.
Yeah, there's, there's many, many reasons, I mean,
and like my favorite example is always when,
when I set up a server,
I'm happy running Debian on it, right?
I'm more than capable of dealing with that and fixing it.
But when you're a company and it's mission critical
-- and you're, if someone quits your
-- infrastructure
and who says you're going to be there next week?
Yeah, exactly. Like I, I totally get it.
-- It makes perfect sense
-- because the other thing I'm looking at, for example,
here's a hypothetical is what about,
you know,
S balm identifying chat GP T or stable diffusion generated content that I
suspect will become a concern for some people long term because perfect example is
uh like marking and cheat detection for like university projects,
right? We already have plagiarism bots for essays.
Well, we're
gonna end up with and, and this also kind of,
I was kind of thinking about this and I'm like certain programming problems,
there's really not that many different ways to program up a solution.
Like if I ask you to, you know, one of those classes like build me a linked list or,
you know, swap two variables in place with a system with no memory or,
you know, whatever those goofy examples are like,
yeah, your answer's gonna look pretty much bit for bit like, well,
the stack overflow answer because that's
the correct answer,
you know,
so fun fact. A I generated content can't be copyrighted.
Yeah. The whole um the monkey that took a selfie with a camera
and they ruled that it had to be a person holding the copyright.
Now, here's the thing. The A I can't hold the copyright
but the company or the people of the company can hold the copy
so far. Ok. So I actually just listened to a
radio show about
specifically Chat GP T I forget who it was. They were talking to a lawyer,
an intellectual property lawyer.
And the lawyer said that at this time
based on existing law and precedent in the courts
that any content generated by like dolly or Chat GP T
is
un copyrightable by any party.
The A I generated the content, the company that wrote the A I doesn't own the content.
The person who asked the question doesn't own the content,
the content cannot be copyrighted.
What happens if they A I generate content and then have a
to massage it a bit.
-- If a human changes it, then it is copyrightable by that human
-- because,
and how much does it have to be changed though?
One pixel? And
well, that,
that's
no, no, there is a,
I, I forget those terms. I'm not a lawyer obviously.
And again, if you're getting legal advice from this podcast, you're screwed.
So, but no, there is a, there's a legal
precedent about how much you have to transform a work before it becomes derivative.
Like, and I don't know what what it is, but there is a legal definition of that.
So you have to take the original work and turn it into a
-- derivative work
-- because I could see like this is going a bit dystopian,
but I could totally see like sweatshops and cheap countries with people like
tracing digital art to, you know,
say that it was human generated. Uh let's not give them any ideas
seriously.
But,
and that's that, you know,
so because I'm looking at this from sort of
a practical point of view of what's going to
happen in more the near term, but also long term, like more like to put it simply,
there is not a single
major application on my phone that runs
without access to some service on the internet.
Yes,
that is correct.
And, and to date,
there's really nothing in the
bomb universe right now that accounts for things like services.
And I understand that because I think
that is one of the probably second or third step beyond where we're at.
Like,
i it's very crawl, walk, run. Right.
And, and I think we forget that a lot of times and there are people who complain about,
oh,
bombs don't do services so they're useless.
And it's like, well, I mean, not yet but they, they will like, it'll come,
I mean,
it's kind of like you've been talking about security vulnerabilities in the cloud,
right?
No one's tracking them or paying attention to them. Like,
that's weird. You know,
mostly because they're not, I hate, well, I think fundamentally they're not so bad
that we've had that moment of, oh my God, this is truly terrible.
And that's also not even happen for real software where we've seen,
well, like ransomware, for example, has, you know, actually, oh,
the British government just identified ransomware as like, what do they call it?
Like a tier one concern.
Yeah, I remember reading about that. It's very bad
is basically what they said and for English people to call something very bad, it's,
you know, it's serious,
like they were putting it up there with terrorism.
I mean,
I won't disagree with that.
Well, when you think about the cost, I mean, here's the thing, if I,
if somebody did, well to put it bluntly, if,
if you have a problem that's costing you hundreds
of millions or billions of dollars a year.
Yeah, that's, that's a real problem.
Well, remember when all the UK hospitals shut down
of ransomware for the not Pet M ss?
Oh, here we go. UK government declares ransomware a tier one national security
on security threat,
on part with terrorism and military crisis between states
and the other thing to think too is like,
there is a lot of ransomware that is, you know,
they live in Russia,
they don't attack Russian systems.
Right.
Well, they can't, they don't want to get in trouble. Like
-- there's an agreement.
-- There was a guy called Fons Klaus
that talked about this a long time ago,
you know, real politic and such.
So, yeah, I don't know. It's, but back to the SBA
thing.
Well,
we have to walk but at the same time it's
also sometimes useful to know where we might want to go
two or five or even 10 steps down the road.
I mean. Sure.
Sure.
And I think a lot of people are thinking about this stuff
and we know things like services are going to have to come.
We know there's a lot of other artifacts we're gonna have to track,
we know we're going to have to do a better job.
Like here, here's a great example actually. So in a, in a running system,
right? When, if we look at the list of S bombs, uh what is it called, run time?
So there is currently
a question about runtime of what is included in a runtime S bomb.
And there are some people who say, oh, I just want to know like everything on disk
and there's people who are saying I want to know what every process running is
and I want to even know like what is in the memory of those processes.
And like that is not an unreasonable ask in a lot of ways
I can think of things where I would color it.
-- But
-- at the same time, like I agree, that is a good idea.
But I think for the moment like,
let's just figure out what's on disk and then we'll look at what the processes are.
But you know what I mean? Like
there's so many questions and there's so much unanswered,
but there are a lot of people working on this, I mean,
one of the things I always talk about, so I've got that SBO
everywhere meeting, which I'll, I'll put a link in the show notes.
If anyone's interested in joining the group, like it's open to all.
We, we, we'd love to have you. But anyway,
every time we have a meeting,
I learn about some new, like s
bomb working group or SBO
project or S bomb, something that I've never even heard about.
And I feel like I'm pretty deep in these weeds as it is.
And there's so much, I don't know.
Well, and so, and then there's another thing I was thinking about was ok.
So we recently went through actually iso
9001 certification at the cloud security lines.
And it was funny because the others like, do you have a list of all your suppliers?
And I'm like, oh, who do I ever have this giant spreadsheet that goes way back?
And it's not, it's a list of every supplier. Why we use them? What we use them for?
Do they do H SSL and TLS? Right? Because it's that,
which at the time was a good question.
Where is there GDPR statement, stuff like that?
You know, do they process pi I, what kind of P I,
is it transitory like or is it stored or blah, blah, blah.
Anyways. And
one of the things
he raised was, why do you use these vendors?
And I'm like, well, because we have like some case, we just have to like,
we use Microsoft Office because that's what you do.
When you get a word document, you pay them.
Same thing with Adobe.
You know,
if you do digital design, you pay Adobe.
And
one thing he taught me though, it was interesting was
like, not only why did you pick them but how hard,
like what would it take to get rid of them?
And I'm like, well, some, we just can't. And so I started to think about the
fib.
So some are pretty fungible. Like we use
Syd and Mail Gun
and
yeah, it would be a pain to get rid of one and just use the other one.
And so we have, we have two because they have different capabilities
but some things we just can't get rid of like, again, Adobe or office because
that's it. You got to pay that like sales force, you gotta do that.
And so I was thinking about this in terms of S
bomb and software.
So we've learned from supply chains that for example,
if you're building a car and you're missing a few chips,
you can't build a car, right?
Like if you're missing spark plugs, you just,
you can't ship 99% of a car by weight and be like, oh yeah, it's mostly there but,
you know, like just hook it up to a tow truck maybe.
And so like, remember there was that I think it was Ford or something,
those Ford expeditions where they were like shipping
without the climate controls in the back.
And then you could come back later and get them installed because
they basically kind of tried to make the car as serviceable as possible.
So you could ship them and get some money.
And so I was thinking so traditionally with software, if I build it,
I have and assuming I do a hermetic build,
I have all the bits and I can't kind of like run out of screws
right
now, ignoring people who do builds that involve like a curl something bash
where you could run out of those screws. Because what if that site's down that day?
Well, you can't build your software, right?
That
is
true. And so I was thinking,
but there are
analogous situations where, for example,
I am pulling in a piece of software,
I need a certain version and it's got a
CV SS severity 10 remotely exploitable flaw in it,
right.
Well,
I can't just pull that in and ship it and be
vulnerable to that in some cases or maybe I can't.
And so there are like I said, analogous situations where
your supply chain gets disrupted
and maybe that thing is not available.
And,
and the extreme case would be like you're doing a
curl bash thing and that server is not available,
you know, or somebody deletes the package off N PM like left shift.
Boom, you know, all the screws are gone and your packages all break
left pad, sorry. Right.
Like somebody deleted all the screws that hold all of N PM together.
It's rare though. So, you know, but
-- it can happen.
-- You're not incorrect. I think that's a fair comparative.
And so then that leads to, you know, do we want to give things a fung
il score or like how hard would this be to replace? Like a web server? You know,
depending on how you use the web server, it might be really easy to replace.
Like if it's serving static assets, Engen
X or Apache pick one, I don't care. But if you've built a flask application,
you have a flask application,
right?
You're using Python and there's no way to go
-- around that or
-- if you build it with uh Django
and Django goes away. You.
Well, perfect example web finger dot io, it runs on cloud floor workers.
If I don't have cloud floor workers, I got nothing
like,
I mean, that's been,
that's true of everything and it's always going and that's actually
so Toyota,
what do they call it just in time supply chain or something like that
and
just in time delivery.
So I was reading some articles about all of the just in time stuff that
Toyota created and they,
they were mocking the fact that the vast majority of companies heard just in time
and then they just stopped keeping inventory of everything. Whereas
the actual
kind of how just in time is supposed to work
is you do exactly.
Like you're saying, you determine what the products are,
that are commodity and what the products are that are very specialized.
You make sure the specialized stuff you have some buffer room for and
the commodity stuff you're like whatever we can buy screws from anyone.
-- We don't care and,
-- or you can change your process a little bit. Yeah.
Right. Right.
And, and I think software is kind of similar, but I also want to say again,
coming back to the PS A,
this is a very young and new industry.
We talked to Caroline the rust episode and she was, you know, talking about the,
the rail industry taking 80 years to do something.
Oh yeah.
To,
to change from uh from a localized mechanical brakes to
the air brake system where if the pressure drops,
they all clamp shut.
Yeah.
And, and as software as an industry, we're really only what,
20 or 30 years in probably.
Well,
-- but
-- we also keep throwing away all the rails we previously had in getting new ones.
Like that's true. That's true.
Mainframes used to rule the earth like dinosaurs and now they're in zoos.
No, seriously. Right.
Like I remember in 1999 giving a security talk at Vanguard Security Expo
where I had to explain like client server programming to
these people because they were mainframe people they were like,
we have a computer,
we have dumb terminals or actually now it's dumb terminals running on P CS.
They're like, we only have one computer to deal with. The rest of everything else is
literally the, the most fungible dumb terminal possible.
And so now it's like, oh no client server,
like the client does some stuff and the server does some stuff and magic TCP/IP.
What's this?
You know, computers plenty.
But that's the thing, right? Like,
I mean, we, we're again on that show with Rust, we're talking about like,
we need to throw out C and C++,
we'll ignore the fact that there's several trillion lines
of code by line and dollar value out there though that we have to replace.
-- But look,
-- this is the story of Rust though. You don't have to throw it away.
You can slowly make it better
but that you're getting rid of that old stuff.
Well, we do have to get rid of the old stuff.
But anyway, we're, we're, we're running ourselves out of time here.
So I, I think we should,
we should probably clean this one up.
But yeah, I think at the end of the day it's just really, like,
this is all really new and if you don't know what's going on with
that bomb or you've never really heard of it or you don't know what's happening
and you think everyone else seems to have, have it all together.
They totally don't, no one really knows what's going on.
This is a brand new industry. It's brand new ideas
and anyone who pretends like they have all the answers for you,
they're full of crap and don't believe anything.
They,
they're trying to sell you something.
Well, probably that, I mean,
and if you need bombs I'll, I'll sell you something. So,
it's as
long as they're on desk.
Right. Right.
So, anyway, anyway, yeah, I don't know.
It's going to be an interesting couple of years I think. And, and I will say I'm,
I'm optimistic for where things are going to go. I think we have a lot of work to do.
And I think there's a lot of, there's a lot of, kind of wishful thinking
that I think there's people who don't want to do the hard work.
And the only way we get past this is we need to do the hard work.
-- Like there's, there's no plan B,
-- well,
and the other thing is we have to do the hard work because we actually have
to experience and figure out what we need and what we don't need and everything.
Right. Like, that's why I built a web finger server is because
I could write a paper on it. But
I would not have learned seven of the things I did learn by doing it for reals.
100%. 100%. Absolutely.
Payne is the best teacher, Kurt.
-- Well,
-- but it's also, there's emergent behaviors and there's, you know, having,
having something to show people is way different than here's a slide deck.
No, here's the thing you can poke at,
you know, get more requests on and, oh, let's,
you know, and it came up a Christmas dinner of all things where they're like,
why can't we have email address?
Portability? And I'm like, huh, that is a good question.
Right.
You know, there's some other anyways.
So yeah, I think with that bomb
we're gonna, well, the good news is it's happening
and it's not just happening,
but some large entities like the US government are saying it's going to happen.
Oh,
yeah, yeah, they're, they're the biggest driver of it for sure. Right now.
Well, I think they're smart enough to realize that like
they don't want to get bushwhacked by some random library blowing up, you know,
half of their it services.
Yeah,
-- that's right. That's right.
-- Like log for Jay with free volunteers.
Yy, 100%. All right. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show. Not Susie
Podos Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye,
the