We're recording a podcast.
We're a security podcast. Remember?
Hello and welcome to the open source security.
I'm just going to leave all this in from the time I said,
or a security podcast.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
-- and my partner and this is not technically job. So we're ok, Josh Pressers.
-- Ok.
So it's funny you say that because it amuses me every now and then I'll get an email.
-- Like I get a lot of pitches for guests like a lot. You know
-- what's
weird is I get pitches and they don't CCU
but then I'm like, oh yeah,
and sometimes we're both CC and it wouldn't shock me
at all if we each get the same pitches.
-- Oh,
-- maybe they don't know how to use CC maybe.
-- And
-- if you go to the Contact Us page, like you and I
both listed anyway, every now and then someone will be like,
how much money do you want for this gap?
And I'll always say something like
we don't accept money. Our currency is ideas
and they have never once replied when I say that to them,
what does that tell you.
And I love when they're trying to pitch them and make it sound good and I, I, like,
look them up or I look up their thing and it's like to be blunt.
Wow, they actually hired a pretty good pr firm, like,
because they're trying to real hard, pitch them and stuff, but, like,
they have nothing to pitch and look
ok with that, like, hire apr firm, pr firms doing it like whatever. I get it.
-- I get it
-- all well, but gets music clearly. Never listen to the podcast
either.
That too. It's like, do you know who you're dealing with?
And who was it? There was, I don't remember who.
-- Now we had a guest one time
-- with the Minder.
The minder.
That one amused me greatly.
-- We've had what I think we've had two or three guests now with Minders which,
-- 00,
lots of people have the, the, the handlers, whatever.
That's fine.
I
don't mind it.
Anytime I do stuff with work they send a handler along to for some reason.
Yeah, for some reason.
Anyway,
anyway,
there,
there was someone one time that they were a
guest and then they sent me an email afterwards.
You're like, you guys are just like yourselves in
because they, they, they didn't expect it. Like this is who we are.
-- Like this isn't some like persona.
-- We're not like radio show hosts,
right?
And so the before, like during the recording and then after it was,
this is what you get,
like, what did, what did you think you were going to get?
Like, I'm sorry, I disappointed you, I guess, I don't know what to say.
And maybe the difference is in, in the sort of professional, like,
newscasting type world.
They, they are kind of almost actors in a way that's probably fair.
And so there is like a professional persona of, like,
the way they read sad stories and talk about sad news is, you know,
not how you and I would do it.
Yeah. Right. Right. And, and we,
we, we're not getting paid.
No one's here to be like,
we're taking your money away if you don't start
-- acting like professionals
-- or the sponsors will pull.
And that's why I don't want sponsors either because
we can be clowns and no one cares anyway.
All right, we, we have an actual topic. We've,
ah, I don't know,
but to be fair, the right sponsor for the right price. We're open to it.
Look anything over a million, like you're in like, yeah,
we'll literally talk about anything for over a million dollars.
Just, just throwing that out there.
No, not cheese. No, no, man. I live in a place with lots of cheese. I don't need cheese.
What I need is a million dollars,
million dollars each.
No, I was actually just expecting you to take the million bucks.
And, well, that's true.
I could just take it, I have basically total control over this process. But
anyway,
anyway, so
this is sadly related to the topic. Let's get to the point.
Yeah.
So, so what happened is,
I guess Equifax either got suspicious or wanted to
try an experiment or something and they basically,
Equifax used to be a credit ratings agency and by, used to be, I mean,
like decades ago now they're like every piece of data about every human
on the planet company basically and probably jealous of Facebook and they,
they have data like payroll stuff and all that.
So anyway,
so they basically brand the data and found out a
bunch of their people had more than one job now.
Ok, let's set the stage here for a sec.
Number one people who apparently work for Equifax sign an agreement,
a contract that says they will only work for Equifax.
And so to be blunt, if you sign a contract and then violate it,
yeah, that's gonna suck for you
because that's kind of the whole point of contract law is
we agree
on a thing
and sign it and then abide by the rules of it. And then
if we don't, there's penalties or like getting sued and stuff,
I signed the same contract when I went to work
at Elastic where I was not allowed to take on
extra work without first consulting with
like the company. And that's fine.
-- I mean, I was fine with it. They
-- basically
what really gets me is how do I put this nicely?
A traditional problem with white collar work
is we can't
measure productivity now for a lot of blue collar jobs.
That's a really critical thing.
Like if you have a machinist running a million dollar CNC machine,
well, he
like seven parts that Met specs versus this other
guy who produced like 14 parts that Met specs.
Ok.
Well,
maybe we can have the 14 parts person train
the seven parts person and figure out a better workflow
and, and that's where you get into like six sigma and efficiency management,
all that, you know, Taylorism and blah, blah, blah.
Right?
And,
and that works actually shockingly well for like
the manufacturing and stuff world because like,
as you can see now,
like I can get random things from China delivered to my
doorstep in a day or two and most of them work.
I I want to clarify a point there because I
think something we forget is manufacturing has been more studied,
I think throughout history.
And so
it's not that you can't measure white collar work.
I would say it's, we don't know how to measure a lot of white collar work.
I would say it's even worse than that.
Do we even know what success means?
-- And
-- I'm not starting that conversation
and,
and I would say we probably don't even know really what success means.
So then how do we like, what do we measure
-- share price.
-- I, I think it sort of comes down to the end of the day is you have companies
and fundamentally the thing the company is going to look at is the
revenue coming in. Right.
They expect the revenue to be growing quarter over quarter year, over year.
-- Yeah,
-- and profit and whatnot as well.
And profit is another story that's kind of different now in the universe we live in.
But basically you want revenue to go up, right?
And if revenue isn't going up, there's something wrong.
But the problem is especially when you have some of
these large companies revenue can go up company wide.
But you could have parts of the company that are like extremely sick
and actually dragging everything down around them.
We don't always have a good way to figure that out.
Well, you can also have an entire company that's doing well,
but is essentially in a dead end industry.
That is also true. You know.
So for example,
all the companies that were didn't make the transition to smartphones.
A lot of them had really good,
like Blackberry up until the end had some pretty good quarters and then just
off a clock
-- that
-- is
-- like
-- literally like and anyway, so
-- let, let's reframe this now.
So you've got Equifax looks at their company.
Here's, that's not as scary as the the story I dug up from business insider.
They found there were people have been found at some of these companies, like,
literally collecting paychecks from two companies
at the same time,
two full time jobs, like, in Equifax's case, some of the people were doing that,
it sounds like.
And a lot of the people just had a second job,
like they were doing something in the evenings or whatever,
one of my concerns there would be.
So, if company a is paying you for, let's say,
for the sake of argument for 40 hours a week.
Yeah, I mean,
what's to say?
Somebody can't work 80 hours a week and just be really busy and sleep and work and
eat, take out food.
I, I'm like, I'm not saying it's, it's a good idea,
-- but it's
-- the business insider story.
They don't explicitly say it,
but it is well suggested that people were not doing their jobs.
They were basically barely doing enough to not
get fired while working at two companies and basically
-- doubling their pay.
-- Well.
And see this speaks to why does it take so
many months for these companies to figure this out?
Like, literally,
if somebody like is on an assembly line and not doing anything that day,
you hopefully figure it out pretty quickly when like the tires
start falling off cars at the end of the assembly line.
Right? And that's the thing with white collar work. It's hard.
But at the same time, like people, well, I remember simple things like a red hat.
We kind of kept a log of what we did. Right.
And sent it in every, what was a week or something. I want to say
it was, it was weekly and I, I do that now. I mean,
I am on anchor's management team and we fill out a management report every week for
Anchor
and, and that's cool. Like,
the,
the problem I have is like, what can I put in like 100 million things I've done,
I can put five in, like which five should I put in?
-- So I,
-- I mean,
this is an example of why I like ticketing systems and things because it's like,
I don't have to fill,
it's just like here's a pile of tickets I touched and solved and opened and whatever.
It's like turning your get commit messages into the change log for the release.
-- And
-- I get some of it was tough because I remember at Red Hat,
I got grief for not doing enough, but I'm like, I'm not gonna put like, doing email.
That's like just
things that I like, how can I not do email and my job?
So I want to reframe this conversation because
I think we're getting a little off track.
And the reason I was interested in this topic when you kind of
brought it up and brought it to my attention is that I think
measuring
or I shouldn't say measuring, but rather understanding
what people are doing at work, especially from the new work from home universe.
Where in the past you had managers staring at people, sitting at desks,
typing away doing something.
And now you have people at home so that environment doesn't work.
But then we look at things like the world
of security and how many security teams have no way
to show any progress or effort that they're doing.
-- And I feel like there are enormous parallels
-- here.
You said the word understanding,
which I find fascinating because I would say a
lot of places aren't even at the observing stage,
let alone understanding stage.
I don't think observing is important.
Well, observing is step one because without observing,
how can you then understand?
Right.
And which I think this actually speaks to what a lot of companies try to do,
which is they put on these horrifically intrusive,
monitoring things that like monitor your key clicks and stuff
because I suspect many of them equate observable with understanding,
which speaks to you saying all managers used to like walk around
the floor and observe their workers and know that they were working.
-- No, like half of them were doing the New York Times portal. They were,
-- but they,
they're sitting in a chair so they could justify paying that person for,
for working.
And I put that in air quotes versus now I can sit at home and watch
youtube all day and they wouldn't know it because they don't know what I do.
And there's no way to show that my day
resulted in this particular outcome for the organization,
right?
And so we're going to leave that whole
aside because it's way too complicated.
Now, as far as security goes, for example, there are sometimes directly observe
things.
So a perfect example is this weekend,
I enabled two of a for everybody in our Microsoft 365
finally got that done.
I was supposed to enable single sign up for docusign,
but their documentation doesn't match their webinar face and it didn't work.
I think I know why I didn't work but I want to make them make sure that anyways,
I I don't basically want to troubleshoot
it when their documentation should be correct.
That's fair.
You know,
we're in the process of finally getting like everybody up keys and rolling that out.
So
for example, like, one of my basic goals this year is to get everybody up keys,
get our Google locked down to hardware authentication tokens, only
Microsoft two fa because I'm not willing to pay for,
what is it E five or E six or whatever the heck
it is to get single sign on and all the fancy stuff.
And you know, most of our documentation goes public anyway.
So I don't really have, it's,
we're a nontraditional organization in that way and
that like the majority of what we produce,
we actually desperately want people to read
like no. Right. That, that's one of the reasons. I like working for Red Hat.
It's like, oh,
you read our source code, huh?
Yeah. Did you find any bugs? Can you please tell us?
Right? Like, we can't pay for it. But
-- can you please tell us?
-- Actually, I have a funny side note there is.
So I'm helping out a first robotics organization at my son's high school.
I'm the programming mentor for the group, which is a ton of fun.
Like, they're great kids.
I'm, I'm learning a lot.
Like,
it's stuff like I'm not III I would love to like
actually program the robot because that would make my day.
But I, I I'm not allowed to.
You can make it so much better than these kids.
I know, I feel like come on, I've only got 30 years of experience over you.
It's so simple anyway. So it's funny because
they have a Discord.
They have a github.
They have all this and like, they give it to me.
And the first thing I did was like, I just,
I opened it everything wide open and they're like, what are you doing?
The other mentors? I'm like, this is just way easier. Like default to open, trust me.
And it was funny,
they thought I was like a crazy person and after a month they're like,
this is a lot easier.
Like I told you,
yeah, like least privilege is great until you actually have to get work done.
-- Especially with kids.
-- I know, it's horrible.
And they're like, you're a security guy, I'm like, you'll see
anyway, anyway,
back to measuring security.
And then,
and then another thing I would point out is essentially cloud security
lines and data breach are not words you will find in Google.
-- I
-- mean, not yet. Don't, don't ever say that so
far.
I've done a decent job and that's part of it. Right.
Is, is a perfect example because I was talking to my son, you know,
because my recently my credit card got compromised somewhere and on Sunday a
week ago, you know, it got popped and used in Singapore to order food.
And so I was talking with my son Felix about this,
you know, talking about how blah, blah, blah.
And, you know,
I pointed out like one of the things I did at the CS A to make
sure that we would never have this happen is we just don't handle payment cards.
Like we outsourced it to paypal and braintree,
which is totally the right thing. I made that choice over 10 years ago.
And like not my problem just if, and if paypal gets reached like I
man, who else am I gonna pick? I get? Not everybody can do that. But
the thing is like, there are
sort of measurable things you can do to
try and
improve things.
Yeah, like as far as sort of the day to day goes, it's,
it's like basically doing plant maintenance it's like, yeah,
-- I tightened all these bolts and, like, nothing caught fire, I guess I did my job
-- and,
and so that's part of the challenge I think is when you are in many of these roles,
if nothing happens, you've done your job.
You know what I mean? I mean?
And that's one of the funny things sometimes, like, if you have a programmer,
you can say, oh, this programmer
wrote this much code. But I, I remember I was reading
added a feature.
Well, I,
I was reading an article and I think it might have been Ken Thompson who did this.
But they, they worked somewhere and they, at the end of every day,
they were supposed to,
they had to send a report saying this is how many lines of
code I wrote this day because someone decided they were going to measure programmer
output lines of code
and they, they,
they deleted a bunch of stuff like they were like clean refactoring code or moving.
And so they sent the report where like I wrote minus 10,000 lines of code today.
-- That's an incredibly important
-- sometimes.
But their manager got really mad at them for
that because they obviously didn't understand what was happening.
But at the same time, like there have been days I have written
10 lines of code
and it legit took me eight hours to write those 10 lines.
And there have been days I've written like hundreds of lines of code
and the 10 lines,
-- like where I was far more proud of, you know. So
-- you weren't on the last GSD call.
But I showed them my myro board with my,
the kind of layout of the software and it's like,
that represents tens of hours of work plus, well,
sort of implicitly hundreds and thousands of
hours of understanding spanning back two decades.
And all I've got is basically a one screen size thing with like 20 post it notes.
But it's,
and everybody was like, oh,
-- it's actually really good. But
-- that's the thing.
That's the thing.
How do you show
that you're doing work in an environment like that?
And especially like one of the other things I was thinking about.
So let's say you've got a situation where someone's like, oh, are you,
are you doing your work?
And
I have been on projects that have taken like more than a week
before we had a result.
So at the end of the week, I could be like, well,
I've been working on this but I literally have nothing to show for it.
Well, it's funny because there's a war blogger
pin who talks about this, how he talks about um
scientific advancement
isn't like in a computer game where it's like, ok, go, you know,
uh uh send a million dollars or a million minerals
to buy the upgrade for the building armor or whatever,
like in Starcraft
in the real world. You spend, um,
a jillion dollars
and like you, you might get nothing or worse than nothing,
you might end up with something that's poisonous.
Right.
It's not like, it's, it's, if I give you a billion dollars to do R and D,
it's not a guarantee that you're gonna
get something useful out of that.
I think R and D money is rarely wasted
because what happens in the world of R and D and this is actually this, that we should,
this might be the key.
So in the world of R and D,
you're given money, you're told to do something,
you do the thing and then you write up a huge report whether it works or doesn't work.
And if it doesn't work, you gain new knowledge that you can then apply
in some meaningful way in the future.
Whereas I feel like in the world of security today,
we often are in a situation where it's like here's,
I need a million dollars to buy this tool
and then you give me a million dollars and like did the tool work and you're like,
-- I guess
-- like
again, it came up like in the scientific, like there's no controls, like,
yeah,
we spent a million dollars on this uh security system to reduce the
number of flaws uh through our software in the C I CD pipeline.
Well, would they have happened without it,
-- would they have been caught without it? Like, is it you know what I mean?
-- Like,
yeah,
like I have a SIM, right. A security,
what information and event manager
manager?
Yeah, I never remember that.
It's funny.
I've worked,
I worked for a company that freaking made one and I can never remember it.
I still have to look up how to spell red hat with the space or without,
who cares. Anyway,
-- like,
-- well, the point is, like,
I worked there for seven years and I still have to look at like, oh,
and you're wearing a t-shirt and it's wrong.
I'm wearing a literal
red hat. But this is the
shirt but there's no space in the
shirt I'm wearing. But
my guess is if I worked there,
the brand people would probably yell at me for earning this shirt.
I, I've kept some choice red hat shirts.
But anyway, ok, so, so let's say we have a SIM. Right?
And this is a great example of it. It monitors incidents. It looks for events.
You're, you're digging, you're sifting through all this data and
the people using it are very busy. Right. Extremely busy. Probably too busy.
-- But does it, does it matter?
-- Well, no, I know many security teams that are just,
they, they need more work. Like they're complaining they're bored, they need some
have never met a security team.
I'm being sarcastic.
I
like,
I,
like, I want, I wanna work on that security team.
But anyway, the point is right. I've got a Sim, I've got all this data. It
doesn't matter. We think it does
but we can't actually prove it. Does.
Have you actually used it to, like, block or stop an attack?
-- No, you've never seen one actually stop an attack.
-- Well, or not to stop an attack.
But like the cat, like my credit card got, they caught it finally when they're like,
oh, a couple of $500 transactions for food in Singapore that might not be current.
-- Maybe we should stop it.
-- That's fraud detection. That's different.
That's something different. We're not, I don't want to go there. Uh
Sim, specifically. So here's the thing with Sim. Right?
You can have your endpoint, what, what do you call the, the new
antivirus, endpoint detection? Sure. We'll call it endpoint detection,
right.
You've got like,
-- your endpoint detection running
-- or endpoint management or control
-- the
-- stuff that, like, looks for
strange behavior
and like, shoots the process in the head or whatever. Right.
I have no idea what it's called.
So,
you've got some of that and I have very
little experience with that doing actually catching bad things.
Generally speaking
99% of the time it's false positives.
Then you have SIM alerts where you've got like weird traffic on your network.
You've got weird log entries and that's the thing,
like throwing up constant errors to the,
the security analysts looking at it. Right. Then you have the,
like, post
incident research that's being done.
And that part where you go look at log files,
you look at what's in the SIM you tie all this information together and you can say,
OK,
this malware got on this laptop
and then it later moved to this server over here
and then it stole this data from that server
like that.
It's very good and useful for. But some of the other things
I, I can't tell you it like actually, I mean,
now if you ask any company that works on it, they're gonna give you
tons of examples of it doing its job. But I can tell you that I,
I am more suspect of that data.
So question does the si have a thing built in to
sort of capture and build an artifact around that event?
Because I'm thinking about the real world and
real world security where when there's an incident,
there's always an incident report and or maybe even police report,
like everything gets
like,
like you can go like the Edmonton police service has a GIS database
that
you or anybody on the planet can go look at like
neighborhoods in Edmonton and say like over this 30 day period,
what happened, you know, like
and, and see that data
and
because what I'm thinking of is like in the real world, it's,
it's really easy to get data and statistics and stories,
not just anecdotal stories,
but like news stories like properly researched
things that have been confirmed and verified
about
criminal incidents, right?
Like uh think about the news like that,
that's one of the main things the news covers typically.
But in the cybersecurity world, like how many companies put out really,
like really truthful
uh detailed post mortems of security events. And like, I there's like five r
like there's like Google cloud flare.
Well, look, they, they don't even put out the kind of data you actually need.
So what happens in this universe is
what you really need are things like IP addresses and
operating systems and behavior you've seen on
your network and there are sharing platforms
you can, there's things like sticks and taxi which have the intent
is that you have like organizations come together
and share some of this like threat material.
Well, heck we run one like
true star like we're,
yeah, but, but they're not,
they're not super useful, like there's some good stuff in there. But the problem is
I think
what you see in the world of security, a lot of companies want to kind of
hide a lot of this information and they don't want to share it so they don't share.
It's not like
when you're talking to the police,
the police legally have to make all this stuff public. You know what I mean?
-- Well, in not all jurisdictions
-- but yeah,
well, but you know what I mean?
Like generally speaking it, it's very different whereas
companies and this is something where,
when you see things like the SEC in the United States,
the Securities and Exchange Commission
saying like, if you experience a breach, no matter how small you have to report it.
And some of that I think is going to
change some of this because now we have a situation where
organizations have to start reporting what's going on versus today,
they generally don't report things unless it's like a really big deal.
Well, like a simple example, I was talking with some people about cloud S
bomb and I'm like a lot of these companies really don't want to
do that because then they're just gonna get like weird scan reports saying,
hey, you use this version, it's out of date and like, no, we trust me,
we
know
we have a compensating control or whatever
or worse, the press will get on to it and then they're really screwed 100%
going back to the security thing.
Like I'm also kind of because there's been those
reports now of like all those like fake interview,
like deep faked interview videos with, you know,
you asked the interview person to turn their head to
the side so you can see if they're real or not
or you know,
that hacker news thread where people were like being solicited to essentially
go take an interview as this person's name.
Pretend you're them, we'll pay you 500 bucks to do it, blah, blah, blah.
And I assume that, that's the classic, like, show up,
collect the paycheck because if you collect a paycheck for a month or two,
spending 1000 bucks to scam a company
and look a lot of these companies,
it is very difficult to fire people in many instances.
If the company has such bad and weak internal processes that
it is so susceptible to this kind of fraudulent activity,
I feel like they're kind of up the creek regardless. It's like all the,
you know, it's like all these places that are like, oh, you know,
we don't really have this or this security and it's kind of like, well, cool,
the ransomware guys are gonna,
so, you know, they're gonna love you because that's the
thing like
it used to be like 20 years ago.
If you had bad security, you could kind of hide and not probably be attacked.
But now with ransomware and all this automated stuff,
you're gonna get hit eventually.
But it
doesn matter.
Look, look, here's, here's something I've been thinking about a lot.
There is, this is due to a discussion I had um very recently. But
so
if you look at the world of like automotive safety, we pick out, right?
Or even worker safety in factories,
there are a lot of rules and laws and process
that have to be followed and if you don't,
you pay fines and people can get hurt and die, right?
Like that's what happens.
Whereas you look at security and like, let's say secure programming.
If I write an application and I sell you an application and my application
is full of security flaws and I know it's full of security flaws.
What happens then? Nothing,
right?
There's no accountability,
there's no action you can take against me that says you have to
fix this or you sold me something that was known to be bad.
And I don't think it's ever gonna change
until software literally kills like millions of people,
-- which may never happen
-- even then to get the remedy takes so long and
is so onerous and so expensive to pursue in a court of law.
Yeah.
Well, but here's the thing when you have a situation where you have
some overseeing regulatory body like the, you know, the OSHA or whatever,
then you're outsourcing the cost and saying the taxpayers pay for it, right?
And it's not some entity like a company that
like a company is not going to buy a piece of
software for a million dollars and have it feel horribly and then
sue the seller and deal with that because it's gonna cost
easily more than a million dollars to pursue that
and
time and
you're not guaranteed to win.
I mean, you know, it's, it's to the point where,
what is it IBM is banned from doing business with the
new South Wales government because they've messed up so many times.
I heard that
and, and that's,
it's rare enough that it makes the news and that's the thing.
It's like to get an actual remedy against these companies is so difficult.
Like, oh man, just eat the law and move on
-- and,
-- and that happens a lot and, and here's the thing too.
So let's, let's tie this back to the original topic, right? Where you have
employees, let's say mo purposefully defrauding the company
and
there's a couple of pieces to this, we need to tie together.
There's the issue of someone is committing fraud against you, right?
Which there may be legal action.
Maybe, I, I don't know, it depends on the jurisdiction.
Like you're hiring people all over the freaking planet now.
It's very strange and I don't know how that all works.
You have the issue of measuring what people do
because
if you can't really say someone is or isn't doing their job,
how do you take discipline
action against them?
I'm, I'm gonna say this as a hypothetical,
but I know somebody that worked at a place where
their job was so ill defined that under Australian contract,
like employment law,
they could not be fired because their job was so poorly defined
that. Right? Like, and that's what gets me is like, and, and sometimes it's,
I don't want to say it's appropriate, but it's maybe necessary because like,
my role at the CS A is not defined,
like
I'm the it guy who set it all up and sort of still manages it,
but I also do the Blockchain stuff and I also do
the GSD stuff and I do a bunch of other stuff.
But the difference there is,
I have a high trust relationship with the CEO that goes back now.
-- 25 years.
-- Right. Right. You are
-- different.
-- Our iso 9001 auditor looked at my spreadsheet of all our,
um, suppliers and was like, wow, you have like
a
sheet of all your supplies. I'm like, oh, yeah.
And I'm like, and you know,
there's like 20 fields of stuff about security and everything.
And I'm like, and here's my favorite.
I like, here's the one about, have we backed up the data or not?
Does it need to be backed up? Is it a gap? And here's the one about their criticality?
And she's like, how do you find criticality?
And I'm like, how much would Jim yell at me?
She's like, what I'm like, it's how much would Jim Yell? I mean, she's like, I mean,
you have to write that down and explain it somewhere. I'm like, ok,
but that's the thing.
So that is not a sustainable way to do things,
especially in larger organizations that
you can't have somebody like me come to IBM and try and implement that system.
We, we literally are going through this right now because the,
the NISSDF which is 800 to 18, I think.
But the, the secure software development framework
and and obviously we sell to the government.
We have to follow this as well as we have a
product that's going to be used by people to meet this.
Right.
And
anyway, I was having a discussion with someone.
They're like, uh, do we know what we have to do? I said I know what we have to do.
It's all in my head and I'm like, that's not particularly useful to you or me,
but like,
dressed assured we're in pretty good shape and I know what we need to do.
I need to write this down now and it was just like, yeah, it's one of those things,
-- I mean, I, I get that
-- and that's,
and that's something really competent people tend to forget
is like we need to document what we're doing.
And again, that's I like ticketing systems because for example, I use it as like, oh,
I did this thing,
I need to add that to the doc like, so I, I just added a checklist for a thing
for making changes to the email footer where I actually documented
how to test it to make sure the footers are working.
Because so
anyway, anyway,
-- kind of tying all this one up. The thing
-- is
and, and then, but the, the problem then is
that you get these kind of like process heavy systems,
but
either people maybe don't understand and say, oh, it's stupid.
Like, why do I have to do this? And this piece of paperwork.
It's like, no, there's a good reason for it,
but they don't understand and then they try and bypass it and things go, you know.
-- But,
-- but look, that is
like the history of manufacturing
-- is filled with examples of that, of people taking shortcuts. Oh,
-- yeah.
People putting a rock on the emergency stop
button.
-- And
-- right, and, and
I worked in a paper mill in my summers while I was at university.
And
a a frightening amount of the training we had to take was like
this is here. So you don't die, like stop doing things against our rules.
Like that gate is locked for a reason, do not unlock the gate and prop it open.
And that was like everything. And I think
this all ties together this way we do security.
The way we're measuring work from home, like everything it is,
the industry is very mature and something we have to do is we can't just say,
I wish this was better.
We have to actually
make the effort to understand what's happening to document failure.
That's especially important because we suck at documenting failure,
document success. And basically you need to use like science, a scientific method
behind all of this. And that's what it really comes down to.
If you have employees working from home and you don't know what, what they do,
that's not their fault
well, or how they do it or
-- how much of it they're supposed to be doing.
-- That's right.
This is all like, if you honestly go read about manufacturing,
that is my best suggestion here as to understanding like,
what is coming into a system, what is the system doing?
What is coming out of the system?
The problem becomes though is when you have people
like me that do work where it's like,
well, I have like a, you know,
it's like 1/6 order effect on sales where it's like
I do a thing that does a thing that does the
thing that influences a person that does a thing that
does the thing that influences another person to finally make.
-- But
-- Kurt, you have inputs and you have outputs.
-- the problem is I can't directly correlate them
-- because
-- you haven't written them down. No, no, no.
But what I'm saying is like,
how do we correlate the work?
Like, for example, OK, the problem is some things can be documented,
like when you remove a user,
you have to actually boot them out of slack otherwise their connection stays open.
And if they don't log out of their device, they're still there receiving messages
even if their accounts been deleted out of Google and using single sign on.
But, but that can
be
proves my point,
but that can be documented.
But something like,
OK, you know, Dave does like social media posts.
Well, how does that tie into sales directly?
Well, then it's up to Dave and sales to figure out what the inputs are,
what the expectations are and how you're going to measure the output of that.
Like, that's what it is. We do.
I don't know how to do that today in many
instances because it's just we're making this crap up.
It's not done in a scientific way.
And I guarantee people had these conversations about manufacturing 100 years ago.
Part of it is you just have to accept that right there,
there are people doing jobs that where
there isn't really a good measurable outcome or
correlated thing. And that's OK.
I disagree. I disagree.
I think we, we're going to end this now because we're way over time. But I think
it is
the cowardly way out to say we can't measure this job.
I, I firmly believe everything could be measured. I'm not,
oh,
I don't think everything. Well, I don't think everything can be measured. I think
-- I,
-- I, we're going to, we're going to agree to disagree on this point.
And
I think if you can't, I mean, it's the classic, I forget who said it.
I'll put it in the show notes.
But the classic mathematician, if you can't measure something,
you can't understand it.
And I think I, I firmly believe that everything can be measured.
Everything.
How happy am I? Your happiness is two chickens. That's what I'm going to say.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to over
our Security podcast.com.
Hey, the show,
Not
Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag to let Kurt know how happy he is.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the.