Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in looking suspiciously at packages.
Josh
reser.
Why are you looking suspiciously at packages?
Because for example, I, you know,
I go to pi pie and I type in a search term and I
get a whole bunch of results of which some look a bit dodgy.
Some are horrifically out of date.
You know, I haven't been updated in five or 10 years. Some
are like really 0.0 0.2 and you know, hopefully the big one with lots of poll is legit
because how else do I assume? Like, how else do I tell which package is quality?
And I literally just which ones was downloaded the most times.
So when you said packages in my mind, I was thinking like stuff delivered to my house.
Not,
-- not those
-- kind of
that stuff open it,
it's fine.
Yes, it's perfectly fine. There could be nothing bad in it.
-- Hey,
-- well, like I got my flipper zero. This thing is sweet.
Oh, you did get one. I still
haven't ordered one I
need.
There's talk of making them illegal because
well,
you know,
aren't,
I think all the,
all the designs are open
source. I could probably just make my own.
Yeah.
But do you want to do that or do you just want to fork over some money and have it show up?
-- I
-- love making stuff. It's very exciting.
I'm
ok.
But the thing is, this thing has such a nice physical
and
-- well, look,
-- yes.
If I make it,
it's going to be a giant 3d printed brick thing that's going
to be hideous and cut you if you hold it wrong.
But that's ok.
This is just so nice, like the way, like the way it fits in my hand and you know, oh man,
I know,
I
know.
Anyway,
-- anyway,
-- so what
actually, well, not pipe. We should talk about N PM packages.
I want to start with N PM. And the reason I want to start with N PM
is
I have been talking about the N PM data I've collected for like
more than a year now, probably almost two years.
And I finally just wrote a blog post that goes
into some of the detail of some of the data.
And it was published on Anchor's blog because that's where I wanted to put it.
And
it is horrifying and beautiful at the same time.
And so I think it's absolutely lovely.
And then the second half of this is like literally the day after I published my blog,
there is a research paper that comes out from the Sandworm dot Dev folks
that basically say half of the new N PM packages are Seo spam,
which Seo is search engine optimization.
And I was like this is
poetry
well and and Seo spam is a lot worse than people realize
like a perfect example is we use that circle platform from higher logic
and you can sign up and basically it's linkedin think of it
as linkedin combined to a bit with Facebook for business and stuff,
you know, for serious business.
Anyways, the point is you sign in you create an account
and you can create your profile and have links in your profile
and
you know, and you can post discussions and stuff
and we got hammered with spam and of course, I immediately was like,
ah
you know,
and I go dig around the settings and there's a couple of settings to help like,
you know, require first time post moderated
and then after that, let them post, you know, the usual kind of anti spam stuff.
But what's interesting is about four or five days later,
we got an email from from higher logic saying essentially like
we're sorry, we've had to change some defaults,
like basically reading between the lines,
all the higher logic customers got nailed by this big time.
Um you know,
thousands of accounts being created thousands of comments for for backlin span,
right? So that's the thing like these Attackers.
What happens is they find something that works,
you know, they find some site that juices their seo
and
-- they come through like a, a herd of wildebeest.
-- Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I remember probably a decade ago now.
I ran a,
what is, is it media wiki, wikimedia, whatever the Wikipedia wiki is. Right.
I ran that
and I had no
authentication on it because obviously being a public wiki,
I wanted everyone to edit it and, yeah, one day,
like some seo spammers got a hold of it and I shut it down
at the end of the day because at first I tried to save it.
-- I'm like, you know what it's over like I
-- lose.
-- No, you just have to burn it with fire
-- because I couldn't even clean it up.
I didn't have a good backup that was worth using
and there,
there was so much garbage and I was too dumb to figure out
how to just basically say like delete every transaction that's happened today.
And I was like, you know what I'm done like this is it, I'm out and I gave up anyway. OK?
Before we, before we go down that rat hole,
I want to talk about my N PM blog post because I think it's, it's very exciting.
So I titled it Open Source is bigger than you can imagine.
And the reason I did that is because
I have talked to an enormous number of people
over the last couple of years. About open source software.
And there are enormous perception problems around open source, I think.
And it's generally on one hand, no one realizes how just completely gigantic it is.
You know, what really sort of interrupt.
But what really blows my mind is we had the log for J event we had the the Dutch,
forgive me, I can never remember the name of their service.
And with that sorry, massive github
list of affected products.
Like
I know the plural of one data point is not
data,
but that log for Jay is a compelling data point that says,
yeah,
-- open source is everywhere and
-- II I cover that
and that was one package
of one language ecosystem being Java which is kind of the boring corporate one
and
like, yeah PHP Python, all of those are just the same now
-- like it's everywhere.
-- So I cover this in the post I call log for Jr Kaiser Soze
moment
which if you've never seen Usual Suspects,
I'm just going to spoil the crap out of it for you.
So too bad. You should have seen it.
But basically at the end, yeah, when,
when the detective is looking around the room and he
sees like all the things that the the story was about
and he's like, oh crap like this dude was Kaiser. So
like, oh my goodness, like the phone calls are coming from inside the house
and that's what
it was funny too because as someone I work
yelled at me. They were like, no one young knows what Kaiser Soze
means. I'm like, I don't even care like
they can look it up. It's too good not to use.
But anyway, anyway, so there's the enormity of the size of open source.
Does that make sense? The enormity of the size? There's the enormity of the size.
I'm just going with this.
Then the other piece of it that is not understood is how much of this is
one person or as you're going to say just now is less than one person.
Because technically,
yes, technically correct is the best kind of correct. We all know.
But you get the idea most open source like and this is true of literally everything.
This isn't like just N PM isn't just like crappy little packages
every way I have tried to slice and dice this data to prove myself wrong has failed.
Open source is predominantly one person doing something
-- and
-- well,
-- but
-- no, I'm serious.
Do you know how hard it is to convince another human being to have a sandwich,
let alone to write software?
But here's the thing,
the perception of everyone you talk to
is that open source is this gigantic,
healthy community where there's lots of people doing lots of work.
It's survivor bias because
the projects,
the kind of projects that you're using
are things like
Cooper Nets
-- and a patchy blank.
-- That's right. And those get the attention
but,
but worse you're looking at the pier and ignoring all the stuff underneath of it.
That's right. Exactly. 100%.
Here's what I want to describe this as because I was talking to
someone about it and the XK CD Comic of course comes up.
But here's the thing,
the XK CD comic is wrong because it shows one package holding things up.
The reality is the XK CD Comic is a beautiful tower
standing on top of 10,000 single maintainer packages all stacked on top
of each other three miles into the sky.
And it's teetering there.
That is the reality of open source.
It is not the XK CD comic because that gives a
hint of it only being one thing instead of literally everything.
Well and, and the thing is though you can remove some of the packages,
you can live without fine, like no big deal
and some of them, if you remove them from
a, a
the dependency chain, everything just horrifically breaks.
I don't think you can say some of them you can live without,
-- I think
-- well or rather you can live without them in the
sense of it'll degrade but not to the point where it breaks.
I don't know how true that is.
I think the vast majority of people let's, and again,
I'm picking on N PM because it's very popular and their data is very good.
But I have looked at this data in the Python ecosystem in the
ecosystems. And they're very similar like this M PM is not special.
Well, but that's the first thing people say is they say, oh
N PM is special. For some reason, Python will be completely different.
Every time I talk to people about this, they create
mental gymnastics to justify why this is not how all of open source works.
And I'm saying I am
very confident
-- this is open source. This is not special.
-- Here's a perfect example. Curl on github.
Uh
We got,
wow. Yeah, we got Daniel with 17,223 commits.
Then the next person is 2586 commits.
-- Then 1911 100 it's going
-- to be a typical power distribution curve.
It's
a really steep power
distribution curve.
Like by the time we get to number five,
we're at 659 commits by the time we get to the bottom,
like to number like number 30 is 24.
I'm not surprised
that is a vertical wall that is open
source, Kurt.
And that's what I'm saying.
It's like curl is easily one of the most popular, widely used things on the planet.
And to put it bluntly,
if he didn't get any contributions from anybody
that would be like looking at the numbers here. OK.
Well, this one person actually did do a lot.
But if you basically, if the top four contributors to curl
did all the work and everybody else went away, we probably wouldn't notice.
But that's, that's how all of this works.
And, but that's true for almost all projects, except for maybe the Linux kernel,
that one.
Linux
has really scaled sideways quite well.
-- I think about that one a lot.
-- But also the kernel is special in that.
Like I can write an Ethernet subsystem and it has no
bearing in relation to your sound card or your whatever.
And I think that's one thing that makes the Linux kernel special is
it is so massive. It's like city sized, but they're also
in some ways, although they're tightly coupled obviously because it's the kernel.
But like, yeah, I mean,
I can do whatever I want my Ethernet driver
and that's not going to affect your sound driver.
Now, I say that and I'm actually struggling with the windows, you know,
my sound blaster,
Odyssey FX is completely pooping the bed and I figured
out why it's because the drivers are from 2015,
that's
fine.
And the minute I enabled PC I bifurcation to put in my um my uh M two card
PC I bifurcation, I don't even know what that means.
-- PC
-- I bifurcation lets me take a 16 lane PC I slot and break it up into four by four.
And so I have a card that has four M, two slots on it
and each of those gets four PC I lanes. So I have four
M two drives each being driven up for like, so it only takes up one slot physically.
And the moment since I've enabled PC I bifurcation, I been using that card.
My sound blaster oy
has just been
garbage
and it's a driver issue and there's no new drivers since eight years ago.
So,
you know, I have a new
uh sound thingy on order and there's nothing you can do.
But yeah, I think, but the thing is even the Linux kernel is still, you know,
the top 100 or
1000 developers is the vast majority of work compared to
probably
like this is like commercial software houses where you hire 10,000
people and all make them work eight hours a day.
Now, I have a question that you are forbidden from answering.
This is for the audience, I'm going,
I,
I think about this all the time and I would love to
know what people think like just add us on Mastodon or something.
And, and maybe we'll talk about this in the future but
is part of the Linux kernels. Massive cooper
success. Is that a word Cooper Cooper success?
Is that because it's GP L versus Apache two do
not
answer. I see. No, no, I can see.
I can see
that's
a
good question because licenses
-- licenses matter.
-- Anyway, now we're not talking about that today.
We're talking about N PM today,
but maybe another day we could discuss that because I, I
I think about that one a lot. And I
-- will say I go back and forth on a regular basis
-- and let me ask a follow up question
with respect to the GP L, the Apache and the BS D license, who's the user?
And it's a lot more subtle than most people think
that
-- you could write a thesis. A phd thesis on that question. Oh,
-- more than one thesis
anyway, it's moving along
right. N PM. OK.
So
we talk about the size of N PM gigantic.
I will say though the one thing I want to add, I'm,
I'll have the link to my blog post in the show notes,
like go and look at the picture or maybe I'll just make this the,
the image for the podcast because like holy crap,
it isn't most beautiful graph you will ever see.
Even though now we know half of them, half of the new packages are seo spam.
-- Like it's a gorgeous graph
-- though. One quick question, the seo spam packages.
Do they ever do updates or do they just one and done?
It sounds like they're very one and done and I wouldn't expect updates.
My follow up question would be
is, are you able to differentiate the seo spam from the people
doing the tutorial of uploading a package?
Uh I probably, I have a suspicion that the N PM folks have the ability to do this,
but I don't know if they'll want to because their incentive is really around show
growth.
Oh yeah, we have 3 billion packages,
right? Like we want to be, we want to show the most growth of any repository ever.
So they like is there really a downside to seo packages?
Like are they violating the terms of service? I don't know,
but I I have a suspicion they're not going to push hard on this because
growth at all costs, man. Like that's the way.
Well, it's kind of wild to me because N PM, js.org is clearly won like they don't,
it's like github or
you know, like
no, but, but here's the thing. Ok.
So the growth I think matters in an environment like this
because what happens is one of the reasons I think N PM overtook Ruby is N
PM was showing massive growth while Ruby was
showing a more constrained growth at the time.
And now we probably know that that was because Ruby was a little harder to get into.
We'll say N PM was a little bit
more of the wild West
useless on its own. You need rails full stop anyway.
But I, I think in the case of NP MA lot of people saw the growth and they were like, well,
this is clearly the future because it's growing so much faster.
And I think if N PM slows their growth and another ecosystem has larger growth,
people are going to say, oh,
this new ecosystem is the future. Now, we should all learn rust or
whatever. I don't even know what the new languages are.
Everyone's pointing at except Rust.
Oh my
God.
You get the idea though, right.
There's a lot of perception issues that I think are going to come up in any,
any kind of discussion like this.
So, and, and
we talked about a couple of episodes ago,
I thought N PM was a foundation N PM is owned by Microsoft.
So Microsoft from a business perspective also
has an incentive to show enormous growth.
Right.
Well, the, the manager of it, I'm sure one of their KPIS is
make that number go big.
Yeah,
I
mean, I've dealt with this, you know, I'm not going to name names but I mean,
dealing with that online service that they wanted more user sign ups.
And so we had lots of user sign ups and it was 99 to 99 and
a
0.8% spam and scams on the
thing on the
Kpiki.
I
tried
-- for
-- cleaning the service and was smacked down hard
and
then I realized, oh yeah, it's linked to their bonuses. So it's not happening.
Yep, it's cobra effect 100%.
Ok. Ok.
So we cover the data a little bit and,
and the one other thing I want to bring up that's
probably people are going to say is they're going to say,
oh, this data,
the one maintainer packages that only applies to N PM because it's so big.
And if we look at only the important N PM packages, the trend doesn't hold the trend.
100% holds,
it's the same power distribution. A, a, an enormous amount of a single maintainer.
This is like the top 5% NP MP
or
exactly. It's stuff like that. 100%
-- dot Js or colors Js or whatever it was.
-- Uh right there, there's tons of them.
And so that's the point is every time I have tried
to find a, a
a trapdoor in this data to explain it away.
Every time a person has suggested I have to
look at it some other way because I'm wrong,
this graph is held and so I'm,
I am completely confident this is the way it is. It just is.
Well, to be honest, it,
it jives with all my research I've done over
the last 20 years into various ecosystems for security purposes
of it's
the exact same thing.
All the ecosystems are a ridiculously steep power distribution curve,
not just for the packages and popularity,
but the contributions to packages for the
security advisor zone packages for ad nauseam.
-- And
-- actually, so, you know what else?
I have a, I have a script, I wrote a long time ago that can take a G
repo and put it into a plastic search and I
can generate similar graphs to this open source stuff.
And you just reminded me when you're talking about Linux kernel,
I did this with the Linux kernel at one point.
And Linus of course, was the number one contributor unsurprisingly.
But the funny thing was I remember looking at the data,
you can tell when Linus goes on vacation because
there's like a noticeable dip in kernel development.
It's like, oh I get it.
And
I, I should,
I should do something similar to look at what
the contributions look like because I have a suspicion
the power distribution curve is going to be similar.
These power distribution curves are essentially
a symptom, not a cause
and the cause is more sort of just fundamentally how humans organize.
No, that's it. Like that's it.
-- Uh I I, I'm OK with it
-- because this holds true across every endeavor of human,
everything that I've ever seen, like the number of places that are not a power like,
like what is it that like um the,
the the square root of the organization does like half the work.
So if you have like an organization of 100 people,
like 10 people are doing half the work, stuff like that.
-- Like it's
-- just
I believe that when, when I
was at
elastic,
I remember looking at some of this data at one point because
it was part of my just have fun with elastic search program.
And
I remember looking at all of our contributors and yeah,
like there were basically a handful of developers
that accounted for an enormous number of the commits
to all of the elastic products across them all.
To go back to what Tomas said,
like to properly understand a code base and be able to contribute
to it both at a deep level or just in general,
more than a few lines of code
that is
thousands of hours of understanding and knowledge.
And if you have three or four people that have done that work and understand it,
why on earth would you have more?
It's hard to do
-- and it's
-- not just hard to do.
But if those people can do that work,
wouldn't it be better to have them look at some other code base that you use and get,
you know what I mean? Like
you have three or four experts in a code base. Why would you want 10 or 20?
Well, and especially, and then we're talking about an organization with no money.
I want to clarify something on this point though.
And because I think you also,
this is a reason people get scared off sometimes and they think, oh,
I have to invest all this time.
You don't approach something like this saying,
I'm going to become an expert and that hundreds and
hundreds of hours it slowly creeps up on you.
And my story I use here is minecraft.
When I started playing Minecraft with my kids, I was like,
I just want to dig holes and build fun things.
I'm never going to need to do like this Redstone crap or I'm never
going to worry about enchanting or I'm never going to have to worry about,
-- like, farming,
-- making a water elevator with signs.
That's right.
Yeah, exactly.
And so anyway,
obviously I started playing and playing and playing and
after I probably had hundreds of hours of playing
I would be like, oh, I want to do this fun thing.
Oh, I have to learn how Redstone works now.
And yeah, by the time I'm done I have like, right, like mob farms
that are using the water elevators to kill, but I wouldn't completely kill the Mobs.
I would mostly kill them.
So then I could murder them with a stick or something and then get all the experience.
And I had like an automatic chicken cooker that would like,
it would lay eggs, the eggs hatch, the chickens grow
-- so they're automatically
-- fed into a hopper. Let's not be night like let's not.
-- Oh,
-- there were hoppers and every, it was all completely automated. Like,
yeah, and when, when too many chickens died,
it would like send new eggs into hatch new chickens that,
that were only there to lay eggs for the sacrificial chicken.
Like it was this incredibly
complex machine I built
and I remember thinking at one point I'm like, I have like, I have become the thing.
I, I made fun of years ago when I started but, but
that's how it works. Right? Is you slowly turn into that.
And before you know it, now you're like maintaining a
popular package on NBM or something.
So, I think for anyone listening and anyone, you know,
like you can't approach it with a, oh,
I don't want to do this because it's gonna eat all my time or oh,
I can never be that smart.
Like you, you grow into it
-- if you want
-- to
remember. This is
sometimes,
sometimes
there have been
more than once
that I found myself
in charge of something that I'm like, how did this happen?
And it's because
usually I told the people in charge they were a bunch of idiots and
they dared me to run it and then I did and then I'm like,
oh crap like they,
they Tom Sawyer and me. It's too late now. But anyway, anyway, OK, so back to M PM.
I want to set the stage here. So now we know NBM is gigantic, right?
Open source is gigantic.
There's no denying it's bigger than you can imagine, right?
We also know that we're seeing seo spam in others, seo spam and N PM.
I 100% guarantee there's seo spam
all
and
everything.
It's,
that's why you can't put a URL in your Twitter bio.
They don't allow URL S on Twitter bios. I guess I didn't know that I don't,
-- no,
-- they do not.
I haven't run Twitter in so long, man. Like
I was
trying to put a URL to the thing and then I just put the OO
whatever for the Mastodon thing.
-- Wait.
-- No, I put a URL to my Mastodon account. It's
not,
it's not clickable.
-- No,
-- it's not clickable. I know that that's fine.
That's what I mean. You can't put a on
anyways.
I
understand.
Yeah, you can put the text in. But
yeah, yeah, I'm fine with text. That's fine.
I, I should, I need to shut down my Twitter account at some point.
That's another story.
Anyway.
OK,
so what was the point
we've just yammered on about kind of what does setting it all up?
Well, just that the data is the data, there's a power distribution curve,
it is what it is.
And I think here's my take on it.
It's not gonna change like you were involved in that group was like that was like,
what is the correct number of maintainers for open source?
It should be more than one. And it's like my response to that is
that's like asking for cows that don't fart methane. Like it's just
-- gonna
-- happen.
That was the open SSF
and the open S SS F is trying to
do things like scoring what constitutes good open source.
-- And so now you get into these questions like, oh well, it
-- needs
more than 1000 people use it this week.
There's
maybe, but like these are good questions.
These are the kind of things we you have to wonder however
at the end of that conversation,
it doesn't matter if there's some scorecard or something, it's,
if a developer finds something that solves their problem, they're going to use it.
Like they don't care if it has four downloads,
they don't care if it hasn't been updated in four years, they have work to do so now.
Ok, here's the real reason
I really wanted to talk about this
and I have an ulterior motive
And it's because I think
we have reached a point in the open
source universe where everyone is looking around,
everyone is noticing they're using open source in literally everything.
Our
Kaiser
Soze
moment again, I'll keep bringing that up because if,
if you haven't seen the usual suspects like go watch it.
It is
a magnificent piece of art.
But anyway,
so
there is this perception I think especially amongst many of the large corporations
that they can control open source if they try hard enough.
Because
historically, they've been able to like that is
the whole point of six Sigma is control everything, control all the variables,
control all the factors
and get that like six nines of
whatever it is you're producing, reliably out the door.
If we look at some of the things like the Linux kernel or Kubernetes or
the, the G new
C compiler and, and Lib C and some of this other technology,
a lot of big organizations were
able to exert control,
look at red hat red hat exerted enormous control
over open source for a long time for decades.
But that is done now.
That's not how this works.
And so the real purpose behind all this data, the real reason I wanted to publish this
and, and this is even,
I'm even seeing this in the open ssf where there's people talking about,
how do we control this?
-- How do we measure this and say like good, bad,
-- how do we? It's too big.
Of course, it's too big. But people don't understand how big it is, right?
The point of all this.
And this comes back to the conversation with Tama comes
back to our open sources and natural resource discussion like
this is all so huge. Now
there is nothing we can do but consume it.
We have to consume it and then look at consumption, we can't control consumption
because its consumption is too big.
Like the German Sovereign Tech Fund, we can influence a few
critical things that we've identified.
And I'm saying
influence not control
and they don't want to control it
is
-- exactly
-- right. They're smart.
No, seriously, they're smart like that,
that slide deck is like I went through it like wow, yeah, they
out of that, you know, it's
no, absolutely. But again,
I think this is where when you look at a lot of regulation,
there is regulation, that's very yes, yes, no type. But most regulation is about
influence, not demands, right? There are things like safety regulations.
I'm fine with that.
But many other places it's really about,
we're going to suggest you do this thing and here's the reason and here's how,
what happens if you don't, like, you don't get tax breaks, you don't get
government funding, we're not going to buy things from you.
-- If you don't do the things we want you to do
-- or
insurers say, oh, you didn't,
you don't own, like, you have a building without a fire sprinkler system,
right?
Yeah, we'll insure it. How much is the building worth? Ok, that's your premium.
No, I
that's why you can't buy overland flood insurance
in North America.
Right? You can't
because the cost of the insurance is like, ok,
what's the value of your home and its contents?
-- That's your yearly premium basically?
-- Right.
Right.
And, and I, yes, I, I think that's exactly it. And I think that
the point of all this is, I think we have to think about
how we use open source, not in the context of controlling open source,
but how we use open source in the context of
I need to first understand what I have.
And then it's not as much about telling people what they should or shouldn't
do as it is keeping an eye on everything happening in my universe.
And I think
-- that is more important.
-- This kind of reminds me of the discussions around rewriting
memory, unsafe language software into memory,
safe language software in the sense of
like, you can't
stop using the open source, you can't get rid of it.
And I'm not, I,
I think part of it might be even less about like inventorying
it all and understanding it all and maybe part of it is
like faking it till you make it in the
sense of let's start adopting more mature practices,
like
using source control because not everybody uses source
control yet or using source control correctly.
Right. Again, not all places like there's a lot of places using github
and then you see how they're actually using it.
And it's like, no, that's absolutely not how you're supposed to use git and
github.
You know,
um like my favorite being
the organizations that like disable issues so you can't file
issues and there's no path to like reporting breaks.
And it's like
this is not how you open source,
you know, you let the community at least talk to you and complain once in a while
or, oh, I was, I was trying to use uh Sendgrid library
and there every single thing in github was like, please don't file an issue,
please use our support for whatever.
And one person straight up was like
plug this error message into your support for and nothing
useful comes up like your support for does not,
the search doesn't work like it's useless
and
you know,
yeah, anyways, but I think that's part of it is,
it's kind of like cloud computing, people just started using it because,
and especially open source, like you can't really stop people because
it's not going to show up on a spending report, right? Like it's,
it's not like I need to go sign contracts and
get approval from legals before they'll ship it to me.
-- Well,
-- and here's my other favorite.
So when, when you and I started at Red Hat,
there was a technology called SC a source composition analysis
that's all about, oh, we're going to find the open source your developers are using,
right?
And they would scan source code and the
things were very slow and inefficient and they,
they worked well enough and they would look for a common open
source because it's easy to measure if someone say using N PM.
But what if they're copying and pasting coming off N PM?
Here's the thing 20 years ago,
you could do this because the amount of open source was
like literally like a millionth of what it is today.
Oh, it fit on a CD,
like
face
but like a Linux distribution fit on a CD with spare room
and
everything.
That's right today.
That is anyone telling you they can scan for
any open source in your product is they're,
they're, they're lying.
They either don't know they're lying to you, which is scary
or they know they're lying to you, which is also scary,
right? Like just absolutely not. There's too much of it. It's too complicated.
It's completely out of the question.
And especially with things like stack overflow, like
it's everywhere. Like you can't, you can't scrape all the stack overflow. All of
un copyrightable code count as open source. Is it quasi public domain?
-- We
-- are unqualified to have that.
And I'm not going down that path because we are
-- nearly out of time
-- because now that you say that I'm
wondering like what is all the output of chat GPT count
us because if that counts for the open source universe,
man, we are up the creek.
The courts have to decide that at the moment A I generated
source code carries no copyright because it has no human owner.
But that is going to be a discussion for the
courts that we are not going to have until the courts
decide because we're basically two talking idiots versus the judge
who will say probably also doesn't know what they're doing,
but
that's another problem anyway. All right, I wanna, I wanna take this one home.
So
going back to my sc a topic and I want to end it on.
This is in the past, I would say we, you could think of something like source code,
source composition analysis as you had
the big scary open source world
and you had the developers and sc a like sat between the two,
right where you're trying to control what developers were taking from the outside
that doesn't work anymore.
So now the way to think of it as you've
got developers and then you have whatever they're doing,
going into some sort of production
and it's really that step from developers going to take
whatever they can find and they're going to use it.
And I think trying to control developers is probably a lost
cause for many reasons that we could discuss at length.
Well, you can, but you're going to hobble them so hard.
They just aren't,
they're either going to quit or they're gonna find a
-- way not to
-- unless
-- you're
-- like a government agency,
your competitors gonna raffle stomp you.
Right. Right.
And so now it's really about how do we go from having a,
a thing that the developers built to at least doing some sort of
reasonable effort of verification prior to going into production.
And I think that's what we're at now, right? Like we have to move our tooling
after the developers
and we have to make sure that
we have good environments to run in.
We have to use technologies and languages that don't let them like,
shoot themselves in the foot.
And so I think that's the key now is trying to control developers will fail.
Like if you think it's right, like it's just, you've already lost
it.
-- It's
-- also
-- not cost effective. Like,
OK, I'm gonna
talking about seo spam. OK? The cloud security lines has a DEV
ops working group that has the six pillars of DEV
ops
and they're currently or just about to be done updating it. Basically,
it's like cloud computing
in that
you can either fully try and control it or you can accept
that it's going to happen whether or not you like it.
And so build for like my host got hit by a car right a couple of years ago
and I literally did a bit of research into boards and some other possibilities to
prevent because I actually do kind of live the way the streets are laid out.
There is a potential for another car to drive into my house.
And I'm like, I don't really like this,
but I'd have to like, put boards across my front driveway, which I'm like, well,
that gets really expensive really fast to have the ones that go up and down.
So I'm like, whatever, I'll just live with the risk. Yep.
Because fun fact, if a car is going to drive through my garage and into a wall,
-- it's going to be the wall right next to me here, which
-- no one can see because
if you ever see me get crushed by a car, please call the cops or something.
I will do my best.
-- But
-- basically like with this de
ops thing,
yeah, you can either
pretend you can control it and say like we're going to have spherical cows,
we're gonna have these rules or you can say realistically,
here's what's actually going to happen.
People are going to suck in a bunch of open source.
Let's at least make sure, like, yeah,
we are aware of it and we're going to poke them when it's got a known security flaw.
And let's make sure we're shipping stuff often
enough so that we can actually update it.
Right.
Because that's the thing that always these discussions
seem to quietly ignore is none of this matter
-- if you can't actually update and ship the software or service.
-- Absolutely.
And it's, it's bigger than you can imagine. All right, I'm going to call this one.
That, that was fun.
I don't feel like I have a lot of great answers, but I do,
I do still maintain like we can't control it.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
Go to Social Security podcast.com. Head up the show. Not, it's Su Pound dos podcast.
Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt, have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the.