December 15th. We made it, we're almost there 10 days to go.
I was,
yeah, I was about to say halfway but I, yeah, the same
on the 25th, not the end of the month. Math is hard. Well done.
My experience of time this year has been very, very
non
standard. I hear you man.
I
hear
you.
So this is annex A 0.15 0.1 of is
2007 001.
So iso
2007 001 is basically, it's a security standard. That's all you need to know.
It's like the security standard pretty much. Yeah. And annex A
15.1 is supplier relationships and I like that the security standards
are getting better about acknowledging how the world actually works,
right?
Because let's face it. There's a lot of security standards from the nineties and the
what do we call that decade? The odds,
the two thousands. I don't know
the, the decade between
and I'm gonna say this and I'm,
I'm just 2000 to 2009 and I know that's not how decades work, but shut up everybody.
It's fine.
Just
number beginning with
care.
Nobody cares.
And it's interesting how many of these standards were a combination
I think of here's how we want things to be,
which I'm ok with that.
Right. I'm ok with security standards that,
you know, say basically like stuff's on fire, here's where we want to go.
But they had that combined with then
ignoring how the world actually is in the sense of OK,
but how are we going to get from point A to point B?
Right? And so they would just set objectives that were not
achievable. You know, it's like me saying, I'm going to get in shape this year.
I've seen this as a problem in organizations
where the security teams will show up with
an iso control and say you have to do this and the admins are like,
we have no idea what this means.
And the security people say you just read it and
they're like we did and it doesn't make sense like,
well read it again then and they're like, you don't know what it means either.
Do you?
-- Well,
-- and
I love, for example, when I start talking to people, I'm like,
you know, let's talk about the security of backups.
And I'm like, oh yeah, we have to have backups, blah, blah, blah.
And I'm like, well, yeah, you probably do. But how are you security the backups?
Right? Because if somebody grabs the backups, like they don't have to
attack your production system, if they can just grab the backups
if information disclosure is their thing.
And it's clear to me that quite a few of them have,
I haven't really thought this through.
So anyway, what's the topic we're talking about?
Well, I think basically it boils down to.
I like that these security standards
are acknowledging how the world actually works
and they're
willing to be a bit more compromising rather than,
-- you know, you must meet this perfection,
-- explain this particular annex
to the ISO standard.
So it talks about essentially your supplier, your technology supply chain,
monitoring them, review
them and managing changes to them.
And one thing I keep coming across that this doesn't really address,
but that is becoming more common is the simple fact that
people have suppliers who will not change or do anything.
So a great example of this is like Amazon or Microsoft Microsoft ships Windows,
they're not going to modify it for you, right?
Amazon has Amazon web services, they're not going to tweak it for you
full stop. And that's ok. Previous attempts at this would say things such,
oh, you need to talk to the supplier and bully them into being secure.
Well,
-- you can't bully Microsoft or Amazon and
-- anyone
you can bully you should be highly suspect of
because I mean,
so I've read more than one thing where these really
small start ups will just say yes to whatever you
ask and they know they're never going to do it
but they need the money so they don't care.
Well,
and that's the difference between being a software shop and being a consulting shop
and they are desperate to bring any money in.
They will do the consulting side of things and not hold the line sort of,
or they'll tell you they're doing it and they're not.
I mean, so this is, this reminds me, I mean, we talked to Alan Friedman about S
bomb, what it feels like seven years ago, but I think it might have been last year.
Yeah.
And I love S bomb.
But the thing I keep coming back to over and over and over again is
no one's going to do this unless you make them somehow.
And I think putting some of these questions
and ideas into a standard that organizations are following
is the first step.
Well, making them achievable
that too. Absolutely.
Because I see so much security advice that applies to
large fortune 100 companies because they have a security team,
but you just cannot do that.
Not just a security team.
Most of the banks on Wall Street have a security team bigger than most companies.
-- I mean,
-- a
classic example being how do you do separation
of duties when you have five employees?
You don't.
Yeah,
because you know what you're worried about,
you're worried about keeping the lights on.
Exactly.
That is one of the other hilarious things there.
So many of these standards where you,
I, I, I've been part of small organizations where someone shows up is like, oh,
you know, show me your
iso 27,001 report. We're like, we're like six people. We don't have one of those.
-- You
-- know,
you know, here's a question.
What is the smallest organization or company that has achieved sale?
Talk to certification.
I mean,
there must be somebody out there that just is a one
man company that did it on a because they had to,
for some contract.
I'm sure it's possible.
But anyway, we're out of time so we're not going to answer that.
But if you listener happen to know the answer, let us know.
We'd love to hear on to December 16th.