Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
Yeah. So I'm pretty wound up today
and this week's bias is anchoring.
The first thing you judge influences your judgment of all
that follows and it applies to what we're talking about.
-- This week.
-- Last week's bias was anchoring. Well, it might not even be last week.
I don't know when this episode's coming out.
Yeah, because I just edited it a couple of days ago.
Yeah, I did
that.
It can't be anchoring again.
Let's, uh,
we are a completely professional podcast for any new listeners.
Hang on a second.
Here's the better. No, here's the one I actually wanted. Whoops.
Ok. Let me restart.
No, I'm not. I'm not letting you restart
-- the
-- bias. I actually wanted. Sorry, was the decline is
you remember the past is better than it was
and expect the future to be worse than evidence suggests
will be
like that.
Sorry, I spaced out. Yeah, because an
anchoring was on top because my goal was to have the ones we've used on top of the pile.
So I don't use them again, but of course,
I anchored on it and I was like this one.
So yeah, so this is um well,
I was gonna say this shows inspired by a hacker news posting,
but it's something that we consistently see every month or two.
-- Somebody complaining about.
-- Totally
let you explain because you sent me the story. So it's, it's yours.
So essentially there's this like issue in github
for Docker and the person replies, sorry, I missed your comment.
As of many months ago, I no longer build software. I now make furniture out of wood.
The hours are long. The pay sucks.
And there's always the opportunity to remove my finger with a table saw.
But nobody asked me if I can add an RSS feed to a DB MS. So there's that,
of course,
then there's this huge hacker news thread about
basically how I guess to summarize it,
the old software industry was good and the new one is bad.
I think that is a completely accurate description. Yes,
-- and
-- it's completely wrong and stupid. Of
course, so
-- many reasons. That's
-- why I'm so wound up about this one.
-- I know
-- where
-- to
-- even begin with this. So
well, you know, reread
the bias. You just read
decline
is,
you remember the past is better than it was and expect
the future to be worse than evidence suggests it will be.
There we go. That's where we start the past
-- in the context of software development.
-- The golden era of software development.
Ok. It was categorically worse than it is today.
It wasn't just worse. The, the
were worse,
the amount of effort it took was worse every time
I load a file in emacs and emacs is like,
oh, this file is bigger than 10 megabytes.
You sure you want to do that? I'm like, yeah, shut up. Just do it.
-- Wait,
-- do you still run emacs?
Yeah.
And it's a, there's this default for 10 megabyte file size, same thing in send mail,
right?
When you set up, send mail, it's a default 10 meg max attachment size.
And I remember when that mattered because my system had eight megabytes of ra M.
So you load a 10 megabyte file on a system with eight megabytes of ram.
Guess what happens? It goes, boom.
Well, no,
the whatever sound your hard drive makes you get to hear
-- that for the next 10 minutes
-- and then it goes,
boom.
-- Well, it works. But slowly,
-- well, maybe, I mean, it depends. Om killer off.
It'll kick in and murder something.
I had like 40 or 50 megabyte swap file.
-- That is sad.
-- I had eight megs of ra M. At least my buddy had four,
you
know, and he didn't even have an OK. And my friend didn't even have a numeric
Coros.
So it was faster for him to compile the Linux kernel
on my 46 DX 266 with eight megs of ra M
and download the compiled kernel off and modules off
my system over a 9600 bod onto his 386.
Yeah. But that's because the kernel could fit on a floppy disk.
But I mean,
the point is like it was faster to compile it somewhere else and download it at 9600
bod than to just wait for 3 to 6 to chew through it because he had no numerical
coros
and not enough memory.
I mean,
what gets me is like the stuff you and I both did
with monkeying around with make files and hand editing source code to.
And I don't mean like downloading some project where oh it's a little bit broken.
I'm talking about
downloading, you know, something from like
ISC,
this is a major software release that's supposed
to basically run the internet and yeah,
it doesn't compile out of the box.
Yeah, that was, that was super common. So OK, let's even ignore that aspect of it.
I just want to focus on. So here's, here's my view of this.
So if you look at the past, we had limited languages.
In fact, I just had this discussion with, with my son,
-- dude, we had C and Pearl
-- basically. And, and so the context of this was
he was asking me about programming languages and kind of how
did and it came about because he actually in one of his classes,
the kids were told in his, it's called digital literacy,
which is what we would have called computer class back in the day.
And digital literacy. Basically, the teacher said, here's a bunch of free tools.
You have to pick one,
learn how to use it and then make a thing with it.
And my son picked Inscape because he's,
he heard of me talking about it in the past because
Inscape is a vector drawing program and if you're making like low
or anything, you got to use vector graphics, right.
-- Anyway, then they resize and they get all chunky.
-- Yeah, exactly.
So he basically says like, how is this free? Why is this free? What's the deal here?
-- It's a
-- good question. No, I remember people ask like, how's open source work?
-- How are you going to eat? And I'm like, people pay me to work. Right.
-- Right.
But so we were walking the dog and it was,
I had about 30 minutes to explain and I think I used all my time
-- captive
-- audience, the dog
head. Exactly.
But anyway, like I was talking about the fact that when I was in high school,
if I wanted to do software development,
my option was essentially c there was really no,
-- like nobody wrote Pearl or Python and
-- what we think of as,
as the modern tool chain barely existed.
Well, and it didn't, you had to pay for it and very expensive.
Well, and just getting like getting GCC to compile something was,
I remember hand editing stuff,
running it and then it would fail halfway through
ignoring that though even Kurt, just if you wanted to write C code, you had to pay so
or Microsoft or someone like that, an enormous sum of money.
And then Linux appears and we have all these amazing free tools and it's
like this is literally thousands of dollars worth of operating system and tools.
Oh,
easily I remember pricing out. Yeah. Was it so's
compiler or
it was one of the,
all of the compilers,
compilers or it was one of the compilers that doesn't exist
anymore because they went out of business because quite frankly,
like, yeah, GCC ate their lunch and yeah, like I didn't have thousands of dollars.
-- Right. Right.
-- I mean, I remember, like, I think Borland was the cheap one.
Borland.
-- Yes,
-- that was it.
It was a couple of 100 bucks and I didn't
-- have a couple of 100 bucks
-- for the student edition.
-- Yeah. And, but if you wanted it for a corporate, like commercial use pony up.
-- Right.
Right. Exactly. And,
and so anyway,
we, you can say, OK, so that was the golden age of software development.
It was c and you had to kind of artisan
generate all your libraries and make everything work together
-- and it was terrible
-- to make stuff cross platform was,
it was an art like it wasn't simple like it is now.
But like I remember people arguing that you can't use,
make S temp because it's not portable across platforms.
-- And, well, the reality is it wasn't,
-- well, that's, I mean, that's where pai
came from, which was the,
oh, we unify everything except it didn't,
-- well, it made it less worse.
-- It did make it less worse, but for sure it was still,
-- there were weird isms everywhere. There was
-- just missing stuff.
Yeah. Right.
Right. Right.
Well, and part of it too is like,
software development is getting better and I'm not talking, like, 3% a year,
but like, 10 or 20% a year.
At least I remember when Pearl CP Pan became a thing and it was just like, oh,
my goodness, I can just go get a Pearl library easily and by easily, I mean,
by modern standards, everybody would cry.
It was
back in the day.
It was, it was so much easier because literally back in the day it was like,
I need something that does this,
I guess I'll use maybe Altavista to search for it.
Maybe if I'm lucky, find a library because it's not like we had github
or Source Forge or some Unified space where you could look for stuff. Right.
You had to track it down on some random university site.
Yeah, exactly.
And I remember literally downloading just random
libraries compiling them and being like,
ok, this one's completely broken, it just wouldn't even compile.
I'd get like, two or three that would compile, I'd run them and I'd be like, oh my God,
this one actually does what I want.
Hallelujah.
You know. And then
now most at this point people would say,
then I checked it into my source code repository, I think.
Well, we didn't have that.
Yeah, we did. We had R CS and CV S. It was fine.
Yeah, we had CVS
and, well, I never used R CS, thank goodness. But we had CV S and that was terrible.
It was terrible. It still is terrible to be clear.
But yeah, I mean, I,
I literally had a problem where I wanted to take a list of words and fuzzy match them,
not exactly match them, but fuzzy match them to other words.
So, you know, color and color with you like a Canadian spell it for example,
or industry terms
and have fuzzy matching and the math behind that and to build
that implementation yourself and see would be essentially back in the day.
That would have been thesis like phd level work, right?
Like if you built a working implementation of fuzzy string matching
20 years ago,
that easily you would have presented that as your phd defense and they've been like,
yep, that's, yeah, absolutely.
And now in Python it's import fuzzy wuzzy and then like I actually
fit the code I needed to do the work into a tweet,
not a long tweet either like a 160 character tweet.
OK? I think we're stuck in the past too much here. The point is
it's easy to think of the past as a lovely, wonderful place.
-- But the reality is if you actually sit down and look at it, it was
-- terrible.
-- Everybody had cholera and died at the age of 27.
-- That's right.
And I, I can't
but wonder, I think part of it is,
is a combination of people think they understood the past and they really didn't.
It's no, it's exactly what you said. We love as humans.
We love to look at the past and say,
oh, how much better it was.
And
there's obviously this is just part of being a human, right?
It's,
it's our biases work this way and sometimes I'll think of how
much I enjoyed using Linux back and say that the early thousands.
But the reality is, it was terrible. But I don't remember the terribleness.
I just remember, like,
how proud I would be after spending two weeks getting my laptop to boot.
-- And it's like, now that's ridiculous.
-- Well, it also reminds me of like cars.
You know, people are like all old cars, you could, like, fix them yourself.
And it's like, I don't want to do that. I just want the damn thing to work.
-- And
-- that's so this is exactly where I was going to bring the conversation.
I'm glad you bring up cars. And
so I, my father in law restores classic automobiles that is like,
that is literally his job.
He owns a company that restores classic cars and he's, he's quite good at it.
And the work he does is phenomenal.
And I love listening to him though because he will complain to no end about how
dumb cars are today because they're full of computers and no one can work on them.
But here's the deal. Right. Those old cars, the gas mileage is terrible.
You can't go very fast and if you get in an accident, you're going to,
I, you know, you said something very subtle there, no one can work on them.
And the reality is obviously people can work on them because they get fixed.
Well, you need a village now though. Right.
Well, exactly what you need a village and you need technology.
You know, it reminds me of carpentry.
So, carpentry in Germany is still very much a very,
it's like a protected term basically.
And there's the concept of, you know,
a master carpenter versus a regular carpenter.
So I have a cousin in Germany who's a carpenter and
like, essentially that is culturally in Germany,
like being a doctor like that is a high skill, high wage job.
So here we go, master carpenter.
After working as a journeyman for a while,
a carpenter may go on to study or test as
a master carpenter in some countries such as Germany,
Iceland and Japan.
This is an arduous and expensive process requiring extensive knowledge,
including economic and legal knowledge and skill, blah, blah, blah.
The point is for my cousin to become a carpenter in Germany.
He took several years of apprenticing. One year of
ong where you have to travel for a year with only what you carry in your backpack.
And then he became a carpenter and then he actually went to school for,
I think it was three years in France to learn
new techniques of using like engineered wood products to build
just crazy stuff that again, 100 years ago,
a carpenter would have been like what spaceship don't understand?
Right.
But now with like laminated wood products, you can build just insanely cool stuff.
The table saw, comment about cutting your hand with a table saw.
Well, now there's a table saw that will detect it's a hot dog or a finger and stop
and I see people complaining about
and about the cost of it. And it's like true.
It is quite a bit more expensive than a $300 table saw. But like, what do fingers cost
like? Seriously? What do fingers cost? What are they worth on the chart?
I mean, in the context of us,
our fingers are extremely high value to us because if I chop my finger up,
-- I
-- would
-- assume this is true for a carpenter as well.
Funny you say this because I have a table saw in my woodshop and
I've taken all the safety guards off of it because I hate them.
Yeah, me too. I
keep them in a bin with some other random parts.
I finally threw them away when I moved all
my woodworking tools around because I moved them from the
garage up into the top of the garage where I have a nice room and I was like,
why didn't I do this suitor?
And I found my box of table so, stuff.
I'm like, you know what, I'm not even going to pretend I want this anymore.
Like I dumped it out in the trash or whatever it's gone.
Well, and that's the thing though.
There are like, chef's knives,
those things are wicked dangerous because they're really sharp and you can, like,
you know, if you can joint a lamb, well, you can cut your hand off with one.
No way, man, a dull knife is more dangerous than a sharp knife. Exactly.
But, so that's the thing,
things that are inherently dangerous are typically do have safe ways to use them.
Like a table saw.
You have that little hockey stick shaped piece of
wood that you use to push the wood through.
-- You don't use your hand.
-- I do.
I have my hands never get anywhere near the blade and I have all the crazy
little holdy tools to make sure that's the case we're off on a tangent again.
That's all we do is tangents.
Well, but the point is, you know, it's back in the day, you only had these kind of
tools that were not
as good, you know, like, yeah, given a set of chisels,
I want the super sharp chisels that will take my hand off if I
mess up with them because they're actually easier to use safely than a dull chisel
for sure. But the thing is also, there's, now there's better options.
There's, you know, various power tools that can do what that chisel did.
The A Dremel, for example, like I remember when Dremel came out and holy geez,
they were expensive now, you know, there are 100
they're less than that.
I, in fact, my dre needs to be replaced and you can get a really nice one for about 50.
OK.
-- Exactly.
-- So I,
-- I, I just looked into
-- this, we have literally for carpentry just like software.
We have better tooling now
that allows like the things you and I can do with power tools.
It won't be as pretty or as good as a, as a professional carpenter, obviously.
But the fact is we can get it done.
And that's part of what I think happens with this software thing is like
I need to do fuzzy string matching, import, fuzzy wuzzy, two lines of Coke.
I
get a nice CSV output of like all my matches with Weightings.
That, that is insanely amazing to me.
There's a second part to this as well is that if you look at the artisanal,
it of the past,
you had to be an artisan to use it. Right. Normal people couldn't do it.
But now we've reached a point where almost anyone can learn to write an application,
using the tools available.
It's actually quite trivial to stand up, let's say like a Hello World Web app.
Whereas in the past standing up a Hello World Web
app would have required an enormous body of knowledge.
Again, my friend who, you know, would compile his kernel on my machine.
We had to reverse engineer subnetting
because there was no documentation on how subnetting worked.
Like what was the bit mask?
It was in the RFC Y
Well, yeah, that's what I'm saying.
We had to like read the RFC and figure out how no, no, we had to,
we had to come up with a specific bit mask to make it work, right?
And we finally figured out that, you know, it's how the zeros and ones match up.
But I mean, it's not like we had some like networking for dummies book. We had an RFC
or
overflow. Yeah. Yeah.
Those things are not like instructional, those are reference documents.
-- There's a difference.
-- You know, actually it's funny you say that
because you say reference documents, instructional.
But I come from a time where reference documents was all you had. Yeah.
Well, exactly. So I view them as instructional even though that's demented.
Well,
they are instructional but they're instructional in the
way of you're already a journeyman carpenter.
-- Here's how this Dovetail saw works.
-- I would agree with that 100%.
-- In fact, the only now if I tell someone to go read the RFC, oh, you're
-- being
a jerk.
I'm, yeah, exactly. I'm like f, you go read the RFC
and I think the reality is software much like cars got much more complex.
Now,
you can still have a single person effort
to build software and build good useful software.
But it's more rare because, you know, if you want to build an operating system,
you're going to generally, like you said, need a village,
not just a team but an entire village.
-- You know, somebody's got to do the icons and the artwork,
-- right?
I mean, I think the idea of some random dude sending an email to a news group that says,
oh, here's my little kernel.
I'm making this a project.
I'm skeptical that would ever work again at all.
There's literally one documented case of it in recent history and it was,
it's a very sad story.
-- It's not a sad story. Linux is
-- awesome. No, not Linux.
The, the other one, the one written in Assembler,
it involves mental illness and some other stuff.
-- It's,
-- oh, you mean the Temple Os guy? Yeah. Yeah. That's something different.
It's sad.
And I think part of it too is the bar is raised.
You know, you can't just write a Hello world app and run it on the command line.
You, it needs to be a web app like you said, which means you need a web server, dns.
Oh, well. And now you need SSL,
you know, you need certificates.
Perfect example of this.
I remember paying money.
Like I bought a copy of Red Hat Stronghold Secure web server.
And then when I bought a certificate from my website,
the poor company didn't know what to do because they're like, you're not a company.
I'm like, no, I'm an individual and I own
cre.org. And they're like,
ok,
-- I guess if you show us your passport, that'll work for proving that
-- you're only
$300 pretty
-- much.
-- Yeah.
Even just to get a fax,
like to scan a copy of my passport and send it to
them was a whole ordeal because I didn't have a digital camera.
-- Ok,
-- let's tie this back to automobiles, right?
Because now automobiles are complex and scary.
And in the early 19 hundreds, there were literally hundreds of car companies.
And if you just had four wheels and an engine,
you could build a car and drive it on the road.
Right.
-- If you did that today, you're probably going to get
-- a ticket.
It's funny because like,
you remember when on top gear before it got all kind of weird and grumpy, you know,
where they would have those challenges to build a car and
they built like an electric car and it's just like this,
it's like some children's drawing of what a car is with, you know,
-- like the angle steel and like,
-- does it look like the cyber truck a
worse,
much worse and it's, like, held together by tape.
-- So I've never seen an episode of Top Gear.
-- It's, it used to be good.
-- It used to be good, but now it's not.
-- And that's how most things work
again.
You know, the past was better, but we'll put a link to it in the show notes.
The reality is, yeah, software. We expect more of software.
Well, as we should though.
I mean, it's like as any product and industry ages and develops,
it changes completely.
And I mean, look even in the context of automobiles,
like the skill set you have for cars even,
let's say 50 years old is completely different than the skill set you need for cars
today and you think all electric cars are
going to be a completely different skill set.
I'm not saying there's anything wrong with old cars,
but anyone who says we should still build them
like that I think is woefully confused by progress.
Simple economics. Yeah.
A modern bumper is anywhere from 1 to $5000
because of all the sensors and stuff going on.
That is what like 20 minutes of medical bills
-- when you hit somebody,
-- right?
And, and not only that if you hit someone or even if you get hit in an old car,
-- you are probably going to die. Should
-- we put a link to that where they crash?
Test the old Bel Air and the modern Bel Air? Yeah, we should totally do that.
I don't have words for like,
the intrusion into the passenger compartment of the steering
wheel on the old bel Air is horrifying.
Yeah, they said the driver of the old car would have been killed instantly.
The driver of the new car would have literally walked away from it.
Yeah, I mean, that's, that's bananas.
What always gets me is those f one crashes where essentially it's
not a car crash so much as a small plane crash,
like the
speeds that are
involved.
And those guys are literally walking out of those things.
-- Yeah,
-- it's completely nuts. I agree. But again,
their primary focus obviously is on safety. Right.
They have cars that go fast, but safety is a huge part of that.
-- Those drivers are expensive. Well, that
-- too. Right. It's totally worth the cost.
Right. No, it's like fighter jets. Fighter jet pilots are insanely
-- expensive to train.
-- Heck, aircraft, man, aircraft are a great example too. Right.
Old aircraft. They had like six parts, new aircraft are computers fly them.
It's,
it's not comparable in any way with old aircraft better.
It kind of depends how you're going to define it.
But I would say mostly, no, no, it wasn't.
They have that Garmin Auto Land thing working now it's an
emergency system where you literally press you press a red button
and then the plane lands itself at the nearest
airport safely and tells you what it's doing.
-- Yeah. And
-- remember the old movies where it, can anyone fly an airplane on board?
-- And
-- then Mythbusters and a couple other places tested that
myth and let's just say it always ends poorly.
Yeah. Right.
And even with, you know, they took like a single engine pilot, put him in the,
you know, the flight sim and it was like he, he got to the runway.
No, in fairness,
he got to the runway on approximately the correct glide slope and then no big plane,
not like small plane.
You know what I always laugh at is in, I think it's the movie Madagascar the kid,
the cartoon where the Penguins say any landing
you can walk away from is a good landing
after
they crash the airplane.
-- And it's, yeah, that is completely true. I love it.
-- Yeah.
-- Except in cartoons nobody dies.
-- Right. Exactly. Exactly.
-- I think
-- part of it is just the world changes. Some people roll with that change.
Like I've done like I have a rule now that basically says anything.
I know technically that's more than three years old like that.
I learned more than three years ago is probably not just wrong but might be harmful
in the sense of like, oh, I should run my own mail, sir. No, Kurt bad.
Slap your hand
like use
you know, we're using Google and Sendgrid and Mail Gunn and a bunch of other stuff.
It's not easy to live like that, you know, to literally, I,
at one point I had two bankers boxes full of o'reilly books that
I had read and made notes in and highlighted and digested fully,
you know, the send mail book.
-- Oh, man, that thing was a monster.
-- Yeah, it's useless. Just try and forget it.
Like, make space for, you know, other stuff.
And that's hard.
Like it's, it's, you know, it's basically I'm saying, like,
everything I learned prior to, well, 40 is, yeah, just forget
it. It's garbage useless.
And you know, what is useful is some of the metal level stuff where I understand,
like, if something,
you know, every time like cloud flare breaks, I'm like, oh,
I think my site broke and then I'm like, oh CNN also broke.
So it's probably not just me. What's the commonality? Cloud flare?
What actually happened? Oh, you know, either cloud flare fell down a bit or?
Oh, it turns out, what was it like that major network provider died and
everybody blamed cloud flare briefly because, you know,
they were spitting up airs because like 10% of the internet died.
Fundamentally,
you have to grow and you have to change and
you have to work really hard at learning new stuff.
And
to be blunt, for a lot of people, this is a job.
Well, it is, it's not something they love to do.
And I get that because they have hobbies and
family and they'd rather spend time doing that.
And that's fair.
But then you can't complain about the world changing and not keeping up with it.
Yeah, I would agree with that. I think there's nothing wrong with saying it's my job.
I mean, like, I would take an auto mechanic is probably a great example.
I bet
any, like, someone who restores old cars, that's passion. But if you work on new cars
it probably pays the bills and you probably like cars. But I bet it's not,
it's not going to drive you in the same way.
Well,
I've met people who are into technology in whatever
facet of whatever it is that they do,
like, on the local slack, you know, security slack.
We have some people who,
well, a great example.
There's a locksmith who's into tech and, you know, there's,
there's some really cool technologies.
Well, the lockpicking lawyer is a great example. Right?
Every time he touches those electronic locks, I'm like, yeah,
they're not ready for prime time.
Exactly. Yeah, they're so bad.
But anyway, so, so here's,
here's kind of my thought on this.
Right is that we live in a world now where you don't learn
a skill and then use it for the rest of your life.
Like, learning is part of our basic skill set,
I think in today's world because it doesn't matter
what job you have everything around you is changing
in dramatic and strange ways.
How many people, people are struggling with work from home,
with basic computer literacy skills and they've been
in the white collar workforce for decades.
I know a lot. Right.
It's brutal cause like I'm literally hearing stories about these people who
can't get their work laptop onto the internet at home.
And it's kind of like, but you have wi fi at home, like turn it on.
-- That's easy for us to say
-- I've seen these stories now about people who literally
this is my favorite.
They emailed the person who's still in the office saying,
can you please print this out,
this document that was sent to me by email? Can you print it out?
-- Scan it and email it back to me?
-- What? I don't doubt this but
-- ok.
-- Right.
Because well, they can't like it's, it's the they want it in the PDF format,
not the other weird format that came in or something.
And that's fair and that kind of stuff I can sort of forgive because like getting,
getting say a one document format into
PDF can be difficult on windows specifically.
Yeah, on a Mac
-- Easy on Windows. No, not easy.
-- Right. And Exactly.
And like on Linux, we've been doing this for decades. So no one cares.
But the point is, and I think you're exactly right.
And I think this is where something like people
keep saying how like a pandemic is basically speeding
up change where things that might have taken 10 years are now going to take one year.
You can no longer hide certain inefficiencies and problems.
Whereas before, you know,
you could just eat that cost or hide it or you could have really inefficient,
you know, people who have a meeting and then, like, 20 minutes later for
what they discussed. Right. I worked remote.
I've worked remotely for 22 years and I remember being on a call
where my boss was like, Kurt, you know,
are you doing this with the rest of the team?
And I'm like, what, now, what are you talking about?
He's like, he's like, basically, like, damn it, Kurt, like,
it's like every email I send, you know, to you, you're ignoring.
I'm like, I read all the emails you send me, you're my boss.
Like I,
I read them and I internalize them and I like to the best of my ability do what I can.
He's like, no, Kurt. It's like you don't read any email on the at home list.
And I'm like the what list?
And I hear the silence for like five seconds.
He's like, can somebody check if Kurt's on the at home list?
It turns out I wasn't on the main list that
they were using to communicate policy changes and stuff to all
as workers.
And, and that's the moment I realized where I, I started telling people I'm like,
unless you explicitly tell me in an email, I don't know it.
Right, because I'm not there. I'm not at the water cooler.
I'm not hearing those phone calls and maybe I am.
But for the purposes of safety and brevity,
if it's not in an email that's been sent to me, it doesn't exist in my world.
And I've lived by that rule now for two,
like, almost 20 years and it works.
But there's a lot of people though,
having to learn that rule now because they've not worked
-- from home before
-- because when you're in an office it,
the dynamic is definitely different.
Bob. What about? Oh, ok. Thanks.
Right. Yeah, you just pick your head up over the cubicle and, and yell. Exactly.
Exactly. It's, it's completely different here is how I will end this.
This will be my closing thought is
if you are complaining about the state of the industry you are in,
it is almost a certainty that you are the problem and not your industry.
Yep.
-- 100% agree. That's
-- it.
That's what I'm going to say if,
like, at me, if you want. But that's, that's my standing.
And the funny thing is if you want to do old stuff,
there are absolutely jobs out there restoring classic cars or what was it?
New Jersey was like, we need coal
programmers, like by Thursday or
else
we can't, I forget what, like their unemployment system was going to fall over or?
Oh, carpentry is a great example.
Like, there's carpenters who specialize in restoring old stuff,
using the old techniques.
-- Yeah.
-- I'm familiar with this problem.
-- Oh, yeah. Yeah, because you own that historical house.
-- I own a 100 year old house.
And actually, so funny enough you say that is
so I enjoy fine woodworking. It's a hobby of mine.
I wouldn't say I'm a professional or by any means. But I do. Ok.
And there are certain things in my house,
I won't hire someone to do because I'm concerned
-- they won't do the job the way I want it done
-- every year.
I like going to the cabin show locally because there's about two
or three German carpenters at the cabin show and they're awesome.
And I mean, and again, like they are proper German carpenters wearing the clock,
you know, the uniform
they do is
unbelievable.
Like you look at, like,
the pictures of the modern place versus the pictures of the place these guys,
what these guys build.
Yeah. Like they're going to build you something that
it'll be there 500 years later.
-- Well, to a degree now. No, no,
-- no.
Like I've, I've lived in Germany, I've lived, like,
I lived in a town where they were renovating a house
that was over 500 years old.
No, I'm going to stop you because you're,
-- you're claiming the past is better and in some ways it was, well,
-- yeah.
But you don't have plumbing or electrical wiring and
that can make a difference.
But I'm going to tell, you know, anyone who says, oh,
they sure don't build them like they used to.
I live in the way they used to and I assure you there's plenty of jank, like,
it's not perfect
and when it goes wrong it goes really wrong.
It's tradeoffs. Right.
Yeah. You know, we, we now have climate control in houses that, you know, don't
-- cost $5000 a month to heat in winter
-- in a cold winter.
I will pay $600 a month to heat my home.
Yes.
Yeah.
See, that's why you got to get more squirrels living in your wall.
That's
right. I need them to bring more nuts into the attic to insulate it all.
I
was
just
heat.
Squirrel heat. No.
You know, actually in all seriousness, I had squirrels at one point and I had,
I called an exterminator to help get rid of them.
And he said, uh,
squirrel pee is the problem with squirrels
in your house because they pee everywhere,
I guess
whatever.
Anyway. Alright.
I'm calling it. This was, this was I feel better.
I feel better after complaining about other people complaining that
it's very matter.
Anyway. Thank you everyone for listening.
If you made it this far, well done, you can go to Overs
Security podcast.com. Head up our show.
It's Suzy Pando says podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You
-- too, thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.