Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 144
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Baking Crime,
Josh Bresser.
Oh, my goodness. So, all right. The context for you listener
is that before the show, Kurt says 100 and 44. That sounds like an important number.
And I said, I don't know.
And then he asked, well, what's, what's a gross, which is 12 dozen, 12 times 12?
And then Kurt said, well, it's 100 and 44.
And then we had a discussion about the fact that I can
literally not do math in my head in any meaningful way,
even though I've taken very advanced math classes through my college career.
And quite frankly,
I don't care because I literally walk around with a
calculator in my pocket all of the time now.
Yeah. No, that's fair. I agree. It's completely fair.
And I think memorizing math now is a waste
of what precious little brain power I have left.
Uh I think some basic math is good to know off the top of your head.
-- Like people that, you know, can't make change.
-- Uh, I can't make change either.
So, who cares?
And, and right, and actually that, that, that, that ties into,
you want to talk about money today
and I can't make change and I don't care because I think cash is horrible and stupid.
-- So, there you go.
-- Well, ok, where do we want to start?
So, there's, there's sort of two entry points,
there's Banksy or there's my credit card you pick.
-- Uh, what about your credit card? So
-- the other day I was at the store buying some food
as one does and, uh, my credit card wouldn't work. Ok, luckily my debit card did work.
And so, you know,
I checked to make sure I hadn't accidentally like gone
bonkers on Amazon and maxed up my card or something
because the terminal was giving a weird error. It wasn't like a connection error.
It was just, or like, you know,
it was just saying it was declined and I was like, well, you know,
um,
but yeah, so basically my credit card didn't work.
My debit card did work thankfully because I, I generally don't carry cash and I,
I actually keep trying to make a habit of carrying cash, but I keep,
I just can't be bothered to, but it got me thinking that.
So there's been some people talking about, you know,
cash versus debit versus credit and versus, you know, uh, Bitcoin and whatnot
and something very fundamental to cash that none of these other systems have
is cash doesn't require you to ask somebody for permission to spend it.
Whereas all these other systems, debit cards, credit cards, Bitcoin,
whatever you have to ask somebody for permission or multiple,
somebody for permission
to spend it.
Right? Like if I want to use my debit card, my bank has to authorize that transaction.
Same thing with the credit card
in Bitcoin,
you have to find a miner that will take your transaction and add it to their pool and,
and run it through.
You. You, you know this whole thing of like, oh, you can just spend Bitcoin.
It's, you know, you don't have to worry about anything.
Well, it's a little more complicated than that.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
So,
ok,
I mean, what's your point?
Well, just from a security point of view, it's interesting is we're trading,
we're giving some tradeoffs now.
Don't get me wrong. I love cashless. Right. I love
having, you know, being able to just download my banking record and be like, oh,
here's how much I spent on gas or this month or here's how much I spent on
candy this month or whatever.
Um, but it really, it, it's, it, when it does break, you know,
when there's a communications outage or,
I don't know,
for whatever reason the terminal just wouldn't let me use my credit card
and, you know what's funny is I was tapping my card.
It didn't even occur to me to stick it in and try that.
Hm.
Taps
in
Canada for, I don't know, 10 years.
-- I,
-- I love when I can tap
and, and it's even better because now I have, uh,
Google pay on my phone and so I don't need to take my wallet out.
Just whip out the phone, touch to the terminal and pay my bill. It's beautiful.
Yeah,
apparently pretty much all of Asia and the developing world is
skipping tap cards and just moving straight to cell phones.
Which totally makes sense.
So
you don't have to mail a card out and deal with all that garbage,
you know?
Right. Right. And a phone, a good phone has much better security than a credit card,
you know,
I
have
to,
my phone
to use it. Whereas my credit card,
in fact, there was, there was a story I read one time where somebody had one of the,
like, the handheld contactless readers
at a festival in Europe and they were like, walking around, you know,
like tapping people's legs and stuff trying to get their, their wallets.
And
what is it in Europe?
I think if the transaction is like €20 or less, you don't need to sign.
So the contact list just goes through.
So here I'm just trying to think of the,
so it, it depends with, uh, there's different rules with debit versus credit cards
and, uh, for some, it's, the merchant can set a max.
So for example, a lot of convenience stores will have like a max tap of like,
say 50 bucks.
I know at Costco the max tap is 100 bucks, which is useless at Costco because
like, it's a Costco,
I did actually spend less than $100 at Costco one time
and I tapped my phone.
Then I'm just standing there like an idiot and the lady says you don't need to sign,
it's fine.
-- I'm like, ok, that's neat. Anyways, well,
-- you never need to sign here when you tap.
But, um, what will happen is you'll tap and it'll be like, you know, you can't tap,
you have to like, stick your card in and use your pin
to actually authorize that much. But I was buying something that was over 500 bucks
and,
uh, I just force a habit I tapped
and the guy's like, oh, that won't work.
And I'm like, oh, yeah, probably will because it was a credit card, not a debit card.
And it went through and he kind of stared at me and I'm like, I'm like,
do you want me to sign that receipt?
And he's like, yes, please.
Right. II, I recall having that and
I was in Europe
and I think I was buying tickets at the train station. I use my phone
and the guy said, oh, you can't tap for this amount.
I said, well, let's just see if it works. And it didn't he? Like, was speechless.
I looked at him and I said, like, I'm from America,
like our credit card laws are a disaster.
Well, that's the thing. Right? It depends.
Sometimes the merchant sets a maximum amount, sometimes the,
the payment processor sets some maximum amount.
Sometimes you're issuing bank or whatever entity sets a maximum amount.
So, who knows? Right.
And, and then also the rules on, you know,
whether or not you're allowed to tap or you have to stick it in,
in pin or whatever that, that also varies.
And then, you know, and I love that
like I have an American credit card for work and
it doesn't have a pin number and it just, every time I use it
physically, like when I travel, I'm like, oh I forgot the damn pin number
and I get like really annoyed and then I'm like, wait, no, calm down.
It doesn't have a pin, it's OK
because we have a chip and sign which is idiotic. Now, I've heard rumors
that they want to switch to just chip. No signature. Who cares? And let's face it.
Nobody ever looks at the signature ever on these cards.
-- The,
-- the only reason for signatures,
we have 500 years of case law saying
it's extremely illegal to forge somebody else's signature.
I mean, ok, it's like,
it's like why you can fax a document to somebody
but you can't scan it and email it to them.
Uh I think some of the laws have changed on that recently.
-- But I, I get your point, you
-- know, it's just, it's,
it's why do we do it that way because that's how we've done it for 500 years.
A signature, please.
And you know what's funny is like here, for example, you go to the post office
and you have to sign for your package or whatever,
but it's like an electronic signature.
But if it's like a credit card slip, they make you sign the slip,
you know. So it's, it's nothing's integrated. That's the other thing, right?
Everybody assumes technology is nice and integrated and
works well. No, it's like a bunch of hodgepodge
anyway, we've, we're in a hole. I think.
So, here's what I want to tell you about cash is
I detest cash and here is my reason why
I think your point about it being readily available
-- has a certain amount of merit.
-- It's not that it's readily available.
It's that you can spend it without permission.
-- That's the one advantage, the same
-- thing.
So
I I'm going to say that is a fair point.
But I think this is one of those instances
where if you put all the positives in one bucket
and all the negatives in another bucket or even
the positives of something else in the other bucket,
I feel like the scale tips drastically away from cash.
And the reason being, first of all, I have to go get cash,
which I almost never do because I don't like
-- computer printed out. It's annoying. Right. Exactly.
-- It waste my time.
I have to go to the bank or an ATM and, like, physically acquire the money.
-- Well,
-- wait, so what time out because a lot of stores here will do cash back,
like the grocery store, Home Depot, whatever they actually
prompt you. Do. You want cash back when you make a purchase?
If you use your debit card, you can do that.
But if you have a credit card, when you get a cash advance like that,
you end up getting charged a certain service fee.
So I'm definitely never doing that.
You guys have debit cards, right?
Well, yes, we have debit cards but don't use your debit card.
So from the risk perspective, if,
if I lose my credit card or someone steals my credit card,
none of that's my money. I don't care.
And the bank deals with it.
In fact, my credit card for it hasn't in a while,
but it used to get stolen about every couple
of months and I never cared because whatever they,
they overnighted me a new card and I was back in business every single time.
Now, your debit card, if you lose your debit card or someone steals your debit card
and they start charging things to it.
Your money is disappearing out of your account and you have to go deal with the bank.
Usually they'll put some of it back
and while they're doing their investigation and
additionally, depending upon how the investigation turns up,
you could be out of some money for quite a long time.
And so
when you use a debit card,
you're putting a substantial amount of the risk on yourself actually,
versus a credit card where, where like 99% of the risk is on the bank.
-- And I just don't have to care.
-- This is true.
And I, I know locally there's, I've had,
I've heard some hilarious stories where people had
either, you know, like
my debit card, whenever I go to the cabin,
it, like, works in one of the towns but doesn't work in one of the smaller towns.
It's,
yeah, it's really bizarre. And then conversely I think, uh, a person I know.
Oh, I forget if it was credit card or debit card. But, like, all of a sudden, like,
the, the, basically the person made, like, a purchase of, like,
1000 bucks of alcohol at, like, two in the morning,
which would be generally out of character for this person.
And, you know, and they weren't called until tomorrow and they're like,
because it was actually a gas station purchase, like,
hundreds of miles away and they're like, oh, and there's,
there's this other charge that did, did you, you know, did you do that?
Do you, do you know about this?
And of course the person is like, yeah, No,
I wasn't buying alcohol at two in the morning.
So, the, the fraud systems to protect you against that are, yeah, they're not great.
And as you said, yeah, like, at least in North America legally.
Uh, what is it?
You're only legally on the hook for,
I think it's the 1st 50 bucks of credit
card fraud assuming you reported lost or stolen.
But, yeah, in general, all the companies are like, whatever. We don't care.
We want people to just use these things.
Yeah,
I've never paid a dime for having my card stolen and I've
had some hilarious conversations because I remember one time I was,
I was out for dinner
and I, I, you know, give the, the server my card and they come back,
they said it's been declined and I say, ok, well, here's, here's another one,
use this one
and then I get out of the restaurant and I call the credit card company.
They're like, uh, yeah, we, uh, were, were you in Washington DC or Seattle today?
And I said
no, they said, yeah, you've got in and, right. So, anyway, it was,
there were various charges, like I could not have traveled to the places
that, and I assume that's what tipped off the,
the fraud system is the fact that there were like, impossible charges from, uh,
you know.
-- Yeah,
-- they'll have rules like you can't move more than 500 miles an hour or whatever.
Right.
Well, this was, I,
I think they told me there was a purchase at a gas station in Washington DC and then
like a Target or something in Seattle within an hour.
And I definitely not me, you know.
But anyway, anyway, so
that, that's where I see the enormous advantage to credit cards.
A, a quite frankly an enormous disadvantage to a debit card.
A debit card I would use after I use cash in all seriousness in like the,
my hierarchy of, of spending money
because debit cards are, they, they come with
all the risks of a credit card, but they're my problem instead of the banks.
And I know, like I said,
I know there's a bunch of laws that I can generally get all my money back and stuff,
but I don't want to have to deal with that.
Right. So, like that, that's part of it. Now,
at the same time
with cash,
cash can be stolen from me.
I can lose cash
and
obviously I can't make change in my head so somebody
could easily be ripping me off and I wouldn't know.
Right. And so I see those as major disadvantages to cash.
Yeah.
So going to banksy,
one of the nice things you can do with and I have to qualify here paper money.
Not so much with like, you know, in Canada we have polymer money now.
Like it's plastic money.
-- Right.
You can rip a dollar bill or I
think in the case of Banksy it's a 10 pound note.
-- It's
-- a
-- thin
-- half, like it's, it's something he made.
-- No, no, no, it's, it's
-- not a real note.
-- It's an actual real 10 pound note. Are you
-- sure?
I thought they were fake.
-- They are fake.
-- They have Princess is
fake.
-- They're
-- fake.
Oh,
damn it. Well, that's,
that's even better.
I love that.
I'm annoyed now because I was gonna say one of the
one of the advantages here is you get to piggyback on
an organization that has already spent an obscene amount of time
and money trying to make things that are hard to fake.
You know, because the classic spy movie thing, right?
Where, how do you authenticate two people with a physical token?
They each have half a bank note
ripped in half and you know,
-- meet a dark alley and you should
-- explain there's some
context to this because you need to explain Banksy,
you need to explain pest control and you have to explain what they're doing.
Yeah. So Banksy is a famous British artist or possibly a collective.
-- I'm not 100% certain
-- graffiti artist slash criminal is
the right description here because while I love Banksy,
uh
he or she is technically breaking the law
with nearly every single art display created.
Uh So, yeah, anyways and so Banksy's work is quite,
quite highly valued like in the tens of millions now,
I believe uh especially that one painting that
when it was finally sold at auction, it,
it activated a shredder and tried to kill itself,
which I think is awesome, which made it only worth more money apparently.
But obviously authenticity of this stuff is a, is a hard problem. And
how do you authenticate something that cost $10 million?
Well, the answer is they have a certificate of authenticity which, you know,
that's totally legit.
Right. Couldn't fake that.
And then they have these
has it.
And I'm sad now it turns out these fake 10 pound notes with uh Lady Diana on them.
They rip them in half,
-- right? And so one half stays well.
-- Who's they though?
Uh oh, sorry pest control, which is the organization business entity that you know,
sells Banksy's work because my understanding is
that it is Banksy is still technically anonymous
-- now
-- to my knowledge.
No, like there's, there's some,
I've read some things where people are suggesting they know who it is.
But I think like fundamentally,
Banksy is anonymous for the most part and pest
control is like the legitimate wing of the Banksy empire
that then deals with the sale of the various paintings and works
and the ability to verify the real and part of Banksy.
And this is where those,
those bills you're talking about come into play
and it's quite clever what they've done.
So explain how this works with the,
the fake bills which are hilarious but explain them, please
so they basically rip the bill in half, which
means you have a physical object
or you have two physical objects now that
you can match together because faking a rip.
It's, it's a classic NP, hard problem in that. It's,
it's very easy to verify the answer once you have the answer,
but it's very hard to create the answer, right.
You know. So
you basically rip this thing in half and
yeah,
it's relatively easy to put the two pieces of
paper back together and see if they match.
But it would be really incredibly difficult and time consuming
to
create a fake half
similar to like a shaw signature on a file.
You know, you can very easily, once you have the shaw signature on the file,
you can very easily validate it.
But to create a new file, like if I give you a shaw
256 signature
as far as I know with quantum computing power, even that we currently have,
you just you can't really create a
valid file
for that signature
in a reasonable amount of time and effort.
Not for sha I mean,
this is why MD five fell because there is research done into easily creating
-- MD five
-- collisions. Was it using playstations? I think
the cell processor? I want to say
there might have been some early work into that.
But I mean, if we've reached a point,
you could probably do it on a freaking raspberry pie.
Pretty efficiently.
I mean, it's there've been some really cool research happening there and this is
so in fact, this is one of the interesting things is so sha one
you almost certainly is going to have a collision problem at some point,
we just have to wait for the research and the compute power to catch up.
But I think it's sha 256 or 512 were
designed in a manner that collision should not exist.
Well,
Shaw 256 is currently widely available and my
understanding is that for the quantum crypto resistant,
we'll just simply be moving to sha 512.
Uh that that could be, I, I don't know,
I haven't actually paid much attention in that space in a long time.
Yeah, it looks like mist is headed that way
and, and right on. I mean, that seems to be the key to quantum.
Well, because to be blunt, what else are we gonna use?
Uh paper money, Kurt,
we'll just use paper money because quantum computers will ruin credit cards.
I'm gonna reel this back in for a minute because as interesting as Banksy is and we
could probably do a whole show on just some of the crazy shenanigans he or she has.
-- Let's, let's reset
-- again.
I love that we could just make stuff up about him and nobody would know
you're not wrong. I'll give you that anyway. Anyway.
So I, I wanna, if, if we're talking about money
I think one of the really important things to hit on is cryptocurrencies and,
and like Bitcoin and stuff because there are a nontrivial number of people
who will tell you that Cryptocurrency is the future and it's untraceable and
it's magic and it does whatever you want it to do because Blockchain.
Right.
Uh, how do I put this nicely? They're pretty much all wrong.
Like I, I just did a little, I wrote up a little thing about this
back.
Well, no, but I mean,
fundamentally part of the prompt too is when you say even when you just say Bitcoin,
what are you talking about?
Exactly. Right.
Are we talking about the kind of Bitcoin people who
actually have their own wallet with their own Bitcoin?
And if they want to do a transaction, they, they have to,
you know, actually find a miner that will take their transaction and blah, blah,
blah
or we talking about a Bitcoin holder like, well, for example,
um in Canada, I, I personally use shake pay.
They claim to have my Bitcoins.
Uh I hope they do. Uh
for all I know it's just a couple of guys in
Toronto that have my money and are never giving it back.
That's entirely possible as well.
But for example, um
you know, shake pay if I were to
convert my Bitcoin into uh Canadian dollars, well, shake pay is like,
cool you do that.
Here's your money,
right?
They don't actually have to do like a Bitcoin transaction because they're,
they're holding the Bitcoin in the wallet.
Right.
You know,
and so for example, I can get my,
I can get my Bitcoins turned back into money in theory and
emailed back to me in a matter of less than five minutes.
Whereas if I was actually holding my own wallet,
I'm not even sure how I would do that without
using somebody like shake pay to turn it back into,
you know,
regular
-- service.
-- I mean, so I turned Bitcoin into real money using Coinbase. I think it was
last year or the year before.
And basically the transaction to transfer coin into
Coinbase took like two days,
which was really annoying
because what happened was this was when Bitcoin was getting like out of control
and I wanted to move,
it was a really small amount, it was like 0.1 Bitcoins or something.
It was, it was a fairly trivial amount of Bitcoin and I let the client pick the
transaction, uh the fee, right?
And the fee it picked
was fairly low.
And then all of a sudden all the fees like shot through the roof.
And here's the other trick to Bitcoin is once
you have a transaction sitting in the mem pool,
which is like the magic ethereal place
your transactions go before they're accepted.
Uh You basically can't get them back out without taking extraordinary steps
and I wasn't willing to do that because part of those extraordinary
expire,
uh, eventually they will age out
with, but it takes like weeks to age out.
So there
is a time out. But it's, it's absurdly long.
Right. Right.
And so my assumption was just, well,
I'll just wait weeks and eventually somebody picked it up and it went through
and then
I, I turned
my Bitcoin into real money and then I transferred my real money to me and like, yes,
I have $50 from Bitcoin and then I claimed it on my taxes and the IRS never called me.
So I assume I did it right. But no, for real, there's
outside of a service like that. If you have Bitcoin,
-- uh there's nothing you can do
-- off topic.
But what happens if I do the minimum,
my understanding of the minimum transaction yet?
So here it is
0.00000546. Bitcoin.
Can't you just fill up the men pool with a pile of garbage and mess it up?
Yeah, you totally could. And the main pool is fairly small.
It's only like 500 megabytes or something like that.
And yeah, it's definitely a plausible attack
except that attack would actually cost you real money. Well, no, you could just,
-- no, it would cost you real money because the, the miners fees, not
-- necessarily.
Here's the other part of it though is there's no reason you
couldn't just fill up the m pool with transactions that have zero
coins as a transaction fee.
So there's definitely some attacks you can do against this and I'm not
going to get into all the details because I don't totally understand it.
But, but basically yes, a malicious person could totally hose the M
pool.
Yeah, because from what I've looked at Bitcoin and, and most cryptocurrencies,
they're surprisingly fragile against these types of,
I guess you could call it like layer seven attacks.
You know,
you actually start exploding the logic of
the system and how it handles transactions.
Right. Right. Yeah, there's definitely some shenanigans that one can do.
-- Oh,
-- did you hear the recent thing about the Ethereum? The terrible wallets?
Well, the, the you can choose your own
number for like your key. Now you should
have a computer,
generate a suit like a good cryptographically secure pseudorandom number,
right. For that,
you know,
key.
But apparently some people pick like one
totally random.
And so, yeah, apparently what's happening is because if you can guess the secret,
you can hijack that wallet.
Like that's kind of the point, right?
You have the private key, you have the wallet, that's
the whole premise of these things.
And so what's interesting in this article is
not only that people have chosen bad key values
and had their wallet stolen, but if you choose a bad key value and put it on chain,
it's gone in seconds apparently.
And there's more than one actor doing this
Yeah, I saw that they, they traced kind of,
most of the emptying of these accounts to a handful of other, I guess account holders
and at,
at the high point they figure
the money they've stolen is worth about 50 million US D
which is,
that's,
-- that's pretty wild right there.
-- That's, that's not bad. Well, it's the classic.
Well, no, I wouldn't.
It's not even the Superman attack because some of these
walls probably had a decent amount of money in them.
But, um, see, this is what really worries me about cryptocurrencies is that
with regular money, depending on the circumstances.
Even with actual physical money, you can,
if it somehow gets lost or destroyed, you can, you can sometimes get it back.
So, for example, like through insurance or,
uh, well, you know, you have your deposit,
you deposit your money in a bank and their FDIC insured in the US.
Right. So, if the bank burns down,
it's not like, oh, your money's gone, sorry, or if the bank even goes bankrupt,
you know, you, you get up to, what is,
I think 250,000 in the US or 200 grand or something.
Anyway, there's some, like, cut off.
It's quite a bit though.
Yeah. Well, for, for the majority of us working poor that it's not gonna, you know,
and I know that there is actually a thing for working poor and it's pretty grim.
But, yeah, most of us don't have 200 grand in the bank,
right. That's what gets me about these cryptocurrencies is,
you know, if you lose that private wallet, like that guy that throw
the hard drive with like 5000 Bitcoins on it.
And so yeah, I'm the other problem is the,
the the transaction speed and volume capability, right.
We've talked about this before you dumped
all the Bitcoin transactions into your elastic.
And how many total transactions were there? Roughly?
Uh it's a hair over 400 million right now, like 402 million give or take.
So they've
actually done
one day of visa transactions.
Right. Right. Yeah,
like, yeah, here we go 65,000
plus transactions per second.
And that's just visa,
right? There's Mastercard, there's Amex, there's
discover, there's
good Lord. There's I mean,
yeah,
yeah, when people say, oh, Bitcoin will destroy the banking industry, no,
Bitcoin won't now Blockchain will Blockchain absolutely will be sort of the new,
I think data fundamental primitive
that we base a lot of the new technology on just like http hate the world,
right?
And, and I think that's the an apt comparison because http by itself is nothing
as Blockchain by itself is nothing. It's all up to implementation.
Well, and, and the things that you wrap around it, right?
Like with our certification thing, we're using Blockchain as an immutable ledger.
Cool.
And we're not keeping people's data in it.
We're keeping just validation records in it. So that
for example, when you know, you have a GDPR request to forget it's, well, no problem.
We didn't put your data there, it's not
there. We just,
we don't, you know,
it's public so we didn't really, we didn't want it there. And
so there, there are technologies.
Well, like you said, like http, first of all,
you're going to need stuff like encryption and hashes and validation,
you're also going to need much higher level things like,
well, you know, in http we have javascript
and in the Blockchain, we're gonna, we're gonna have smart contracts. And
I'll be blunt right now again,
smart contracts terrify me because these people are like, oh,
we'll just replace all this
programming and business and process logic for the smart contract.
And it's like, ok, well, number one, the, the,
the smart contract is software so it will have software flaws.
And number two
logic and business process flaws,
like there's a reason lawyers charge a lot of money to write contracts.
Right.
Because
you know,
there's that famous Canadian court case between a telecom provider and a
telecom infrastructure owner where it boiled down to the placement of a comma
and that comma was worth several million dollars.
It was whether or not they had to pay to put the, the, the lines on the polls,
if they had to pay extra,
if that was included with something they'd previously done or something.
Right.
Right. And, and now wasn't, I think it was a theorem that had the smart contract
h
where somebody basically set it up. So it kept transferring
uh, money to their account anyways.
The point is the thee was like, you know,
that thing we never said we do where we said we'd never, ever, ever like
change transactions or roll back transactions or fork, do a hard fork for bla
Yeah, that's what we're doing.
Yeah, that was neat.
You know. So that's the other thing is despite all of this, oh, you know, 51% attack.
Well, no, actually a 51% attack is actually quite
possible in, in some circumstances.
Now, it's not going to be as simple as somebody getting 51% of the mining and
hijacking it. But for example, if,
you know, if a second Mount gawks were to happen
in Bitcoin World would Bitcoin roll it back and
declare a shenanigans do over.
I don't think so.
I
don't think,
-- I
-- don't think it would happen
because, yeah, the miners,
there's enough miners that simply wouldn't let it happen.
But, but it's possible
and there's no regulatory oversight and
I,
and I get it, that's part of the benefit of this
is that there's no regulatory oversight of the system,
-- you know?
-- Right.
But
for myself wanting to keep my money in something like that, that's,
I'm definitely not putting all my money there.
And there's another really important thing.
I think people sometimes forget about smart contracts specifically is
a lot of these smart contract systems are being touted as turn
complete and turn complete is just kind of a computer programming term.
That means you can,
you can write a program that can basically do anything you can think of.
But here's the problem is
if something is turning complete, it's also impossible to secure.
Because obviously, if you have a essentially a state, a
state machine
that can do anything,
you can't secure that because the possibilities are infinite and
we can only secure a finite number of things.
And, and I know some of them even include polymorphic code and stuff.
So they actually are explicitly like very powerful systems.
And yeah, I mean, it's just, there's no bound on what the system can do.
So yeah, securing that system.
That's a tricky one.
-- And by tricky, I mean, basically impossible.
-- OK. So, so let's do this.
I'm, if I was gonna rank
my financial vehicles of choice,
I'm gonna say credit card number one,
cash would be my number two.
I would put a debit card as my number three and I
would put Bitcoin last because while I think Bitcoin is amusing and,
and enjoyable to be a part of,
I don't view it at this point as being a serious financial vehicle.
Yeah, I mean, well, it's like the web back in 95 to 99
you could put your apps
online via web.
But No, you, most people,
you did classic client server type stuff because the web just wasn't ready for it.
And now here we are. And I literally,
I spend much more time, you know,
doing word processing and doing spreadsheet stuff in
Google Docs than I do in Microsoft Office.
Well, in fact,
I, I just ran into something yesterday
where
I was,
it was some product that wanted me to download their client.
And I was like, no, I'm not doing that. You know, I'm gonna, if it's not a
page now, just, no, I'm not,
I'm not interested in installing your piece
of garbage software that's going to overwrite.
Who knows what on my system. Just, just, no, I don't want to do that.
For me,
it would be credit cards first and one of the biggest reasons
would be is if I buy something large and they don't deliver
the darn thing I can get my money back real easy from
the credit card company and actually have that happen with a couch.
Uh Second, I would say debit card, but that's because I live in Canada
and third cash and Bitcoin would be a very,
to me. Bitcoin is not a practical currency.
It's more of an investment vehicle or product,
right at this point. It's just part of it is just
it,
ironically,
I don't think Bitcoin is liquid enough because when you
look at how long it takes for transactions to happen,
uh I don't think you could consider it liquid at all.
Just given the amount of time it takes to turn Bitcoin into money.
It's also very, very thinly traded. That is to say
like if you look at the daily Bitcoin volume,
something like 80 or 90% of that is Bitcoin washing.
So it's people just tumbling Bitcoins back and
forth to make them less traceable because it
turns up Bitcoin ain't anonymous at all.
It's fully traceable, you know,
and heck you have every Bitcoin transaction in a giant graph network database,
right?
I cannot trace transactions though. It's actually complicated to trace them.
-- So what ends up happening is
-- complicated but not
impossible. It is not impossible.
And you have to be watching the men
because that's where you have to figure out who put a transaction in place.
What was their IP address? But like I don't have any IP addresses in my
-- data, the ledger itself. No IP S
-- but it's thinly traded.
So the actual daily volume,
the majority of that volume is actually kind of I don't want to say fake volume,
but it's not like actual
transactions involving exchange of value between like a buyer and a seller.
It's just people moving their money around to make it harder to trace.
And so when you look at the actual number of Bitcoins being like
converted from like people buying into Bitcoin or
people selling their Bitcoins and getting out,
that's an incredibly small number.
And so, you know, there's that paper basically looking at the, um, the ramp,
the Bitcoin ramp up to $20,000 back in 2018.
And, you know,
saying quite convincingly looking at the data and it looks like essentially it
was one person or one small pool of speculators that drove that up.
I believe it because it crashed hard when it came down. Yeah.
What was that? There was a Bitcoin
uh themed cruise
that,
or was it a Bitcoin conference?
Either way they, they weren't taking payments in Bitcoins because the,
between the time it takes to convert Bitcoins into money and the time
and the, the, the, the fluctuation in the value
they, you know, it, you just can't get paid
sensibly.
-- Yes. That, that I think is very telling if, if that is the case. So
-- I think even New E
stopped taking Bitcoin.
They were taking Bitcoin for a while and
then they had to stop because the fluctuations.
Yeah, I believe that. I would not doubt it. So.
All right, man, I think we should call it, I guess in summary.
Just, yeah, bury, bury your money in the yard. That's probably the best bet
if it's plastic notes, if it's
right.
That's true. That's true. My, my US paper money. Well, I guess cloth, whatever.
I don't know, whatever it is.
Cotton. Sure.
I thought it was denim or whatever.
I, I have no idea.
Who knows there and they change it all the time too.
It's probably made of like shaven yak here or something at this point. I have no idea.
Whatever they, they change it. They, they get rid of the counterfeiters.
So they say uh so anyway, anyway, I'm calling it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes,
you can use the Pound
Os as podcast hashtag to hit us up on the social medias.
-- And yeah, Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.