Hello and welcome to the open source Security
podcast episode 100 and 12 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- How you
-- doing, man?
I am doing quite excellent. Actually,
my kids start school next week.
-- That's awesome. Good deal.
-- We survived summer.
I know.
Oh, my goodness, teachers are so teachers are so underpaid. That's all I have to say.
I,
yes. Anyway, I,
you know what it feels like sometimes is
it, it,
it's like when you're the security guy trying to
wrangle like all the developers who are like,
security is dumb and we don't like you.
That's what I imagine being a teacher must be like, except
all the time, not just for like, two hours every now and then.
Well,
plus you have their parents yelling at you
every time you do something that annoys them.
-- Right.
-- Which actually, no, that's exactly like the security people. Right.
The managers of the devs yell at us. Like, why are you going to mess with my schedule?
Why do we have to fix this CV E?
That's right.
Oh, it's nice to know every industry is exactly the same,
including teaching
Oh, man. All right, cool.
So, I, I think this time let's lead off with,
uh Google has made a hardware security key.
I found out kind of like a UI
key competitor.
Well, it's, it does the U two F. Right.
So, yeah, I mean, it basically implements the U two F standard,
but my understanding was is that it had like an internal,
sort of like,
I don't know what to call it, not a secure boot process,
but it essentially it had like some internal magic to make
sure it wasn't being like fiddled with or tampered with.
Ok. II, I don't know a ton about what's going on inside of it.
-- Here
-- we
-- go.
They are built with a hardware chip that includes firmware
engineered by Google to verify the integrity of the key.
My understanding of that and from what little reading I did is that the key is,
I guess we would go with tamper resistant,
which I mean, that's, that's,
you know, well, we always say in security, right?
Oh, well, if the attacker has physical access, it's game over.
Well, no, no, that, that is not always allowed like, well, great example,
being nuclear weapons, right?
It can't be like, oh, well, he stole the nuke,
I guess he gets to do whatever he wants with it, right? Uh What can we do?
-- Well, I mean, if you have a nuclear weapon,
-- so the good news is
you can probably do what you want.
No, they're, they're surprisingly difficult to set off.
And so my understanding is the US ones, you know,
they have the permissive active link code, which was set to of course,
six zeros back in the day.
But they basically, if you enter the pal incorrectly several times,
it basically like locks itself and won't fire, you know, because
yeah, just because the nuke falls into the wrong hands,
you don't want them using it on.
Well, whatever, right? But uh no.
So that's because my understanding of the U two F key is essentially that
basically if somebody hits me in the head with a brick and please don't do this.
I I would not like that and takes my UB key, they can just use it
-- because all they got to do is plug it into a computer and touch
-- it
pretty much right?
From what I know of the Google
Titan key. That would still be the case, right?
It's, it's literally, you touch it,
it doesn't have a fingerprint reader or anything.
It's just like something touched me.
So it works.
But I guess what this internal firmware thing
would help or would accomplish is I guess theoretically
if you have like a really high stakes situation,
like, oh, I don't know, maybe you have working for Google and you,
you have access to their internal C A by internal, I mean, their public one.
Like you have access to the internal systems that control it or,
you know, you have access to the DNS controlling google.com.
You know,
they don't want somebody messing with that token and giving it back to the admin,
right?
So they like, steal it from the admin's key ring while he's sleeping and, you know,
modified in some way to like, you know, allow them to,
to siphon the key or whatever off.
Right. Because let's face it. Right. Google.
Google has access to some, well,
stuff that basically runs the internet at this point.
-- Well, imagine if you got access to the chrome update stuff, I,
-- I guess so.
Here's my, my thought on this is
I, I think there's value
in having any piece of hardware do some sort of verification on itself.
Well, even just preventing like silly weirdness, right? Like ECCRM like, oh a cos
and gray hit me. So I'm not going to,
-- yeah,
-- that's probably more important.
And that's fair.
I guess the golden goose of,
-- of U two F keys is the private key stored internally
-- or doing proxy attacks, right?
Uh
No, no, no. But if you fiddle with the key, they would
in the sense of if I can
for the sake of argument,
I steal your Titan key and I am
somehow embed like another chip that's wi fi controlled
that I can remotely trigger the the button press.
OK? No, look, if, if you're at that level of infiltration of this key
like,
yeah. No, you're, you're a state
level,
you already have so much control over it.
But theoretically we can,
we're getting to the point where we can build hardware devices that are
very resistant to that form of attack.
Yeah, it's, it's getting there and, but here's so, so here's,
here's the point is that the primary competitor here is probably ubico,
-- right? With UBI keys. Which,
-- well,
honestly, is there anybody else making U two of keys?
Because like, I, I looked a long time ago and there wasn't,
there are a couple I've seen they were all really bad and I
don't even know if the Google Titan Key is going to be good.
Like, the reason I love the UI
key stuff is because I can run it over with my car and it still works.
And I've owned, I've owned a handful of other things in the past that were,
they were not well built. I, I bought it was called a crypto key.
-- Maybe I forget what it was.
-- Oh, yeah. The, the crypto nitro key guys.
The GP G key.
Yeah, the German GP G key guys.
Yes. It was like their very first
and I ended up like wrapping the whole
thing in electrical tape because it kept falling
apart.
Not
at
-- scale to be reliable is, is tricky.
-- It's more than that though.
There's, there's building at scale, right. Which let's face it.
Like you can find factories in China that do that. No problem.
But the bigger problem becomes
where is the key provisioned?
Because there's essentially a private key on these things. And now, yo
is really, they're very transparent about the fact that yes,
the UBI keys are built in the United States and Sweden
and then they're provisioned only after
Uki
Yo receives them and before they send them out.
So there's still a possibility that Yo
is, is storing the private keys because in fact,
I think Gemalto got caught like storing private keys once.
Uh wasn't that also? RS A?
It's probably everybody, right? It's probably everybody.
-- Well,
-- it's like diesel emissions.
-- Oh my God, they were caught cheating on their diesel emissions.
-- Who knew?
I had no idea. Right? Like where you're slowly shuffling the paper under the desk,
you know, the whole industry all of a sudden managed to fix diesel emissions.
And I'm like, ok, that's,
you know, they don't all have the same
technology but I
guess
good job everybody.
Uh Well, anyway, and so the issue, I guess with Google right now is Google is saying
they're not talking about this very much.
So, the assumption is they're probably coming from the factory provisioned.
-- Does Google ever talk about anything?
-- No, they never do.
Uh So here's the thing though,
people are concerned that maybe like if the factory is nefarious,
the factory could like, save the keys,
they're dumping into them and then Google might
not know if they did or didn't do something
well, see and that would be part of the firmware self check if the firmware,
for example,
validates that the chip can only create the key and it can't be imported.
You know, because that's one thing, right?
There's, there's a lot of hardware security tokens
where the key is generated somewhere and then imported to the token.
So for example, like a a lot of hardware security modules for, you know,
certificate authorities support that mode of operation because
you want that because you actually want to generate a key somewhere
and back it up and then put it on a hardware security module
and the hardware security modules is like,
you can't copy that off me. Ha ha ha.
You know, and that's a very valid thing to have.
And for something like, you know, like a UB key though
there is
probably a lot of value
in the UB key, basically being able to essentially attest that
there's a key on me. But I generated,
it was not imported
in any way, shape or form. Right? It was generated on me.
You,
oh, no, it's, that's an incredibly difficult magical thing to do,
right?
No, no.
Yeah.
Oh, I get it.
I get it.
And that's part of the problem, right too is, yeah,
like I generated a key using what is the source of randomness, ah, you know,
stuff like your dice roll three,
the number three. Exactly.
Yeah,
I was on the side.
I always love when you're like, with a kid, you're like,
guess a random number between one and 10 and then you're like
seven and the kids, like, how do you know? And I'm like, everybody picks seven.
-- so
-- actually it's funny you say that we were, we were watching a show on TV.
I was watching with my kids where a mentalist
was doing his thing and they're like, how does he do this?
And I said he made them pick that and they, he said how
he knows things like he knows how to make you do things you don't want to do. You're,
you're an irrational bag of meat. You don't get to beg.
But anyway, anyway, so I guess here's,
here's my overall take on this Google hardware key thing is
maybe the factory
has been compromised,
it's conceivable,
but
there's so many hardware devices around now that could all be compromised.
-- I feel like complaining about this
-- one blunt,
I'm
trying
to think of anything electronic that I own that doesn't have a made in China on it.
There's nothing seriously
and, and not just not just that Kurt, not even like,
like ignoring the potential political
implications
or not something
in
it are probably made in China.
But, but even more than that, the company you bought it from,
almost certainly contracted with, with a third party supplier, right?
Like
nobody builds anything.
Well, the NSA was doing those interceptions and hardware modifications,
remember?
Right. It's just,
it doesn't even matter where it's built anymore.
Nobody actually builds their own stuff because they just can't.
And so I think.
Right. Right.
And there's, there's certainly value in being concerned over your supply chain.
But I have a feeling that picking on
Google in this particular instance is probably not
helpful or wise.
Well,
I think this is a perfect example of security people basically doing that classic.
Oh, it's not perfect. It's trash, right?
Because how often do security people do that? Where?
Oh well, there is this hypothetical attack.
Like if the owner of the company is compromised and
somebody holds his family hostage, you could subvert them and
you know, like, well, what do you want?
You want like a bunch of like people with no families to run this company
and you want this company to be like
living in a plexiglass building in the middle of like Manhattan
where everybody can see what they're doing or something like,
-- you know,
-- no,
no.
What,
-- what we do is we complain incessantly about unrealistic scenarios and
-- to be fair,
Google is
trying to do things better,
right? Like as far as I know my UBQ is just like her
dip whatever. Yo.
And that's honestly pretty fine.
Like I it would suck if my UB key was
somehow compromised and could be remotely used or finagled because
well, that would definitely mess me up and you know,
the C class care lines who I work for
but fundamentally is that likely to happen? No, not really.
Now Google as a victim, you know, is a bit of a juicier target.
You know, you, you subvert the chrome updater and Voila,
you got everybody's computer.
But there, the thing also that gets me is like,
like you said, you know what I said about, you know,
having a device that's like I generated the key securely and it only lives on me.
Yes,
we're not there yet.
We're getting there and there's some implementations of that that are pretty good.
They're also pretty expensive.
And that's the other thing to keep in mind. Right. These UBI
cos
well, like they retail, they're not cheap like the UB keys.
I know the ones I buy are like they, I think they retail for about 50 bucks us.
Which, yeah, it's kind of pricey but
which is the same price.
And when you consider what a hardware security module costs,
those things are like tens of thousands of dollars.
And here's the best part.
They're typically like basically a Raspberry Pi running Linux sitting in epoxy,
you know,
like straight up like you and I could be
building them and all we'd literally have to do is
yeah, literally go to Home Depot, buy some like non conductive epoxy
voila,
you know J and Khs MS.
Right.
Yeah. Well, ok.
Yes and no, I mean, technically, yes,
but these things are also certified by various agencies.
So they have like, some, some standard,
some of them are, some of them are not,
I've actually found HS MS that are not certified and I'm kind of like, wait, what?
Yeah. Don't buy that.
-- Don't buy that. That's going to be a huge turn.
-- You know what the sad thing is?
It's probably about as good as the certified one.
But, yeah, the certified one at least, you know, is this tall to get on the ride?
Right. And, and they have certain internal
as well
is, is what's very important.
Yeah, like IO 9000, they, they, it may not be good processes,
but at least they're documented.
Right. Exactly.
So.
Right. I, I guess the next one on my list is struts.
-- Well,
-- and
the
news.
-- Yeah,
-- it's,
so,
here's the thing I love about struts
is fundamentally struts is the kind of technology
that
number one, it's, it's a broken piece of poop because it's
just the way it was built and the time it was built
it's a broken piece of poop.
And number two,
the kind of people that build stuff using struts
are just inherently up the creek without a paddle because
we should tell people what struts is because I bet there's a
lot of people who actually don't know because let's face it.
Struts is freaking old man.
I was gonna
say, if they're lucky enough to have never programmed in Java, then God bless you.
You're in a better place than some of us
and we just lost half the audience.
But basically, yeah,
struts is what happens when you take a Java app and you need to put it on the web.
Plus somebody designed this 20 years ago
-- and built it 20 years.
-- It was like brand new.
I mean, so OK, so for people who don't know like we should let,
let's give history lesson right old man, old man story time.
So
way, way back in the day
you had a web server
and you needed to do stuff and it was called CG I,
which I don't even remember what CG I something
Tommy
gateway interface.
And like I remember writing, I had a job like I was actually paid to write CG I in CC.
It was the job security was phenomenal.
Yeah. When I saw what
people were
doing,
-- I actually preferred Pearl.
-- It's, it's quite bad. Uh Pearl is well funny enough.
So we started in C and then kind of pearl came along and Pearl suck too,
but it was better than C
and then
it did.
And then John was kind of a thing and Java was fairly new and people were like,
I want to do this web stuff with Java
and so kind of struts and Tom can and that whole ecosystem came of it.
And struts gave you the ability to basically build like web applications in Java,
which was essentially impossible before that because there was just like,
no way to connect Java
-- to a web server because,
-- oh,
there were ways I saw some of them. It was, it was pretty horrific.
Well, you couldn't do like CG I though, right?
Because like Java took too long to start up. And the reason CG I worked
is CG, I would essentially like, it would start a process,
handed a bunch of stuff and then just dump whatever
came from the CG I script back to the user,
right?
And Java took, you know, 10 to 20 seconds to start, which was totally unreasonable.
And now Java takes 30 seconds to a minute to start.
Well, that's how we ended up with the three layer cake.
Remember when we had the web layer, the application layer and the database layer
with Java in the middle, I mean, and that was kind of the result of that is, yeah,
because you had to have these Java things
running all the time because yeah, otherwise it would literally take
20 to 30 seconds to service a web request
which even back in the nineties was unreasonable.
Yeah. In fact, I remember, I mean,
I had another gig. I did some, some contracting work one time where it was a website
that took three minutes to load and they wanted it under one minute.
I was like, well, at least they're not a
real high here
under like 60 seconds for, wow,
it was terrible.
And this was back when web browsers would, would load,
is that something like we want a list of everybody in the US who has a cat
because that would be a reasonable,
that would be reasonable.
Uh The issue was they were loading lots of things off of remote servers
and like ads, it was mostly ads.
And the issue being that back then web browsers would basically load
in all of the html and display the page at the end.
So there was no like lazy loading.
Like I love now how I go to click a link and then an ad takes its place and
I click the ad and then I see ads for some ridiculous product for the next six months.
But anyway, anyway, right. So struts, that is what struts does. OK?
So, so struts is very old
and let's face it, it comes
from a time when moving fast wasn't a thing.
Well, part of the problem is it's not just very old in the sense of its old code,
it's old culture and old ideas.
And I think that's the, that is the crux of the problem with struts.
Well, that's the crux of two problems with struts. It's the same root cause.
But so you have a lot of security flaws in struts because for example,
it does its own serializing and deserializing of data
and very poorly. Quite often there's flaws in it.
And the second problem is by definition,
if you've built something that uses struts,
you can't fix or rebuild it
because it's all technology and it's got
20 years of business knowledge embedded in it
for you to do a rewrite in a new clean language
is going to be failure
expensive.
Well, but, but, so here's the bigger issue though.
There's a security issue in struts.
You're not gonna fix it in five minutes.
Right.
Because you're not struts isn't the sort
of technology you're doing continuous deployment with.
If you're running struts,
it probably takes you somewhere between 30 minutes
and a week to deploy a new version.
So the Struts app that I most dealt with, I'm not going to name names
to do a new version.
Well, not technically six months to do a new version,
but a minimum of 1 to 2 months to do a version,
but six months from like we need to do X to shipping X.
But, and, and that's just the problem,
right is that it literally was something that was
picked a long time ago and it works kind
and they're sort of, you know, like I said, if you pick struts,
it's one of those things.
It's like I,
oh I decided to build with concrete while you're kind of stuck with concrete.
That's just how that is, you know, such a fundamental design decision.
That's a good analogy for this actually.
Yeah, like you picked Java. Well, what else are you going to use?
-- No, like, seriously? What if it's not struts, what else would it be?
-- Right. Exactly.
You don't have a choice. For the most part.
I saw some Frankenstein Monsters back in the day to get Java Apps online
where they, they had like the three layer cake design and the, like the front end,
you know, this is before, like glass fish and Tom cat and,
yeah, I'm
ok. So for the glass fish was something that sun.com made.
Sun.com no longer exists. So it's ok if you don't know what I'm talking about,
they ceased to exist
the,
probably about 10 years ago
they were the dot
dot com
until, you know,
were,
yeah, they were
-- killed them. Right. Yeah.
-- Well, a lot of things killed them. Yeah, that's true.
You know, and then, uh, but yeah, so,
yeah, I mean, literally if you're going to build something in Java and,
and quite frankly, back in the day, if you had a large system that you needed to build,
especially when it involved more than one sort of
organization. So, you know, like a large company with,
say, marketing and sales and
whatever
Javis
was kind of your only option.
You know,
I,
it's like, it's like, it's like we want to put something in orbit.
Well, you kind of have to learn how to build rockets and build complicated things.
That's just, there's no option. B
Right. Exactly.
You know,
and so, like, quite frankly, if you picked a Java
Yeah, really. The only way to get that thing online, realistically speaking
was once it existed and still is, is struts and I, I
don't know
of any other sort of framework or any
package that
basically gives you what struts gives you.
So,
yeah, like,
you know, we, we,
you know, we decided to build with concrete because, well,
we need to build a 50 story building.
Like, what else are we going to do?
Uh Right. And now, now here's, here's where we should build on. This analogy
is
when you build, say a bridge out of concrete and steel,
right?
It's going to need maintenance eventually and it's going to be difficult to,
to do anything with.
And the problem is
you can ignore it,
but eventually, like it becomes so bad,
you can't ignore it any longer.
And basically,
I think struts has reached the point where like
the technical debt and the issues it comes with like
the bridge is falling down. What are you going to do
-- is no plan
-- B, you basically gotta,
you gotta build a new bridge and quite frankly that a
lot of people don't have the budget for that
and, and nobody ever does.
However, if the bridge completely falls down, you don't have a choice. Right?
Well, the thing is, it's not like the bridge falls down and stays down, right?
Like, oh, you have a full on struts.
Uh you can maybe put in some compensating
control like a mod security thing to filter it
or you can try and work around it. Like, I've seen people
do some, you know,
pretty horrendous stuff to work around struts because they have to,
because if they upgrade struts, the whole thing breaks for sure.
At that point
it's, the bridge isn't going to fall over with the struts flaw.
No, it's just every, like, six minutes a truck's gonna drive off the side of it.
And eventually people might get annoyed
that, that their truck fell off the bridge,
but no fundamental.
That's something I've come to terms with in the security industry is
there's a lot of stuff that just is not worth fixing.
Oh, totally, man.
Because quite frankly, you know, it's gonna, we're gonna lose like 20 grand a year.
No offense, but 20 grand is like
a month of a developer's time plus overhead plus opportunity cost.
And you are suggesting not fixing it is a better option.
I'm not suggesting not fixing it is a better option. I'm simply saying not fixing.
It might be a pretty rational option.
-- Uh
-- It, it very well could be, in fact, so I,
I was talking to someone the other day who was
there,
they had a small business that was basically compromised and they got whacked good
and they basically said, what do we do?
And I said, you either replace all your gear or you just say
I'll live with it,
you know, and you're probably,
or something more subtle.
Uh, it was,
it was all of the above
-- and my response would be not so much
-- tax,
replace all the gear, but
move it into the cloud, get somebody else to.
Right.
That's, that's also, that was one of my suggestions was like, honestly,
your best bet is to get in the cloud as much as you can.
And
because obviously they're like, oh, what can we do today?
I said, well, you can buy on your computer and they said, I don't,
we don't want to do that.
I said, well, then you don't really have another choice.
But I mean, totally, man, that's, that's exactly right. Is
sometimes
the, the risk is worth it
depending upon what the environment is.
And I think that's another thing, security is really bad at
how many times have companies screwed up and
lost our personal data and it's turned out,
ok, like Air Canada just lost 20,000
people's data bad.
Oh, wait, it's passport data. Oh, it's really bad.
But what am I going to do? Not fly?
-- You're not going
-- to do anything and, and not only that, it's too late,
the data is gone.
I mean, this is where some of the goals of GDPR I think are maybe laudable.
But, I mean, in all seriousness, like today in North America,
if a company loses your data.
Oh, well,
uh,
-- you,
-- you can't do
anything
with
consumer.
Right. Exactly. Like they don't care.
And as a consumer you can do very little.
And in fact,
as history has shown it basically doesn't affect the company negatively in
any way outside of maybe a stock dip for three months.
Right? Like,
that's just the way it is.
So if, if you're a company, like that's something to think about.
If we secure this, it's going to cost X, if we don't secure it, it's going to cost Y
the thing is no, no, no, it's even worse than that. If we don't secure it,
there's a chance it will cost zero
and there is a chance
that it will cost more than zero.
And that number is variable.
So if you do security it has a set cost.
Yep.
Well, not and, and actually it's worse than that.
If you do security, not only does it have a set cost, but there's an opportunity cost.
So for example, like I just, uh, so disclaimer, I,
I've been the director of it at the cloud security lines for over eight years now
and uh I'm going full time now and so I'm cleaning up a lot of our it
and I love it because I'm, I'm looking at stuff like, oh damn it, why,
why is this all messed up and like who?
Right. That was me. Right. Because we made this,
you know, like just whatever, whatever. Like,
you know, I, I've done things like run Fedora 14 in production for three years
and if you know anything about Fedora's life cycle, then
-- two
-- years too long.
Well, but we have cloud flare and mod security and some other stuff.
Filtering and, you know,
nothing bad at, like, literally nothing bad
-- happened.
-- Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And, you know, it's a public facing web server with no data, no sensitive data on it.
Right.
So, yeah, I'm, I'm willing to live with that and if it gets hacked fine,
I'll rebuild it on a fresh server.
You know, now we're up to date and everything's been updated within the last week.
And that's awesome.
But fundamentally,
you know, we've gotten lucky partly and part of it is I've done other things to,
you know, prevent these things,
right? There's other ways, you know, than just
because the reality is if you rely on having up to date software to be secure,
you're doomed
because
even if you play the patches within 10 seconds of the vendor releasing them,
there are still, I mean, for example, what was it?
Uh Wednesday, I want to say there was that thing on Twitter, the,
the zero day privilege escalation in windows
that somebody posted on Twitter
on github
link,
you know.
So if somebody also has a zero day that
lets them get into a less privileged Windows process,
well, now they're like, oh sweet.
Now I can escalate to, you know, the systems,
right? So
to be blunt,
relying on your software to be up to date to be completely secure.
It won't work,
but updating your software is, it's kind of like filling potholes. It's not
a lot of fun.
It's not very glamorous.
It does make the road nicer though.
Yeah.
II, I do agree.
You know, like it, it does make things
less worse.
I won't say it makes things better but it definitely makes things less worse.
Um, and a big part of updating software too is, you know,
can you update your software without,
without breaking the other software?
And that implies that you have some control and
visibility into what you're doing and you know,
what you're doing.
If you can't do that, then you're doomed. And that's the problem with struts.
You know, these people have struts and they're stuck with it and,
you know, they don't know that updating it is gonna break the app in some weird way
and it might,
it totally,
I remember.
Oh, yeah. Oh,
some of the, just,
well,
and part of the problem too is some of the changes
that need to happen to struts to fix these security issues properly
will so fundamentally break it.
They just, no,
yeah, it, it's got to go, I guess, I guess the advice becomes
if you're starting a new project,
don't use struts
if you,
yeah, that's fair.
That's fair.
-- We can't wait for the hay
-- mail. Like, use rails. Rails is at least,
-- you know,
-- dude, Ruby is like old and lame now too. Right.
But it's only old and lame this year.
-- That's true.
-- A decade
ago.
So, I, I guess
if you're running it,
good luck
and may the force be with you or, or something,
I think fundamentally if you're, if you're running it,
you're probably making money off of it.
So, you know
how
all
hopefully.
Oh, all right, cool, man. I, I, I'm calling it.
So. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com to hit up the show notes,
UZ pound Os S podcast hashtag
to hit us up on social media
and if nothing else, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.