Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner, Josh Bresser.
Just your partner. Not.
So I was gonna, I was,
I was trying to think of something clever to
say about locational and knowing where you live.
I mean, you do know where I live, you send me stuff.
Yeah.
Well, or do I like, is that like a po box? And you have somebody forwarded on to you?
-- No, it's an address, you know that
-- like,
do you actually live there or is it just like a like is it a Potemkin Village?
I guess just the front, like a picture of a house and you actually, you know,
live in a shack somewhere else?
-- I
-- mean,
I'm confident you could prove that relatively well
using like Google Maps imagery and satellite pictures
that my house is, in fact a house.
Yeah,
but I don't have like a picture of you standing in front of your house or whatever.
Like,
oh,
so my favorite thing is this judge thought that the defendant that was like
a virtual hearing and that he thought
the defendant was actually threatening the plaintiff
and he's like, go outside. Show me the house number.
Bam. Like, what a
clever way to,
like, where are you? Oh, I'm at home. I don't think you are. Go outside.
Show me the house number from the front.
-- I remember watching that. That was pretty wild.
-- Yeah, judges are smart.
-- Who knew
-- most of
-- them?
-- It's funny how such low tech things can.
Or, I love when the people do,
like the Reddit A MA S they hold up like the little sign with the date on it or whatever.
And like, that's very simple but it works. I mean,
-- and
-- that's my favorite thing about the Instagram account
recoveries. They can do that because they have pictures of you.
-- I know, I know anyway.
-- Well, and that, that actually feeds directly into this is like
we now have the technology
to put a, like because you could always put a tracking thing on stuff,
but it had to have like massive batteries because it had to like,
connect to the cell phone network to beacon out.
See, and that's my favorite thing about GPS, right?
Everybody's like, oh, it's a GPS tracker.
And I'm like, well, GPS receives a signal and yeah, it'll, it'll know where it is. But
like either you have to physically go retrieve it
and download it or it has to beacon out.
And I guess your choices for beaconing really are cell Wi Fi Bluetooth
and, or you know, custom radio frequency stuff which probably like,
military and law enforcement has access to, but we don't.
And
the beauty is Apple built. Apple air tags.
Well, it's more complicated than just saying the beauty is,
but fundamentally the point we're going to focus on today is Lufthansa
tried banning air tags.
Can you say that again? Sorry, just say that word again. Lufthansa.
Ok. Look, I'm American.
You're lucky. I got it that close. How do I say it?
Yeah,
that's true. Ok. In fairness. Yeah, like
Luft
Luft,
we don't have the noise in English.
It's like
it's like my name,
-- you know, whatever
-- I give up,
say it again. Say it again for me,
Lufthansa.
I hear the same thing I just said, but whatever,
I
-- don't care,
-- I don't even care.
I apologize in advance to any German speakers listening to me pronounce Lufthansa.
OK.
Anyway,
anyway, now I want to, I want to also, but before we go on, I want to clarify that
apple air tags are clever
and I also recognize the negative aspects of it
from kind of the stalking and unwanted tracking perspective,
which is a very real thing,
but that's also not the thing I want to discuss today because I think
that is far more nuanced and there are people far more qualified than us.
And
I will put some links in the show notes. I know of people who have
about this and talked about this that have actually done a marvelous job
rather than curt and I spouting nonsense.
-- I mean,
-- to put it simply Apple at least has
the appearance of having thought about anti
stalking and added some basic capabilities.
It falls short in many ways.
Well,
the problem is it's a fundamentally difficult
-- problem to solve
-- which we're not solving,
we're talking about luggage.
And so it's, it's one of these kind of dual use technologies where it's just,
it's fundamentally
easy to abuse and hard to prevent abuse at scale, especially at scale.
But
so I don't want to say we're going to ignore that,
but we're kind of going to ignore that because yeah,
we're not qualified to talk about,
like you said, the nuances of it.
So like, for example,
I have a couple of air tags and I actually have one
in my car in case my car gets stolen that way,
I'll be able to find it hopefully quicker.
Um You know, and,
and like all my son's backpack and stuff just to make it easier
to find uh in case it gets left at school or something.
Yeah, like, so they're kind of magical because they have like a built in battery that
-- I don't know how long it lasts,
-- like
around a year give or take because my wife has a couple
and
I it, it just takes AC R 2032 that like
-- what American quarter size battery, I
-- call it the quarter battery.
Yeah, but we live in a place that has quarters. Most other people don't.
-- Ah,
-- that's a good point. Yeah. Germany 20
cents.
Which makes more sense. I'm not going to say it doesn't.
But that's another discussion
-- for another day.
-- Coinage.
Um,
so, yeah. And I mean, and if the battery runs low you can just
swap it out.
-- Which
-- is great because the old trackers had built in batteries and like a tile.
I remember I had a tile, I got at a conference.
It lasted one year and then Tyler was like, well, this is done now,
I'm like,
this is terrible. And the other thing too is, and the,
again, tiles were terrible for this. I had some tiles.
Their sensor network isn't nearly as big because Apple threw the magic of just like,
hey, here's a software update.
Now, you're part of our tracking network.
You don't
have. Can you turn that off? I think
you can't turn that off.
I, not that I'm aware of. Maybe they've changed. But I last, I checked, I,
no,
it's like the Amazon sidewalk thing. Right? Like it's like, can you opt out? No?
-- Sure.
-- Anyway, anyway, we're going to talk about air tags in luggage specifically.
But here's the thing. This is a perfect example of where it went from.
Yeah, it's possible, but it costs $1000 and it's a real pain in the butt.
To sure you order one online.
It's $30 you put it in your luggage and there's like no step too that it just works.
-- Right.
-- I mean, this is very reminiscent of the episode. We just did
a couple ago about
the basically all these hacking tools becoming extremely affordable. Right.
My understanding of what was happening is basically customers are putting air
in their luggage
and then inevitably your luggage gets lost at the airport,
which happens sooner or later if you travel any amount of time and then
they call the airline and the airline is like,
we have no idea where your luggage is and they're like, I can see it here.
It's like sitting at this place at this airport.
And then my suspicion is the airlines were like,
-- whatever. I don't, I don't want to hear this go away.
-- Nerd.
Well, it's embarrassing to them. Right. Like, because I, well,
for example, I've had luggage lost where I was on a flight from Argentina to, well,
Canada
and in Sao Paulo,
they popped the emergency slide when they were opening up the doors for first class.
So they basically had to clear out first class,
which meant they bumped a whole bunch of people in the back like us.
And so my luggage essentially wasn't an indeterminate state.
So I get to Canada and of course the the
customs guy is kind of like looking at me suspiciously, you know,
because I have like no luggage, just a little backpack.
And uh and I'm kind of shivering in the airport because it's like December and I,
I don't have winter clothes
and he's wearing rubber gloves and I'm getting a little nervous but, you know,
he let me go without incident,
but like, literally the airlines, like, well,
we didn't lose your luggage and I'm like, ok, cool.
Where is it? And they're like, well, we don't know.
I'm like, do you know what country it's in?
They're like, no, it's in the system somewhere.
And like three days later I get a knock at my door and a guy, you know,
from Air Canada hands me my backpack and it's like, thanks, like,
thank goodness I was going home
and you figure in an airport there are literally iphones everywhere.
-- There's thousands of iphones at every
-- airport
and the staff has them too. So that's the other secret is like
the, the areas that you and I do not have access to.
And here's the other clever thing,
like, if it's in a basement, yeah, I can't see a cell phone network or anything.
It's dead but somebody with an iphone walks by it,
beckons out the iphone does its magic and,
you know, like two hours later the data pops up.
Exactly.
Ok.
Anyway, I,
I don't want to talk about this part of this because
I think the far more interesting story here in the parallel,
-- think that we can tie into security is the fact that Lufthansa basically said,
-- well,
they threw a tantrum.
-- Well, they
-- got obviously
annoyed. Well, no, no, no worse. They got embarrassed.
-- I
-- mean, that could be, but regardless,
no, no embarrassed is bad.
Companies hate being embarrassed because, like,
when you pants a company they hate that.
My suspicion
is
the,
the airline
has very different ways of tracking this stuff in probably every
airport because I'm sure every airport is a little different.
It's luggage takes. It's right.
It's the barcode on the luggage take it moves through scanning devices.
So it's a point in time scan, just like the package.
And so the problem is if somebody takes it
off the conveyor belt throws it in the corner,
it's not lost.
Exactly. Exactly that and then no one's ever going to find it.
I remember seeing a picture on Reddit
some years ago of a, a suitcase like laying in the middle of,
of the runway or the tarmac, whatever you call the area, the planes move around and
it, uh it showed someone like just walk past it
and they were like, not my job or something like that. Right.
And, and there was someone who had a comment
that said, look when you work at an airport, like it's,
if it's not your job to touch stuff,
you don't touch stuff like that is how it works because
when you start messing with things that aren't your job,
people start asking weird questions and you have problems.
And so that is totally expected like there is
someone else's job is to come and pick up that
case. That was not that person's job.
And I kind of get that and I feel like now I wanna tie kind of all this back to
the world of, well, I should say there's one other piece of this. Right.
So Lufthansa gets embarrassed
and they basically end up walking it back and you're like, oh, I guess it's not, oh,
I should say part of this story is
the Lufthansa claims that the German government told them they
can't put these air tags in bags
because they're a transmitting device or something.
Right.
Well,
-- the battery and the transmitting aspect
-- and then people obviously start freaking
out and calling them out on it and then they're like,
oh, after all, I guess it's ok.
Which is the best part of this story.
Somebody pointed out that Lufthansa at one point was
trying to sell luggage that had built in tracking
stuff,
you know.
But actually if you read it, what Lufthansa did is they actually read a piece of,
they were like, oh, look at this piece of government regulation that says blah,
blah, blah.
And they were basically being weaselly
because
technically, yeah, it's a battery.
We,
we can't not have small batteries in luggage like
that just because everything electronic has a battery now.
And people travel with electronics.
-- I, I don't know if you've noticed, but that's the thing. Now in 2020 two
-- can you check.
No, I, when you have baggage you're not supposed to put lithium.
Well, they say lithium
ion, which Airtag do not have lithium
-- ion in them. They are the cr
-- 2032.
-- Yeah,
-- those, those, um, half cell batteries, they're, they're very safe and stable
and I, I've never heard of one even leaking. Much less catching on fire.
Yeah, exactly.
We should do an experiment. Can we make a nickel cell light on fire?
-- My guess is no, uh,
-- you can actually make them leak.
-- I accidentally put some in my charger.
-- That's a different problem.
That's not happening on an airplane.
-- But,
-- well,
but the thing is even then it just kind of leaked a bit but nothing happened.
So,
so I want to tie this back into security now because I think
this is an interesting parallel is how often in the world of security
do we see
someone say something like, oh,
that's not a vulnerability or we're not going to
-- fix this problem
-- or that's not allowed because.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. And then
they
go to the court of public opinion.
They are shamed immensely.
And then they're like,
oh, we were just kidding, we're going to fix that after all. And I feel like
this is so totally that story
that is literally how,
like
large companies like Google doing dumb things and
then getting called out on hacker news works.
And I love that when people point out that this is not a sustainable way,
you know, for example,
Google just turns off your developer account because some
reason that they won't tell you and they're like,
we can't tell you because then the spammers will know how to avoid the spam.
Yeah, I kind of get that but at the same time, like,
you know,
yeah, I
the,
it's,
there's this huge power imbalance between like Google and me
and yeah, if I can get maybe enough traction on hacker news or Twitter,
I can kind of get it fixed.
But that is not a sustainable way to do things and it's not,
it's not really fair. I feel.
Well, no, it's not.
And it's never been, I mean,
there's historically always been a massive power balance between,
we'll say large corporations and people
because,
yeah,
I mean, you look at nearly all regulation that exists from auto safety, food safety,
you know, any of that stuff,
these large corporations were taking advantage of people and often lying
and then eventually
the government had to step in and do something about it.
And in the case of tech and things like, you know, Google,
canceling developer accounts or putting air tags in your luggage.
It's gonna be really hard to get the government to care because generally speaking,
the government only cares when a lot of people get killed.
Well, and a great example of this is, for example,
like all those Uber and Waymo driver cars like messing up traffic in San Francisco.
Yeah.
You know, or that food delivery robot driving through a crime scene.
Right. Right.
And the cops are just like, what, like, and, and I was thinking, I'm like,
what do you do?
Like, do you stand in front of it to make it stop and then tip it over? Like, can you,
can you be like, halt robot? Like, let me talk to your human supervisor?
No, like, seriously, what do you do?
What's gonna happen is nothing
because the human response to
unknown situations
is we do nothing. We basically freeze in panic mode,
observe and report,
we observe for a while and by the time anyone understood what was happening,
the robot had probably exited the crime scene, right?
Is my suspicion on how that
that's basically what happened.
It's human nature.
When something ridiculous happens, we often just stop and stare, you know,
often with our mouth hanging open
and then it's like what now?
And I mean,
this is part of what makes like the security universe
so humorous is because like in an event starts happening
and then we're often just like
in shock and panic for some period of time
and then hopefully sanity takes over eventually, but sometimes it doesn't.
And I mean, that's where that's why having things like playbooks, for example,
where you like literally write down what to do is helpful because now
instead of staring and starting to do dumb things that don't make sense.
I can say, oh, I'm going to open a playbook
and I'm like, step one, don't panic. And then we go from
-- there.
-- Well, but, and the thing is I've been thinking is
there's going to be some fundamental changes in the next few years.
Companies don't react quickly to this stuff.
-- And so it catches them by surprise and scares them.
-- Ok, that's the key,
that's the key to this discussion I think is talking about
the reaction of companies
because
I think fundamentally
if we look at how most people react to new things, it's,
there's the Douglas Adams quote about what things that existed before
you were born are normal things that are invented before you're
like 30 you can make AAA career out of and then
everything after you're like 30 or 40 is an abomination.
And I think the thing to understand is a lot
of these companies have existed for a very long time.
And so if we look at it in that lens,
they're often seeing some of this change in progress as an abomination
because now they have existing process,
they have things that are working and you introduce change, change is hard
and some of them will accept it. Many won't and they'll fight against it.
And I think this is true of dealing with security vulnerability reports.
This is true of dealing with
-- air tags in your luggage. I mean, well,
-- what about putting air tags in your packages.
I'm, I'm kind of thinking about this now because, like, I know people that,
for example, you can buy a Mercedes car, like,
from Germany drive it on the test track and then they ship it over here
and,
like, I, I know cases where essentially the car has been lost, like,
not lost forever, but just
again, the classic, like, it's not lost.
We just don't know where it is and it's a
freaking car in a shipping container and it's like,
can't you put like a
couple $100 gps tracker on it
because I mean,
right, like to manage customer expectation and give them that little PAC man.
I, I guess ironically as part of that too is historically, there was no tracking.
So you just wouldn't know where anything is no matter what
because you gave the car to the shipping
company and then the shipping company gives you the
card back later in another place and you have
no idea what happened from there to there.
And we, we've become a bit spoiled in that regard.
And so for example, there's, there's like the, the,
the artificial avocado and artificial fruits
that they used to put through industrial
systems to see like where's the avocado getting bumped or smashed or banged
so that we can improve our process to like not smash up the avocados
or same thing for packages, right? Like how long have we had those G
shock stickers for packages that are sensitive or the tilt stickers, you know,
with the little beads in them that if the package tilts the
beads fall into a little chamber and can't come back out.
So, you know, if the package got tilted or not.
And so a great
this is like what happens
when we start putting like something that is a combination
of an airtag with a G shock with a,
you know, all the sensors, temperature,
whatever and start calling out shipping companies on their BS.
This brings us back to the
organizations dealing with change. I think if you have a package
and you put one of the tilt sensors on because
let's say it's some scientific equipment that can't be tipped.
And I get that because that exists.
Obviously, when you go to the shipping company,
the expectation is you're going to explain the situation to them and they're going
to charge you extra accordingly because now
they have to treat your package differently,
right?
And I think in the case of someone like Lufthansa,
the expectations of the customer have changed,
but the agreement between the customer and them kind of hasn't.
But at the same time, it's a very shaky agreement
because
the understanding is basically I buy a plane ticket,
I give you my bag when I get to where I'm going, you give me my bag back, right?
And that doesn't always happen. And then people get angry.
There's, well, there's no room for negotiation and there's no, uh, like,
I've actually had this happen where I've flown to Germany
and I get out and I wait
and my bag doesn't show up for like, two hours
and then it finally shows up and they're like, they give me some BS excuse.
And I'm like, did you guys put it in like the wrong cart or something? He's like, well,
yes, that's actually what happened, right?
Some, some baggage handler, like misread the tag, threw it in the wrong cart.
So it went to some other luggage hall,
went around the, you know, went for a ride on the conveyor belt got bored.
You're lucky it didn't go on in the wrong airplane, man.
I know right.
When it works, it works. But when it doesn't work,
there's this massive, well, what can I do? Nothing?
Actually,
you just reminded me of something and I want to bring this back to
Microsoft in the early two thousands when
they would deal with vulnerability reports.
Because any security researcher in the early two thousands know
that if you brought a vulnerability report to Microsoft,
they were basically going to do everything they could to discredit you because
you were the enemy and vulnerabilities
were a marketing problem from their perspective
and they would send lawyers and all sorts of stuff after you.
And I think that's an example of
if you think about the power imbalance Microsoft literally
had all the power in the early two thousands,
they were in charge of literally everything.
And if you didn't like it ha ha, too bad, there's nothing you can do.
But now you have these security researchers show up and this is I, I,
I'll put a link to Isaac Joseph Men, I think, wrote the cult of the Dead Cow book.
And he talked about a lot of this where
you have these groups of these like renegade hackers basically
that
they went out of their way to embarrass Microsoft.
It,
it turned into the power dynamic who flipped
around where all of a sudden you had these
random hackers
with all the power and Microsoft had none of the power
and that's not a situation they can be in.
So when you put someone like Mike, you know, old Microsoft in that situation,
they don't, you know, stop and reflect on what's going on around them. Oh goodness.
No,
they become a caged animal and they were lashing out
and they were acting completely just ridiculous in many instances.
And eventually
I think after the court of public opinion, plus just probably some amount of self
introspection,
they finally were like, ok, we need to change the way we're doing this,
but it took years, right?
This wasn't like, oh yeah, I guess you guys are right.
No,
the other problem is you can't treat Microsoft as
like some cohesive entity that has a belief system.
It's a pile of people who are competing
and jockeying for power and have conflicting visions of
what they want Microsoft to be and to do,
I mean, I think we can all agree that like Bill Gates,
Steve Ballmer and Satya Nadella very different.
CEO S
two of them did a pretty good job and one of them didn't,
one of them threw chairs,
the Lufthansa.
I,
I'm pretty sure the person running their Twitter account
doesn't have like a real strong opinion on this,
-- but they're being told what to say by somebody who,
-- of course they are, look,
I'm not going to give them a pass because they're a collection of people.
Well, what I'm saying is, it's like, it's not like people,
I think often view companies like the borg as
-- a, as a cohesive collective
-- and
-- I'm comfortable doing that. They're
-- not though, like, remember that time,
Sony Suit itself, that's their problem.
But what I'm trying to say is part of the, one of the problems here is that companies,
you know, you might have a new way of viewing the world,
but unless somebody really champions it, it's not going to happen,
-- but
-- that's normal, right?
Because
the world changes,
-- many companies don't and they stop being companies like
-- that's ok.
Oh, and somebody actually, sorry,
somebody pointed out on the Twitter thread that like, if you put like an, I watch
like an apple watch in your luggage,
-- that's a tracking device.
-- Is that, is that legal? Have they banned that I mean,
you know what that feels like?
That feels like the, did you ever read the,
the television typewriter story from the old, um, hacker folklore?
So, it was, I, I, I'll dig this up but there was, uh, according to legend, there was,
this was mit early days, like, you know, sixties,
there was, uh, one of the hackers was in the hospital
and his friends wanted to bring him a computer
and so they show up and the guards, like, what is that? They said it's a computer.
He's like, it's not on my list of approved devices. You can't bring it in.
And they were like, what he's like, here's my list
and they look at the list, it says television and typewriter.
They're like, oh, sorry, we meant it's a television typewriter.
He's like, oh, that's on the list. You can bring it in
and it's like,
I
guess,
and, and that's what that feels like where,
where the airline might say no air tags and you're like, oh,
but this is an Apple watch totally different
but whatever, whatever it is, what it is.
But anyway, anyway, I want,
I want to tie this all up before we run ourselves out of time.
I feel like the parallel I keep thinking of in this regard,
especially around security is that
there's all this change, especially,
it feels like there's more change than ever.
And I don't know if that's just because I'm getting old or
it's true.
Well, I think part of it is a combination of small batteries that work really well.
Access to the internet. Right.
All this stuff now has Bluetooth and Wi Fi built in because
it's like a five cent chip and you can have an operating,
like you can make an intelligent IOT device from scratch by yourself.
Like I have friends that have done this with uh what is it, those
eos 32 chips
like to make CO2 monitors and stuff for like,
like the whole thing with a 3d printed case, like 50 bucks out of pocket.
And obviously at scale it's going to be a lot cheaper.
But I think that's the secret is all of a sudden we've got batteries,
we've got internet access and we've got compute
and we've got software and software development kits
and you can build intelligent devices that can talk
to the internet and have all sorts of cool sensors
and you can build them like one off for less than 100 bucks and let alone at scale.
This changes the world.
It's like when cars went from being horrific death traps to like, yeah,
they just work,
just buy one.
Yeah. Right. Right. Right. So, so anyway, kind of trying to tie this all together.
Right. There's all this change. It's always interesting to me watching
how the change is embraced and how it's not embraced.
And I think especially in the world of security, I see this a lot where there's,
there's all these new ideas around the security universe, right?
Like some of the, the n
standards even, I'm shocked by how cutting edge they can be.
Like the, the, my, my favorite whipping boy right now is the SSDF,
the secure software development framework from this.
Like,
it's pretty good. It's not that bad.
And then you look at some of the other new things
you've got like salsa, you've got sig store, there's just,
there's so much happening
and some of it will work. Some of it won't like, we don't know which it is.
But fundamentally as, as security practitioners,
we have to understand what this is because if we try to
hold on to the way we did security even a year ago
that's ineffective and we're functionally
going to just, I, I guess
old person ourselves out of a job, you know.
Well, like the world changes.
So, you know, a good example of these,
these regulations talking about baggage tracking tags.
Well, when they were written,
baggage tracking tags had huge batteries and powerful radios and now
Bluetooth, low emission and like a tiny little cr 2032 battery.
Like it doesn't it, you know,
it's
what was envisioned as a problem no longer is,
well, but this is very common as well. I think
you see, like, like let's face it,
what Lufthansa did had nothing to do with regulation.
They just,
they didn't want to be embarrassed and they were trying
to use regulation for their advantage and we see that
in
all regulation where someone might not want change
and they will try to use regulation to hamper change.
And it, it literally never works right,
because eventually someone finds a way around it or the regulation gets
or whatever.
So I think trying to hamper positive change is always just,
it's a losing battle in almost every instance.
I mean,
I can't think of a single instance where
someone tried,
you know, enforcing change
-- and it failed because it's just, it's almost always
-- better.
That change is coming for a reason.
Usually because it's better, it's more efficient. It's more effective like
the horseless carriage
turns out,
you know, because here's the thing, if you park a car for a week
in a box,
it'll start in a week. If you put a horse in a box for a week and don't feed it.
You're probably going to jail now.
Maybe not nowadays.
Yeah.
No, I, right. But at the same time
you had no purpose to park your horse for a week because
I mean, when I park my car for a week,
I own horses, they go lame all the time and spend a week in the box just not moving,
standing there looking stupid because they, like they stepped funny on the ground.
-- I
-- mean, that could be, that's what I feel like.
No, like horses go lame, especially at competition. Like
I, like,
I've walked into a barn and seen a horse covered in acupuncture needles, like,
because it was getting therapy, like
horses go
-- all the time. That's not how
-- horses worked when they were tools. Like
you didn't, you didn't fix the horse, you sent the horse off to the glue factory.
If you had another horse you could just use instead.
But that's the thing, right.
So this change is obviously coming for a reason and yeah,
trying to push it back or trying to hold it back.
Well, if it's, if it's change, that is like, and again,
this is a perfect example of survivor bias, right?
Because we're talking about change that like happens.
There's a lot of change that happened and fizzled out
like
a great example like voice
condition back in the late nineties, early two thousands.
-- I bought a copy of Drake and dictate.
-- I remember that thing. Then it was
terrible.
It was garbage.
And now,
you know, I can say, hey, Siri, buy me a pony on Amazon
and like half of our subscribers are going to yell at us.
Let's hope, let's hope that's not a thing.
But
anyway,
and, and I mean, so my favorite example I'll use, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna pick on NFTS what?
Six months ago, NFTS were like the super hot thing and now everyone's like, whoa,
that didn't work out real good.
Yeah, it turns out that all these Ponzi schemes were Ponzi schemes.
We
knew
lots of people
that
don't buy them.
What's funny though is it didn't work? But the,
it would not shock me if in a couple of years we see a,
a practical use for the technology behind NFTS used in a reasonable way.
-- Oh,
-- we
absolutely will. With, with respect to, like, inventory tracking and stuff.
But it'll be boring corporate stuff like.
Right. Exactly.
Right. No one's gonna care, like tracking legs. Who cares?
I don't, I don't want to know that.
But anyway, anyway,
it's
luggage as NFTS and you pay and you own the luggage and
gives it
up.
Don't give them any ideas.
Seriously. Seriously. Don't,
it's, uh, whatever, whatever
flying already sucks. Actually, I just, I just went on a trip,
what, last week it was last week from the time we're recording. This is it,
I think it was
no kinds of a time anymore. But it was flying.
I mean, flying always sucked and it's just so much worse now.
I feel like, because all the, all the flights are super crowded.
People are grumpier than normal. I feel like, and it's just like, oh, man,
I have a friend who's flying to Vancouver and back and
first of all, they canceled both her flights, then they,
for a new flight
and then she's like,
but no return flight shows up on this thing.
I'm like, you probably need to call them because
in the past I would have just assumed like you paid
like
this person paid for a return ticket to Vancouver
and
like there's not been a refund. So like in Pao,
we've been like, yeah, for sure the airline will take care of you nowadays. I'm like,
I might wanna
really double check that
man.
Make
-- sure you're not on standby.
-- So, although one funny thing I've, I've, I've learned
so this is, it vaguely ties into this and then we'll, we'll end it.
I flew American Airlines, which I normally don't fly.
But they,
they were going to where I needed to go for the best times and the cheapest price,
I'm like, whatever.
I have no status left anywhere anyway. So, what do I care
at this point?
So,
Americans planes are pretty new now and back when I started flying a lot,
like 10 years ago, their planes were like the worst.
They were really old and they were, I didn't like them.
So that's why I didn't fly American ever.
And they're fairly new. And now
I, I was flying a lot of Delta and Delta has like the screens on all the seats,
right where you got like your little entertainment, whatever.
-- None of the new American flights
-- have that. Everybody brought their own screen.
That's right. That's right. And I'm like, wow, this is wild progress, right.
But at the same time,
how many millions of dollars did that probably save in the cost of that plane?
Because dude, the weight
that too, I suppose. Yeah, that's a good point.
People from, yeah, like, I don't like the, the,
the cost of the screen is mostly a one time upfront
charge because they're pretty reliable and don't need a lot of,
you know, ongoing maintenance and administration.
But the weight,
like, you add 100 pounds to a plane over the life of that plane. That's a lot of money.
-- More than
-- 100 pounds. I bet. I bet it's hundreds of pounds. At least
they each way. Yeah, a couple 100 seat.
Half a pound. Yeah. Anyways, the point is,
yeah, just, and the simplification you can make the seats thinner,
maybe cram in one more row of seats you can get no seriously,
like plane seats have gotten thinner and, you know,
if you can fit one or two more rows of people and that's one or 2% more profit.
This is why I'm glad I'm not like a giant person like you. I fit
when I get on my
-- plane,
-- we'll have to put that picture of Andre the giant in a plane.
-- Oh, yeah.
-- Yeah. You know where he's in, like first class taking up two seats. Right.
Right.
You know,
but
I think it's going to be interesting because as people
gain this, you know, ecosystem of tracking and sensing and
kind of telling the truth,
like what happens when my baggage has a little camera in it
to see if it's being abused or not like a drop sensor,
you know, like things like, like that guy that had to write that, you know, song,
like, uh I think it was American Airlines or Delta.
Why did you smash my guitar?
Like, he's, he's like sitting in the plane watching and he's filming the guy, like,
just smashing the bejesus out of his poor guitar.
You know,
he wrote a song.
It, it went viral on Twitter and, you know,
they finally got him a new guitar or whatever.
But again, that's not a sustainable model for, you know, the rest of us.
It's always been the model though.
Kurt, like the, the concept of making things go viral.
I mean, think about what is it, uh uh what was it? The book Unsafe at any speed
was, is credited with a lot of auto safety.
You had the, the, the guy who created the poison squad where they were,
he had these people like eating food.
Oh, this was, this is a US thing.
Kurt's looking at me funny like, I don't know what you're talking about.
I'll, I'll find, I'll dig it up and look.
But in the US, obviously,
our food safety was terrible at the turn of the century in the early 19 hundreds.
I can't say turn of the century because that was only 20 years ago.
Um in the early 19 hundreds.
And this guy created a group,
he called the Poison Squad where he was feeding them preservatives
and documenting how sick they were getting from this stuff.
And then his research led to a lot of the food regulations around, you know,
what's safe and what's not safe.
And,
and I think spectacle has been the only way that true change has been driven, like in,
in human history.
And I'd like to say it'll change, but I don't think it will. I think
like spectacle is what, how we're going to have to do a lot of the things we do.
And then eventually, if you get attention,
maybe someone who has the ability to actually create
-- the change will create the change so
-- well,
the reality is life has so many threats and problems
and
just things that don't work, right?
We kind of have to pick and choose which do we fix because there is,
that's true. There's an infinite number of problems.
They're not going away. All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Head up the show,
not Susie Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye
one.