Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 117 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser,
-- man.
-- You still don't sound very good.
Kurt. This is how it works for me though.
Is I get sick and the, the how sick I look and sound
is about 24 to 48 hours delayed behind how sick I actually am.
So my throat feels a little sore but like, you know,
I slept for like nine hours last night and
I, I feel great.
Ok, compared to like 24 hours ago,
I'll take your word for that.
Sweet.
All right, man. So, so I guess other than sick, what else is new?
Uh, well, I mean, I'm not even sure, kind of how to frame this, but, you know,
Linus Torvalds,
I guess you could say finally came out of the closet.
Maybe
I,
I feel like this is going to be sort of the,
I don't want to say scandal because it's not a scandal, but it's kind of the,
it's the big unspoken mess of
it in general. Let's face it,
you know.
Um, especially a lot of the open source world where it's kind of more exposed.
I,
I do agree and I guess for the sake of
posterity and anyone who maybe doesn't read the news.
So historically speaking,
the Linux kernel community and especially Linus has been, we'll say abrasive and,
and I use the word abrasive in quotes.
I was just about to say that it's funny because that's the word that we keep using.
And I feel like it's almost turned into one of those
terms of,
you know,
that's not what it really means though, folks, like,
it's quite a bit worse than that.
Let's face it. Linus is a dick.
I'm just saying
well, and, and, and more to the point though, it's not just Linus, it's,
this is an endemic
problem.
Yes, I agree. I agree.
So,
let's frame the Linus conversation first and
then we'll bring it elsewhere because I,
I'm totally guilty of this as well.
-- And
-- literally, and I'm not trying to
hijack that. Hashtag I just, I don't know. Me too. Like, literally,
I, I also have been a dick.
Yeah.
Right. OK. So anyway,
uh Linus has been a terrible person and he
basically finally sends an email that says I'm,
we just, we slow to,
I wouldn't say he's been a terrible person.
I would say he's a person who has had some terrible behavior.
Ok. That's fair. He's probably quite nice.
-- And in fact, that's, well, that's
-- something that,
that's another thing that's come up is, is a lot of these people,
one on one in person are actually quite reasonable human beings.
It's just
right.
Yes. I, I remember saying that a lot is, oh, I hung out with.
So, and so they're very nice in person.
I've now come to realize that's not OK.
-- It's just online professionally. They're a dick.
-- Right. Right. So, anyway, Linus.
Linus was quite mean
to the Linux kernel community and, and there's
a
and to be clear, this wasn't just a one time thing. This has been
like two decades
basically since Linux started.
And so anyway, he, he apparently due to a variety of reasons,
had a bit of a come to Jesus moment where he's realized
he's not acting very nicely and has decided to seek help.
And
I, I will say I'm slightly jealous of the fact that
this guy has the resources that when he decides he needs some help in this regard, he,
he can get it
right, because many of many of us can't.
Actually.
No, I, so the way I, I had similar issues were to be honest, I was a dick,
especially back in the, like we're talking 20 years ago
on Irc, you know, I was a dick.
I was mean to people, I was rude, you know, tough love and all that.
Luckily though I
had enough self awareness to realize I was being a dick and
it was also not a very fun thing to be a dick.
Like to, to basically just,
it's like being an asshole driver intentionally, like,
nobody actually wants to do that really?
Unless they're kind of crazy.
Uh Fortunately, I'm not super crazy.
And so for me, it was a combination of two things.
One, I backed away from the sort of environments in the places where that
behavior where I did that behavior a lot. So,
you know, to put it bluntly, it's like I stopped going to the bar
and then the second part was
is I, I actually
went out of my way to yeah, to learn some empathy.
Um
And when you say people lack the resources to it.
Uh There's a lot of places where you can go
learn about empathy for, for free or for very cheap.
And for example, one thing would be um
if you have any local Buddhist groups, right? Buddhism is huge about
suffering, right?
Life is about suffering and, and a major component of suffering is having empathy
and understanding that suffering and then
working to alleviate it, right?
So I, so I just, I mean, it, yeah,
it would be nice to be able to afford one on one therapy and you know,
uh behavioral talk therapy and whatnot.
Uh Yeah, and the reality is, most of us don't have like 200 bucks an hour to spare for
dozens of hours. But
uh there are a lot of because a lot of problems
and a lot of situations boil down to step one.
Empathy,
step two, understand empathy, having, helping you understand
the other parties in this. You know, I, I go through this with my ex-wife.
We don't get along,
but I try very hard to have empathy for her even when she drives me nuts
and, and
that's fair. It's,
it, it, let's, let's back up even a little more first
and, and
focus on Linus
and then, and then go from there.
And so he's, he's getting some help and then we're going to see where we go next. And
I have seen reactions to this
every which way you can imagine.
I actually haven't read any reactions.
I
saw quite a few and I,
I didn't even, I didn't look for them either. It was a lot of it showed up on Twitter.
Yeah, I don't read my Twitter feed.
That's one of the things I realize is just
I, I'm very selective about it.
I've created some lists that I use specifically for, for infosec stuff
which,
which I enjoy. But anyway, it showed up on there a lot and, and there was
a number, a lot of people were praising Linus and saying this is great. I'm also in a
similar situation or they might have said I've gone through this
before or I agree this is a problem and that's fair.
But then,
so here's,
here's the thing I struggle with and I don't know if I agree with this or not.
I also saw a number of people basically say
you can't say you didn't know you were being a
jerk because everyone should have some base level of manners.
And, and this is where I, I
remember being in situations like this and it's like,
I don't think you're wrong, but I think it's more complicated than that.
It's actually vastly more complicated than that because let's start with,
are you neuron
nom
or not?
Because there's a lot of neurotypical people, for example,
on the autism scale or on the Asperger's scale
where? Yeah. No, they don't know that they're being an asshole.
They, they just don't,
their brain isn't wired to know that. It's like
I have a son who's high functioning autistic and
there are certain things that his brain is just
not wired up to understand or know or to comprehend in the same way that we do.
And it's, he's not trying to be a jerk. It's just
um he, for example, doesn't really, he doesn't understand personal space.
All right.
And he's also a twin.
So he's, he's grew up in his entire life with this person where he,
you know, him and his twin brother, ha don't his twin brother who's neuron
nom of also has problems with personal space
in the sense of he's not used to it,
right? Because he's used to this person who literally,
you know, they share food like they share drinks, they
they
dog pile each other and it's just no big deal, you know.
Um So that, that would be my first question is, is, you know, what is the
sort of, what's the underlying
basis or what's the underlying stuff around this behavior? Right?
It may be that the person is
not neurotypical
and they,
if they have asperger's or autism in some cases,
they lack those filters or they lack those capabilities to,
to process like, oh, is that person smiling or like making an angry face at me?
Like there's people on the autism spectrum who literally
learned that by like
having flash cards
interesting
and like memorizing.
OK, smile is corners up, frown is corners down.
-- That's
-- no iii I think that's really fair.
And actually you saying this, it, it, I I'm getting flashbacks too. I remember
I was, I was doing a group project one time a really long time ago
and I, I keep
now, I guess just
to start, I'm,
I've never been diagnosed with like Asperger's or autism or anything.
It would not shock me
if, if I went in,
I was,
but
I remember dealing with,
with groups at one point where I would say things and they're like,
how can you say something like that?
And I was thinking, what, what's wrong with that?
And I remember that the one that always sticks with me is there was someone
who was working at the company I was at
that had like one eye that always pointed off in the wrong direction.
And someone said, well, well, who's so, and so I said, oh, he's the guy with the,
the goofy eye that points off in the corner.
-- Yeah, Josh, you can't say
-- that. And that's the thing.
I'm like, what's wrong with that? That's like that, that's who he is.
-- It's factually
-- correct.
It's totally factually correct.
-- This is where
-- I have a problem I acknowledge because part of me is like, well, yeah,
but that is factually correct and quick and efficient.
What more do you want?
Like to this day
in my brain, I don't see a problem describing someone like that, but I know I can't
because I've, I've learned through, through many years of,
of interacting and reading books and getting yelled at that.
There are certain things you don't use to describe a person even if they are true.
And you know, part of that is, is
for some of these people on the,
that are not neurotypical or even for people that are neurotypical,
sometimes it boils down to
fake it till you make it and you may never make it. You may just be faking it. Like
I literally had a boss at one point who was definitely on the on a spectrum, you know,
and he literally once was like,
so this is the part of the conversation where
I'm supposed to ask you how you're doing.
Although I don't really care and I'm like,
I appreciate your honesty and I appreciate that you actually are
going through the motions of asking about how I am and,
you know,
and I, I understand that for you this, yeah, you,
you really fundamentally don't care,
you know, it's like a, it's like cat levels of antipathy towards people, you know.
But yeah, so back to Linus and so
I, I, you know, it's like any problem, step one, recognizing you have a problem.
I agree.
And, and I think ignoring the, the,
the past behavior he should have known and I'm not going to argue whether he should
or shouldn't have or did or didn't or any of that because it doesn't matter.
And, and I think
that's the most important point.
People sometimes don't realize when you're in a situation like this
is,
you can't keep digging up the past, the past,
doesn't matter what you need to focus on is the future.
And he said, I want to get better.
So that's the conversation and that's the thing we need to focus on. Like, for real.
Yeah.
Well, the challenge is a lot of people are very hurt potentially from these actions.
And,
you know, I mean, I've dealt well and I've, I've,
I'm dealing with, you know, professional organizations where
in some cases,
some members of these professional organizations have behaved so badly
that, um,
we voted them off the island.
Uh, and this is after things like other companies saying
these people are no longer allowed to talk to our
people if they need to talk to our people.
Here's our point of contact in our legal department,
right?
And,
and this isn't like
about legal stuff. This is about just this.
These people being so fantastically rude and abusive.
That's wild man. Iii I get it.
I have a filter for open BS d.org I don't accept email from them after the second time.
They were so abusive to me that my
twice in my career uh and this is like 15 years apart.
I've dealt with the Open BS d.org.
People tried to be helpful towards them and they've been
so abusive that even my manager stepped in and said,
Kurt, you don't have to talk to them.
They can talk to me.
I was like, you know what? No, it'll be fine.
But yeah, this,
there's a couple of key members in the open BS D org community that are,
are infamously known for being abusive
and
I suspect that's actually one of the reasons open BS D I mean,
it's still plugging along but
fundamentally like,
yeah, it's not that healthy anymore.
II, I agree with you.
I mean, I,
I remember interacting with a handful of them a
really long time ago and it was just like,
I, I don't like this, this isn't cool.
They were
because I remember it was Irc and stuff and people were just,
they weren't nice and helpful and that's
because I remember I got into Linux
and then I started learning about, you know,
everything going on in free software and open BS D.
I thought, wow, this is awesome. Like this is something I really want to do.
And I remember I bought CD si,
remember when you bought C DS
and they did,
they came with cool stickers and they had a cool logo for every version like, yeah,
I'm gonna, I'm gonna get into Open BS D and
after a couple of months I gave up because I said this is not a place I want to be.
Yeah, I think it was around version
2.12 0.2. I just went never again.
And even though I really like Open BS D had some really amazing capabilities,
I was using that, Linux still doesn't really have
anything comparable to like the firewall fail over stuff.
You know. Open BS D has been doing that for like a decade now trivially.
And I was like, no, I'm literally,
this is what made me really quite sad. Open BS D is quite a good set of software tools
but the community I found so painful to deal with
it made it not worth it.
Yeah, totally.
And, and this is one of the other things I'm wondering is if Linus starts being nice
-- is the Linux community going to explode?
-- Linus doesn't even have to be nice.
He just has to be not mean,
nice would be great. But,
like, frankly, no, I mean, like a lot of these communities,
they don't have to be nice. They just have to not be mean and nasty.
Just be neutral.
-- Professional. Literally just be professional,
-- really low bar.
Yeah. And yet here we are
and, and I feel like the security community is totally guilty of this as well.
I mean, I, I remember back in the day
when people would make a security mistake and it's like it was on, I mean,
we were terrible to them,
you know, well, like Troy Hunt, for example, just wrote an article about, you know,
the value of publicly shaming companies.
And
it's interesting to me because
specifically he's talking about
companies, not people, but companies and see and, and that's one of those sort of,
to me, one of those dividing lines, right?
Like
I think it's fine to,
you know, when, for example, when Linna says, like
you and Vidian holds up his finger, I I would say, uh as directed towards a company
that was quite fair actually,
but had he directed that towards actual specific NVIDIA developers or anything,
then I would have said, no, not cool.
And that's one distinction to make is, is
again, we're not talking about, you know,
everybody being super polite and nice all the time to everything and everybody.
No, but we're, we're talking about like a basic level of professionalism, you know,
no more ad hominid attacks.
Let me ask this then is Linus
calling all security people masturbating monkeys acceptable,
whether it's true or not.
I
don't think it's acceptable. And I also, I was about to say, I also don't think he's,
I don't think he's actually that far from wrong on that one.
I think part of the problem is, and this goes to the empathy piece.
For example, if you ask me about my thoughts on that comment, I would say,
I think Linus is correct and I also think the security people are correct.
And I also think Linus is wrong and I also think the security people are wrong
because it's a complicated question
with multiple viewpoints and multiple own versions of reality
that are correct for those people, but maybe not correct for other people.
You know, a security person might be willing to make the trade off of, oh,
I don't mind a crash once in a while as
long as nobody gets into our back end account system
and cleans out our bank.
Linus's viewpoint is Linus's
Linux rather is running on everything at this point.
And even if we only break one in a million devices, that's like a
kajillions light bulbs.
So Linus really has this thing about stability and safety and
not breaking stuff, which I totally get that, that's a very valid worldview.
Um
You know, and
for example, maybe he needs to have a bit more empathy with the security people
and not necessarily do what they want but maybe understand
what and why it is that they want these things
and maybe together they can find a better solution
or maybe they can't, I don't know because honestly some of these problems are so hard
that there is no
quote unquote good solution. There's just like the least worst set of trade offs.
Right.
Well, and I think historically,
security people have been really bad at accepting
tradeoffs because we love perfect or nothing.
Nothing always wins
pretty much. Yeah, here we are.
So, you know, and,
and I think that's a basic part of empathy is not just empathizing with the, the human
but trying, you know,
one thing I would love to see from hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy
is the point of perspective or was it point of view gun?
Right?
Remember that gun and it, it forced your enemy to see things from your perspective.
And I thought
that's actually a really clever weapon
because everyone's the good guy
-- in their own personal narrative.
-- Exactly.
So, yeah, I know, I think empathy is stage one, you know,
not only for seeing these humans as humans and maybe
treating them a little less terribly and more professionally,
but then also to understand, you know,
well,
why, you know, why are they saying these crazy things? Why,
you know, there's a lot of people who engage with
communities that a lot of us find
not very pleasant or in some, in some cases, very despicable,
you know, like the far right neo Nazi movement, I'm like,
didn't we establish in like the 19 forties that this is not a good ideology?
I thought we covered this, you know,
and yet here we are today,
right? OK.
So you have a really good point that I was actually just
about to ask you about is so let's say Linus stops being terrible
to people in email,
but you have to draw a line somewhere because let's face it if,
if somebody shows up and is like, I want to talk to you about, you know,
pushing a far right agenda in the Linux kernel.
He's not going to say, oh, let me sit down with you and understand what you want.
He's going to be like,
no,
right.
And I think that's OK.
Well, there's, I'm of two minds of that on the one hand, yeah, it's like I,
this is the reason I just stopped all contact
with the open BS D community because it's like,
I don't want to deal with these buggers
on the flip side though is unless we engage with these people and, you know,
to court Jordan B Peterson for which I'm going to be probably labeled far, right?
But to quote Jordan B Peterson,
unless we tell these people a better story and pull their heads out of their butts,
you know, I'm paraphrasing his quote.
But basically, unless we help educate these people and, and
convince them of
what is better in some cases, like, objectively better,
how, how are we going to bring them out of the craziness that they're in?
I, and, and on the flip side I totally get,
I don't want to be that person because Holy Keck, I do not get paid for that.
Right. Right. I think,
I, I guess this might be the next challenge now. Right.
Is, so, I think the days of being terrible to everybody are,
are probably coming to an end.
I won't say they're over,
but I think they're coming to an end.
And I also think this is going to be a rough patch for
security folks because we are notorious for being difficult in this regard.
But I guess here's, here's the thing I wonder then is
so if we're not mean to people and let's face it.
Part of being mean, drives large groups away and, and you, of course,
get many reasonable people in with the crazy people and let's face it.
If you've ever been involved in open source,
you've run across crazy people who want to do
bizarre things for like, literally no good reason.
And, and it's like, I don't want to deal with you anymore. I mean, I,
and I remember dealing with some people back in the day that, like, thought
CV E was a government plot and, and they were, and it's,
oh, my goodness, just go away.
I've been accused of having CV E powers and using them for evil and I'm like,
I have powers and I can use them for evil.
How can I monetize this? Right. Yeah.
Yeah, that was my second question.
But anyway, so, so here's, here's the question is, let's face it,
the bad attitude drove away many people
and, and if we, if we don't have no note, I'm not justified bad attitude,
most of
them
permanently Because you know what? Even if
-- they're
-- never coming back,
even if we were handing out free hugs and cupcakes, they'd be like, yeah, no,
you're probably going to shove that cupcake in my notes.
And I think this is going to be Linus's
challenge now is convincing people that he's actually changed.
Well, first of all, he has to actually change, which I'm not,
I'm not convinced that's going to happen.
-- It's bigger
-- than that though. It's not just no offense.
The Linus, the Linux community is not just Linux,
-- totally,
-- he definitely
to some degree can set the tone
and what is and is not generally acceptable.
But
uh
you know,
these people following him, they also have free will and they can also choose
a variety of different behaviors.
And so I think it's great that Linus, hopefully from the, from the sort of
the, the helm of the ship is steering it a bit,
but fundamentally, you know, hopefully everybody else gets on board with this too
and they have a code of conduct
-- that they're implementing and, and that should help
-- clarify
the
one.
I don't know which one it is.
I don't know if I haven't looked to see if it matches anything else but, but whatever,
here's, here's my point though
is
if we're going to be nice professionals,
how do we deal with people who are coming in
and being unreasonable? Not, not on purpose necessarily,
but like if, if somebody wants something and it's in the past,
Linus would have told him to f off.
But now what do you do? Right. How do you tell someone in a nice way?
Like go away, you're an idiot.
So part of it would be, is to have them state their case
professionally and clearly and if they can't, they can go away.
Right? So I think we should do X
OK. Why state of business case? State what's,
you know, we're making changes in the CV world and,
and a lot of these changes also boil down to, well,
why do we need this? What do we need this for?
Is there actually a reasonable business case, you know, a need for this?
Can you state it clearly and if they're not willing to do that work, then I,
I would say you probably aren't really required to,
to listen to them.
So a part of it boils down to is, is meeting these people halfway.
That means they also have to come halfway.
So if we're going to behave professionally and politely and nicely.
I would, I would expect that standard from them.
And for example, if they,
you know, are just incredibly rude and abrasive and abusive, I would,
I would ask them
to not be,
I would say, you know, we're, we're trying to be a professional community.
Here's our code of conduct.
If you actually want to get involved, a, you have to sign off on this
and I'm actually look like I'm pushing right now on some CV, working groups
to make that a requirement. You know, we'll have our contributor code of conduct,
uh you know, www dot contributor
hyphen covenant.org.
If you're not willing to kind of sign off on that, then, well, thank you. But goodbye.
You know, if you can't and,
and we're not talking like this is not a very high bar to set this thing.
And then secondly,
assuming they're willing to behave like a somewhat rational human being,
you know, have them state their case, maybe they have a case,
maybe they don't have a case.
Uh part of it too would be, you know,
is this something that's been asked and refused multiple times in the past?
Maybe for a good reason,
you know,
and maybe they're being somewhat unreasonable or maybe
the circumstances have changed and now it is
less unreasonable or maybe it is entirely reasonable.
Ok. I, I,
like what you said,
I think that that makes perfect sense and I guess here's the other half of it is.
I'm, I'm thinking back to when we talked to Steve Mazak about selling security.
If you have a pushy sales person
that doesn't want to leave you alone, like all you owe them is a,
I'm not interested. Thank you.
And then you never have to reply to another male of theirs again.
And I guess that's the way open source is going to
need to be is if somebody shows up and says,
oh, I want to, you know, I want to do this crazy thing.
You can say
no, thank you.
-- And like that's literally all you
-- forgot. Option B, you forgot.
Option B which is great. You go do that.
They have the source code, they can fork it. I mean,
no, I'm serious.
I'm just saying that there is,
there is a rather significant option B where we can be like
to put it bluntly,
there's a lot of cases where I've
seen somebody propose something crazy and everybody proposes
it and then they go and do it and show it and then we're like,
oh, we were really wrong.
That is a cool feature
and that's fair.
But I don't even think that's option B I think if you're the one told to go home,
that's your
-- not
-- the
-- project.
I'm just saying when we tell people to go away,
we're not actually fully excluding them like other
situations, right?
Open source is a unique situation in which we can tell you,
we don't want to play with you,
but we're not going to actually exclude you. Here's the source code. Go nuts with it.
Is true. Right. You can go do your own thing.
Um, and this has happened, you know, Oracle, but son,
uh, what was it called before it became Fork Jenkins. Travis. Travis C I.
Right.
And the community generally didn't agree with Son and oracle and Son and oracle,
I guess, didn't agree with the community.
So that begat Jenkins and Jenkins one,
you know,
and so that, to me is sort of one of those safety valves of
just because we told these people to go away doesn't
mean if they actually turn out to have like a
really good idea and be correct and we're all wrong
because we have some weird old view of the world.
You know, we don't run that risk of completely losing it. Right.
Yeah, that's fair. And there's, I know there's a handful of examples like that too.
Yeah,
because one of the,
one of the challenges with these kind of group
politics and dynamics is when you start excluding people.
Well, hey, yeah, we,
there's a lot of stuff in the world with histories of
excluding people and we all know where that has ended,
ended up,
you know,
to put it bluntly, it is
like, what 90% white males
in
-- America?
-- It's, it is really bad.
I, I agree with that. And that's
diversity is like a whole another topic.
But I do think this is going to be part of that conversation because
we, we scare people away
and, and
I think,
I, I don't,
I'd like to say, I don't think anyone does it on purpose but I think most people don't.
So, at the Cloud Security Alliance we've actually had to,
um,
how do I say this politically and without getting in trouble,
um, there are some cases now where we have female staff
who, when they send out email announcements don't do it from their person, like,
from their accounts that are labeled as such,
-- uh, because of the abuse problems we've had,
-- I've,
I've heard of things like that or I heard there was
a,
it was, I don't remember it was job interviews or VC or what it was,
but there's a woman who, like,
had her own email address and she created a fake mail account
and the male one got, like,
three times as many responses than the female one did.
-- And it's like, ah, man,
-- well, they did the thing with the chat bot,
the, the support chat bot on a website. We'll have to find a link to that. But
they, I think they tried with a female male and, like, a neutral avatar or something.
And like, yeah, no, the female one got a horrendous amount
and it's not just that they get abused but it's the type of abuse they get,
they get stuff that,
-- uh, if somebody said that to my face, I would call the police.
-- It's, it's horrible.
I agree. And I,
man,
people suck.
That's, well, the problem is only, you know, if, even if it's only like,
0.01% of the community,
but if 0.01% of humanities decides to start spitting on your shoes
or on everybody's shoes, you know, that's,
-- that's going to be a really unpleasant world to live in
-- it.
It is true. And this is, I'm, I'm hopeful.
The,
the current wave of change I'm seeing continues because I think
it will be for the best at the end of the day
versus some of the things that have happened in the past. And now,
uh what was it?
John Oliver has a show and he, he actually, he talked to Anita Hill who was,
uh it's a long story but it's related to current events essentially.
And basically we thought in the nineties things were going to get better
and they didn't.
And we're there again and it's like, I hope it sticks this time.
-- They
-- got a little bit less worse.
-- It kind of, I
-- mean,
people with alternative, well, quote unquote, I don't,
I don't know what the term to use.
The LGBT Q community,
people who are alternative to the mainstream are no longer
us downtrodden.
That's,
I mean, there's a long way to go and I guess this is ok this is how we're going to end it.
And, and I think you've just hit on a very important point that,
that especially as white males in society,
we, we get stuck on is,
it's better than it used to be, is what we say. Right. But this is,
-- that is not how you measure
-- progress.
It's
worse
and
it's even, right. Less worse. Right. It's like, what is it?
JWZ has the famous quote of suck less is in progress
and sucks less is where we're at.
Right. It sucks less, but it still sucks. And I think that's the thing
we need to be very,
uh, uh aware of
and we need to make a point of making sure we
don't become complacent just because it sucks less for other people.
Doesn't mean it's getting better the way it needs to get better.
And I think it is sometimes easy to fall in the trap of saying,
well, it sucks less. That's good enough. I'm, I'm good now. Right.
It's, it, that is not the way it is. Do not think
you're doing the right thing
ever.
Always strive to be better. Right.
Yeah. Well, and ultimately, yes, strive to be better. Strive to do better.
Agreed.
-- There
-- we go.
And, and I guess I will commend Linus for striving to be better and I truly,
truly hope it sticks
well, not just for him but for everybody,
you know,
you can
inspire
some
-- people that
-- too. That's that's a good point.
Let's hope, let's hope many others take his example and, and they run with it. So
awesome, man. This has been,
well, probably a little different than most of our conversations,
but I do think it's a super important topic and I'm glad we talked about it
so.
Well, that's a big part of it. Right.
There's so many things that just used to not be talked about at all and still, I mean,
things like the words like neurotypical and neuro, you know, non neurotypical.
-- Those are new words for a lot of people. I know they were for me,
-- right?
They, they're new to me. I'm not going to pretend they aren't.
It's, it's not something I've dealt with in the past. So
thank you for educating me.
Thank you.
I will say thank you everyone for listening.
Thank you, Kurt.
And you can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes,
you can use the Pound Os s podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
then. Yeah, I guess uh just let's, let's keep trying to make sure that sucks less.
Isn't our version of progress? Thanks, Kurt.
-- Thank you, everybody.
-- Alright, bye bye.