Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 180
-- with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh
-- Pressers.
-- Yeah, 180 is definitely not prime. How is
-- it? Because it ends in a zero?
Sure, that seems fair.
But it's, I think it's still technically qualifies as quasi
-- prime because it doesn't have too, too many factors
-- not talking about this anymore.
No, we, we had a lengthy discussion of what quasi
prime means prior to hitting record and I understand
less now than I did before we started talking.
So we will not subject anyone to that conversation. So anyway, how are you doing?
Good, good, a little cold. But you know, that's life in January.
That's right. When you, when you live in the Arctic circle, like it gets cold.
-- Who
-- knew
my,
my only real concern right now is the uh the Alberta Energy
Systems Operation Group is uh forecasting 100 and 1% energy demand tonight.
What does that mean?
Well, it means you have
100% of energy production
and they're forecasting 100 and 1% demand.
Yes. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for
so it means you better turn some lights off
otherwise there might be some brown oats or blackouts.
-- Oh,
-- so people just don't get power is what happens the
last time. Ok.
As far as I know, there's never been like, like there's been,
I've had power outages but, you know, due to squirrels, that kind of thing, right?
Like local power outages or, you know, like a substation poops itself and
whatever,
but not, you know, like, um, remember the old, a couple decades ago, the, the,
the California rolling blackouts due to
Enron manipulating the energy market there.
I said it, we all know
they had that like months ago because of fires.
Oh, and the fires? Yeah. Well, no, no, no.
That was because they wanted to prevent causing more
forest fires because they've cheaped out on their maintenance.
And so in the wind, apparently when it gets windy there,
all the recruitment sparks and starts forest fires, which is fantastic.
So,
no, here it's just simply put, demand is really,
really high because it's currently, oh, it's actually up to minus 33 now.
Wow, it's warming up.
Holy cow.
So fun. Fact for everyone listening
minus 40
is the crossover point for Celsius and Fahrenheit.
So if it's minus 40 where you're at, you can just say it's minus 40
you don't have to explain if it's Fahrenheit or Celsius. It's
sad.
-- What about
-- Kelvin
man? Like
whatever
-- minus 40. Kelvin is it? There's not a minus 40
-- Kelvin. Exactly.
That's the whole point. That's the
-- joke is
-- there though. I don't know. I don't know.
Maybe there is. Maybe, I don't know
because my understanding was absolute zero was absolute zero.
-- Maybe, I don't know.
-- This, that was kind of the whole point of absolute
zero. Like you hit zero. There's, that's, it's absolute.
-- So why can't you have negative temperature?
-- Oh,
ok.
Yeah. No, six years ago, quantum gas glow goes below absolute zero.
You know, remember as a kid when there were like four states of matter, right
gas, liquid solid plasma, it was like OK plasma. Oh Fancy. And now I think there's 27.
-- I,
-- I have no idea. I don't, I don't keep track anymore. I've,
it amuses me but I,
I also recognize that
the
world has moved on so far beyond my level of understanding that
yeah, whatever,
whatever fine.
It's kind of like, you know what it always reminds me of is colors.
I have like six colors in my vocabulary.
So
people are talking
about,
oh it's just
blah. But you know the the a Taupe is my favorite.
I don't even know what Taupe is supposed to be.
-- But isn't that
-- what you get when you mix all your play
-- together?
-- I have no idea.
But
it's one of those things that I have like the the
primary colors mostly and if you start using other words,
I'm like I
explain it to me in one of the following six colors, please.
-- I don't know what you mean.
-- Taupe is gray with a tinge of brown
and then there's like pictures of khaki and cobblestones.
And I'm like, I don't think either of those are Taupe.
So it's brown, maybe tan, tans in my vocabulary.
But that's what I feel like sometimes when I start reading about
all of the
just crazy physics stuff that's been happening is
I have a primary color vocabulary and they're
off inventing the Crayola 6000 colors and I have no idea what's going on anymore.
And I just like, I want a blue crayon. Please
hand me.
I remember what color Taupe is. It's named after moles in
the word for Mole in French is uh uh I can't pronounce it properly
-- in
-- no way. Does any of that information help me? Moles
are like a dark brown
-- because they live in the dirt. So it's basically the color of dirt.
-- But I'm
now I have to remember the French word for male to remember the color of a thing.
I can't whatever this is dumber than my
question
during French lessons in school. Oh, wait, you don't. Oh, yeah. No. Do you guys?
Hey, there's a question. Do you have like a mandatory second language typically?
Oh,
no, I actually took French when I was in high school and I learned very little.
So I would say
I have no functional French vocabulary.
That's fair.
Me too.
You, you live in a country where French is one of the,
the, the languages
of
the
two
languages.
And in fact, in the United States, we don't have an official language. So, go figure
that seems like a very American thing to do. It's just understood
American
or something. I don't know.
Anyway. All right, we should move on. This is
as fun as this is
related to. This is how the world has changed. We've got two
apparently pretty serious security vulnerabilities,
one from Microsoft and one from Citrix
and,
and I think the handling of these security vulnerabilities by
the two vendors literally could not be any more different.
I,
you keep
OK, so I'll, I'll fill the,
I just wanted to complain about Citrix
today because I think that the whole thing is a circus,
but Kurt insists on also talking about the Microsoft thing and
I'll let it go.
But just so, you know, it's the,
the Microsoft handling so far has been relatively benign and understood.
I think there was the what the minor leak a little beforehand but whatever, well,
-- the
-- leak of its existence because apparently what Microsoft was doing
is they consider this flaw so bad.
So it's a flaw in the crypt 32 dot DLL,
apparently something to do with ECC certificates and you can spoof them,
which actually is a show we're going to do some other day about, you know,
why crypto is so hard to get.
Right.
But anyways, spoofing ecc certificates is obviously pretty bad,
especially if you're, you know, relying on them heavily.
And apparently Microsoft shipped the security patch to some governments,
like probably the US government and maybe some other allies
and, uh, some large companies in advance,
which is probably how that kind of leak happened.
Right. Because,
well, let's put it bluntly right.
If you know, you tell two people it's not a secret anymore.
Yes. That is completely fair.
But on the flip side, they managed to keep it pretty quiet.
Like it's only within the last day or two that it started brewing.
Krebs
leaked it more than a day early and
-- I mean, who knows what he knew? But he
-- didn't leak any actual information
-- other than we know it's a crypto flaw.
-- Here's my take on that is don't tell anyone
because like you said, they're going to leak it.
But then how do you ship the patch early?
Right. It's one of those things
if you tell people and in fact,
there were people on Twitter who got this right
where before? Because basically
what, what was said was it, it's basically affects all windows from 2015 to now
and someone looked back and, you know, they added in 2015,
they added ECC encryption in 2015.
They were like, oh, it's probably something to do with ECC
and it's like,
it, it always reminds me, I forget which one it is, there was a security flaw,
one of the http
21 dot something TLS. Not att my brain.
One of the TLS one dot Something attacks.
It was like beast or one of those where
basically someone gave a little bit of info on Twitter
and a security researcher was like, oh, I bet it's this. And it was exactly that.
Well, part of that though is Survivor bias and that there's,
there's been a lot of speculation and if there's enough,
if enough people buy lottery tickets, one of them will win,
it's not that
people buying lottery tickets are all picking winning numbers.
I don't know, Kurt, that's not what those commercials say.
True.
But, um,
but no, I think, I think in general it looks like Microsoft, you know,
handled this reasonably well.
They got, uh, the patch out. Um,
it didn't really leak too, too much and, you know, now it's Microsoft Tuesday patch,
Tuesday and everybody's
patch in the
side
of
it.
That's fair. And let's frame this against Citrix
because the Citrix
-- flaw
-- remind me, when is that patch coming out for Citrix again? Is it
they took
at
the end of January and we're currently in
the middle of January recording this episode.
So we'll see, I guess.
And,
and that's only for some of the versions, the other versions will follow later.
Yeah, it looks because the, the, the, the firmware affected is 1011, 1213.
You know, that's,
oh, and
gateway, gateway firmware net scaler.
Like it's a big pile, like it basically looks like pretty much
-- all of their code.
-- So, let's explain this though. So, here's what happened.
Basically, Citrix
has a security flaw
that allows for unauthenticated remote code execution,
which as far as security flaws go is basically like the, the worst.
-- There's not,
-- that's the holy grail for Attackers. Yeah,
-- exactly
-- two things.
Number one, you can easily scan the internet for vulnerable systems or number two,
you can just spam the attack out.
Right. Right. Like once you have working exploit code, you're good to go. Right.
And so essentially what happened was
this flaw became known
and
Citrix released
instructions to mitigate it, but their instructions are monstrous.
My understanding is the mitigation also isn't 100%.
I don't know any details about that.
But if you, I'll put a link to the mitigation instructions in the show notes,
they're enormous.
It's funny because in some ways the flaw is really stupidly simple,
but because it's sort of one of those stupidly simple flaws,
actually fixing it will be kind of a nightmare.
And it's literally a dot dot Path traversal.
Uh Right. That's it. Like you literally go and ask for VPN slash dot dot slash VPN
and it goes, oh, ok. You want the contents of the VPN directory? Cool. Yo,
that's it, folks. Sorry,
I just gave it away.
-- But
-- then there's another flaw
-- that lets you write files.
-- Yeah, exactly. So, yeah.
Well, the thing is you can get access to that VPN S directory or VPN directory,
whatever it's called.
And, yeah, and then you can, I mean, it's just so ridiculous that,
like, in this day and age, first of all, there shouldn't be a path traversal flaw.
Right. That stuff should be normalized before it goes to Apache and a path serves it.
That's
like,
like, haven't we been doing with saying that for 20 years?
Well, I mean, look, that's easier said than done.
I mean, people make mistakes and look, I'm not going to argue
whether this flaw should or shouldn't exist
-- because it does
-- basic fuzzing would catch this
basic http fuzz.
-- It
-- is irrelevant because I think talking about the source of the flaw
takes away from the response Citrix
has had to this because it has been atrociously bad
when you have a critical flaw in your product.
I think taking a month to get a fix out is
that is terrible, especially one of this magnitude.
And the best part is I'm looking through the workaround. It's actually reasonably
straightforward.
You add a responder to the web server to handle those dot dot things and you know,
make sure they don't get to the server.
But more of the point can't that at least be like usable
in an automated sense then like here's a web page with instructions,
I would think.
I mean, I agree with that's the first thing I thought of was why isn't this a script?
But then part of me also wondered,
is it not a script because it's
fragile or is there the potential to like, ruin something between steps?
Like I, I don't know it,
I agree though. It feels like why this should be a script you download and run.
Yeah.
And it's smart enough to detect what version of whatever thing you're
running like you have one script you just run because I mean,
remember when we were at Red Hat,
Red Hat started doing some scripts like this for someone,
I don't think they were fixing scripts but they were detection scripts for.
What was it? One of the intel ones, I think
uh for
-- a, a number of things.
-- Yeah.
And you know, I mean, it's not
easy but at the same time it's not rocket science
-- and it's
-- hugely useful because you do have people, I mean, look,
even if Citrix had a patch ready on day one,
there's going to be people who can't upgrade immediately, right.
And I mean,
part of the problem as well is that so they announced
it was an issue and then a couple of days later only
somebody had created an exploit, you know, a functional exploit for this.
And at that point like game over pretty much,
I don't know what their thinking was here.
If,
if they thought maybe it's not as bad as it is
or if they thought people wouldn't develop exploits for it.
One thing I've noticed
and I think it's sort of against survivor bias.
The kind of company that would have this kind of
flaw is also the kind of company that would think,
oh, these security flaws, they're really difficult and tricky.
-- Nobody's going to figure it out.
-- I
-- mean, maybe that's not unreasonable
-- because looking at this flaw, it's like, wow,
that's super simple.
-- Like this is not,
-- right?
This is not, you know, some 20 or well, not 20.
This is not some like five page email from a security vendor saying like, OK,
so in the Linux kernel when it's a full moon and
you plug in your USB and you know this blah,
you know what I mean? It's not one of those flaws
-- where it's complicated.
-- It's, those are my favorite. Yeah.
You know, it's, it's literally dot dot Path traversal with, yeah, like a file,
right flaw.
And then the thing just, it runs stuff that you tell it to
with privilege
like
that. That's it. That's
I've just described them like I've given you enough information that
you can go look at this product and write an exploit.
Well, and you know,
what else probably makes this really bad is I bet in a lot of
environments they poked a hole through the firewall to let the Citrix traffic in.
Yeah, you have to, right. If you want remote workers and the whole I mean.
And that's,
and that's part of the problem is like the
whole premise of a lot of these Citrix products is
you want to give quote unquote air, quote, finger wiggles secure quotes here,
secure access to your internal systems,
you know, presenting them so that, you know,
people can easily cut and paste data out of them or
run arbitrary commands or code or do whatever
in theory when Citrix works, it's actually not a bad solution.
It's just, it's pretty cool.
It just seems to be one of those companies that has like
a legacy code base that has a lot of technical debt,
especially security debt.
I have no doubt. I mean, I remember Citrix
being around,
it was what, the early two thousands, I think it kind of really, I mean,
that's when I, I remember it for, I don't, I'm sure it's older than that,
-- but that's kind of when it 19
-- 89.
What? That's bananas.
Holy cow.
Yeah, I would not have guessed 1989.
-- Like
-- did networks exist in 1989?
Not for most people? Holy cow. That's something.
Ok.
I,
I'm gonna hope
there's no code from 1989 still in use.
No,
don't do it. I know you want to but don't.
But, but regardless I think
I, OK,
I would bet that there is code or something in there from at least the late nineties.
I believe that.
And the only reason I say that is because Apache wasn't released until 1995.
Uh
-- Apache was released in 90
-- five. Initial release date. April 95.
I feel. Wow, that means I was using it shortly after it was released.
I guess I never realized that.
Well, it was either.
Well, like literally, you know, if you weren't using the N CS A one,
you were using the patchy
version of the N CS A one, which was better because they had patches
and, well, didn't son have a web server.
Everybody had a web server.
They were,
yeah, they were.
That's fair.
They're still terrible.
It's called,
I'm having like all these floods of terrible memories now.
-- But,
-- yeah, so, I mean, I, I love the fact that this is just OK,
spoofing encryption certificates
is bad
but it's typically at least a two stage attack.
Like, I'd have to get you, like, here's an, here's a signed update, you know,
check the signature on it before you run it
or, you know, something along those lines. Right.
Whereas this is like, ok, is your, is your Citrix machine on the internet? Well, yes,
maybe not directly on the internet. But is it on a network?
Well, yeah, because why else would you be running it?
-- That's, that's the point.
-- Exactly.
Generally of computers nowadays is to put them on the internet.
That's just sort of how it is. Uh, anyways.
So, are you vulnerable? Well,
yes. Yes, you are.
Unless maybe magically you have some like web application, firewall,
sing in front of it that happens to have
a rule of blocks dot dot directory traversals,
which
-- I think most of them kind of do.
-- I would hope so.
I mean, there's very few instances where dot dot slash should be in URL.
Never,
I should,
I want to write a web server that primarily deals in dot dots and slashes in the,
er,
-- maybe
-- Morse code.
Right. Right. I like it.
But
anyway,
and the fact is, I mean, you know,
like this is going to be a classic enterprise security patch and that Citrix
is going to release a patch for like the most up to date version
and maybe the, you know,
current version minus one and then maybe the current version minus two,
a few weeks later and then maybe
an older version that's also affected
later
so on. And so like they're going to dribble fixes out over a period of weeks or months.
Uh That's kind of what it sounds like. Also just a fun factor. I've been listening
dot
is E in Morse code and dot dot Is I,
so I don't know what we can do with that, but it sounds interesting.
Makes sense. But what really gets me is like
this is going to take Citrix,
-- how long to push a patch out.
-- Uh It's taking them a long time.
It's, it's going to be more than a month,
which is unacceptable for this sort of issue.
I mean,
I remember dealing with these and now I'm not going to
-- tell Citrix what they should or shouldn't be doing
-- internally,
they should drop everything and fix it is what they should be doing.
Yeah, that's, that's what needs to happen.
And if they, if they have dropped everything and it still takes a month, like,
you guys have some problems that you probably need to fix.
Yeah. I,
I the proof is like if I take my car in to the mechanic and he's like,
it's gonna be a month.
I mean, it better be an import where I need, you know,
parts delivered from Japan or somewhere
on a pack mule for that to take a month.
Otherwise it should take like two days.
Right. Exactly.
I mean, I, well, OK,
it can take longer than that because my favorite example here
for just terrible security issues is I remember working on Mozilla things
and like just building
Firefox, the web browser takes 24 hours
because it is gigantic,
right?
And there's only so much you can run in
-- parallel and
-- we didn't have fast computers back then.
Uh
Yeah,
I remember some of the machines people built to compile code and like
literally just shoving as many fast cores as they could in them.
And the problem being is that at some point you get diminishing returns.
Like the compiler is just like,
you know, the compiler is like 100 and 28 courses. Fantastic.
-- I only need like eight of them.
-- Well, and you know what? Always got
things like Fedora,
I'll pick on just because they're public and this is kind of widely known is
when you support lots of weird architectures, some of them are really, really slow
and you might only have one
and one slow machine
-- like mps or
-- arm. Right. And so now you have to wait for it to build.
-- Yeah,
-- like the thought of even on a Raspberry four, which is a pretty fast arm.
CPU the thought of like recompiling a Linux kernel.
I wonder how long that would take? I haven't, I haven't built a kernel in a long time.
I can't even tell you what it takes.
So, so anyway, anyway,
the point is
I'll give him a week maybe because something like this, I think worst case scenario,
get it done in a week, right?
-- A month is ridiculous.
-- Well, or at least get an interim patch out that like
ha
fixes
work around
instructions. So that I know
that, you know,
because the thing I always hated with these configuration workarounds is,
are we sure it fixes it?
Like, are we sure I implemented it correctly?
See that's the advantage of updating a binary.
Like if I'm running that up to date binary with or up to date library or whatever,
then I'm almost certainly
ok.
But if it's a configuration change, well, you know,
now I need basically a defanged exploit to test it for me to really believe it.
And even then,
well, ok, so they got this one avenue. But what if it's like
slash VPN slash dot dot slash VPN slash dot dot slash VPN slash dot dot slash VPN?
-- Like what if I put two in or three in? Does it still work? Maybe? Let's
-- hope not.
But ok, so let's,
let's turn this around now because I feel like
we're just flogging the dead horse at this point.
So you wanted to compare this to what Microsoft has just released.
-- So
-- Microsoft working with partners, you know,
they found basically as far as crypto goes
in the crypto world, this is pretty much the worst case scenario right?
Here's a certificate, I can spoof it because you don't check it properly.
And this is why I don't like elliptical curve
cryptography is because it's so easy to get wrong.
And the problem is especially with stuff like
RS A&E CC is you can have an implementation
that is
security wise broken
but still works and interoperates with other crypto
implementations.
Well, and it should be noted here as well.
They're crediting the National Security Agency of the United States for,
for disclosing this.
I'm kind of wondering if those guys were doing
some crazy high level certificate fuzzing against implementation.
It could be, I mean, the thing that comes to mind always when the NSA
discloses something like this is either they found it a
long time ago and it's burnt now for whatever reason,
or they found an adversary using it so they want to burn it on them
or that they were doing legitimate research and found this and said, oh,
-- we better tell someone because this one's pretty bad
-- back to the problem.
The NSA has a dual mission, right?
To break into other people's
communications and to secure America's communications
and those two things are incompatible may not be the right word,
but that's the only word I can think of.
I always love it when I talk to someone from the NSA
and, you know, they be like, I work for the NSA.
Oh no, the part you like though, it's like, oh, ok. Yeah.
Yeah.
And the thing is, I mean,
the beauty is even though Microsoft did a patch today
and got a patch out early to other people,
I mean, it's not like this patch is going to have 100% implementation.
It isn't, you know, it's,
it's one of those classic S curves where you're going to hit 80% probably,
hopefully in a week or two,
90% in a couple of months, you know.
Well, this one comes with some mitigating factors.
So here's, here's where we can compare and contrast. So
we understand what's going on here, but we don't know what the problem actually is.
Now someone's going to figure it out in probably the next
24 hours is my suspicion from the time of release.
I suspect it might take a little longer because just
I'm guessing
if it's maybe something to,
it might be something to do with the math implementation.
So it's not just a simple but probably within a few days or a week or two at the most.
-- Let's
-- assume a week. Ok. I don't think it will be, but let's just say a week.
So now we understand the problem,
but now we have to figure out how do we actually exploit it.
And I don't know the details on what it looks like.
And of course, when we're talking about cryptography,
it could be a huge range of problems.
I suspect it's a tiny bit more complicated than putting
-- dot dot into your request
-- string one would hope so.
But now it's going to take people probably at least as long to
exploit is my assumption as it took them to understand the patch.
So let's say in two weeks, there's a functional exploit that's out,
right?
Even when that happens,
you have
a certain amount of lead time between patch release and functional exploit.
But then
this is also they've rated it important because like this,
you can't just connect over the internet and attack this one, right? You basically
from the
I shouldn't say that I shouldn't say that
from what I understand at this moment in time,
it is about code signing and running executables
which is not very internet friendly.
Well, that would be the most obvious threat vector.
But for example, if it's, if it's deep in the crypt 32 dot DLL, for example,
what if you're using ECC client certificates to authenticate clients?
And they don't say that can happen and I have
a strong suspicion they would say that if it could be
pretty, yeah.
You know what, I'm going to agree,
they've Microsoft has actually been pretty decent about
in the last I would say half decade, decade or so of, yeah, actually copying
the realistic exploits where there are certain other
vendors who shall remain nameless where they're like,
oh yeah, you can only do it this way and then of course, a day later,
you know, somebody like Tavis is like, what about this, this way and that way
-- in the next day? No
-- other way.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, and then like 17 avenues of exploitation later were like,
can you please fix the root cause?
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And so I, I mean,
given that the NSA reported it to them and they looked at it
and I'm sure Microsoft didn't put the B team on this one.
Right.
Here's what's fascinating to me is Microsoft could have and the NSA,
I'm sure could have easily
gone, you know, with quote
unquote, an anonymous researcher. Uh
-- Right. I mean, if they wanted to, yes, they could have.
-- No, no, they couldn't.
Here's the thing
-- to say,
-- but
a reported, it makes this real people.
But at the same time, I think there's two sides to that.
There's the aspect of people who pay attention.
But then there's also the angle of you can,
you can't keep a secret, right?
If the NSA reported this to Microsoft and they're like, oh,
an anonymous researcher in
six months, we would all know it was the NSA 100% guaranteed.
And then the NSA has apr nightmare because everyone's going to be like,
so, like, were you guys hacking with this or what's the deal? You know?
Well, I would hope they were hacking with this.
Isn't that literally half of their job?
I'm not going to get into that.
Yeah.
Anyways, I mean,
the reality is if a country has a capability in their military or security services,
then they should probably be using that capability. Otherwise, why have it?
-- I,
-- man,
we could do 100 shows on this topic.
This is my, this is my German, half real politic coming out, you know,
good old Hindenburg
than Bismarck.
There's, there's so many views on this and I,
I don't have an opinion because my view is,
I don't understand the dynamics of this well enough
to say we should or shouldn't be doing this.
And I'm comfortable saying that and I'm comfortable letting other people
argue about it and that's pretty much where I stand.
I would say, I think at a minimum, we at least need to be maintaining that,
that capability.
Like we don't want to have the NSA not have any people who can, like, create exploits.
I feel like that would be really bad long term,
you know,
much like the US let go of their intelligence capability after world war one and,
-- you know, had to basically rebuild it for World War Two
-- and
now it sucks again. So,
yeah,
this, this whole thing with Citrix at first, I kind of thought it was a joke
in the sense of like, well, it can't be that simple and it can't take that long to fix.
Right?
I hear you, man.
And what's really interesting is there's,
there's other vendors like cloud flare has been doing a lot
of stuff and I didn't really get it at first where,
you know, so cloud flare will proxy your website, you know,
eat up your D dots attacks.
But now they're doing traffic sort of the other way.
They're actually saying, you know, we confront
for your SSH server and give you, you know,
basically a secure SSH login that goes to your server
or same thing for applications.
We can basically act as a VPN slash W A for applications.
And then like your team around the globe
can, you know,
securely connect to whatever dot your Corp and
that's proxy through cloud flare super secure,
you know, much faster, you know, blah, blah blah.
And I was at first I was kind of like, I don't really get it,
but now having seen the Citrix thing, I'm kind of like, yeah.
Ok.
I'm beginning to understand that. I, I
think we're at the point where
this is just normal, right?
These enterprise software that have this, like, remote,
not only do they have a remote code execution
flaw and not only is there public exploit code,
but it's like you're going to have to wait a few weeks for the update. And
this isn't generally the kind of stuff where you can just
turn it off and live without it for a few weeks.
Because if you could do that, you would have done that,
you would have gotten rid of this it
thing that you don't need.
-- I
-- mean, actually, actually I hadn't even thought of that,
but I wonder how many organizations are going to use this as an opportunity
to just finally get rid of it and be like this is ridiculous.
I'm done.
The problem is with, with whatever Citrix is doing,
it's delivering an application to people that they by definition need.
Otherwise you would have killed it.
Like I'm in the process of the CS A of,
of getting rid of some old stuff like our mailing
list server finally getting to kill our mailman instance.
Hallelujah. So happy
-- which means I get to get us out of the business of handling email directly.
-- Right.
Right.
Ok. So I, I'm sorry, I'm going to interrupt you.
I saw a message on Twitter from the NSA about this,
this issue and it does say it says http S connections,
signed files and emails and signed executables.
So it probably does affect websites which is huge if it,
well, websites using client authentication with UCC certificates, which
if memory serves, what do those dut common access cards use?
I don't know if they use ECC. I'd be shocked if they don't.
Yeah, because kind of thought C A CS were using ECC stuff now because well,
smaller keys faster, more efficient.
-- They, they probably are, I'd be surprised
-- if they are.
So, yeah, I mean, if you found, OK, so for those of you don't know, don't know. The US
Department of Defense has this thing called the common access card
and it's essentially
-- like a PK I smart card.
-- Everyone has smart cards.
Now, man, you got to like the hospital,
you go almost anywhere and people have smart cards.
So I feel like in that case,
the NSA would prefer to have all the dod systems secured rather than have
this exploit that they can use once and then hope Microsoft patches quickly.
Yeah, I mean, that's probably fair.
That's true.
They
had an incident a while back with authentication and everyone.
So,
right. Anyway,
-- so I
-- guess, I mean,
what's interesting to me though is Microsoft went from
literally being the poster child of not just incompetency
but basically malice and evil in the security world 20 years ago,
I would agree with that.
Like, literally where they were threatening people and they were, you know,
I remember those timelines coming over.
It's like I told Microsoft you're reading the timeline, you're like, oh,
they told them in January, that's not so bad.
And then you realize, wait, no, no, no, that wasn't this January.
You know, what year is that again?
And in some cases, it wasn't just like Microsoft took a long time to fix it.
It's like people would spend six months
trying to convince Microsoft they found a flaw and they'd be
like sent working exploit code to Microsoft and Microsoft you,
like, who are you, what are you talking about?
We've never heard of you before, right?
And not just random people but people in the industry with like a known track record.
And now they're pretty much,
uh, honestly, they're kind of as good as the cats, the
security response.
Like,
you know, old me is just like
in a padded room right now rocking back and forth.
Well, look, I, I think, and we'll, we'll end it on this note because we're,
we're basically out of time.
But I think this is an example of what
happens when you shift your mindset from security is being
just an annoyance that costs money,
which is quite possibly like what Citrix is doing right now,
just given what I've seen versus Microsoft where
they view it as like doing the stuff,
right?
Is
it, it, it gives them a competitive advantage in the industry
because nobody can match them in
-- this regard.
-- If they want to maintain their leadership,
they have to.
-- Right.
-- Yes,
I, I think we'll end it there.
Yeah, totally.
I like it. All right. So thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.