Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner who is now possibly one or two hours away from me.
Josh Bresser.
-- Oh,
-- come on.
I asked Kurt to open this with my partner in Daylight
savings crime because I think daylight savings is a crime.
But
I don't, I don't know what time it is for you.
Do you, did you change your clocks, like, two days ago, three days ago?
No, because the computers do that,
whatever. Actually, I have three clocks in my house. I have to manually change.
-- Yeah,
-- I have about a dozen.
Wow, that's, well, I have all these, like, humidity, temperature
sensor on it. Like sensors that have cloths.
They're little cheap ones.
And I actually found they made a huge difference because I, I,
the upstairs temperature of the house gets real
wonky because all the heat rises and blah,
blah, blah.
And so I put these temperatures and because basically,
yeah, I was getting too hot to sleep and I'm like, what's going on? Well, heat rises.
Yeah. Imagine that.
So,
why do they have clocks? Who cares?
Well, because that's it, it just it has temperature, humidity, clock
dates.
It's the cheapest one you can buy on Amazon.
I got you. I got, you just take a piece of tape and cover up the time
-- anyway. Anyway,
-- it's, it's,
I find daylight savings maddening because right next door to us is Saskatchewan.
And they've just never done it and they, they seem ok.
-- It's
-- the dumbest thing ever. I'm actually really jealous.
I work with some people who live in Oregon, the country in the United States
and
the
state, a state, whatever.
It's, it's, it's,
man, I'm not, I'm not doing well. I'm serious.
Like daylight saving every time I change the clocks. I'm not right for a week
anyway,
the state
of Oregon
never has to change their clocks again. And I am so jealous of that.
And it's one of those catch 22.
Like I know,
I'm pretty sure BC has a law on the book saying they can get
away from it as soon as the US to the south of them does.
But,
right, because trade partners, like you don't want to for six months of the year,
be an hour off from your major trade partner.
I mean, that seems fair.
Although, although
I used to live in the state of Indiana, which,
when I lived there did not observe daylight sings and I found it very frustrating to
struggle to know what time it was anywhere but where I lived and I kept complaining,
but then, then they instituted daylight savings and I assure you that was worse.
So, like, take that for what it's worth.
I, I just, I love that.
It's such a perfect example of things in security that people
just don't want to change because it would mean changing something.
-- That's right.
-- Change is hard. So, let's just never change
anyway. Anyway.
All right.
-- Speaking
-- of change. So, things have changed a little bit
at
-- Github.
-- That's the worst transition
ever. And now it's our sponsor.
Nothing's changed at github.
-- Well,
-- no, they, they, they, they forcibly took down an exploit code.
They did.
There was an exploit for the recent Windows exchange.
Well, no, it was not an exploit. It was a proof of concept.
-- I thought it was
-- weaponized.
The original one was not weaponized.
Ok. Well, either way, who cares
github? Someone put up a proof of concept. Github yanked it
and
everyone's crying foul because Microsoft owns github and obviously this,
this exploit was targeting
Windows operating systems.
And now there's this big debate about was this good or bad or what's going on?
Well, so one thing is number one,
like most websites that allow posting content,
they have a phone book of restrictions,
right?
So they acceptable use policy compliance with laws, blah, blah,
blah content restrictions, you know,
ah here we go is unlawful or promotes unlawful activities.
And then the next one that might be applicable
is contains or installs any act of malware or
exploits or uses our platform for exploit delivery such
as part of a command and control system or
uh infringes any proprietary
right of any party, including patent trademark, trade secret, copyright,
right of publicity or other, right.
So basically the first two are kind of the most applicable here.
The problem is that means any
hacking tools technically fall under this, like like Net catt is widely used by
pen testers and bad guys to the point where Net Catt actually gets, you know,
detected by some A V programs and stuff as being a malicious thing.
Yep. Yep.
And I mean, it's just Net Cat, it's just a network socket.
-- Actually,
-- you know what's really wild is I was helping someone I work with,
they were basically building there was this,
this uh security detection rule that they were trying to bypass.
And basically the rule had a 10 minute window where
if Net Catt starts and then Net Catt connects, then flag it. So
he's like, I just want to start Net Catt because there's a,
there's a version of Net Catt that is like like a little command line type
the interface. He's like, I want to start Net Cat wait 10 minutes
and then do stuff. And he's like, I'm struggling to do this with a shell script.
And I said, well, let's just use Python.
And so I, you know, cranked out a little Python script to do it for him.
And Yeah, like sure enough, that's all it took.
And then I said, I'm like, why don't you just flag all net catt traffic?
And he said you wouldn't believe how much of the cloud is run with Net Catt
-- behind the scenes. And I became
-- scared.
-- Yeah, when you need to move data from system A to system B
-- well,
not even just data like like connections between,
between microservices and stuff.
-- And I'm like, that's horrifying to me
-- like it works man
and a developer
given a choice between it works and it doesn't work.
We'll choose, it works every single time, especially it works with no other setup.
No keys, no passwords. No, no,
nothing to set up. It just works.
So
github yanked a demo exploit
and you know what? I guess here's the way I've been putting this into my brain is
I don't agree with it,
but it's well within their rights. Yeah.
Part of it is the optics are bad and I also wonder
what does this accomplish? Like here's the thing, what are the pros and cons?
There's because there's a whole pile of cons like some
of the communities annoyed with them and so on.
-- What are the actual pros to yanking it though?
-- I think
they were probably under fire. There is a certain,
I think group of people
that have this obsession with keeping things secret even though it
wasn't a secret and it's available all over the freaking internet.
-- Even
-- worse. All the exchange servers that can be hacked have been hacked.
Yeah, basically.
No, really. But that does make a bit of a difference.
It's not like, basically all the bad that can happen has largely happened.
Well, not necessarily. I mean, it's always amusing when you see
II,
I set up an elastic search honey pot one time and it kept getting hacked back and
forth from two different pieces of malware And it amused me to no end to watch them,
like, constantly flip every couple of hours, a different one came in and hacked it.
-- It was
-- if somebody had a proof of concept or an exploit code that wasn't widely used,
there is potentially some value in taking it down
because it slows the spread of people using exploit,
you know, to attack things.
-- But at this point, every exchange server had been hacked.
-- I disagree.
I don't think it's slow to spread at all because
the people who are going to actually weaponize this stuff,
they had a copy long before it hit github
-- guaranteed. Right. Well, in this
-- case, yes, but I'm talking more in general.
Ok. Ok.
But I think, but I bet even in general it's probably very true where the bad guys,
-- they have ways of getting stuff like this that isn't
-- github.
Sell it to each other.
-- Right.
-- But anyway, anyway, I, I do think
there is this cult of secrecy that has developed
inside of security and I think it is unhealthy.
It's not that it developed inside of security.
It actually, from doing my reading,
it was largely imported from the military because
the military has a very rich history of,
well, the phrase, if you can see the target, you can kill the target.
Right. And it's true because if you, you know, it's true in real life. Yeah.
Well, but the problem is they,
they've moved these metaphors directly over to information security
and they sort of work, but not 100%.
And so they have this idea that, for example, you know,
if we can control the flow of information and
prevent people from knowing what a gun is,
then we don't have to worry about guns being used to attack us.
Right.
Yeah. No, that ship sailed guys. It sounds good.
Like if, oh,
if we don't let the Attackers have any details about the security
vulnerabilities and we don't let them have exploit codes and everything.
They'll be at such a disadvantage. And the answer is, well, no, they won't.
Where do you think these exploits are coming from in the first place?
Like people find them,
like people like me and Josh can find them.
-- You don't need to be that sophisticated
-- and we're not what I was gonna say.
We're not smart.
Right.
Right. No, I agree completely.
And I think the, the true danger in all of this and this harkens back to
various discussions that I know we've had in the past and I think I wrote,
I might have written a blog post.
I'll see if I can dig it up. But basically deleting
stuff like this, I think creates a false sense of security where people think, oh,
it's exploitable but the exploits not out there.
And the exploit is 100% out there.
And I think making it on, available on something like
github is,
you can't pretend it's not there because like it's literally right there.
And I think that's part of the thing is it's the whole,
the emperor has no clothes situation.
I think it's really what it boils down to
100%. And people do not.
People who are invested in the emperor supposedly wearing pants do not like that.
Like a brief search on Google. Actually, I found something better than it.
It's, it's a huge blog posting like, oh my goodness, this is like 1020 pages long
and it's, it's walking you through how
-- the exploit works and how to build one.
-- Oh That's very exciting.
Send that, send that to me. I'll put it in the show notes but I want to read it.
It's
uh
yeah, I mean, and that's the thing, right? This, this is not hidden information.
I think part of the challenge is this didn't really accomplish much.
I mean that from the practical side, from, for example, a legal side,
it did accomplish a lot.
It, it made Microsoft's lawyers. Probably much less grumpy and angry.
No. Really? Well, because when we both worked at Red Hat. Right.
That was one of the mantras.
Is that Red Hat could never share or disclose
anything kind of exploit Cody that could remotely,
ever end up being weaponized.
-- That's true.
-- That's totally understandable.
Like large companies, you know, they have to worry about these things.
No,
I'm going to call BS on that because I think I
suspect nothing bad would ever happen but try convincing the lawyers.
Well, no, no, no. The lawyer's job is to be overly paranoid about everything
and the job of business leaders is to tell the lawyers we've listened to your
feedback and this is a decision we're going to make against your better judgment,
maybe in some cases and sometimes that's ok.
Sometimes, obviously it feels miserably.
I think when you end up in a situation where the lawyers are driving the bus,
it's becomes a sad pathetic bus.
Oh, absolutely. I mean, and maybe that happened here, we'll never know.
I mean,
it would not shock me if Microsoft had zero input into this
decision and github just was like off on their own doing it.
I don't know.
Well,
and that's the other thing people treating these companies like they're
big cohesive entities that know what's going on with each other.
Right? Like, come on.
No, it's like, it's like a dumpster barely held together by string.
These companies sue each other internally all the time,
Sony's content production division suit their anyway, Sony sued up part of itself
and the thing is too,
there is massive value in the good guys having
exploit code two main things being number one,
the vendors that want to
create signatures for this or, you know, some sort of workaround or something.
And number two, the people who are basically saying, look,
we really need to patch this and we need to do it now and we need to have some downtime.
And no, I mean, it, because now here's this, see, look what happens when I do this,
tap, tap, tap.
-- And now I'm admin
-- now, one of the arguments
I heard was people were saying, oh,
you shouldn't like wait and give people time to patch.
But the hilarious thing about this is it was actively exploited for several
weeks before the patch came out and like everything was already pun.
So
let, let's, let's pretend that's not the case. And let's pretend
that
patch comes out, exploit comes out same day, right? What do you think now?
-- Well,
-- so here's a question, what is a quote unquote,
reasonable amount of time to give people to patch,
-- right? A day? 30 days,
-- more than zero hours maybe.
-- Well, but how long? No, I want a number. Come
-- on.
So, I mean, I don't have an opinion on this because
I,
I've experienced this from every possible way you can imagine.
There's plenty of organizations that, that patching immediately is not an option.
And I understand that well,
-- and
-- also remember that one year where a whole bunch of attack,
uh
exploits dropped and if they dropped, like two weeks later,
they would have consistently fallen on, you know,
holidays like Thanksgiving and Christmas and New Year's.
And so here's the reality.
Would it be nice that everybody had like a solid 30 days of no exploitation to patch?
And then after 30 days the exploit code
goes out and whatever bad things happen happen.
Yeah.
But we don't live in that world and trying to
pretend that we live in that world is insane.
I, I agree.
That's like saying you shouldn't look both ways when you cross the street at a
pedestrian crosswalk because you have the right of way and it's a marked crosswalk.
Yeah. Tell that to the old lady.
They got run over by a city bus, you know, two years ago.
And, and I think you can,
there's always going to be people who argue the ethics of releasing
an exploit without waiting some amount of time.
And I don't think it matters how long you wait.
-- There's always going to be someone who complains.
-- Absolutely.
But here's the real problem I find with this whole thing,
you can argue the ethics and morality of this.
All you want. The reality is the world isn't that way.
There will be bad guys who will do this stuff.
I don't want to blame the victim but it has to get better
and faster at patching stuff because that's the world we live in.
If you can't patch stuff or fix stuff quickly or release an update quickly, you're,
you're doomed to failure.
I mean,
I think that you, this,
this conversation might have been valid in the early two thousands.
But I think today, like
it, it's move fast or die. I mean,
well, or stop doing that and outsource it to somebody who's better at it than
no, no, no, like II,
I understand why so many places have infrastructures
because that's what they've done for 2030 years.
You know, MS uh, managed service providers, you know,
helping small medium businesses
with their, you know, Microsoft Exchange server,
their Microsoft business server, whatever the products are called now.
And cool, I get that.
But also I'm sorry,
as much as I hate on these huge monoliths like Aws and Microsoft 365.
The reality is
that's where we're headed and that's what works
and it's cheaper and it's less hassle.
And I get that there's regulatory issues and compliance issues
for a lot of people who are outside the US.
But again, the world is the way it is and we can
try and argue and say ethically blah, blah, blah, but it's that,
that's not going to happen.
I mean, I, I kind of agree. I think you have to plan for
any time a critical security
update comes out.
-- You should expect that the bad guys have an exploit
-- even simpler.
There's been a whole pile of S sds
with firmware issues that break after 40,000 hours.
And so if you can't,
for example, take your storage server array down to update the firmware,
so it doesn't die after $40,000.
-- Which is what, like three or four years,
-- you're not going to have much of a choice,
are you?
-- Yeah.
-- And I mean, I, I get that, it's painful to take down your main storage array.
Like that's,
you know, everything else breaks when you do that.
But the reality is you have to be able to do that.
You know, I don't want to own a spare tire,
but I just spent 200 bucks buying a full size tire for my spare tire.
So that if my,
you know,
I don't have to run on a donut tire for God
knows how long if I'm out of the cabin or whatever,
you know, and I can't get, I can't get tow truck service out there.
Why
I
don't go places without internet. So it's fine.
So,
you know, there's, there's the world
we want to have and in that world, yeah,
there wouldn't be exploits and there wouldn't be people pulling stuff.
There'd be secure software that just works well. No, we don't have that world
and there's the world we have where
there are bad people doing bad things to your systems and
if it takes you 30 to 90 days to patch them,
well, basically you're screwed.
Or you need to start doing some addition layers of security, like only allowing,
you know, VPN access and hoping that none of your workstations get popped.
-- I mean,
-- maybe anyway, I want to move on because I think,
I think we beat this one to death.
I guess we would love to hear why we are wrong, please. At Kirk
-- on Twitter.
-- Well, people will tell us why we're wrong.
It'll be the same old reasons of, oh, this gives Attackers blah, blah, blah,
whatever.
Well, the same can be said for a copy of, you know, programming C++
Yeah, don't, don't use that either because that's probably more dangerous than
the
anyway. Anyway. All right.
OK. OK.
I want to move on to the next thing we wanted to talk about and this is the,
the Linux Foundation has announced a new open source software signing service
and they're calling it sig store.
And from what I understand
the intent is to make it significantly easier for open source developers to sign
their releases with some sort of trusted signature.
Yeah, here's the problem with signing an encryption in general is at some point,
you have to have a piece of trusted thing that is securely stored A K
-- A, the private key. Well,
-- they're actually doing some clever things with this.
-- And exactly, and that's part of what they've addressed here.
-- Yeah.
And see, that's always the problem I had where everybody's like, oh,
all software developers should sign their software securely.
I'm like, cool. You're all going to buy them,
you know, five or six hardware tokens and give them, you know,
a safe deposit box to keep a spare one in case
their house burns down and so on and so forth.
No,
this solves a lot of those problems.
But the problem is software signing doesn't really
-- do what people think it does.
-- Well, I know that's what makes it funny.
Well, and it's very similar to https in that respective https,
doesn't really do what people think it does.
Well, so here's my favorite part of this.
And now I think I want to, I want to start this out by saying,
I think the Linux Foundation and
what Red Hat's part of this and there's some other companies,
I think this is marvelous and I think
this is exactly the right thing to do
and I'm hopeful they make it a community and not a committee.
But I think all in all this is a great idea.
-- I
-- hope they make it as simple as less encrypt with CF bot.
-- No, seriously, it needs to be that
-- it does, it needs to be simpler.
But
the thing that made me laugh out loud
is everyone's talking about this in the context of the solar winds attack,
this would not have fixed the solar
winds attack
because
you would have released signed malware.
-- Well,
-- and,
but more to the point they did monkey with the signed binaries and the response was,
oh, yeah, just smash that
and install it and ignore the signature error.
That too.
Right. So
that's the thing. It, it, again, it reminds me a lot of
tps and that we have this whole online certificate,
something protocol that, you know,
you can check if the certificate is still valid or not.
Right? Has it been revoked?
The problem is you turn that on
and number one,
you have a performance hit because every time you hit
a site you have to ask is the certificate valid from
privacy hit.
And I was about to get to that the privacy and now you're
telling everybody where you're going to look for stuff up until recently,
most of these uh, certificate vendors couldn't run a reliable enough
revocation system.
Like it just, it wasn't up 24 7. So, and if it's down, what do you do?
Do you feel closed and stop browsing the web or do you
keep going anyways? Because it's probably not that bad.
Well, the answer is if you keep going anyways because it's not that bad.
That means the attacker can just block the request and
yeah, now revoke certificates don't show up as revoked. That's right.
That's right. So, yeah, this whole software signing thing.
I like it because what it basically allows a software developer to do
is to do a bunch of work come up with an artifact,
be it a tar ball of source code or a binary
and then sort of freeze it in amber
and if it's signed
using something like this, they can sort of wash their hands of it and be like, look,
I'm done, I've released it.
Anything that happens past here is kind of not my problem
unless the signing key leaks.
Yeah,
trust it.
Well, and, and that speaks to having, you know, like a, like public repos of,
you know, here's the signature, here's the hash, here's what, you know,
the file name is and where it is and part of me would like that too,
just for discovery of stuff.
Right.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, I agree.
There's another side to this as well, which is,
there are loads of projects
that sign what they do today
and literally nobody checks the signatures and I won't lie. I'm a security guy.
The number of signatures I've checked is probably 10 or less like in my career.
Unless it happens automatically
nobody checks.
And I, I remember Souza Lennox sent out a security advisory.
This is like over a decade ago, maybe a decade, whatever, a long time ago
and they improperly signed it and I
noticed it was not properly signed.
So I contacted them and they re-released it properly signed.
And then about a week later, I condo, I'm like,
how many people actually complained and he's like three
that's higher than I expected.
But here's the thing, the signature things and computers kind of fail so often.
We just sort of
because, and 99 times out of 100 it is not an attack. It is
-- a glitch.
-- It's like, it's not just 99 out of 100 current.
It's like nine trillion nine. You know what I mean? It's like 100 nines out of
100 and one. You know what I mean?
-- It's,
-- well, except for that one time it was the Attackers at solar winds.
It's almost right. It's so rare,
but even then, like, signatures wouldn't have necessarily solved that problem.
-- And
-- that's the other conception is that signatures are here to stop this.
No, they're, they're an alarm.
They're not
in my mind. Signatures are meant to be like a tripwire funnily enough.
There's a product actually called Tripwire that signs all your files and monitors,
monitors them for changes to
say whoa, oh, this file changed. Maybe an attacker did something.
Maybe your admin was monkey in there.
-- Tripwire
-- is a hilarious example because as soon as you update your system,
which you need to be doing on a regular basis, Tripwire loses its mind
and the fact that Tripwire doesn't handle
better,
that's shameful
assuming
they don't. But whatever
the point is that it's, it's like http S,
it's every time you hit a site that's broken in some way.
The user offered a choice.
Do you want to proceed? Right. And unless you are in the HSTS preload list.
And now it's interesting is if you're in that preload list,
it will not let you bypass certificate errors.
The number of people doing that is a couple of
websites.
Well, when things break, they don't want it to break, break,
they want people to ignore that error and go on
-- to their banking website
-- or go buy things for me.
-- Right.
-- So that speaks to me that the reliability of these systems,
you know, I have a smoke alarm every day. About, between nine and 10 o'clock.
-- I get an alarm because I cook bacon.
-- You cook bacon every day.
Yeah, two strips of bacon, two or three eggs every day.
It's my breakfast, like clockwork,
it's Keto and it's actually low calorie.
But anyways, the point is every day I, you know,
because I like to cook my bacon a little crispy.
I get a smoke alarm. Right. And it's annoying. Like, you know,
I got to whack, I'm tall enough that I can just hit the thing and tell it to shut up.
I've considered moving the smoke alarm out of the kitchen and then I'm kind of like,
well, that sort of defeats the whole purpose of having one.
-- I
-- mean, it totally defeats the purpose of having a smoke alarm. I agree.
Like that, that, that, that is the most likely place to have a fire in my,
when I had my whole house rewired, I made them put a smoke alarm next to my furnace.
The guy's like,
you don't need this for code. I'm like, I don't care what code says.
-- Put the freaking smoke alarm,
-- dude. Carbon monoxide. Right.
Right.
Carbon monoxide and smoke detector.
I'm like,
this is literally the place I'm going to need
this more than anywhere else in this whole basement.
Like put one there, put one over there, it'll be fine.
-- Yeah,
-- I have two boxes of fire in my house. One is in the kitchen and one is my furnace.
Yeah. Right.
Exactly.
Seems pretty.
Anyway.
Anyway,
the point is until these systems essentially have, you know, zero false positives,
almost no hassle to set up and use.
-- It's just not gonna happen
-- and, and look, I think the,
the thing sig store needs to do
and I, I don't, I,
from what I've read, I don't think this is true yet, but it's very early. So we'll see.
But there, there seems to be a lot of focus on the developers.
Whereas the focus needs to be put on the consumption because if consumption is hard,
who cares if it's even signed?
Because no one's going to verify it,
they'll try, they'll fail and they'll smash that ignore button.
Yeah, exactly.
And you get, like,
basically in the world of security you get one chance and if you screw up,
people decide you're an idiot and they never ever want to talk to you again.
Well,
or they change the default to just allow
any unsigned binary from anywhere to run which,
you know, I have to do this on my Macs because I want to run software that I need
that isn't available through the App store, for example, or
whatever, you know, and I'm not talking dodgy stuff.
I'm actually talking reasonably legitimate household names.
-- But
-- even then, I mean,
things like signed executables on Windows and Mac
researchers have shown time and time again,
it's trivial to sign malware.
Like,
so again, that speaks to signing doesn't do what people think it does, you know,
a website certificate for td.com.
What is td.com? Well, it actually happens to be my bank,
you know,
but walmart.com pretty sure that's Walmart.
But what about like Walmart dot Some random new top level domain?
Is that
Walmart? Well,
hell,
I,
I would assume it is because I would hope Walmart is
smart enough to register every Walmart dot Something on the planet.
-- I don't know,
-- man, there's a lot of TL DS now.
-- Is it,
-- it's 1500 or 2000, 300.
-- I forget which, and
-- I imagine it is up to the right on a regular basis.
Well, it's a, what is it?
$180,000 give or take to set up a TLD and it's a,
it's a way to print money because people do defensive registrations.
Yeah. Right.
That's what it boils down to
the signing has to work perfectly for both the cons,
the creation and the consumption.
There has to be essentially no false alarms because
if you have more than two or three false alarms for every real alarm,
people ignore it.
And we're talking, you know,
hundreds or thousands of false alarms for every real alarm here.
Yeah.
And
my favorite thing too is I would run into software that had a signature error.
And, well, what do I do now?
And, you know,
I would try and report it and it was invariably
some sort of glitch or error or just got ignored.
90 9% of the time if I try to install
something and it says the signature is invalid or whatever,
I'm going to ignore it and do whatever it takes to get
it installed because I probably need it to get something done.
-- And I don't care about the stupid warning.
-- Pretty much.
-- The thing I do is I fire it through virus
-- total. Yeah.
Actually I've taught my kids, like, all their,
all their mods they install for their games.
I'm like, put it through virus total every time.
I mean, so far it's working but like,
even that isn't obviously 100% but I feel like it's close enough that it'll work.
We get these Excel Macro viruses via Gmail,
but actually flag in virus total in two or three of the Chinese ones.
But none of the rest. And it's so bizarre
because I would have always assumed that.
Well, I know the virus companies share virus samples.
Right.
I mean,
it's in their own best interest because otherwise coverage would be a nightmare.
But, uh, yeah,
it's weird to me that these things do detect by a
handful of vendors but the majority of them don't detect.
It's very strange and,
and that speaks to the whole false positive versus
real positive versus false negative and real negative.
The numbers right now that we have are, are hysterically terrible.
Yeah, I agree. And so people just get alarm fatigue and ignore these systems. Yeah.
-- And
-- I mean, that's, that's going to be the challenge right now. You said something.
I think that's really interesting that I've got turning in my brain is
you talk about this has to be perfect.
And the thing is,
I think you're right in the context of encryption because
encryption is a very all or nothing sort of universe.
But
now obviously building perfect things is virtually impossible,
but especially building like a brand new, perfect way to sign and verify things is
a horrifying thought and, and I don't think they can do that,
but it's also creates a very high bar for the point where you can call it good enough.
Here's part of the problem to this is something where when it goes wrong,
-- you're expecting a human being to pay attention and take action and
-- that's true too.
When it does fail,
humans have to get involved and that creates another high
-- bar and
-- so you can't false alarm them constantly.
Yeah. Yeah. Right.
You can't constantly, you know,
it'd be like having a buzzer in your car that any
time if you were not going to break and hit something,
the buzzer goes off.
Well, of course, you're going to probably break and not hit stuff constantly.
But imagine if you had a buzzer that went off every time, you know,
you're driving at 60 kilometers an hour
towards a red light where there's cars stopped while
the buzzer goes off because unless you start braking,
you're going to slam into them.
Right.
That buzzer would get
the hammer treatment
right away
probably.
And,
and that's kind of the situation where we are is we get all these false positives.
We get alarm fatigue, the humans have to ignore it because it's just, it's,
it's tiresome.
Well, and I, I think this, I mean, in the context of cars,
the solution isn't to warn humans. It's to just not let humans drive
-- or take them out of the loop.
-- Well, yeah. Right.
You know, with adaptive braking or whatever stuff or full driving at some point.
So, yeah, and I hate saying it has to be perfect,
but when something alarms and involves a human being,
it has to be close to be perfect.
Or the humans will very quickly learn that it cries wolf and it needs to be ignored.
Yeah. I mean, I kind of agree with that. I think,
I mean, alarm fatigue is a problem, especially in security and, and we all know it,
it's, it's easy to say it's hard to fix.
People who design these systems need to be a lot more aware
and careful
with how
they interact with the users, especially
grabbing their attention and time
and, and I guess we're going to find out
if, if, if it, if it works because I, I do think
a project like this is hugely important. I think it is going to be very easy to goof up
and
I,
I am hopeful
that
the right people are working on this in a way that will be impactful.
Stupid question.
Have we ever seen anybody discuss the metrics of this security product?
How much human time and attention does it eat up? I don't think I've ever seen that.
I bet that's not a friendly number.
Yeah, because I,
I very specifically will not do anything security
wise that requires my care and feeding.
And that's a good,
-- that's a good one.
-- It has to be set it and forget it or I'm not touching it.
Yeah.
I mean
that,
I, I don't know.
Something else we need to think about is this is being touted as a great solution to
supply chain security.
Whereas this is solving such a narrow problem that isn't really even a problem.
Well, it's also solving a problem at the end of the supply chain.
Yeah, there's so much else we need, think about and
hopefully this doesn't turn into a, oh, this project will fix it.
I remember,
I remember from the early Red Hat days
we were transitioning to the Brew build system.
Brew is what Fedora was using to build packages.
And the running joke became brew will fix it for no matter what the problem is.
Brew will fix it
and for supply chain, I truly hope we don't end up in a situation of,
oh sig Store will fix that when it's like, no, it won't.
You can't keep saying that because it's not true.
-- Well, do you know what's in your banana bread?
-- My banana bread has bananas in it.
Yeah, hopefully.
But I mean, that's what always gets me is these, what is in your software and they go,
what do you mean?
I'm like,
give me an exact list of what's in your software
and what's it licensed for and prove to me that,
you know, these four offensive words don't exist in your code base at all.
And they're like, uh
and, and I think like SB
is vastly more important
and the SBA
universe
like the tooling is terrible.
The data formats are terrible like everyone talks about it but,
but it's a hard problem.
-- It is, it is, it totally is.
-- It is straight up a hard
and, and again,
again,
this has to be 100% automated because if you have humans curating your list, it
is out of date and wrong. No questions asked. Right.
Like it has to be a magic system anyway. Anyway, we've run ourselves out of time.
This has been, I feel, I feel like I,
I have no conclusions to either of the things we talked about today.
-- I think it's
-- progress because there are, at least we're trying new things
and,
and that's true.
And I think just making sure you're, you're talking about it,
even if you don't come to a conclusion
after the conversation, just,
just getting these in our brains to think about is I think a big first step.
Well,
and hopefully understanding it a bit better so we can maybe make better decisions,
you know, look at what has and has not worked in the past, what has failed,
look at how current systems fail and, and build on that.
That's a really good point when things do fail,
like write down why it failed and turn that into data you can reuse
because I do think we are notorious for anytime we do something good.
We're like, oh yeah, look what we did this worked
and we still don't really turn it into reasonable data, but like,
especially when you fail, like that's valuable knowledge and we, we,
we almost never talk about it, I guess.
Yeah, we'll, we'll end it there. So, thank you. Kurt. Thank you ever for listening.
Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag You hit us up on social media. Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too, thanks everybody. Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye.