Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 163 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So this is another one of those episodes where Kurt has a secret topic
and he won't tell me what it is and it's driving me insane.
So, all right, man, out with it,
it's not a secret. It's something you have known or should have known about.
Just stop it. What are we talking about?
The death of Python two in
three months? 21 days, 12 hours, nine minutes and 50 seconds. As of this recording,
you have one of those, like retirement calendars up on the wall or something.
Python clock.org.
I will not miss Python two.
I will admit, I, I moved all of my stuff over to Python three some time ago
and I have no regrets.
Was it only 10? I feel like it might have been more,
pretty much
well, and there's some arguments that,
like Python 3.1 wasn't really ready for prime time, which to some degree.
Yeah. I mean, there were, there were problems but, um,
I mean, realistically since about five years ago,
at least Python three has been pretty rock solid and
if your libraries that you depend on haven't been moved,
well, then
you need to move them or find new libraries
that, yeah, you probably need new libraries.
That's almost certainly an unmaintained project at this point.
If they haven't updated it. Well, unmaintainable.
Well, that, that could be too actually because,
but here's the thing, the differences aren't that great if you can't put your code,
like, what kind of horrible code do you have?
Yeah. Well, I mean, yeah. Yeah. Yes.
Anyway, that's, that's all there is to say to that. Why is this our topic? I Python two
is great.
Uh, hacker news, like, lost their collective mind.
That's what hacker news does. That's their job.
If they didn't lose their minds or whatever the topic was being discussed,
I would be very concerned.
Something is wrong with the fabric of the universe.
Well, but it also feeds into that sort of whole, what is wrong with security.
And here's a great example of so Python two, they literally, if you go to the website,
it says
here, let me read a word forward to make sure I get it right.
Sunsetting Python two,
we are volunteers who may take care of the Python programming language.
We have decided that January 1st 2020 will be the day that we sunset Python two.
That means that we will not improve it anymore after that day.
Even if someone finds a security problem in it,
you should upgrade to Python three as soon as you can.
And then they say why they're doing this and how long? And blah, blah, blah, blah.
And that's all fair.
And, I mean,
man, how long was Python two? Around,
like, two decades?
I don't even know if I remember Python one. I don't, I don't know.
Maybe I do and I just don't know. I know,
but I feel like it has been Python two as long as I can remember.
Yeah, it's been anyways.
Here we go.
But, um,
version 1 January 94.
Uh, that's one thing a lot of people forget is how old Python is. Right? Like
Python two,
I
bet Pearl
is older than Python. Oh,
yeah,
for sure. Python 2.0 was released in October of 2000?
Wow. Ok. And I started learning Python in probably, 01 or 02
somewhere in there.
Well,
the biggest thing I think, well,
for what I'm used to is like when R PM depended on Python.
That's kind of what made it real,
you know, all the systems then needed Python.
Um,
I think it's safe to say they, they still do.
I mean, if you run a Linux system,
a nontrivial number of system utilities are Python underneath.
It's, it's what Pearl used to be.
Well, and this got me thinking about the whole security thing. Like,
it's good and healthy
to sunset old code.
Yes. Like 100
has been
on
like like Python three
unicode support man. Like you, you just can't do Unicode and Python two
like you technically can but you can't,
it's still not great but it's, it's better. I actually, so you'll love this.
I remember I wrote
my own backup system back in the day. In fact, it's still in my github.
I named it S four YNC which stood for S3 sync.
And actually Amazon sent me a takedown notice which I ignored and
they never did anything about because I put S3 in the description,
but
I assumed that was good.
Anyway, anyway, so
I was backing up all of my stuff into S3.
It would encrypted and do a bunch of other things. And the challenge was I had
a blue Oyster cult
CD ripped to MP3
and the O in oyster cult
is like an o with the um
lot. Right. Right.
And
it took me longer than I want to admit to
make that work in Python two where you could actually
like, like read store, write and restore
the 01 stupid character.
Yeah,
that sounds about right.
Yep. Yep. Oh, man, those
were.
And, and I, I,
I've not, I don't maintain this or use it.
So please, if, if you go digging, do not, do not use it. It is bad
code.
If,
if somebody is having a problem getting rid of
their Python two to move to Python three.
There's no way that application is ever getting proper security updates.
Uh. Right. Definitely not by definition.
That, that is not a healthy, well, it's not a maintainable application.
Right. And this, I think lends itself to a topic
that we've discussed in the past. I know is the fact that
while you can look at something and say it does or doesn't have CV E I DS,
let's say it does or doesn't have security advisories.
But then there's all this stuff you can look at around it,
all this metadata that tells us way more I think
than a project releasing security advisories.
When was the last release of this thing?
Has there been a release of this thing in six months or a year? Right?
When was the last commit? How many people are active in the issue? Tracker?
What are there stars? Are there forks in the case of github
metadata we have there?
And the fact is if you have a project that only supports Python two,
that's like that is a huge red flag, right?
I mean that that's like saying we'll only run on some archaic version of so
os Well, no, just don't run that then. That's the answer.
Yeah, pretty much like I'm looking. Oh, wow. Oh,
because rail six came up. That's why.
So here's what I love looking, a great example of this is looking at Docker hub,
the official Ruby image updated 17 minutes ago.
The official J Ruby image also 17 minutes ago. Red mind 16 minutes rails, 16 minutes.
Ruby gem slash act.
Three years.
Whoops.
You know.
And,
and then there's a bunch more like four hours a
day but there's a bunch of these that haven't been updated
in years
and they have
100,000 plus downloads.
Yes.
And the sad reality is
there. They may never get updated. And
now some of the people just don't know better because
you always run into people who maybe have been using
a
broker
plus
downloads updated three months ago.
This one, a wo service operator,
half a million downloads eight months ago
because I was looking for Aws Docker images to just
use the S3 uh command line sync and stuff,
right?
None of these things have been maintained in months and
the vast majority of these over a year ago,
does Amazon own those or is it just some random third
party random stuff?
I don't think Amazon makes Docker images available in Docker hub or at least
I'm not seeing an official one. Like if you search for,
you know, a lot of apps, you'll find that official one from like
or or not from an official company,
but like there's an official image that's well maintained like like Ruby is a great
example that that official Ruby image is updated like at least once a day.
It seems like it's crazy up to date,
right? That's cool.
I wonder if Amazon has their own registry. That seems like something they might do.
They have the, well, they have their own registry as a service that you can use.
The
Ecr
Elastic container registry. I want to say. Of course it is.
That seems exactly like how they would
because it's code pipeline plus CCR plus CCS
to get your full stack of container stuff and
G
on.
Um,
so anyway, software maintainability.
Yes,
it is hard.
It is terrible
and it's not just hard, it's,
it's expensive.
You know,
somebody was talking to me and pointing out that in Japan, for example,
there's a huge problem in the Japan software industry and you know what it is
gaming in Japan is awesome.
So all the cool programmers go to gaming companies. Why would they go work at a bank?
That seems fair. Actually, there's even more context I can add to. That is
the in, in Japan,
especially for the large multinationals and banks
which I've dealt with in
the past.
They have a very unique view on quality we'll say,
and they don't
like to use things that change ever.
And so this is one of the challenges actually when
they're dealing with software because software generally changes a lot.
And so
they like to find old versions that don't change
but you and I know what's wrong with that story.
And so it's a very unique way of looking at this, I think.
Yeah, well, you end up programming yourself into a corner and then when, you know,
the world changes and you need well, unicode support,
I would hope they have unicode support.
I mean, they're,
they're Japanese. I feel like they should have that
thing.
One would hope
not. I don't know. But I mean, your problem about
having all of the, the good developers, the young people,
especially going towards writing video games.
I mean, I totally get that too just because
I know that the Japanese population is in decline essentially where
obviously there's fewer people being born than there are dying,
which is just kind of the nature of advanced society, I think.
Well, but the main thing is they have like next to no immigration.
Uh that could be, I, I honestly don't know, I don't know how that all works, but
the point is
it's a small place you can easily get around the country is my understanding. And so
you get on a train and go work in the city for a game company, right?
Whereas I know, for example, I'll pick on the United States here.
There's lots of people who live in a place and they may not have
opportunities so that can sometimes I guess lend itself to this sort of industry.
But yeah, totally, man, I mean, if I had a choice between a game company and a bank,
I'm going to work with the game company, right?
Well, especially when you're younger.
You know, there's that perception that it's cool. It's fun. It's hip
and it probably is.
I mean, I'm old, I'd still go work at a game company. I'm not even going to pretend
I
can't complain though. I'm pretty happy with where I landed.
But, yeah, I, I get that. And, and this is, this is one of the challenges. I know.
I know. I know we've talked about it. I talk about it all the time is
you look at, I'll pick on a local government, for example,
right?
Where they've got some web resources, they're running a website,
they might have some servers
and they need to hire a developer to
work on their like internal pothole application,
for example, which I know you'll rant about momentarily
and
like, are you going to go work for the local municipality making well below
the average wage of someone in your field or are you going to go work for?
I don't know, like the bank or the video game company or something in town, right?
It's,
it's a no brainer.
And now I will say though, however,
uh any of you in public service and you're doing this for the good of humanity.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Because I recognize
you work really hard and you're underpaid and underappreciated
and I'm not trying to make fun of you.
I'm just trying to explain reality to those who don't know.
Well, it's just the economic reality isn't.
And I think the
domain had a good solution to this,
which is you sort of need to centralize this and have,
for example,
the provincial government provide a pothole
app that all the municipalities can use
to me. Come
on tell your story.
Pothole.
Well, so we have a 311 phone number where you can phone and talk to the city, you know,
to find out like when is the pool open or report a pothole?
And so, I mean, part of my concern with this is
the app is actually relatively decent.
You know, it'll take a photograph, you can take an address, stuff like that.
But the problem is the process behind it is so hideously slow. Like,
uh, there's been two weeks now a big pile of rubble,
concrete on the road because somebody ripped out their driveway and
dumped it on the road and then cleaned that up.
And then
I dropped a big pile of rocks on the road, like right in front of where the driveway is.
So it's blocking a lane of traffic basically. And it's been two weeks now and
the city finally got back to me after a few days to ask for more information,
including they need all my personally identifiable information.
And I'm like, well, how are you guys gonna protect this and use this? Because
for example, I reported a problem to Epcor
and
then
por anytime you report a problem to Epcor, they give a survey company,
your phone number to phone you and see how your
experience was with them, which I don't want,
especially when they phoned me at Friday at 9 p.m.
Yeah,
that sounds like someone looking to break into houses,
column people and see who's not at home. Yeah. So you know,
so
yeah, I mean, I get it, it's complicated but this is,
I think one of the advantages of cloud right is let's face it.
You give 100 admins,
a bare metal server and a copy of VMWARE and ask them to install it.
And what are you going to get? You're going to get 100 different installs of VM ware?
Absolutely.
And like 90% of them are probably going to be broken in some really bad way
like they didn't
appropriately or they put the swap partition on the
whatever, right?
There's,
I'm sure there's a million things that can go wrong and degrade performance
versus, you know, Aws or Microsoft or Google.
They, they seem reasonably competent at this and,
but they can also do things.
We just can't like they can run statistical models and be like, oh,
this CPU if we take the tweak at this tiny bit,
we get a half a percent more performance,
you know, you and I can't do that.
Uh We cannot,
you know,
so I, as much as I hate this centralization and this sort of
mass gloaming of, you know, control and whatnot. Especially in the software world.
Like, I would much rather have one or two good libraries than,
well, SSL is a great example. I mean, as much as we dig in on open SSL,
can you imagine a world with 100 poorly maintained versions of open SSL?
Uh, the, the world has that and it's terrible and that's why nobody uses most of them.
And I would like to point out your old man inness of calling it SSL instead of TLS.
True.
Very true.
So SSL is dead.
Well, it should be dead by now.
It's mostly dead now, I think, I think.
But actually, actually,
so let's pick on TLS for a few minutes because you brought it up and the topic of
sunsetting software
and this is a protocol, it's not software, right?
And so there was SSL was what we called
it secure socket layer like a million years ago.
And I think Netscape created it.
Maybe Netscape originally created it to ship uh
credit card numbers around the internet safely.
Sure.
And then that's why it got renamed to TL si
believe is because I think Netscape owned like the,
the trademark on SSL and they wouldn't share.
So they're like, well, screw you guys. I'm going home and then
we just called it TLS. So who cares? And
TLS 1.0 I think is still supported by the major browsers
and they've basically slowly sunset these older versions and we've reached
a point again where it's time to kill off an old
version and it's insecure and you really shouldn't use it.
And the reality is
when this happened
for SSL two
was
painful and took a long time and I feel like TLS,
1.0 is going to die very soon and no one's going to know or care.
Well, I mean, the Canadian government has guidance released last year that,
you know, implements TL OS 1.2 or subsequent versions.
Right. Right.
So even the Canadian government is saying, you know,
if you're running a Canadian government website, you should be TLS 1.2 or later.
Yeah. Don't run 11. It's not much better.
No,
I mean, in a perfect world we'd all be 13.
But in fairness there are still a bunch of
browsers and devices that don't quite do 13.
because again, it's like the whole Python two thing.
These people have stuff that's not maintained or supported in getting updates.
And so they're, they're probably up the creek other ways and, and this,
this is just what gets me is there's, there's no,
it's not like there's a good technological solution to this because
even a good technological solution that makes it like, almost infinitely cheap.
Even if it costs a penny,
people still aren't going to do it.
You know, it's like the, let's encrypt guy pointed out, you know, let's encrypt,
couldn't even cost a penny a decade because bam,
that's a huge roadblock for 90% of people right there.
You know, I got to get a po, I got to get a credit card number. It's free
and people still don't use it. Exactly.
Although it is apparently something like 30% of the, uh,
TLS certificates in the world.
Now.
The public, it's quite a bit. II, I think it's substantial now. Yeah.
Well, it's just so much easier than,
I mean, every,
I love how every other certificate sales place I've ever seen still has like
the command line examples of how to create this thing or a web widget,
which will create it for you.
Right. Let's encrypt has a script.
It's beautiful better than a script.
They have a thing that's included now in many links distributions.
Is it I,
yeah, you have to get cert bought or whatever it's called.
Is it on there? I think you're right. I feel like I just got a certificate a little.
Oh, I did,
I did,
I did because of my.
So, so I have a funny story. I'll tell. Actually when I did this, I bought a domain
because
I brought a little Raspberry Pi with me to Las Vegas
with I, I called it Hacker B BS.
And the idea was you connect to an open access point called hacker B BS and then you
can like tell net or SSH or even use a web browser into an old school B BS
and
I,
I got a real certificate that way because the web
browsers were freaking out when it was trying to load a
self signed cert
if I just registered a domain,
I got my certificate. In fact, I did, I just did an app, get install of Cert
bot
and then use that
to do it all. Now, the, the one sad thing in my story is the Raspberry Pi Zero. I used
only does a 2.4 gigahertz Wi Fi
and there is so much freaking wi fi in Vegas right now.
Like I couldn't even connect to it. 2.4 gigahertz doesn't work
anywhere. That's not like rural.
Like I, I remember doing a war drive in Edmonton about 15 years ago.
So I had like a netbook with like four
USB wi Fi things attached to it and I put one on each window and had them, you know,
hopping around and I drove downtown and like in front of one apartment building,
bam, like 300 S si DS
because like one per apartment,
you know,
and so I, I can't even imagine, you know, prior to the five gigahertz stuff existing,
how terrible these people's internet was.
I remember having this problem. Actually, I was,
was it here?
I don't
know.
And
it was basically, I mean,
and I remember,
I purposely I moved,
I think it was a house I live in now because I have Lat and plaster walls and there was,
there's, there's
a couple of multifamily
housing units around me
and I could see like 20 plus access points on 2.4 gigahertz and it was like unusable.
I mean,
it was unusually bad and I remember I went and
bought a bunch of five gigahertz gear and it's like,
I couldn't believe the difference.
It was night and day.
Oh, yeah. Well, early on especially. But even now, like, it's still, uh
I can see and this is a machine that is
almost below grade,
but I can see three of my neighbors Wi Fi.
Right? Like, you know, and I live in a traditional kind of suburb style environment.
So, you know, even uh
that's, you know, I can basically see all the Wi Fi networks within 100.
Think about all the Wi Fi people have. Now you've got
an access point. Like, for example, I, I'll just, I'll talk about me.
Well, by default,
that's what the I SPS give you because they
don't want to wire your house that costs money.
Well, right. Well, not only that,
I have a Google Wi Fi access point.
My ISP insists on enabling their access point, which I cannot turn off,
but I can circumvent at least.
Is that because you're part of their public Wi Fi thing.
I don't know.
It's probably something stupid like that because remember that's, that's
because I know locally that's what I think Shaw was
doing to build out their wi fi support was,
you know, your, your shaw router had the Wi Fi for you and then the Shaw public Wi Fi
it, it wouldn't shock me if it does something like that. And,
but then I've got a printer
which
right now I turned off the Wi Fi but when, like, if you just buy a printer and turn it on,
it's screaming, hey, look at me, I'm an open access point, right?
You have people with phones that will have their access points turned on,
which I think like, what kind of monster does that?
Your battery life has to be 25 minutes.
But whenever I see it all the time, I love that when I'm on a plane and I like, you know,
I'm trying to connect to the plane Wi Fi and there's
other Wi Fi available. I'm like, what?
So actually I am one of those people, I have a,
a travel access point like a travel router. I carry with me at all times.
And what I do then is I turn it on.
I connect it to the plane Wi Fi and then I can connect like 30 devices through it
because it's a pain in the butt to log everything in.
Because I got my phone, I've got a tablet, I've got like my Nintendo switch,
I've got my computer, whatever.
I've got a ton of garbage
and
I've, I've given up and that's my solution now. I, I bring it everywhere with me.
Anywhere I go, I connect it to the Wi Fi where I'm at and then all of my devices are like,
yay internet and I'm done.
So it's beautiful.
Yeah, that's fair.
But coming back to this, I mean, you know, at least with 2.4 to 5 gig Hertz,
there's like, well,
it boils down to 2.4 gigahertz stopped working.
Uh, yeah, I think, yeah, like it, it wasn't that you wanted to upgrade it,
but it just stopped working.
So you had to upgrade and you know, the same thing. Um Well, not so much.
Same thing with what is it like Wi Fi six
or whatever the new standard thing is being called uh
Wi
Fi six? Yes, they're finally giving it a name. People can understand
why are we now in like 802 11 AC
W or something? I don't forget.
I have no idea. That's the thing. I have no idea what it's called. I remember B and G
uh it
is A
X.
It is A 02 11 A
What does that mean?
Like?
Well, that's kind of weird because not from A to Z. I don't know who cares. Uh
Oh, wow. Their website auto plays music and a video.
That's beautiful.
Well done. Slow clap for you.
Oh, wow. They claim up to 9.6 gigabits per second
and four times more capacity for devices.
So this is definitely going to happen in, like,
commercial spaces where you have to deploy that because
I would buy it today if I could.
I don't think they have any, like, non ridiculously priced gear yet though. Not yet.
But I mean, the, the looking at it, it's definitely better than five gigahertz,
but it's not so much better that I'm going to have to upgrade.
Like I did from 2.4 to 5.
I would be happy to upgrade.
Yeah.
Well,
and I think this is the problem with software is by definition
software works until somebody either attacks it and makes it stop working or
it gets sort of so out of date that, you know, for example,
it only talks SSL and everybody else stops talking SSL.
Uh So let me,
let me ask you a sideways question related to that is if you look on showdown,
you will find people running stuff that is comically out of date.
And in fact, a lot of it has been hacked three ways from Sunday
and it's an instance where people will break in
and kick out the last person who broke in
and you know what I mean?
So
there is an aspect of that, but I think there's still many,
many people who either don't know and they don't
understand what's happening or they just legitimately don't care.
And is there anything that can be done about that problem?
No, because for example, I have a bunch of iot at home. Some of it's,
I
think, higher quality, like my smoke alarms.
I've had them actually replaced twice by Google because
they were false alarming and having other problems.
And so they seem to get forced over the air updates. But I have no idea.
Like my Google wi Fi seems to
it, auto updates itself and it seems to be getting updates and it seems to work well.
But,
you know, I have like a Skylink Net system that definitely doesn't auto update.
And I'm,
you know, I port scanned the thing and it
stopped. So I had to like hardware, you know, recycle it to get it back up and running.
So don't do that.
So clearly it's not high quality software.
And I mean, it, you know, this little puck that
talks, what is it?
700 megahertz, all the devices, you know, cost like 40 bucks or whatever.
So I, I'm not expecting high quality software.
So I'm going into this, you know, with my eyes open,
but
all of this stuff is, you know, I've made sure it's not on the internet,
right, because it would get hacked in a minute on the internet.
Right. Because
the Skylink Net stuff is running software that when I bought it,
I'm assuming the software was one or two years out of date already,
almost certainly.
And
that is, this is one of the problems that I don't know
if we're ever going to see a solution to because I think
it is,
it is really easy. The economics. Yeah. Right. Exactly.
You can't support a $5 device.
Yes,
I agree with that 100%.
Unless there's like some really bizarre
economic marketing branding thing behind it
to make them want to support it. Like IKEA is a good example.
IKEA does a lot of recalls, like all those dresses that tip over.
If you don't attach them to the wall,
you can, like, still walk in with them and they'll give you, what is it,
store credit or a refund or whatever?
Uh, yeah, but that's because they can get sued if people get hurt.
No one gets hurt with your crap iot device.
Well, but there are brands that want to protect their brand and will, you know,
kind of keep supporting stuff. But there doesn't seem to be any strong economic
reason for 99.9% of the stuff to get updates for more than some
minimum amount of time months or maybe a year.
I
have smart light bulbs.
They're led light bulbs. So they should last a good long while.
Probably 10 or 20 years.
Are they ever going to see a software update? Probably not,
probably not.
The good thing is they're not IP, they're, they're on that 700 megahertz.
What is it Zigbee or something? Or XZ is one of them there, there's like three or four.
I think the Z
is one Zigbee is one
Z wave. I think that's the one, I don't know if X 10 counts anymore.
I think
X,
I think actually you can buy, I guess X 10 gear, like, by the pound off Ebay.
Yeah.
The stuff is, like, basically free because there was so much of it there for a while.
But, um,
you know, I expect an led light bulb to last at least 10 or 20 years.
So let me, let's reframe this. We're, we're nearly out of time.
So let's bring it all back around.
So we're saying there's no economic model to support
IOT gear
from a security or just any update perspective.
What about, what about Python? Why are people supporting Python? Right.
That it basically has a, a as close to zero,
you know, sales model as you can get
yet. We're upgrading it and we're s sending the old one.
I mean, Python is one of those things where here's the thing. If I
have,
if I find a bug in Python,
I can report it
and I can potentially fix it or find somebody else to fix it.
If I find a bug in my IOT gear, please explain to me what I do with that bug.
Assuming it's not like IKEA or Google or some big company.
Yeah. Nothing.
So you hit on an important point and I was kind of,
I'm kind of glad you made it here because it was what I was thinking of as well is
you look at something like Python and Python has a vibrant community around it.
It has people who are actively maintaining it.
Many of them do this as their jobs because there's
a financial incentive for an organization to hire an employee,
a Python core developer.
And so it, it's, it's open source at its finest now.
There are all open source libraries, like for example, look at my
github.
It is,
it is basically a cesspool of half finished garbage project
that haven't been updated in years in many cases.
And is that open source? Yes. But it's basically your IOT light bulb situation.
Now, on the plus side, I hope nobody's using my stuff because why would they?
And
it is never going to be updated because I don't care and I'm lazy and whatever.
Although someone, I guess if someone sent me a pull request, I might think about it.
But
the point is,
well, that's, ah,
but you just hit on something if somebody wanted to hijack it
and keep it up to date and fix it and improve it,
they, they could, they wouldn't even have to ask you for permission.
Exactly. Exactly. And this is
one of the interesting things I think we're,
we're seeing with all this technology and the way it works,
it's full of open source is
there are large companies that don't need vibrant communities because they've
hired vibrant communities and they have developers working on this stuff
and you look at something like an IOT vendor that is small and doesn't care and isn't
taking care of their stuff that is like
the cesspool of open source where there's kind of
there,
there's nothing anyone can do about this
because you probably can't touch this stuff.
Half of these things as I understand it now are running
like a really stripped down Linux with PHP on top.
It, it would not shock me, it would not shock me at all.
I mean, if, if you had to build software for an IO light bulb or something for like,
say
$1000 in total.
Right. What, what tool train are you gonna pick?
Oh, all open source stuff. Right.
But I mean,
something you're gonna pick something ridiculously simple and probably older and
stable and easy to make work like PHP or something.
Not, you know,
no Js or Rails or
whatever. Uh I
would trust no Js more than PHP at this point, I think. But
it's not,
it's about doing it cheaply and quickly. Right.
Maybe, maybe, maybe, I don't know. I got to think about this one.
I mean, think about it.
The software budget for probably some of these IOT makers is clearly sub
00.
And I mean, but on the flip side, you know what?
My light bulbs all work except for that one time
they stopped working and I had to reset them all,
which is I love the reset process.
You turn them on and off quickly 10 times.
And I mean, it has to be like click, click, click, click, click, click,
like really fast 10 times.
And then that basically does like a hardware reset of it
and it loses its settings and then you get to read
it.
But of the
eight or 10 light bulbs, I have one of them, for example,
didn't want to get, didn't want to update its firmware. And luckily it, it just
the failure mode was, it didn't update its firmware. It didn't break itself.
So that was
nice.
And then I finally,
after some hardware recess and some other stuff
got the firmware on that thing updated.
And then I had one light bulb that just wouldn't let me add it to the cluster
until again, I did a bunch of hardware resets on it.
And apparently after three or four hardware resets that just
unstuck whatever was stuck. So you turned it off and on again.
And it started like I'm standing there,
I plugged it in to a light switch control thing.
So I can like tap, tap, tap, tap, tap
because I found you can screw and unscrew them.
And if you do it like really quickly, you can do it.
But you really need like to sit at a, at a light switch and go click, click, click,
click, click, click really fast.
It's,
yeah.
Anyway,
this is my life now. Right. Like, I got a hardware reset all my light bulbs because,
you know,
they stopped working.
It. It's true.
So,
I guess I will close with one other thing is
it's easy to talk about open source communities and software.
But I think when we start talking about hardware, it is a very different problem.
And I don't think we have a solution today. We may never have a solution. I don't know.
I think it's starting to have like thing,
things like that. It's
starting.
I do love thing.
I think the biggest problem is
the level of skill needed to get into the software world is very low and the level
of skill to get into the hardware world and
make something sort of work is much higher.
It is true. You are not wrong
and you need a
much larger investment because the gear to make hardware work is expensive.
Well, and the iterative nature of software you build, you,
you write a piece of software, it doesn't work.
You, you change a character,
right?
And it generally doesn't light on fire
and burn down your house and things like that.
So, or sooner than half or, you know,
the magic blue smoke because like even soldering a few joints takes forever.
And if you do it wrong, but if you do it wrong, you're, you're, you know,
good luck troubleshooting that
uh
you know, unless you know what you're doing with a multi meter also.
Well, No, you don't use a multi meter man.
You need that telescope if you're doing anything exciting.
But
I like doing those little kits. Right.
And I, I, one of them,
I actually sort of partially cooked the motor while I was soldering it on,
like it got too hot and it's, you know, the one motor is kind of grumpy.
Now,
uh that, that does happen. You got to be careful with those motors, man.
Well, you got to be careful with everything.
If you, if you overheat almost any component, you can create problems.
But I think we need to call this one. So I guess in summary, we don't know.
But at the same time if you're running Python two, get rid of that.
Yeah, you supported software if you can.
Uh Yeah. Right. Get rid of Python two.
I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, use the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt. Have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.