Hi, old Josh here. As some of you may have heard
the podcast is going to be on a bit of a hiatus for a little while.
Kurt put a thing on Mastodon or he's going through a bit of a family emergency.
So if you wouldn't mind reaching out to him on Mastodon or email,
telling him to hang in,
there would be certainly much appreciated when life gives you lemons,
we make lemonade and burn life's house down.
So I'm using this opportunity to take some of the old episodes we have
and remaster them into something
a little more modern now that the technology and tooling has improved immensely
over the last five plus years that we've been doing the show.
So today we're going to look back at episode 42 which is all about Hitchhiker's guide
to the Galaxy and it was a lot of fun to re listens to it.
And
just for a bit of fact, for later in the show, Kurt did not pad the staircase.
That will make sense later on.
So I hope you enjoy it. Thank you so much. Talk to you all soon.
Hello and welcome to episode 42 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
40 two.
We all know what that means. Right. Kurt.
How
-- will they?
-- That's right. Hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy.
I, I was thinking about this and I, I it needs no intro because let's face it.
If you're listening to the show and you know what Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy,
it's just like, shame on you.
Right.
Like, go just shame. That's all I have to say. There's no excuse.
And yeah, there's nothing else to say about FF So anyway,
episode 42 we naturally thought it would be fun to do something.
Hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy related. So, what do we do, Kirk?
Well, I guess we could sort of dissect the film in its various security related.
-- No,
-- you don't guess that's what we better do because that's what I prepared for.
Like,
uh
when we realized episode 42 is coming,
Kurt said we should do something about Hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy.
And I thought, yeah, we should read the book
and then look for security things
and uh yeah, it's a really long book. So we decided
that the next best thing would be to watch the movie because that only will eat
an hour and a half of my life instead of probably a week of reading.
So, yeah. Yeah, that's good. And, and I guess for those of you who don't know.
Also a radio show
and the radio show in all seriousness is my favorite of the three formats.
I love the radio show,
Juan, just to be clear,
I have not heard the radio show and speaking of the three formats,
there's then also the TV series from, what was it?
1981?
Oh, that's right. That terrible TV show.
It was so terrible. It was awesome.
I
love it as
it crosses that line. It has like that in
the
thing.
It was, it was like the doctor who's special effects team from the BBC,
the way they did.
Zaha's
head is a para,
I thought it was awesome. It was paper mache.
-- It was so God awful.
-- It was clearly fake. That's the best part.
Like they obviously didn't even try to make it real, you know.
Anyway.
So
yeah, we opted for the shortest sort of most up to date format right
time and also I guess, be uh
-- accessible to our viewers. So
-- that's actually something else you, you bring up.
And this is an important point is
when I watched this movie, I, I get annoyed by it for a variety of reasons,
but I know one of the intentions Douglas Adams always had was that
his story isn't set in stone at one time.
And so like he helped write the screenplay, you know,
this isn't just some crazy Hollywood screenwriter that went nuts
and
he wanted it updated to match the times he didn't want it to take place back in what,
the seventies or sixties or whenever the original happened.
And so
it,
as much as I get annoyed by some of the things
I'm very sympathetic to the fact that they updated the story.
Like Arthur has a cell phone.
You know, that, that's cool.
And which, which was even funny though because it's not,
it's not like an iphone or anything.
I'm like, ah,
he's got a
gray phone.
I kind of like that. They at least, yeah, it's a smartphone, at least.
Although if he'd had a flip phone, it would have just looked ridiculous.
-- Was it a
-- smartphone? And I thought it was just a candy bar quasi.
Well, it was, it was a candy bar phone but it wasn't like a flip phone or anything
and it kind of had like, graphics on it and stuff and, you know,
anyway, let, let, let's dive in, man, let's dive in.
I'm gonna start with, with that Dolphin. So
I know I hate that song. I'm not even going to pretend like, I hate that song.
That song revolts me when I hear it and I don't have a good reason for it.
It just,
I hate that intro and I think that sets me up for failure for the rest of this movie.
Well, I mean,
I have six year olds so I get to hear Baby Shark 10 times a day off of youtube.
You know,
I do remember those days and in fact, my daughter was, what was she about? I
think when, when frozen came out and that song let it go.
I heard that at least 10 times a day for months.
My one son does that song and it's hilarious because he's just,
he only does like the few sort of highlights
and he literally stands there with his hands in his pockets and
then he, like, do a twirl on his heels.
He'll do like the hair sweep gestures
and like, just occasionally belt out, let it go, you know, like sort of off key.
I'm glad you, you did an escape but he let it go craze. So, anyway, anyway,
I
don't think there's any legitimate security topics or nuance in, in the theme.
-- Oh, there's
-- a huge one.
Well, it's a huge one. Well, they did say they tried to warn everyone.
-- Lack of
-- communications. Yeah. How many, how many times has a firm been warned of
a, not a potential hack but an actual real hack. Like a hack going on and just been like
there
or how many times has a security researcher tried to report
a vulnerability to a company only to be shuffled to,
like, tech support who's like, oh, you don't have a contract with us.
We can't listen to you.
Yeah, I think that's, but that,
that's an overarching theme to the whole story of the fact
that there are many warnings in many places for many reasons
and they are almost universally ignored and
it's, it's less so in the movie. But in the, in the book, obviously, like Lar
warns these guys countless times of their peril and they never listen
-- to him and they usually yell at him and tell him to
-- show
if they did though, the story wouldn't have advanced,
which I think is also an important point.
-- Sometimes you have to do dangerous things.
-- That is true.
So, anyway, anyway, let's ignore the movie and we can open up on Arthur Dent
house. And
so
the plans are in the cellar.
-- Oh, no, no,
-- no, it's worse than that.
But that the 1st 30 seconds of the film,
he smashes his head on that stairway overhang,
apparently every single day of morning,
why didn't he put some padding on it or a warning sign or?
Ok.
So they, they miss this in the movie, but in the book and the radio show,
they kind of come to the point that he is hung over.
Well, that's my point. Right.
He should fix,
you should deal with that issue and something about it because nobody does,
like he's going to smash his head every single day.
Kurt,
normal humans will smash their head every day
and they will never do anything about it.
And that's the,
-- that parallels our whole security industry
-- because I actually
have to do this at my parents' cabin.
There's a staircase and the way it comes down it's
like an inch and a half shorter than me.
Did you pad it?
I'm actually, I didn't do that last year, but this year I am padding it.
You say you're padding it?
-- I'm going to, I'm going to check on you next year and see if you've padded
-- it.
-- It's on my to do list.
-- I bet there's a 50% chance of you not doing it.
-- I'm doing it actually next week
-- now you will to prove you wrong. But
-- anyway,
-- I just all smashed from my ass.
It
really hurts.
But anyway,
so the first thing I realized is when Arthur Dent is talking to Mr Prosser,
who is the gentleman with the briefcase who works for the government.
And he tells him that the plans have been un displaying the planning department
for, you know, the last six months or a year or whatever it was. And
it occurs to me that
this is how the security rules work in these organizations for like, yeah,
we've got all these rules but you know,
like they're literally in the basement in a locked finally cabinet, you know,
and the sign
use lavatory with the sign says a beware leopard like
-- that is basically how it works
-- well or even vendors,
how many vendors have a security page where like
you either know the keywords to find it in Google or you bookmarked it because
you know, some vendors you go blah, blah slash security.
And it just works and there's a security page there but
a lot of vendors you do that and it's like nothing.
I mean, that, that's totally true. Is
it?
It's very much that when you are dealing with bureaucracy,
if you know the combination to kind of get through all the doors of bureaucracy,
you're fine.
But if you're a normal person you're screwed because there is
no way you're gonna figure out what you need to do.
Which, which as soon as I saw that I thought of security
where if you know the security magic words and you
know how to talk to the industry and the people,
you're fine.
Right. No big deal. You can get anywhere you need to go.
But if you're a normal person who kind of just shows up, you're doomed.
You, you have no hope. Is that a bad thing necessarily?
Yes and no, I, I think we, we do miss the, see,
I think it does lead to false negatives in that stuff that really should be.
It
isn't or, and I mean,
how many cases of researchers finding something and giving up have happened?
-- Well, we, we literally by definition don't know. Yeah,
-- I mean
that, yes, exactly. But at the same time,
you also can't have your security team inundated with pointless requests.
So it, I don't know.
I think there's a balance you have to find and, and I think that we,
we tend to fall more on the kind of bureaucratic,
let's keep everyone outside except those who know the secret knock.
Part of what I've been doing with the DWF is, I mean, that, that's why, you know,
you have to use your email address so we can contact you.
And also
so long term it's like, oh, that's Tavis Ormandy or? Oh, that's Josh Bresser's.
Yeah,
I will deal with him right away because I know it's
not going to be very painful and it's probably real versus,
you know, like, I, you know, looking at these CV requests, I mean,
some of them are just terrible.
Like, it's just so poorly formatted or the information is so sketchy.
I'm like, I'm not going to spend two hours fig, you know, trying to figure this out.
Yeah, I, I'm familiar with that.
I, I remember getting some of those but,
but I must say if Tavis shows up you've got a lot of work to do.
Yeah.
Especially if he shows up at, like Friday at four o'clock and, you know,
you're really up the creek,
your weekend is ruined.
But, uh, well, and even simple instructions, like, I, you know,
you have to put in a working email address for me to, you know, be able to contact you
to be able to agree to the terms of use, for example. And, like, people fail to do that.
Yeah.
I mean, it seems totally reasonable anyway, anyway,
let's let's keep on track because we've got a lot of movie to cover.
So, so the next thing I want to talk about is the
Vogons are an A PT attack
where there is literally nothing you can do and even trying to plan for it
-- is a waste of time.
-- Well, but see, the VGOs
aren't even the A PT attack. It's spoiler alert here.
-- No,
-- you don't need to say spoiler alert.
We've ruined, we're, we're gonna ruin this movie
again
if you haven't seen it. Like, why are you listening?
What's, what is the, the lady's
Tricia mcmillan Trillion?
-- No,
-- not Trisha,
the lady that was the assistant or whatever to
the president and is like orchestrating this whole thing.
You know, the dark haired lady.
-- Oh, I don't think she's,
-- does
-- she
-- not have, yeah,
maybe she doesn't have a name.
She has a name
but she's the actual attacker. She's the one that engineered this whole thing.
The Volga are just the tool, right? They're just following the paperwork.
Like literally, you know, there's a destruction order that
-- Zao signed off on. Ok.
-- But, but regardless of who sent them,
the point is that the earth cannot stop the votes
no matter what they do.
And basically, unless you are in another A PT organization,
you cannot stop these people no matter what you do.
Oh, you're going to have some employee that'll take a $10,000 bribe.
That, that's my whole point. Right. That is the point is
anyone who has a PT is part of their threat model. Like
that's ridiculous.
It's like saying that, that, you know,
aliens attacking us is part of your threat
model and you're going to defend against it.
I think you can have it as part of your threat model.
But maybe you either assume the risk or for example,
you have compensating measures like,
oh we're just going to log the heck out of everything.
So in hindsight, we can figure out what happened or, you know,
roll back transactions if needed,
you know, or chase the money down or whatever, right?
You know, banks are a good example of that, right? You can attack banks
and in many cases they have been attacked and compromised and then they just,
you know, basically, like claw back the money, you know, undo like
a great example, Ethereum,
they had that situation where a guy found a flaw and like scored several.
Was it millions or tens of millions of dollars? It
and they just essentially went. Yep. No Mulligan do over.
Yeah, we promised we'd never do this
but we're doing it revoking transactions or whatever.
And I think even more to the point though, it's,
it's the whole point of the bypasses is like, why do we do?
Security? Security has to be done.
You have to build security into your product and your process and your company.
That's true.
That's so true. You got to build bypasses. This bypass is going to be built.
How many places actually, like if you literally went up to them and said, like,
why are you doing security?
You would have a sensible answer other than like, well,
because we have to or PCI compliance or, you know, some other form of because,
yeah, and you know, actually that's one thing that I talk about a lot is
compliance is a reasonable driver of security.
There's nothing to be ashamed of to say. I'm only doing this for compliance.
Well, and like, as a vendor, for example, we have to do security otherwise, you know,
people will buy our products.
-- That's the whole
-- point, right? Is when I'm writing up security features
for products,
I will, I mean, I'm, I'm quite clear, I'm like, look,
we're doing this for compliance.
There's no other reason this isn't about goodwill.
This isn't about because it's the right thing to do what, blah, blah, no compliance.
We're doing it because compliance and then people relate to that though too.
They're like, all right, we have to do this because if we don't,
you know, people can't buy a product
and that makes sense whereas it's like, ok,
uh this is hard to do and I don't want to
do it and it's really just for the good of humanity.
So let's put that down farther on the list. Right?
I mean, that's what happens.
Well, that's what gets me with the whole a PT thing, right?
Like by definition, you look at any piece of software,
they all have security flaws, they all have new security flaws, by definition,
any piece of software you look at
is going to have security flaws,
you know,
and what gets me is like, even like really dumb stuff,
like you should probably remove code that is no longer active.
Like that is one of the fundamentals of security coding, right?
Like get rid of dead code. And I mean, even open SSH got this wrong.
I
know
and to the point of disclosure,
like that's like they literally made a rookie mistake that resulted in a terrible,
terrible flaw.
I know, I
know. All right. Anyway, no, let's keep going.
Do you have any notes before we move on from this section?
Well, just, yeah, that sort of that whole security notification process
and you know what it really reminds me of is like,
they, well, in this case,
they sort of intentionally made the notification process difficult.
So nobody would kick up a fuss, but like how many vendors do that?
And it just costs everybody like
an enormous amount of pain. Like that's one thing I love
with the open source world is, you know,
we're going to be moving to a model where every single
flaw hopefully in the open source world gets a CV and
that CV gets published in the official, you know, CV, database of miter,
like
the second or the minute or the hour it goes public either, like,
if it's public to begin with or, you know, once it's an embargoed.
So that, that notification thing
is trivial. You know,
and especially, like, because I just,
I know what people spend and how much time and effort it takes now to, like, monitor
all of these open source providers for security updates and stuff.
Oh, man, it's bonkers. Absolutely.
You know, like when I found out like, one of the firms I was working at charge, like,
you know, $250,000 a year for a basic threat feed.
I'm like, well, you know, wait a minute.
That's like two full time people, two full time people can monitor all of this.
We're talking thousands of projects now, you know,
probably a core of several 100 that really matter everywhere.
But I mean, yeah, these things are, you know, and there's a, like you look at the,
well, the Linux kernel is always my favorite because it's like, you know,
can you imagine reading every commit,
-- how big of a team you would need? Uh,
-- one really smart person could do it
descent.
I know it's complicated. It's
-- complicated, you know.
-- That's, and anyways, yeah.
So, I mean, it's, I just, I wish people would have more transparency and more,
you know, better data structured, data collected data, you know,
that, that whole data curation piece really needs to happen more.
It'll get there. It'll get there.
Well, we,
no one's really in charge of that and I think you pushing with the DWF will have
hopefully
some fantastic outcomes. All right.
So the, the one other thing I want to point out in,
in the beginning when Arthur is at the party talking to Trillion for the first time,
they have a record player there and he bumps it out of the way.
Like who freaking uses record players at parties. Come on, guys.
That's not believable.
I don't know.
-- No sales were
-- up, not in 2005.
Like,
-- well, true. Yeah, I was definitely going down the toilet then
-- I don't believe it.
No way. I don't believe it.
But I mean, it's just one of those movie tropes, you know, I don't
know, it's a guy at a party
bumps the record just as he says, something incredibly rude and obnoxious.
It's a plot vehicle. I understand that I'm just saying. Anyway.
-- Anyway. Oh
-- one minor point.
So like do you have a plan for the end of the world or even a
plan to deal with your house being knocked down or can you even find your towel?
Right. Most people can't even find their towel, let alone have a plan.
Look, if my house gets knocked down, like whatever,
the least of my worries is gonna be
anything
but the horrific event that caused that to happen,
which will probably be something outside of the realm of sanity.
Funny story.
Housing demolition companies have been known to get the address wrong. They do.
I know.
And you google that and it's like, are you kidding me? Like,
uh, but I guess, you know, you're a housing and, and these guys literally are like,
yeah, we started knocking down the house and then we noticed it was full of stuff but,
you know, whatever
we have the paperwork.
I know. But
ok, you actually bring up a great point is, do I have a plan for my husband?
And I don't know why would I me spending time
on that is ridiculous because the odds of it actually,
I mean,
I might as well plan for winning the lottery
because I suspect there are two very similar events.
Granted,
I know there are people who plan what they're going to do when they win the lottery,
but practically speaking, like they're wasting their time too,
although their time doesn't have a lot of value, I imagine.
So, they're probably not wasting very much
and, and security falls into this trap is we have to plan
things that matter in ways that matter.
Because if you're doing pie in the sky security planning,
you're wasting your time.
And when you're at a, at a, you know, at a company, you're wasting money.
If you're wasting time, let's face it.
Well, yeah, it comes back to that whole, you know,
why are you doing security and most places are not going to present, you know,
a report with, you know, what we're putting in, what we're getting out, what the,
you know, expected return on investment is
most don't even know. Let's face it. Most of them have no idea.
I mean, that's the reality of it anyway. Anyway, let's keep going. All right.
They get out of the heart of gold.
And do you know what the first thing I realized
when I started watching that scene this time?
And I guess, I don't remember this from the last time I watched it is
they say the letter Z
instead of Z
because in all the other media I've consumed on hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy is,
it's
right. It's on
ZZ nine plural Z alpha, which is the,
the, I guess coordinates of the earth
in the Hitchhiker's Universe.
But because this was a Hollywood movie, they say ZZ nine
Z
alpha. And I remember I'm watching it. I'm thinking this is crazy.
They don't say Z, they say Z.
So, yeah, that's funny.
-- I'm not totally not security related but,
-- oh,
actually I do have one thing going back to the beginning but here's the thing,
it's not so much.
Do you have a plan if all the dolphins vanish? But would you even notice?
I would not notice because I don't live anywhere near the water?
Well, and by that, I mean, like, you know, how many times have there been like
situations where people are like, oh, yeah,
the ids or the IDP went silent like a week ago.
-- It happens all
-- the time.
Yeah.
Yes.
-- You know,
-- I, I feel like that should maybe be something people, like,
-- check into
-- people shouldn't do this.
You should have a system in place capable of finding these problems.
Like, if the I DS doesn't check in for an hour, you know,
something's wrong and you should be triggering emails
and text messages telling someone something is broken
yet people can't do that.
It has to be a
chance.
So anyway,
the other thing I loved about the heart of gold is the knife that makes toast.
How did they get that?
A
TS A man likes,
well, the concern I have though is one side of your toast would be nice and well,
toasty hot and the other side would be cold.
You'd have to cut a slice and then discard the cold piece
and then cut a new slice and then you'd have two very warm
sides of one piece of toast.
-- So
-- it needs to be like sort of like the Dolf Mall, the Darth Maul Saber,
like where it needs to be like two knives.
So when you cut it, you get both sides nice and warm and toasted. But on the flip side,
here's the cool thing for making peanut butter sandwiches.
You would have the side that's cold that you could put peanut butter on and
the side that's hot that like you could hold and put in your mouth.
So you get that like still nicely toasted bread, warmth thing going on.
But without that nasty melted peanut butter.
Ok.
Have you not ever put peanut butter on a hot piece of toast where
it gets instantly super gross and runny and like dribbles out the side.
I have a handful of, we say
personality quirks
and
one of my personality quirks is that I refuse to eat peanut butter on toast.
And I have never had peanut butter on toast. And the idea of eating it revolts me.
So I will never eat peanut butter on toast.
-- Would
-- you eat peanut butter on bread on toast? I love
it. I love it on bread.
I eat it in cracker skirt. I eat it with pretzels.
But for some isn't like my, my brain will not let me eat peanut butter on toast.
See, now, if I want to feed I wanna like, now II, I,
this is terrible to admit to but now I'm imagining some sort of like
saw movie plot that involves you eating the toast with peanut butter on it.
-- Yes.
-- That doesn't sound weird at all
anyway. No, I, I don't know.
I've never put peanut butter on warm toast and, and I never will.
Well, because it gets running and it just, it dribbles out and it's a pain in the butt.
I, I can imagine that. Iw peanut warm peanut butter it melts regardless.
You're talking about peanut butter.
I'm, I'm complaining about the TS A, letting me take my toaster knife on it.
-- Well, but it's a private, it's a private aircraft or spacecraft.
-- Yeah, I guess it is.
That's true. Well, was it who owned it?
Well, the government, but
it wasn't like a public transport thing. It was.
Yeah. Well, yeah, I guess it's true because you figure if you got, say a naval vessel,
I'm sure they aren't running all the,
the sailors through a metal detector on their way on and off the ship.
Well, I've actually read funny stories where, for example,
where military units are being transported with all their gear.
And so these guys are carrying, you know, granted,
they don't have the ammunition with them.
They're carrying things like, you know, bayonets and knives
but, and they were literally
confiscating like fingernail clippers.
This is way back in the day, like right after 911 when things were kind of insane.
-- That's
-- all Vogons.
Basically,
you have your insane list of rules and you're going to follow them no matter what.
And it doesn't have to make sense. You're just going to follow the rules and
I mean, unfortunately when you end up in security situations,
that's what happens because it's dangerous and if you screw up, you're like,
I followed the rules.
Now, I felt well,
but I also wonder because sometimes you can't tell people why the rule exists.
Like that whole laptop thing in the Middle East
on the airlines that we discussed last episode.
Right. Like,
they can't tell us kind of,
or apparently they can't tell us what the real reason of it,
you know, for a variety of security reasons, you know,
maybe they don't want to disclose the source or whatever.
Ok. Yes. But let's face it.
If you have soldiers bringing real weapons onto
airplanes and you take away their fingernail clippers,
you're a fool for real.
Well, they don't need a nail clippers. They have a bayonet,
I mean.
Right. But anyway, anyway, whatever
it is what it is. Uh, the other thing I loved from kind of that, that whole scene
is the heart of gold flees the
Bogans chasing them
and one of the Vogons says, bring me the request to pursue fugitive form.
And I was like that, that is so great. I love the obscene bureaucracy.
They give the Bogans and that's the one thing
actually in the movie I think they did really well
is the Bogans are way more bureaucratic in the movie than they are in the,
the radio show.
Well,
and see that leads actually to sort of one of the questions or points I have where,
you know, they actually have a process in place for that.
You're like, no,
think about it.
-- Ok.
-- No, no, but
it's a, it's a made up story
and obviously they just make the Bogans overly bureaucratic in every possible way.
I mean, it's like later on when they're trying to free Trillion
and they bring
the the regular prisoner release form and
they needed the presidential prison release form,
which is blue.
Yeah, which they actually have a copy of, I mean,
a specific note of that but that small office,
-- of course they do because it's a made up show man
-- as much as you can hate on the Vogons.
They did think through like pretty much every eventuality and have a form for it
except where Arthur goes to get the document, there's like 12 slots, right?
They clearly whatever, it's a movie, right? It's fun. It's fun and funny.
And, and anyway, the so, so also the next thing I'm going to bring up is is 42
where
I, I realize watching this when they cut to the scene where they show deep thought,
give the answer of 42 is the answer of 42 is technically correct
because they asked a question and deep thought,
gave them the answer to their question.
They didn't ask a question so much.
They did ask a question, they asked the wrong question
-- and well, they asked an overly broad question.
-- But here's my point is
people come to security folks like us,
they ask these questions
and,
and I now I'll say these days I try really
hard to ask follow up questions and be helpful.
But I remember there was a day when I would give them the answer.
That was technically correct. It wasn't useful in any way
and they were usually too embarrassed to ask a follow up question or
ask for proper help and they'd leave and I knew they'd leave,
which is why I did that.
And I think that's very common
in, I mean, in the computer industry in general,
but especially in security or we're, we're technically correct all the time.
-- It's not helpful.
-- But, well, it's true of any technical field.
Is that the correct technical answer also has a lot of nuance typically.
Yeah, I mean, ok, that's fair.
And if you don't have a really, if you don't have that deep knowledge,
you don't get that nuance.
That is true. I
won't just
-- with that. So,
-- you know, I do the same thing too.
Now where somebody asks me a question, I'm like, wait, what, what, like,
what's really going on?
Like, what are you really trying to ask? Like, what's the problem?
Yeah, like I hear the question you formulated, but I've heard that question before.
I know how this conversation ends.
So let's try something different.
You know, actually, you know,
it's really funny as I'm having a lot of conversations
like that now where I'll talk to certain customers,
I went down and they'll say
I need Kose
authentication.
And the first thing I say is Kerberos
is rarely the right answer to any question. What are you actually trying to do.
And it turns out they need active directory
support and they found out like it works with
Kerberos.
I'm like, ok, there's better ways to do this. Like
Kerberos is terrible if we don't want to use that, if we can avoid it.
That and that's one of the things I love.
So, going back a bit, you know,
is the whole hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy book because
sort of skip them going on to the Vogon ship.
-- I think we should cover that a bit.
-- Is there anything?
But the thing is in the movie, they basically show up.
Well,
the fact that they pick up Hitchhikers and don't
know they have people who boarded the ship.
Well, they don't though the Drei
did it in, in the book and the radio show,
but they don't like they cover nothing of value in the movie.
They, they get on the ship,
they get captured, the terrible poetry is read to them.
And in effect, even on the, once you see the Vogon,
he's sitting on the deer that the Vogons said, I forget the name of it.
He's crushing the crabs
and there is zero explanation of that in the movie.
But if you obviously read the book, you understand that what happened on
Boere is the Vogons of all first and the planet felt bad and made
all these beautiful other creatures that the Vogons just continue to murder and,
and kill because that's what they do.
But anyways, the, the thing I love about his Checkers guide to the galaxy
is, do you remember why
it sold so well?
Because it is slightly cheaper than the, the encyclopedia Galactica.
And it has the word don't panic written in large friendly letters on the cover.
Exactly. So it's not as technically correct, but it's actually somewhat useful.
It, it's not useful. It just is cheaper and has don't panic written on the cover,
which in fact Arthur says at one point,
that's the first useful thing anyone said all day.
Exactly.
Like, how often have we been in security situations where like,
literally the first thing is like, don't panic.
-- Uh
-- You know what's really funny about that is a million years ago,
one of the first jobs they ever had,
I worked with this guy who was, I mean, he was an old dude and this was in the,
the mid to early nineties
and this guy was already fairly old. So, like, he'd, he'd been around
and I'll never forget that like,
a server would crash or the network would go down or something crazy would go on
and I'd like, run into his office and be like,
hey, Pete, like bla bla bla,
you know, he'd be like, hey, dude, sit in that chair right there.
You just need to chill out for a minute.
I'm like, but, but yeah, I mean, nothing working and he's like, it's OK,
we could sit here for two minutes and nothing's gonna break.
And I'm like, it's already broke and it's like, then it's fine. Right.
And I remember at the time I'm like, this, this old guy is crazy,
but now
I'm like,
he got it.
Like, you can't, if you panic, you fail, like, period, you end up like,
deleting the whole file server because you went crazy and type the wrong thing.
Well, like that, that classic, uh, what was it?
Git lab where they, like, just, they had a small problem and they made it much,
-- much worse
-- where they deleted all of their,
-- their data
-- and thank God they happened to have a snapshot,
right? That was a few hours old. Otherwise they would have lost like a day or two.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. That's crazy. It happens though, man. I mean, I get it right.
I get why it happens anyway.
Oh, well, 11 thing that was never really covered in the book or anywhere was so,
apparently the Vogons are immune to Vogan
-- poetry.
-- They write the Bogan poetry.
Well, I could get the author not being affected by it but other Vogons,
other Vogons are unsympathetic bureaucratic creatures.
Why would they be affected by
poetry? They probably enjoy it.
So, I guess, uh, what that kind of leads to is, I mean,
do we have any security measures that we
can use to essentially punish bad guys or make
their lives more miserable that we are immune
to because every time I've seen a security measure
they almost always involve some trade off of usability.
I mean, there's that classic thing of, you know,
like you have to have tradeoffs for security. I mean, that's the old trope.
Right.
No, no, no,
-- there are no tradeoffs. Security loses, end of story.
-- Well, exactly. Right.
And that's the thing, you know, so,
you know, that old trope of, well, you can't have security without, you know,
somehow making it just horrible for people to use this, you know,
which doesn't work.
I'm just, yeah, I kind of was thinking about that, you know, what can we do
to make security better?
-- That doesn't, you know, hurt anybody other than the bad guys
-- today.
I don't think we can answer that.
Well, a great example would be like re listing for email servers,
right where it's just, I'm going to delay you sending the email by a few minutes
because a legit email server will then retry.
But like a spammer won't, the spammer is just moving on.
-- But
-- that stopped the spammers for a while.
But now the spammers just use like legitimate mail servers to send the mail.
-- They got around it.
-- Right.
-- You know,
-- but that, that cut down on the drive bys.
It did.
Oh, it did. And it was hugely effective at one point.
And I remember when the gray listing stopped working is when
I stopped running my own mail server because I thought there's,
I, I give up like you win, spammers, you win.
So this is the end of part one of episode 42.
It's quite long, so I decided to split it in half.
So thanks for listening and I will see you all next week.