Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner of Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So take two.
It always amuses me when, when we have just the,
-- the magic of the
-- podcast in fairness. I've never seen that error message before.
It's
so.
So for you dear listeners,
we started recording a podcast and like literally three minutes into it.
We just had a bunch of ridiculous,
weird technical problems and so we've thrown everything away
-- and we're starting again
-- and here's the best part.
We have no idea what failed or why. So I just went to a different computer.
-- That's right.
-- Computers are magic and we don't know and we don't care. So, whatever.
-- So anyway, anyway, in
-- fairness, last time a reboot did fix it.
-- Why not?
-- If I fix it? I mean, it made the problem go away for at least.
-- Well, the 30 minutes we needed to record it.
-- Amuses me that when
my Children come to me with a technical problem, the first thing I say is,
did you restart it?
And they say no. And then I say, go restart it and come back.
If it doesn't work and they almost never come back again.
I've literally, yeah, like Felix with his online classes and stuff, like,
just once in a while, but
just,
did you try restarting Chrome?
Ok. Do that like that? That's all I got, son.
Like, I, I don't know how to troubleshoot this.
Right. Right. Or, or the other day, my daughter says, Dad, what's the Wi Fi password?
And I said, why do you need the Wi Fi password? And she goes, my tablet won't connect.
And I said, just restart it and yeah, sure enough, it restarted and it was fine.
See, I was clever. I did the, I printed out the QR code with the guest Wi Fi password.
So now people just have to point their device at it and boop they're online.
Well,
you can do that. I didn't know you could do that.
Yeah,
there's a special string that you just literally Google Wifi
password QR code and there's a generator for it.
There's one that runs like on your clients.
So you don't have to worry about your password getting all lowered, knows where.
But it's basically the string is Wi Fi Focal and blah, blah, blah.
And if you have like an iphone, well, if you have an Apple device, it just, it's like,
OK, I know what that string means.
You want me to join that Wi Fi
and if you have an android, depending on what app you're using,
it may or may not be smart enough.
Whoa. That's really cool. I need to look into that.
It takes literally three seconds and it's so much faster than trying
to teach people how to type in your Wi Fi password.
Well, in my Wi Fi password, I have two. My guest Wi Fi password is comically bad.
And my other Wi Fi password will say isn't great, but I don't care.
So if I could only have one
and then
just use a QR code because like we've talked about this at length on the show,
I treat my home network as an adversarial zone.
So I don't care who connects to it.
Nice.
No, it's just, it's just easier, right?
Because, and also the beauty thing, you know,
people don't have to go into their settings and look around with it.
They like with an I device,
you just literally point at the cameras smart enough to
recognize a QR code and smart enough to go.
I know what that QR code means and literally one tab
they're online.
Wow, that's awesome. I need to do that.
It's a way better experience.
So,
speaking of which Apple in the last couple of weeks
and some of the security news is kind of older,
but it's just finally now kind of taking effect.
So we're actually going to be using a timer to bang through some of these, right.
Yeah, I have, I have no idea what's going on. Kurt claims to have a plan.
-- So
-- the long story short is like,
there's literally half a dozen really kind of interesting security things.
Apple is doing some of which are contentious and some of which are also contentious,
but then other vendors followed,
which kind of says it's probably the right thing to do. Like if you're
like, basically if Apple does something and then Google and Microsoft go, yeah,
I guess we should too, then, you know, it's actually probably the right thing to do.
Maybe, maybe. So, let's start with the quickest, easiest one.
Apple has forced quote unquote one year certificate, lifetimes.
It's actually 398 days, which is, what, one year plus a month plus,
like an extra day or two.
-- I mean,
-- that's not just Apple, that's been driven by
-- a number of organizations.
-- Well, Apple was the first to do it. And so c, a
forum, the certificate of authority
browser forum where, you know, they're supposed to cooper and set this stuff
had, you know, they,
Apple and some others had pushed for this last year and the c of course, were like, no,
we don't like this, blah, blah, you know,
you've already driven it down from 10 years to five years to two years or whatever.
And Apple's like, ok, and then Apple's like, ah, we're doing it anyways.
-- I
-- think that's great.
And I think I'm going to give,
let's encrypt all of the credit for this because I think without, let's encrypt,
-- we couldn't have this conversation
-- and Claude flair and a couple others.
But
more to the point like
I, to put it bluntly and I love the counter arguments for this.
So we're going to start the timer.
But basically I love the counter arguments are, oh, you know,
this will increase costs for people.
Well, you just knock that one down. We, we got, let's encrypt.
So that, that one's dead.
The second one and I love is, oh, this creates a lot of manual work for people.
Let's encrypt.
Well, to which I say, if you're manually managing your certificates,
you're already doing it wrong.
This just exposes that you're doing it wrong,
you know, kind of forces you to acknowledge it.
And then of course, there's the whole thing.
Well, like certificate makers are saying that this is somehow less secure.
Exactly
-- if you read the news about any of these companies over the last couple of years.
-- Yeah.
And you know, people are pointing out that like, let's face it. All right.
Certificate revocation.
Remember, like 20 years ago, we were like, oh, certificate revocation.
That's something we should probably deal with.
And OK, you know, we'll do certificate revocation list, right?
Which is literally a list of revoked certificates.
And it worked so well that every time there's a major incident now,
all the browser vendors have to ship an update
with like a manually jammed in CRL to like
block the, the certificates because to put it bluntly crls and then the,
the next one online certificate,
something protocol. What's the s stand for? Nobody cares.
But the point is like number one,
it's a privacy disaster because every time you visit a website,
you have to check with the central authority.
If their certificate is still valid or not.
Number two, if that central authority is down,
then you should probably not go to the site because that means you're being man
in the middle and being blocked from seeing that you're getting a bad certificate.
So
of course, nobody does that because it just breaks the web
right. 99% of the time, everything's fine.
-- It's just the, the side is down
-- prior to cloud flare.
None of these vendors,
the C A vendors could actually run an O CS P
service that was like more than 90 some percent reliable.
And I don't mean like 99.999 I mean, like 95
I would be shocked if it was even that high when
I turned on whatever the mode was to fail hard,
it was unusable.
So the, so there, you know, Apple went ahead with this Google and Microsoft fa
so I think it's the right thing to do.
I agree
100% good job.
I'm not giving Apple any credit for this.
How
do
we
make that?
Ok.
So that's a certificate thing banged out, that's done then the next thing is
the uh where to go, where to go, where to go. Strong arms. Yeah, we did that. Oh
Then the next thing we're going to bang up,
we're going to give ourselves a few more minutes for this.
So Apple
is basically declining to implement
16 new
web based API S in the Safari web browser
officially for privacy concerns.
Yeah, you sent me that story yesterday and I love this.
II, I haven't looked at what Firefox has done.
I feel like they will probably do something similar,
maybe not as strict as Apple in some ways because I think Firefox is
occasionally a different beast.
But I think this is one of those examples of the existing browser market,
I think is heavily focused on collecting your user data.
I mean, that's basically, I mean,
that's functionally Google's whole market and it's different with apple
and so they can start taking a stand here,
I think and I hope they do.
Well, let's give a bit of context. So these, these API
S are interesting actually, I mean,
there's the web Bluetooth which allows Bluetooth or sorry,
which allows websites to connect to nearby Bluetooth le devices.
So for example, that would be useful like I have a bunch of IOT stuff that you know,
I manage through a mobile app.
Well, honestly,
it would be kind of nice if that stuff could
be managed through a website app because you know,
somebody pointed out like,
we're at a point now where every time you go to a coffee shop, they're like,
you need to install our app so that you can order stuff online.
And I'm like, just give me my coffee.
I don't want to install your web app or your mobile app or,
but maybe doing it through a website would be nicer because
then I don't have to install junk on my phone.
And as somebody pointed out the advantage of a web app is you go to the website,
you use it, you leave the website, there's not a whole pile of cruft on your phone,
right?
And then there's a whole bunch of other
things. Like my favorite is the web Midi app.
So for those of you who don't know what Midi is
and actually, I don't know what the acronym stands for
musical instrument, digital interface.
So this is like think old timey electronic keyboards, you know,
like from the seventies or whatever.
And you know, they can be hooked up to a computer. They still exist.
Oh, yeah, exactly.
But they can be hooked up to a computer and programs like when you hit a key,
-- it makes a fart noise or a chicken or whatever,
-- go watch,
there's lots of cool youtube videos about this, just go watch them.
And so for example,
the midi one is especially horrifying because apparently
part of Midi is that you can download little
binary blobs of data sound noise stuff to the device so that it can play it.
And so apparently the web Midi app essentially allows the web browser then to send
like binary blobs to your Midi device that it then processes what could go wrong.
That's so weird to me. I don't understand why.
That's even a,
well, somebody pointed out they made a Midi like a website that has Midi app, right?
Things like that.
Other things are like a magnetometer app that allows websites to access
data about the literally the local magnetic field of where you are.
Again.
The thing to remember basically is the idea seems to be I think you're right,
largely being pushed by companies like Google is that they want to make web based
applications like a first class citizen that
can access all the hardware on your phone
like a mobile app can. So that
because to put it bluntly like I hate installing mobile apps now unless I really
want it like all these mobile apps like that whole tiktok thing recently where oh,
it turns out tiktok is like copying your clipboard
every like what 3 to 4 seconds or something,
you know,
other things like device memory API allows websites to
receive the approximate amount of device memory and gigabytes,
you know, things like near field contact. Oh, this is my favorite one.
The network information API it provides
information about the connection of devices
using to communicate with the network and provides a means of scripts,
sorry, four scripts to be notified if the network connection type changes.
-- I
-- mean, you can easily make the argument that all of these features will,
-- they're
-- useful to somebody.
They could be useful. But I think the potential for abuse is very high.
I'd say it's over 9000
like, but, but again,
it goes back to the whole point of they want to make the
web applications first class citizens that
can access all the mobile capabilities.
Because I mean, to put it bluntly, people are getting tired of mobile apps.
I mean, there was a really good hacker news thread with a lot of stuff.
But one comment that really stood out to me was mobile
apps are the industry's current way of avoiding app blockers.
That's probably fair
because more and more people are browsing.
Like I've been browsing on the desktop with mobile ad blockers for
like a decade because just the web is cancerous without it.
Like literally you will get infected, your computer will get infected.
And on mobile, I've kind of tolerated the ad experience a bit.
But like every time I, you know, read the news outside of like the CBC, it's just like,
oh my, like I go to, you know, reddit and
some like normal
American news site and I'm just like, what is all this like,
you know, what,
you know what I've done actually is so I recently
got an iphone which is a story in itself,
but there is a browser you can get for I OS called Duck Duck Go.
And it obviously is heavily tied in with the Duck Duck Go
ecosystem, but it is phenomenal and it blocks ads by default.
Well,
I don't honestly do a lot of web surfing on what
would be kind of considered normal people websites on my phone.
Like I tend to just, you know,
stick to some new sites that are boring with not a lot of advertising anyways.
So what's interesting is number one Apple is refusing
to implement these API S and people are like,
oh, what about opt in?
And the response is, you know, like everybody
like their mom will be like, oh yeah, click to allow, sure.
Like people always click to allow. I literally, oh, what was I just doing?
I was just at some website and it's like I want to send you notifications and I'm like,
-- no,
-- those are a nightmare.
And my, every time I go and help my parents fix their computer,
I have to go in and look at all the websites they click,
allow notifications from and I disable them all.
So
yeah, I mean, and and oh, here's a good one.
So for example,
chrome allows silent enumeration of USB devices attached to your computer.
Why? Because that's in the spec, it's in the spec, right?
Like if you allow access to the USB devices obviously as a programmer,
you're going to allow people to like basically do a
directory listing equivalent of like what's attached to this computer,
like, does this user have the specific key?
Well, a perfect example. Oh, what's that stupid mouse vendor? I'm totally buy
it.
They had like a really goofy logo. Anyways, to
use the mouse,
you have to use an application that's connected to the internet to set it up.
This is stupid.
Well, and ostensibly the,
the reason is so that you can like save
profiles and stuff for like professional Starcraft players.
You know, have their key maps laid out and stuff. Razor.
That's the one, the Razor mice and keyboards.
Basically, they don't work well or if at all, unless you have like an application,
the Razor application running on your desktop connected to the internet.
So like, honestly,
I used to have a really nice Razor gaming mouse that
I loved because it had 12 programmable buttons on the site.
So I had them programmed to do a whole bunch of stuff, like go to next tab,
go to previous tab, close a tab, you know, for web browsing, it was nice.
The app was way too intrusive and didn't work that well
and had to be connected to the internet to work properly.
And so I ditched on it. It's so dumb. Well, people keep buying these things
anyway. So it boils down to, yeah, these are definitely from a privacy point of view,
especially taken in total.
You know, these 16 web API S definitely allow somebody to, like,
really narrow down who you are and like, where you are.
Because I,
one thing I didn't realize the world's magnetic field
is not at all what you'd call uniform.
And I didn't realize, like I knew the North Pole kind of wandered,
but apparently it's one wondering several 100 yards a year.
-- And
-- not only that, your local geography dictates.
-- Well,
-- your local structure, if you're living in a steel frame building, probably,
I, I bet they didn't
-- DeLoss it when they built it.
-- Of course not.
If you can look up the magnetic field, what it looks like where you live and it's not,
it's not north.
Anyway. Anyway, did you set a timer? We've been talking about this for a long time.
We got two more minutes. But
the favorite thing and here's where it kind of gets
really interesting is somebody pointed out that app like,
so let's put it bluntly, companies like Facebook and Google
are predicated on advertising to you and advertising to you
is based on giving the advertisers a lot of information about you either directly
or indirectly in saying that we can, like
you want to advertise to left-handed males who play Starcraft
on Thursdays between the hours of three and 7 p.m.
Yes, we have that market segment,
um,
or flat out, you know,
the way a broker networks work now is when you click on a web page,
they generate a bunch of info about you.
Like your IP address, your browser blah, blah, blah, attach that to the request.
It goes to these, these uh essentially ad broker sites,
you know that then bid on it like, oh, I, I really want to advertise to Josh,
I'll pay $7 to show him this ad for a new bicycle.
And so Apple can't sort of directly go against Facebook and Google, you know,
for both legal and kind of technical reasons.
But what they can do is champion privacy
and basically got their business model and I'm ok with that.
I think,
-- I
-- think there's a moral question here that I think
is strange is if Apple becomes a champion of privacy,
which I totally would approve of.
-- And I like,
-- well, somebody has to champion privacy.
-- Well,
-- but it also means privacy becomes a feature of the rich. You know what I mean?
Because let's face it, Apple Gear is expensive,
having privacy and having confidentiality has always been
-- something for people with money.
-- I don't think you're wrong, but I think it is
-- exacerbated in today's world.
-- Oh, absolutely.
It's much worse than the class divides.
And somebody pointed out because I was kind of, you know,
I was always one of those people I believe strongly in privacy.
But if you'd asked me why is privacy so important, I would have been like,
because it's good.
But a friend of mine who's smarter than I pointed out. You cannot have.
Ok. Well, I'm going to finish this up. You cannot,
you cannot have social change without people going against the grain.
And that has to be able
to start in private.
Yeah, I, I agree with that completely. That's a really good point.
I'm like, oh, yeah.
No, that, yeah, because things like letting women vote or, you know,
letting everybody over the age of 18 vote regardless of, you know,
skin tone or whatever.
Yeah, these things happen because people could discuss this in private.
Had they been forced to start this movement in public? Well, the established
entrenched forces would have squished them.
Yeah, that, that's a good point actually. That's, I never thought of it that way.
-- That's why privacy is important.
-- I like it.
Yeah,
-- that makes sense.
-- I really hope Apple holds the line on this one because I get why
websites would want these things to make full featured apps.
-- But at the same time and from a privacy point of view. Ouch.
-- Yeah. All right.
What's, what's the last one?
-- So
-- the last one, it's been around for a while and, but it's sort of finally, you know,
being enforced and this is Apple is enforcing notarization of applications.
And so it was sort of initially noticed,
I think one or two Mac Os updates ago where somebody was like, hey, you know,
when I start a script on my laptop, my laptop like stalls out for a few seconds.
And then the second time I run the script, it runs fine.
Like, what,
what's the deal you and the deal is your computer is making
a hash of that binary and sending it back to Apple,
you know, and getting a reply.
Ok. So there's two sides to this that I have thoughts on.
There's the concept of signed binaries
and
-- computer security. It,
-- it totally did. It's not new.
And in fact, in the new Os X, which is what Catalina, I think it was, they enforce it
-- versus in the past they did not,
-- well, they don't
enforce it, enforce it.
They, they force the system to do it but it doesn't like block stuff,
-- does
-- it,
the bar was raised,
we'll say,
and
I'm not opposed to that.
It's not going to stop Attackers necessarily,
but it's definitely a defense in depth move in a lot of ways.
Now.
Apple check something,
anything I run
and phoning home with it.
I,
and we weren't really, I don't remember a pop up asking me for permission on that.
It's,
you can make a lot of arguments you can say, oh, it's just a half.
Well, and for all we know, I, I don't,
I haven't looked into it but they may be anonyms
it like they did for the iphone location stuff.
Remember that whole thing with the iphone location thing.
And it turns out they actually did a lot of work to ensure
that it's anonymized and safe and secure as much as it can be.
And, and whether it is or isn't,
I think is even less important because let's say they know it's me
and
they know what I'm running.
It's the fact that they didn't tell me they're doing it,
I think is the bigger problem.
They technically did tell people they were doing it like in,
through their developer channels and stuff like they announced this, you know,
over a year ago.
But the reality is like, I don't pay attention to the developer channels for so
like,
yeah, exactly.
And apparently most companies don't either because a
lot of them are complaining that like this
-- stuff broke their apps.
-- This is like ebay port scanning your machine.
And then everyone's saying, oh, but
the browsers have had this forever.
It's in the, it's in like section 57 of the license of the terms of service agreement.
Like they may have had this feature,
we didn't know about this feature and now we all
think this feature is stupid because it's being abused.
And so anyway, anyway,
my my take on this with Apple is that
I'm not necessarily opposed to this behavior because
I think there can be some benefits to
essentially maintaining some sort of functional registry of known bad stuff.
Phoning at home.
I'm not as big of a fan of necessarily and not telling me
I'm not a big fan of either. And so this is a fine line
for sure that I think Apple probably took one step in the wrong direction.
Well, and, and the other thing too is to consider the longer term effects of, well,
you can sort of avoid all this by getting a proper
Apple developer account and code signing and blah blah blah,
which you know, basically by embracing and join
the Apple ecosystem fully, you can avoid this, you know,
so all you got to do to avoid this is just totally come in house.
That's ridiculous. Like I, I get what they're doing and why they're doing it.
But at the same time, yeah, it's kind of like, well,
you and I come from the Linux world where
it's completely normal to go download random source code,
compile it and use it
-- because like 20 years ago that that's how it worked.
-- It's still pretty normal.
Have you,
you know, I was running like slacker 1.1 which great distribution, you know,
Patrick Folker thing, man, that dude's a machine.
He's still doing it, man.
I know blows my mind but you know, he can't package everything I want. And so
yeah, you know, like my favorite Irc client had to, you know,
download and compile from source and get the extensions and all that stuff.
So yeah, I don't know, like, but on the other hand,
there's the part of me that for example, I kind of prefer
my mobile devices because the way apps install and
get removed is much cleaner and less hassle.
And I don't have to worry about, you know,
some mobile app completely pooping all over my system and compromising it,
you know, whereas every time I run like
or what, what is it like pip, like when I run pip and it's like, oh yeah,
I want to install this to the system so I can use it properly,
which means I have to run it with pseudo which means like
-- man, I hope that pip code's OK.
-- I don't do that with Python.
-- Python supports virtual environments.
-- Yeah, I know I need to set that up.
You totally need to use those because it's life changing and then you don't have
to ever worry about installing trash because
you just whatever the virtual environments broken,
I delete it and start again
virtual and has been on my to do list forever.
But the point is I'm also a lazy normal human being sometimes which means pseudo
space block. It worked. I'm done. I'm moving on.
You brought us to where I was going to hopefully
slowly nudge this conversation is that I think focusing on whitelisting
and taking hashes of your binaries
is a lost cause
because it is very common, for example, in the malware universe to just, you know,
all you have to do is add a couple bites
to the end of your binary and now it's different.
So
the thing is those, for example,
this will give Apple a much better idea
of stuff distributed through their store that is,
and is not causing problems more to the point.
Yeah. Against like an APT
style attacker who, well, we just had this happen at the cloud security line.
Somebody emailed like all of us an Excel file that had a different name
and different contents like the hashes were all different,
but it was the same Trojan.
Sure. So shockingly, Google didn't catch it. But anyways, I'm not shocked at all.
Two of the scanners on virus total.
But uh anyways,
the point is the majority of us aren't dealing with that we're dealing with,
you know, somebody who compromises, for example,
like uh whatever random text editor you use that's popular, you know,
like Notepad plus plus or Adam or something, you know,
somebody gets into their DEV process or something and put something nasty in.
Well, now this gives you a way to more easily detect and block that,
you know.
So it's,
it's basically the doing stuff at scale where
the supplies and it works quite well there.
All right. So here's my counter argument to that. Nothing you said is wrong,
but it is functionally ineffective and has basically never really worked.
Whereas things like containment
have sandbox applications works and is effective.
But you can't make developers sandbox their stuff.
You don't make the developers,
you build this functionality into the operating system.
You were just talking about
apps
and how apps work.
I mean, that that is,
-- I think more effective
-- well, and funnily enough,
that's where Apple's headed clearly with, you know,
it's good looking at their new arm based
laptops and developer kit.
I'm assuming that the next like when the new arm based Apple laptop thing comes out,
which apparently
has shockingly good performance even with completely, you know, on the fly,
translated binaries to X 80 or from X 86 to arm or whatever.
But I assume
at some point in the near, near like one or two years future with Apple,
I'm going to be able to run all my mobile apps on my desktop.
-- Like assuming I have new the newer arm hardware,
-- maybe whatever, who cares?
That's boring.
Well, honestly, that's kind of what I want because you know,
I have a bunch of mobile apps that I use where on my desktop,
I have to use the website and it's just like uh
it would be nicer just to have the consistent experience.
But even then if you're using your web browser, all the web browsers use sandboxes.
Well, but for example Slack,
I use the Slack desktop app because honestly the Slack web app kind of
-- blows
-- whatever the web app and the desktop app are functionally the same.
But their,
their desktop app is a Turd man.
Yeah, and the mobile app is actually not that terrible.
The other thing I'm thinking is like the mobile apps
running on my phone are running on way less hardware
compared to like these desktop apps and yet
performance and usability seems about the same.
So quite honestly, I,
I feel like my computer would be a lot
faster running mobile apps than these huge electron monstrosities,
right?
All of the desktop apps are just basically web browsers
plus all the other crap shoveled together and held it.
You know, you've tied it up as best as you can with some bailing wire.
It's,
it's a, it's a total map.
I like that Apple is I think pretty clearly headed towards this actual,
I hate to use the word convergence
of the desktop and mobile space,
but kind of with the best of both still being allowed like
it sounds like you'll still be able to run your full fat,
you know, Microsoft Office or?
Oh,
what are those productivity apps that all the content creators use the Adobe stuff?
Adobe Suite, whatever it's called?
Yeah, there's like illustrator and photos
and
all that video editing stuff and whatnot.
And at the same time, have all your mobile apps or if you want the desktop app,
I can't help but feel like this is the future because to put it bluntly,
if I had to pick one device, it'd be my phone hands down, right?
Because it's always, it's actually with me like I actually have it like, yeah,
it would be nicer to have a faster computer.
But the computer I have is the best computer. Right.
And I always have my phone with me.
I hate when people say things like this because that is a, you can't make a reason,
argument.
It's like saying, if you could only have one tool out of your toolbox,
what would it be?
And it's like
that doesn't make sense because
-- hammers and screwdrivers, they're not the same in any universe.
-- True.
But my phone has like, I've owned now what,
three or four iphones and they've gotten a lot better.
-- Of course,
-- they've gotten better.
-- All the technology has gotten better,
-- you know, and well,
compared to my flip phones and my Motorola eraser, like, holy,
like, look, man, write a document, a long document on your phone.
No, that's ridiculous. You need a keyboard.
-- Yeah, I can talk to a Bluetooth keyboard.
-- Oh, whatever.
-- Kurt, you're splitting here.
-- I'm sitting on a Bluetooth keyboard with my desktop.
Exact same keyboard can talk to my phone
as soon as you hook up keyboards and mice to a phone. It's not a phone anymore.
-- That's my argument.
-- That's exactly it. The phone is not a phone anymore.
It's a small computer that fits in my pocket.
-- That's my point.
-- Anyway,
anyway, I would love to, I want to see you do some development on your phone.
-- That's what I want to see.
-- I've actually, well, I've done full operation stuff like
Aws and Ss
Hing into servers to fix them on my phone without a keyboard.
-- I want to see some, no js development on that phone.
-- No, I'm a Python guy.
Whatever.
-- Python's fine. It's all the same.
-- I guess
what it boils down to for me is that the enemy of my enemy is friend
ish. And I definitely hate Facebook a lot more than I hate Apple.
I, I would, I would not structure it in that way.
I think here's how I've been thinking about this.
So you've got these companies and we, we talked about this.
There's an episode in the past where we basically discuss
the fact that
all this data
people like Facebook and Google have on us is, is like nuclear waste
where it's a mess.
And
I think Cory Doctorow has a comment where he compares it
to having like a pile of oily rags in the garage.
Their business model
was built up based upon this whole, oh,
we get all this cool stuff for free and they're just
going to take a little bit of my data or whatever.
It's fine, but it's like anything where it's never enough in.
And I think this is just human nature of
I want a little more or a little more, a little more.
And like my comparison is always, I started,
you know, playing with SDRS for fun and now I'm trying to buy a satellite dish, right?
Like it's always a little more which I haven't found my,
my price is free functionally.
But,
um,
you know, you get the idea is I think it's, it's just human nature to, oh,
just a little more, a little more, a little more.
-- And before you know it, you know, you're,
-- oh,
I've consistently noticed more and more apps.
I get the warning. You know, this app wants to use your location. Always.
Do you want to allow it always only during use or never?
And I'm kind of like, never like
the Starbucks app I get but officially, you know, oh,
so I can find the nearest Starbucks easily.
But yeah, whatever. Yeah, that's
-- not what they're doing with it anyway.
-- Anyway. So, so here's my point. I think
it's, it's a false dichotomy because
this business model these companies created is now growing out
of control to the point we're even noticing it,
which means it's way worse than we can imagine.
That's the thing you always have to remember is
anything we see is it's the iceberg effect.
Now, you look at Apple and I don't even view it as like the enemy of my enemy
rather, I'm Apple's customer. I'm not Apple's product.
So it's in Apple's best interest to do things that are good for me.
It's in Google's best interest to do things that's good for their customers,
-- which is functionally the advertisers and
-- even worse than that for Google,
like they have tried to transition out of, you know, being what is it?
Like, 90 something percent of their profit comes from adss.
Very few companies have ever successfully transitioned business models
-- and I don't see a reason to believe they're special in any way.
-- Well, exactly.
And same with Facebook. There's no way Facebook is going to, like, Facebook has.
Good Lord.
How many things have they tried that are supposed to make a ton of money that have,
you know, flopped.
-- I don't know. I got, I got faith in Libra. Right.
-- There you go, man.
Yeah. Yeah.
Libra.
Yeah.
So I maybe that's what it boils down to is we're actually Apple's customer,
not the advertisers, not the app makers,
-- not the developers and it definitely costs
-- more.
It does. Well, sort of, I mean, I'll end on the story of why I have an iphone now. And
so anyone who knows me knows,
like I have been incredibly critical of Apple pretty much forever.
And
there's a variety of reasons both founded and unfounded for that,
that attitude I have.
But functionally I bought a Google pixel two
phone some basically shortly after it came out and
that phone is only getting proper support for three years,
which is like basically the bare minimum Google offers on phones.
And then there it's getting brutally murdered.
This really upset me a great deal because there's nothing wrong with my phone.
And that's assuming you also bought the phone day one when it came out
-- and I didn't
-- I bought it like two months after it came out,
whatever, close enough.
Right.
But basically I have this phone that's pretty much only working for,
for three years.
And my daughter has an iphone six that's still freaking supported.
Well, dude, my kids, I gave them iphone fives and it's getting updates from Apple,
-- but
-- the iphone five is end of life.
-- Right. That doesn't count.
-- Yes. Oh, it is. But it's been out for like a
-- long time and that's,
-- and, and that's just it. Right. So Apple devices
are currently getting a lifespan of five plus years.
And that's becoming very important to me is the fact that like the fact that
your people are throwing this stuff away every couple of years is frustrating to me.
There's nothing wrong with my pixel phone except Google tells me it dies in October.
The five S was released seven years ago.
Yeah, whatever the five S is six fired.
I don't care about the five S, the six S is actually still supported.
It was released in 2015.
You're talking five years of support and then some, and it's still going,
that is
amazing to me.
And that is what I want. I don't want to keep throwing things out constantly.
There's no reason to do that.
Oh, I agree completely because I'm now clearly at the point where, you know,
like pants, the phones are, you know,
I'm going to get a new phone and then there's going to be that,
you know, crab shell effect going down the line with my kids.
Yeah. Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And, yeah, I bought the iphone Se Two, which is their, their new phone,
the cheap phone.
It was like 400 bucks, I think. And I'm pleased with it.
I would say there's nothing drastically different
about my life having switched phones,
which also shocked me a little bit.
I just want to comment like iphone, the five
is still supported. Like the last security update was a few weeks ago.
Yeah, Iowa is 12.4 0.7. Like it's still getting security updates. That's
my point. Right. Yeah, exactly.
So like every two or three weeks I update all the I devices
in the house and it eats up a couple gigs of bandwidth.
But yeah, I mean, compared to that, yeah,
I bought one Android phone and I just hate it because it's just,
yeah, it's so not properly supported.
-- But
-- again, we're talking about an ecosystem where you're the product,
you're not the customer.
And I think it's really starting to show
the more I just pay attention to what's happening in the universe around me. Yep.
So, all right. There we go.
We talked about Apple and the open source security podcast. Again,
-- it's not the first time it will be the last
-- looking at Microsoft and Apple.
It's clear that open source one and they've embraced it.
Open source is everything is open source. I always, I always love that when I read
a, some report saying, 0 97% of businesses are using open source.
It's like, no, it's 100 it's just 3% don't know what's going on.
-- They
-- don't have licensing compliance. Yeah. Right.
Anyway,
all right, I'm calling it that. This is good. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up our show
notes, U
pound
oss
podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media. Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everybody. Bye bye.