Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in running old websites.
-- Josh Pressers
-- running old websites.
-- I don't understand that. Reference. Uh
-- breast.net is still a thing.
-- It is
-- and it's very ugly because I host it out of an S3 bucket on Amazon.
Yeah. It's one static website.
I'm still very pleased with that website and I will keep
it forever because it's like an LS of slash proc.
I think I should look.
Yeah.
But
-- it's an old
-- website like that.
-- I think your domains younger than mine. Mine is 98
-- uh, 2000
ish, maybe 2001,
1000.
Yeah. Yeah. Your domain is old enough to drink. So it's an old website.
I mean, it, it is. Yes,
it
is. I, I had a website back when that was not
easy to do.
I had
a, I had a closet like I had a closet with a rack
at a co
location
here in Edmonton
with seven systems to run
suri dot org.
So I don't remember how I ran it at first,
but I do remember when I worked at Progeny Linux systems.
One of the
benefits of working there is they gave you space in the server room
and they gave you a public IP.
And to be clear you're talking about physical space. Yeah.
No, I, I bought a computer. I brought it to work. I put it in the server room.
They plugged it into the internet
and now that server was just on the,
which now from a risk management perspective as a security person, this thought,
like, terrifies me to my bones.
But,
but back then, I mean, this would be 2003. Maybe.
-- What else would you do?
-- I mean,
and it was
like, you're a cool start up.
It's one of the ways you get Linux nerds to
come work for you is you give them a computer.
Well, you either do that or they, they shove machines in the machine room anyways.
I mean,
maybe I didn't at the place I worked before that. I don't,
I can't for the life of me remember how I hosted my website though.
I probably knew someone with a shell somewhere.
That's generally how that worked because various
sins. Actually, it's funny you mentioned this.
-- Does
-- anybody
-- still pay for shell servers?
-- Probably.
-- I'm sure there
are,
you know what Irc Bos?
-- Sure.
-- Sure. There's, I'm sure there's reasons to do anyway. Anyway, we have a topic.
I'm, I'm itching to get to
-- because I've been trying to. Well, this is the
-- topic.
-- What
-- do you
-- mean,
-- this is the topic,
this is the hosting stuff, running stuff,
giving it away for free until it becomes so unbearably painful
that you give up. Be it a website, a
software project, open source,
-- a service.
-- Ok. First we need the Clickbait title which is Open source
dying.
-- And the answer is yes. Yes, it is. No.
-- The answer is no, no,
open source is fine.
Oh, open source is dying in the sense of your body is currently dying.
You're losing billions of cells every day.
-- That's
-- fine. Oh my goodness, don't anyway. OK.
I want to start,
why do I do this to myself?
I want to start by saying when I say the word open source,
I know there is the technical definition which is
the O SI list of open source licenses,
which I
am morally opposed to being the definition of open source.
And then there's the concept of like the open source community, like the people,
-- like
-- every fet of verse server,
right?
I would say counts as part of the open source community.
-- It's in the spirit,
-- I would agree with that.
It's in the spirit
-- of, of it.
-- That's right. I, and and I still, I, I
have complained many times in the past that I think the O SI has dropped the ball
-- on keeping up with reality. Well,
-- they don't do services, they don't do,
they do licenses like we've firmly moved on since
in the last decade.
Right. Exactly. OK. So is open source dying.
And the,
the thing that kind of kicked off this discussion is there is a video
I will link to in the show notes where it's this 3D printer youtube person
that basically tried to create an argument, we'll say,
try saying that the future of 3D printing
progress is in patents because these 3D printer companies
can't make money on
their various open source stuff. Be it like
firmware
and you've got slicers and there's all this,
the whole kerfuffle about red out like people want stuff for free.
-- It's that simple. This is part
-- of the discussion.
People want stuff for free and to be clear, it's not
because they're like cheap or greedy,
they want stuff for free because I can't get budget to buy stuff.
I can't, I'm a student in some country and even if I wanted to give you money,
I don't have a credit card
or even if I do have a credit card, it's gonna get flagged as fraud.
There's millions of reasons, but
here's where I want to.
And I, I think framing this in the context of 3D printing is especially Apt.
Yeah, because
if you look at kind of the history of 3D printing where
it started where it went and kind of where it's going,
it's,
I would say it's an act in three parts where in the early days it was literally
like weird open source printer nerds who were
building these things out of like random parts.
They were sharing instructions on the internet,
they were writing the software to make it work and it
had to be open source and you had to share it.
-- There was no other way to do this.
-- It's the same, it's the same story of UNIX.
Your choices were the weird open
source thing that barely works.
Or spending seven figures on an enterprise solution.
Well, no, I mean, it wasn't even 70 figures like 3D printing didn't exist.
That's what, that's what makes the 3D printing story so good.
So anyway, you've got like the 3D printer nerds, right?
And this is where things like rep rap came from
where this was like these people built the future.
Then you hit a point where you had companies starting to
kind of make and sell 3D printers and
they leveraged all of this prior work that was going on.
And now these companies have reached a point where they're whining and complaints
that they can't make as much money as they did.
And I think part of the reason is today, if you want to buy a 3d printer,
you can buy like a million clones, random printers for a fraction of the price of the,
like we'll say official version.
Yeah, I looked into it and I, I decided I was, if I was going to buy one,
I was gonna go kind of with a brand name one.
Not for the brand name, but for the ecosystem of having the 3d
parts to add on to it, the compatible parts, the, all that.
But I was looking at an all in price of like the printer,
about 20 different upgrades to it filament the whole thing about 1000 bucks.
Yes. And that, like, five years ago that wouldn't even get your foot in the door.
Right.
Right. Anyway, there's a third part to this act and this is where I think
the companies are crying foul because
they basically, their work is being ripped off and, and that is
not unheard of in industry. Right.
If you look at virtually every successful product on the planet,
there are clones and copies.
And so when you're the industry leader,
you need to innovate and you need to push the envelope.
But here's the thing,
the innovation in the 3D printing space is not coming from companies.
It's coming from the open source nerds doing the work. There is a project called
Voon. There are Voon
printers. You can't buy a Voon
printer because Voon
printers are an open source project where 3D printer,
people are basically creating the best 3D printers on the planet.
Actually, you can buy Vron
-- kits now. Well,
-- you can buy the kits from a company,
but like the instructions are open,
they even have programs where like as many of the parts as they can 3D print, they do.
And they, I think they call it the pay it forward program
where basically you ask another boron owner to print you the parts with
the promise of I will print parts for the next person in line.
So they kind of hermit crab their way up to moron printers.
-- But this
-- is what's always fascinated me about things like machine tools.
I need machine tools to build machines, tools.
And
how do you bootstrap your way up there?
Well,
and the answer is in some cases you bootstrap your way
up there by starting with a sharp rock and a stick.
No, seriously, because that's how humanity did it. It is.
-- It is
-- except
I don't want to spend 5000 years doing this. I want it done in a week.
Right. Exactly.
There's,
there's a video I'll try to look up where they basically talk about the first lathe,
like, like
machinist lathe
and it's, it's somewhere in Paris now in a museum.
Like it's,
it's amazing to think like literally every single product we use today can
trace its origin back to that machine in a basement in Paris.
It's unbelievable. But anyway, you've got these voon
printers, right?
You've got these people doing this work and they're really pushing the envelope.
And so this has me thinking
in the context of open source because I think you can make the argument that
open source is dying. If you look at like the way Red Hat is acting, you look at the way
Google is acting, you look at the way
Microsoft is acting and I think
there are,
are definite signals from these companies that they're kind
of pulling themselves away from some of the,
like, more free and open universe.
Well, the challenge is like IOT is a good example.
I mean, if I build a really good light bulb and IIOT the design and the software, well,
somebody's going to go, ok, cool, thanks.
And they're going to go produce a million of them in China and sell them for
less money than I do because they don't have
those development costs and more to the point,
they don't care, they probably don't care about quality to the degree I do or about
-- other things. But
-- here, ok, here's, here's my point though. Right?
It's not about that.
It's about the fact that you look at something like open source or
3D printing the companies that basically made their way in the early days.
They have stopped innovating in new and interesting ways.
And I think a lot of open source is basically leaving them behind.
Same with 3D printing.
Like the companies that maybe were blazing the trails 1020 years ago. Who cares?
Like we don't need,
they never needed you.
You know,
that's kind of normal in the sense of like companies used to spend money on R and D
like Bell Laboratories.
They built entire buildings
and paid people obscene amounts of money to
futz around with computer, like
with vacuum tubes and this might be useful and while it turns out it was,
then the problem is, well, ok,
we don't want to take that risk because this isn't
a video game where if I plug in 7000 minerals,
I get,
you know, sharper claws for my little units.
Right. No, that's the thing. Right.
Scientific development doesn't work like Starcraft or Hearts of Iron Four where
you plug in the money and you get a better airframe out.
And so
companies try to reduce that risk by essentially saying, ok,
we're going to buy start ups like a start up will develop a new tech.
The gold standard for start ups used to be, oh, do you have any patents?
You have patents?
Now, we want to buy you. That's
true.
And, and that's literally they were outsourcing their R and D cost and risk by only
so they were paying more but only in theory, buying the winners
in
theory, right, in practice, we all know about synergy and how synergy works out.
So, and then it became a case of, oh, you know what,
it's really cheap just to buy these to
prevent this innovation from ever coming to market.
And it's also patented so tough, but we'll leave that alone.
So
the,
but the problem is there's that mentality of if I spend
all this money doing all this kind of research and development,
I may or may not benefit from it
and if it is good research and development that I
can benefit from and I give it away for free.
Like my business manager is going to look at me and slap me and say, don't do that.
I mean,
so, OK,
so you are correct. But I think here's the angle, I've been thinking of
a lot.
So when we take open source into account for this
in the open source universe,
there are things you can use and just use and you never
have to get back and there's things you have to give back,
right?
Like GP L two, GP L three type stuff. And
I know it's complicated,
it's complicated. Kurt, I'm not going to say
it.
But the point is
when,
when you've got people saying, oh,
we have to make money on this or we have to do this other thing,
-- but we do because I want to feed myself.
-- Yes,
I don't think you're wrong but I think
the, the
20 plus years of free money we had in the industry
has
made that conversation odd because a lot like a lot of start ups are,
are open sourcing, everything.
Red hat, open sourced everything.
There was a lot of it's not bad behavior but it was weird behavior in industry.
Let's draw some quick parallels.
One thing America did as a country
was violate the heck out of British patents.
I mean, we didn't like them at the time. So
-- and
-- so you basically just
took all their patents and filed them in the US patent office. Why is Hollywood as
an industry in Hollywood?
It's as far away as they could get from New Jersey and process servers.
So literally,
we have these giant industries that are built on top of essentially bad behavior,
violating patents, violating intellectual property agreements.
And
as much as I want to support the little
people coming up with new and innovative stuff.
At the same time,
it might be better for society if we don't let them patented and we don't let
them kind of own it and control it and force them to or give them the,
some sort of force
to control it.
And you know, say here's what you can and cannot do with it,
license wise or whatever process wise and let everybody
just have a free for all
the flip side being. And this is what really frustrates me. If there is value,
then chances are companies and organizations will come in to try and capture
that value to do rent seeking behavior to do all these bad things.
I've talked about this a lot, but
the problem is if there's a ton of value there.
Well, ok, we'll take the moral high ground and not do that.
-- Cool, but our competitor
-- does. I don't know if that's a reasonable argument.
-- I think people bring that up a lot.
-- Look
at, look at how Canada is set up now, we have four cell phone companies,
all with basically identical pricing, same with the banks, same with,
we have all these
Oligopoly
systems in Canada, for example, where we don't.
Yeah, I mean, if you don't do it, your competitors do
the thing is you can take the high ground and be like,
maybe this kind of weird little kind of custom bespoke boutique boutique, sorry.
Um, company that isn't too worried about, you know, making $10 billion
and, and you can do that, right?
Like there's a ton of local restaurants, for example,
that will never have more than one location.
Cool. Great. Like
the problem is
especially like with the 3D printers, for example, is the majority of consumers.
And well, for example,
remember on the fed Averse people were talking about this open source
and making their choices based on open source or not open source.
-- Yeah, the majority of consumers don't even know what open source is.
-- No.
And, and that's ok. I I'm comfortable with that.
They're going to buy the cheapest printer,
right? They don't care,
they, they want to buy the cheapest printer.
But I think this is where this concept of innovation
is part of the discussion, right?
And this is if you're doing the same thing for too long,
anyone can copy what you're doing.
And I think in the world of like open source based businesses,
it can be copied even faster.
Well, and something to remember too. Is
your customers may or may not want innovation?
Like a perfect example is we worked at Red Hat.
Red Hat very explicitly sold a version of
that was for people who did
not want rapid change. They wanted 10 to 13 years of support.
-- So the stuff would just work
-- there, there is that,
but that's not how capitalism works because capitalism
demands constant growth and exponential growth generally speaking.
And so if a company like Red Hat isn't growing,
they're going to be viewed as dying even if they're doing fine.
And then you end up with things like layoffs
and weird decisions about how you're distributing your product.
You know,
so,
and back to 3D printers though,
the problem is if I buy a 3D printer and they decide to stop innovating or being nice,
well, they have my money.
You have the printer though,
like,
but it might be a dead end,
right?
I was looking at this one printer that you apparently can only use their filament.
And I was like, nope,
there's like none of those left because, yeah,
some people tried to do that and shockingly it didn't go very well.
I
looked at it and I'm like,
I'm not like
this is why I own the laser printer. I own.
It's because I can buy the, the, the toner cartridges from Costco
and
there's instructions.
There's a good little youtube video about how to rip the chip out
with a pair of pliers and put it in the new one.
And so my printer is constantly complaining
about low toner because it's printed like
75 million
pages.
It's been printing for like three years on the same toner cartridge.
It's doing pretty good,
you know.
And so every time I hit print it warns me about low toner and I'm like, uh huh.
Oh, yeah.
And I actually have to pay attention to the print out because one day it
will actually run out of toner and I'll have to swap in another toner cartridge.
Uh, I think I'm on my third one now.
Nice. So,
but that's the thing with this, with this
part of it is also like customers making informed buying decisions. Remember?
Oh, remember the internet of things?
Light bulbs I bought from Costco thinking, ok,
Costco sells decent products one year returns.
They don't sell garbage. Yeah, they do. Those global light bulbs were trash.
They went on the Wi Fi, they would de
sync all the time. They would start
flashing if you turn the switch off and on. Too quickly.
It would like reset and lose its connection, blah, blah, blah.
So I went with Phillips. U Right. Wait, they cost like twice as much money
but they mostly just work. Cool. That's, you know,
and the thing is though, those are light bulbs.
If I buy $1000 printer, I'm not going to be like, oh ha ha silly me.
I bought the wrong printer. Let's go buy another one.
Right. I'm gonna have to eat that cost
by and large like,
and I, I think that's one of the challenges is,
well, it kind of goes to the market of lemons.
I might buy a printer that is really
well supported by the printer manufacturer today.
But if they stop software updates tomorrow,
oops too bad for me.
And obviously I can hedge that risk by going with a more open
source one.
Uh maybe maybe
like you for
-- example
-- of or
on where
sure a developer might get hit by a bus, but the other developers will keep going.
But to make that informed decision
requires a lot of knowledge and skill and it does
and most people just want a 3D printer that works.
So here's where I wanted us to end and
this is appropriate because we're kind of we're,
we're hitting the tail end of this discussion anyway.
So
you hear people talking about, 0, 3D printing is dying, you know, open source is
and all these things are dying
and
growing 10 times faster than they're dying.
Oh my goodness.
If I was next to you, I would literally stab you right now with something.
No, they're not dying.
Here's the thing I think when you think
about things like open source about 3D printers,
about the Fetta,
about whatever, right? You can see this in the security industry as well,
like it's all over the place everywhere you look,
there's this notion that if you're not like,
appealing to the mass market and everyone can use you,
your service is stupid and pointless and shouldn't exist.
And I blame like Facebook and Google
and even Apple to a degree for this.
Well, it's maximalist growth, right?
It's like, it's like if, if it's not just enough to be growing at 50% a year,
you have to grow and crush all your competitors
and hear the lament of their women and Children.
And it's like
we discussed, you know, we discussed what is success previously on the show.
And it's like,
like uh a perfect example,
the Fed averse if it's one or 2 million interesting people and that's all it ever is.
-- Yeah.
-- Cool.
Yeah, for sure, for sure. Absolutely.
And I think open source is a similar story where
you're never going to see like mass market adoption of a lot of this stuff.
You're never going to see Linux on the desktop take over windows or Os X and,
and nor does it really want to,
-- right? It's not one of the goals.
-- Well, and ironically, it already did that.
Well, it kind of did
Edmonton public school boards is a chromebook shop. So literally every child
in the public school system in Edmonton,
it's a Linux desktop user.
So there's some funny videos I've been watching where
apparently the a lot of school districts are souring
on chromebooks for a huge number of reasons is
everything from the Google services kind of suck to.
A lot of the chromebooks are low quality
and they're actually really expensive to maintain.
Like, who knew? Cheap stuff is expensive.
Well, if you buy cheap chromebooks, you get cheap chromebooks.
-- Like
-- exactly,
like,
because I've bought a couple of chromebooks over the years and the, the, the,
the range and quality and capability is.
But you know what really ticks me off is I would love to buy,
I used to have this little 10 inch chromebook
and I loved it because it was really small.
These,
the specs on these chromebooks haven't changed in like five
years and I just want like a 10 inch.
-- They
-- don't need to. Yes,
they do.
Chromebooks run like crap now. Yeah, they're terrible.
They feel like five year old computers. Like they run like crap.
They, we, I want a 10 inch chromebook that
isn't running a potato inside of it and I can't find one and
-- it annoys me because traveling with a 10 inch chromebook was Chef's
-- Kiss.
Stupid question.
Can you run chrome Os on a non chromebook?
-- Like, could you get a framework laptop and just, yeah,
-- you can.
But that defeats the purpose because the beauty of Chromo S is I could go on
a trip to a weird place and just power wash the thing when I got home.
Right. Well, that's what I'm saying.
-- Could you buy like a framework, laptop and load Chromos on
-- it.
No, because you lose all of those
key hardware protections that come built in with the device.
So
you, you
like actually chromebook running actually Chromo S
and I want it 10 inches because I love,
it's funny because people are just like, oh, you must love the giant laptops.
-- I'm like, no, I literally want the smallest laptop I can humanly carry.
-- I love that.
Everybody thinks I'm some sort of power user.
I'm like, yes, II, I would consider myself a power user, but like
a Mac Air
is actually a pretty beefy system nowadays.
I just ssh somewhere important.
That's the answer.
Actually, it's funny. I was doing some development work at work
and
I would try running some, some of the, the applications on my, our, our, our
product is pretty beefy
and I tried running on my laptop and like, nope doesn't work. But now like the
code does that like remote ssh D bugging and stuff like holy crap. It's amazing.
It's so good.
And so I'm like, yeah, I'm on,
I'm connected to a giant computer in the basement that's making
all the noise in the world. No, it's not the internet. It's in my basement,
but it was
super loud
and, and I love it.
I, I think
the challenge is going to be,
is some types of innovation can absolutely come from a
random person working on their own in a basement.
Like, look at Linux, a
-- lot
-- of innovation does. I think
a lot does, but some types of innovation, can't,
they need to come from a research laboratory
with a health and safe
the officer because you're trying to do
-- something with uranium or plutonium
-- for sure.
I mean, look, think about airplanes. Right.
Would you buy an airplane built by me in my basement? Absolutely not.
Would you buy an airplane from Boeing? Probably.
Let's go with Airbus.
OK.
That's true.
I think we Yeah, anyway, but you get the point right is I think
when you talk about something like open source or 3D printing,
I
think what, what when people say it's dying,
what you're getting is a narrative from giant companies
that are like we're having trouble monetizing this.
So we're gonna tell you it's dying.
It's same thing like what Jerry Bell had AAA Toot on the Fetta.
That was like,
oh everyone's saying Mastodon is dying but the
fact that I have to keep adding servers to
sect that exchange, you know,
maybe he says that that's not true,
-- but
-- some of that is, it's definitely rampant spam and bought abuse problems.
Like as we saw with reddit, this was fascinating to me.
Somebody showed that graph of Reddit use during the blackout.
And it was like you would have to have a
very high end quality monitor to see that pixel difference
because so much reddit activities clearly bought some stuff.
Now, you know, same thing,
like with Twitter where they apparently turned it back on,
but they had turned off your ability to view more than what 600 tweets or something
because they were talking about like scraping and bought abuse and stuff and,
you know, they quietly, now that threads is out,
they quietly turn that off and they're back to it.
But, and that's part of it. Like I was thinking the other day is what would you or I do
if our personal website started getting like a million requests a day or,
or a minute now, you and I are technologically savvy enough to be like,
oh, I could turn it off or I could put it behind cloud flare DDOS
protection or put it in a necessary bucket and serve it as cheaply as possible.
But even that's gonna cost many, many dollars.
But
you and I understand what we could do to prevent that kind of abuse and stuff.
Um
Right.
Uh I'm spacing out, what was the,
what was that open source repo that got hammered by github?
-- So they blocked all the Microsoft IP S
-- oh, I don't remember the name of it now anyways,
the point is
like that requires a level of skill. And also
if you're actually dealing with a malicious actor,
they're just gonna bypass whatever protections you put on.
So blocking that a dozen or 10 or 100 or
whatever IP S won't work and I'm thinking about that.
In terms of, you know, like the fed
is a good example.
What do we do when people come in? Oh Perfect example. We have this happen at the CS A.
People try and register free accounts on our website and stuff
to fill up their profile with links to like spam sites,
to juice their search engine optimization ranking
by getting back links.
And we're like,
I'm like, oh how do we fix this?
Because they're clearly coming in as with humans and doing
this because we got a bunch of protections already.
And I'm like, oh,
like, I guess we have to start crawling these links and seeing if they're bad or good.
Like, oh,
but that, and that's the thing is like as a community, how,
what do you do when a company comes in and
strip minds your open source and refuses to give back?
And, and the guy's answer of, oh, well, we'll go with patents.
No patents are so complicated and expensive and we're talking
tens of thousands of dollars for a good patent lawyer.
And that again doesn't guarantee you're going to get the patent
-- as is,
-- here's my other favorite part of that when it comes to 3D, printing
most of the actual interesting work coming into the 3D
printer universe is not being done by these companies.
So they're not even gonna get the
freaking patents anyway because you've got like random
-- people and research institutions and all these other orgs doing this work or
-- worse,
the companies are gonna go.
Oh, yeah,
we could pat that stuff and pretend it's ours because what are they gonna do?
-- Are they gonna
-- sue that?
Well, there's first to file now in the US,
which is definitely problematic in that regard.
But a person coming up with these innovations in their basement is
the chances of the, the,
the Venn diagram of people who come up
with new 3D printer innovations in their basement
and people who file pens
-- are two very widely separated circles
-- for sure, for sure.
And I think we're going to see a mess for without question. I mean,
we saw a lot of messes in the open source world, man. I mean,
how many times weren't there like ridiculous patents filed?
And people were like,
I literally did that 10 years ago and now it costs like thousands,
hundreds of thousands of hours to undo that.
What would the world look like if the US patent office had
decided that patents don't apply to open source and vice versa?
So that, for example, I like thought experiment. If you open source, your
stuff under
a US patent office proved open source license,
you can violate as many patents as you want.
Uh
-- go
-- not a lawyer, Kurt, I'm not gonna
No, no,
I'm not saying from a legal point of view but like,
what would the world look like if that was allowed?
If you could basically do all this work without having to worry about being sued,
patent violation.
You would see companies open sourcing things for
the express purpose of getting around patent law.
I don't think it would be a good idea. I think patents have value
conventions should be rewarded.
But I also think novel experiment, novel work,
90% of the patents being filed are not novel.
Like, remember
when,
remember when people were literally just like taking old ideas
-- and writing with a computer and they still
-- are,
-- except now it's with a Blockchain or
-- with a,
-- with
-- a,
no, I'm
serious.
I looked at some of these patents and they're, they're straight up like blah, blah,
blah
with an A I mediated system instead of a computer
or a network mediated system or a Blockchain mediated system.
Uh Anyway, anyway.
All right, open source isn't dying.
We knew that though.
Yeah.
Well, it's more to the point,
open source can't die because it's, as somebody was pointing out,
as long as there's two people on a forum that want to talk to each other,
that forum is alive for
the open
source world.
As long as there's one person releasing stuff under an open source license,
it's technically not dead.
I mean, it, it,
yes, that's how it's always going to work.
I think what we're seeing is corporate open source is going to
change and this is partially because of the free money is gone.
Making money is hard
-- and Yeah. Right. It, it is very, yeah,
-- making money with open source
is hard.
Well, making money at all. I remember. So, you know what that reminds me of is
I always wanted to be an o'reilly author when I was young, like, very young.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, I did. Because when
you wrote an o'reilly book,
you could basically get a free copy of every o'reilly book.
At that point, I was like, I could literally own all the o'reilly books.
-- Like this is much cheaper than
-- I had two bankers box full of them. I spent,
I
know, I
-- know,
-- I think on the order of $7000 on o'reilly books into two
-- year period,
-- I
-- guarantee
-- I spent that over my career when I was young.
Like, once I got a job, my first job, I basically spent all my money on o'reilly books.
But one was your favorite,
-- the best o'reilly book?
-- No, no, no, not the best. Which one was your favorite?
My favorite o'reilly book was actually the MH book,
which was a mail system. No one ever heard of that.
I was, I was a maintainer of for a long time.
It was like this mail system started at the RAND Corporation in like
1979 and I started working on it in like 2001 or 2002.
And it was frighteningly useful
and the book was written by, I don't remember the author's name. But he was a very,
we'll say, unique personality and it came through in his book
and it was very, very fun to read and to use.
But anyway, anyway,
there was an interview with Tim o'reilly one time where someone was, like,
aren't you worried?
These authors are going to get these free books and then resell them
and no, no, his comment was what his comment was.
I know how hard it is to sell books. I'm not worried at all.
Well, even more to the point if I get one of every book and I,
-- I resell them
-- like,
no, I know, I know what,
-- I'm sorry.
-- That
-- question
-- is
so
it's a very normal question.
I think that it, it,
it is someone who is not steeped in the world of
-- books probably thinks that is a likely outcome
-- even if,
ok, let's just
like
the envelope. There was, what about 100
books?
It's not supposed to make sense. It's just an amusing anecdote.
Like,
again, we've derailed the podcast. So
the point is though, like, I think corporate open source is going to change,
it has to change because like
the days of just giving lots of free stuff away and not making money
-- are over this. Actually, I also, I saw well
-- making money directly off of it. Ok.
Right. I saw a thing actually, uh this morning that
Evernote apparently just laid off all their staff.
It's done
-- like what does that mean? What happens
-- next?
But here's the thing that's interesting is there are
come like cloud services, cloud services let like,
don't even if anybody pretends that they're not 100% open source
is lying to you.
Right.
There's maybe like a couple 1000 lines of code for
the special sauce on the website in front of it.
-- Oh,
-- you mean everything underneath? Oh, for sure,
-- for
-- sure.
And so there are ways to make money off open source. But the challenge is
the ways to make money off open source and
be a good open source citizen. Let's say
much like Red Hat has been trying for 20 years where
Red Hat actually has a very explicit policy of upstream first.
Like yes, we will
write this patch or we will do this enhancement for the, for the love of God,
we want it upstream.
So we don't have to maintain a separate patch set because
that's a pain in the butt. It's terrible. And I think this is one of the things,
there's so many people talking about this whole red hat thing that I
don't think I've ever had to apply a patch to source code,
let alone take a patch to source code.
And now tweak the patch. So it applies to a 10 versions old,
maintain that for five years.
And I
know
anybody that thinks what Red Hat does is easy.
I would challenge you, go find a random CV.
And apply that source code patch to the last major version
-- every Tuesday
-- at red hat. No, I know. I know. I know how much work that is.
I used to, I did that for a long time but
nobody in their right mind does this. They, they,
but here, here's the thing though, I think to your point,
cloud services aren't selling open,
they're selling a service that runs on top of open source. right?
-- But then
-- some of them are
-- like, remember Amazon and the elastic
-- thing that's
we're not going to talk about that right now,
-- right? And,
-- and that, but that nobody but this goes to are the cloud services
using the open source in a sustainable way or
are they strip mining it and damaging it?
Some of them are, some of them aren't.
I think Amazon is definitely, well,
probably the big clouds aren't strip mining for sure
you can make that argument. But anyway, anyway, the point is
where I wanna wrap this one up and kind of bring it
all home is just the fact that open source is fine.
3D printing is fine. The FTA
verse is fine.
It's just our historic view of what it means to be a successful business
probably needs to be re evaluated in that context. Open source isn't a business.
The FTA
verse isn't a business, right?
Like 3D printing, there are businesses that exist in that world,
but functionally the 3D printing community isn't a business.
Well,
and I think maybe that's the thing to
look at this is there's the 3D printing businesses
but enveloping it sitting on top of it is the 3D printing ecosystem. That's
Yeah. Yeah.
And I think, and, and this is, I mean,
we've just seen this yesterday with threads popping
up where they like literally every hour Zuckerberg was
threading. What's the, whatever that's called threading?
I was about to say tweeting but I'm like, nope,
this is very specifically not tweeting.
It's not tooting, I guess threading. We
have three verbs
about how many users had signed up in the last hour or whatever.
And,
and they were like that hockey stick growth of
like 07 million users in four hours or whatever.
And from their perspective, from Facebook's perspective,
like for their shareholders, that number has to go up into the right man, a rock
pace.
They
-- doomed for sure a
-- 100
percent
Jerry Bell and the fetter
he could, I mean,
he could basically never get a user and I would say that he's entirely successful.
Yeah.
Oh, well,
if anything you could claim he's unsuccessful
because he's spending his own money to
give
him a
structure around.
Yeah. So
which thank you Jerry for doing by the way.
-- And
-- I think that's part of the challenge is these
people are coming at this from like a venture capital mindset
of like we have to sell one of these to everybody
on the planet to make this a billion dollar unit.
And it's back to that maximalist growth.
Not just we have to maximize growth and grow 100% a year or a week or a day,
but we have to like crush.
We have to be the like threads has to
murder every Twitter user and get through threads
and Twitter has to become a barren wasteland.
That's more so than it already is.
-- And you
-- know, I think that is the story when you hear people say, oh, the FTA
verse is failing.
They think if, if the, if Mastodon doesn't murder Twitter, Mastodon is a failure
when that's not even a goal. You know what, this reminds me of Kurt.
This reminds me of the arguments you get into where security teams think
like the business exists to empower them where it's like no security team.
You are literally only here so that the people making a product you sell.
Like that's the business. What you're doing
is not the most important thing.
Let's just leave it with this IRC networks are still a thing. Are they as big as
amazing as they used to be? No,
but there are still hundreds of thousands of people using IRC.
Uh Yeah, for sure, easily. Yep. Yep. OK. I like it. Let's just call it. Thank you.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to
our security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, U
Pound Os podcast. Hashtag
You know what I realized this morning on my bike ride,
I always use a pound of s podcast.
Hashtag that shows up on social media. It only works on Mastodon.
I
know I'm like,
I'm
-- gonna lie like
-- II,
I mean, I set up my, oh, I'm so angry on uh on threads.
You can only use the user name you have from Instagram
and you can't change your user name.
And so I'm curtsey Fried zero because the one of the other three curtsy fruits.
I'm pretty sure West Coast
Kurtz Fried grabbed the curtsey Fruit at Instagram along.
I
see.
-- Yeah, super annoying. And you can't rename your account. Neither of your
-- names.
Faces Kurt. Anyway. Alright.
You
found us this podcast hashtag on Mastodon.
-- I don't check my Twitter or
-- I used to check all that other stuff and I don't,
I just gave up.
So.
Yeah, Mastodon, that's where we're at. Anyway.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your
-- day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.