Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Curtsy Fried and my partner Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
All right. I'm excited. Beyond words. Today, we are joined by Fiona Kroen
Burger who worked for the Sovereign Tech Fund.
Thank you so much for joining us today.
Thank you so much for inviting me. I'm very excited to.
Fantastic. Ok.
Let's just kick it right off and tell us what the
Sovereign Tech Fund is for anyone who might not know.
Sure.
I'm going to explain it to your listeners, I guess,
who know a couple of things or two about open source.
Sure.
The Sovereign Tech Fund is a program that is funded
by the German Ministry of Economic Affairs and Climate Action.
It was started last year by me and a couple of other folks
that have been active in open source funding for quite some years and the
goal of the Sovereign Tech Fund is
to sustainably strengthen the open source ecosystem
and the way that we do that is by supporting open source infrastructure,
the maintenance improvement,
all those things that open source infrastructure needs means libraries,
protocols, inventions, programming languages,
developer tools tools that are needed for using programming languages.
Um Yeah, and our overarching goal is to establish that
open source infrastructure is seen as something that
should be sort supported by the public.
OK, I love this. And I want to add,
I think a very important point about the work you've done is
if you look at a significant amount of other open source funding,
it falls under the category of what I like to call things.
A smart person thought was a good idea.
Whereas you have a PDF on your website, that's 55 pages long,
that details all the work you did to get up to this point,
justifying your decisions and laying out a plan.
So like you folks have done your homework here.
Yeah, we certainly did. And
I mean, we started last year, we started popping up on people's radar,
but we've actually been working on this for the past two years.
So two years ago, I was working at the Open Technology Fund, my colleagues,
they worked at the prototype fund before,
which is a German open source fund as well that supported innovative prototypes.
And at Open Technology Fund,
I was supporting open source projects around internet freedom.
And there was also the core infrastructure fund that was one of the
few funds out there back then that
actually explicitly supported open source infrastructure.
And then in 2020
unfortunately,
the Open Technology Fund was almost shut down
by the Trump administration for various absurd reasons
which made the,
I would say, let's say the sort of global community realized
it would
suck big time. If one of the few funders or let's say the only funder who supports all
missiles infrastructure disappears,
we should create a bit more redundancy in the field.
And so we already had a couple of open years for that matter.
At the same time,
Germany also had the presidency in the European Council and
had this big term dish of sovereignty pushing for that.
And we thought,
well, if we do push for a term like that,
we want to get involved and push for a specific
meaning around open source um individual possibilities of choice.
And um
and
you know, things like preventing vendor lock ins and you know,
push for a certain meaning of digital sovereignty.
So there were a couple of things,
there was a very specific window of opportunity that enable us to ask for funding,
providing this feasibility study.
There was
also
done just
in time for the elections in Germany and the coalition negotiations.
So, and since our current government thinks open source is really important,
our feasibility, I guess came in really handy and um you know,
pushing for a certain concept for an open source
fund that is focused on open source infrastructure.
And I think it was two months later, three months later, that look for j happened,
um
We had nothing to do with that,
-- but it helped, it helped significantly,
-- I think. Yeah.
Log for J was very much a we've been telling you so
please listen
very
much.
Yeah, absolutely.
And by the way, this is going to happen many,
many more times and those are just the beginning.
This is the tip of the iceberg.
Um
Yeah, I guess doing politics with fear is usually not our style, I
guess in this case, we've been warning and we've been saying
there is a huge lack of funding for these kinds of projects.
Um And there's something that we need to do about it.
So
like Josh mentioned you,
so there's a 55 page PDF which I actually recommend people read.
One thing I found shocking is your budget is actually
really efficient, right?
Like you basically have a budget of just a hair under €10 million of which
like 7.5 million is for funding
like and then
uh material costs for grant recipients is 1.1 million.
So like
what is that? 86 and a bit 86.5% of your funding
actually goes to doing useful things, which to me is shocking, right?
Like I because you read about a lot of nonprofits or
foundations that are not as efficient as how we say.
But one thing I didn't see is
in the list of
like,
do you have a framework or a a published process for how
you pick your projects because the projects you've picked make sense,
like curl Open B GP D open MLS for on the infrastructure side.
But for example, FORTRAN package manager, I mean, like a, I'm like,
FORTRAN has a package manager.
I mean, I guess it does. That makes sense.
But like how do you out of the
I'm gonna say millions, yeah, millions of open source things.
Like how do you pick literally
those nine?
Sure. First of all, thank you for calling us Efficient.
As you can probably imagine as a German, I love to hear that.
But then also um that's a very good question. So how do we pick projects?
Um
I would say we have a,
we have two different mechanisms that we are using one of the support mechanism.
The other one is a push mechanism. So
actually, I think
when this episode launches,
there should be an open application ready on our website that is kind of like,
you know, classical open application
that is going to be on a running basis and people can apply and pitch their
ideas or the technologies that they are working
on or even technologies they're not working on,
they know a suitable implementation partner. They say this is actually in need.
This is very critical and there's a certain sense of undersupply.
Um And then we have a team, we have reviewers so pretty classical funding mechanism.
The other one that we have is that we have a
scouting mechanism.
That means that we are actively asking for recommendations
in the field with people who are themselves,
members of communities of practice people that are experts or active in
the field to recommend us and tell us about projects that are currently
need.
Um So that's one way how we are doing this scouting.
Then the other one is actually also research
um listening to those open source security podcasts that are out there,
but then also, you know,
reading articles and then there's actually a bunch of research.
Um So there are a couple of lists out there. I'm happy to
drop you a couple of links.
Um later today with lists that are, you know,
the 100 most critical projects that also have a certain sense of under undersupply,
those that have immeasurable the most dependencies in a certain field.
There's also a growing body of research out there
of people who are trying to develop metrics that
enable us to do some optimization in that regard,
you know, having scripts that we can run over github, for example,
to identify those repositories or technologies with the most dependence.
So, so we also look at those and create them along like certain criteria that we have.
Is this something that we can justify in the public interest?
Because that's our mission with,
with tax paying money and you know, being representatives of the public.
But then we also look at is there a certain sense of undersupply is underfunded.
We usually get in touch with people. Um We then have to.
So the way that we do is we identify technologies,
then we identify who's the person behind that.
Is there a person? Hopefully? Yes.
And if there's a person, we get in touch with them,
it was the same last year with a pilot project.
We knew Carl, we knew that Daniel was doing a lot of good
work for the community.
Um And
then we got in touch with Daniel and we asked Daniel actually.
So how are you doing? What's the current status?
And these conversations are actually so interesting because they show that
whatever you understand,
the dimension of being under supplied or in need is
so versatile depending on what project you talk to,
it can be the classic.
I'm this one random person in Nebraska or anywhere else that
I, I never got any money for this or,
but I'm working on this thing that's being downloaded
billion times every month or it could be,
we are not enough people, we need money to pay our incident responders or it can be,
I actually have a lot of commercial customers, but they will never pay for this,
which is I have 100 and 33 uncas
bugs.
I actually need to do the work and go through these
or even better. I have to remove things from my co
there's a lot of bit rod, I have
to remove features because it's been growing. And
so, you know,
having these conversations and basically
scoping conversations to understand what
is our role as sort of a public interest customer.
And then we do the scoping, we have another review with a review panel and then we
basically commission the work to be done
just as I say, is that something that you can publish? Because I
would love to read
those conversations or summaries of them or something? Because
like that is something that
Josh and I have talked about where it's just
you can't say what does open source need because that's like saying,
what do people need?
Like,
well,
yeah,
-- it's complicated. There's, there's a bit of variation.
-- A
lot of them need money, right? But then what goes beyond money?
Yeah, you're absolutely right. It's like asking what people need.
Well,
I want to point something else out that I think is really
cool you're doing and I think it's really important and not something
I've ever thought of before.
And I'm curious, I, well, I should say I'm curious,
I suspect I understand why you did this.
So you on slide nine of this presentation,
you
break apart who's using, you call them o open digital based technologies.
OD BT S is used all over the presentation which I can't ever remember what that
means and I keep reading them like it's
something important but you have two categories,
you have re users
and then you have kind of the the maintainers and the contributors
and I've never heard the term
reuser used before. But I think that's,
that really makes a lot of sense because that is very much how open source works,
right?
You've got the people building it and then you have the
individuals kind of consuming it in a way and that's what Reuser
stands for. And
I would love some insight on this concept because I think it's very powerful.
So what we're focusing on,
as I think I mentioned before with the open with
the sovereign tech Fund is really the the core infrastructure,
the core technologies,
but they're actually not user facing but actually developer facing
because we've been in open source funding for a long time.
I've been in open source funding,
I think for seven years and we've seen
a lot of funding programs coming out for technology
or open source and specific
and they always have a very heavy bias towards innovation
towards application.
There's usually a topical framing around it that favors application.
So I want to say on the application
layer, but that's wrong because also
model is wrong. But
so what we are really focusing on are those tools that are at the core of many,
many more technologies that are being used to build technology,
like the Fortune package manager, for example, like curl many many times.
And those are the things that we are focusing on because
the existing technologies out there those that are more on
a technical level that are under like under all these,
let's say, shiny and interesting applications out there.
The maintenance of these is usually something that funding programs or
mechanisms because they have their own logics don't usually support.
And as link
seen that we've all seen the result of that and it's a problem that has many,
many roots and causes.
And I think the fact that fans have been so focused
on innovation and applications is one part of the problem.
Well, I think it's safe to say, measuring this is hard
to put it bluntly. No and
no. But for levels of heart that most people don't understand
because like me and Josh have been at the coalface, you know,
digging the open source nuggets out.
Um
That's like defining or figuring out what the critical path is.
I mean, it's much easier to say like, hey, look at this N PM.
It's downloaded 10 billion times a week.
Let's fund that because it's popular, right? And it's easy to sell to people.
Like uh FORTRAN is a great example of a lot of people think FORTRAN is dead.
And I'm like, oh, I have some news for you,
you know, like, remember in COVID where the state of Jersey, New Jersey was like,
we need fortune programmers by Friday to fix
the welfare system where it's going to collapse.
Have really,
-- I didn't know that
-- that happened like a few like they literally
put out an emergency call for programmers to fix the system,
right? Because
so
-- we can't not send those checks out. Just
-- quite one quick info about the fortune.
Do you know why we chose it? Did we add that to the description?
Um
So FORTRAN, there was an article two years ago, I think by someone who said,
listen,
everyone climate catastrophe is real and everyone
who's working on it is using fortune.
So climate modeling.
My mother did her thesis on river flow data and she basically did the back of the
envelope math and it would take her four years to do it on a mechanical calculator.
Or she could spend like two years learning
FORTRAN and like one year running the data.
So my mom learned FORTRAN
like way back in the
oh jeez like late sixties, early seventies because
well, yeah, and
to this day like I worked for the flood forecasting center.
They were running a US Army Corps of Engineers program written in
FORTRAN
to simulate river flows like it's
it's in the climate space that well,
what else are you going to use for massive numeric?
Because I mean, you're basically, you're imitating the earth, right?
You're emulating the earth with all those
different things that are happening on earth,
like a climate like atmosphere, water, air
and foster
was actually great for that. And many people switched to Julie,
but Julia can do all the things that fortune is doing.
And there's actually pretty, the reason we were thinking about supporting Julia.
But then we switched to fortune because there's actually
a very active fortune community that wrote a paper,
I think two years ago or so and said we are
committed to reviving the community to making fortune easier to use.
So we figured
supporting the work on the package manager and making it easier to
use is actually going to benefit so many people out there.
And I think it also makes them,
you know, kind of like the very
nice case about let's improve the existing
stuff out there rather than putting more money
to the new stuff. But actually figure out how to support what's there and needs help.
That's amazing. Oh, that's so good.
So fun fact for everyone when I was in college, I went to college in from 1997 to 2001.
And I had a friend who was a meteorology major and he came
to me one day and said they're making me learn this stupid language.
I need your help.
And it was a FORTRAN book and I'm like, wow, I was horrified at the time,
but now it's like,
yeah, I get it like it was really good at math and they needed it to do math. But ok,
ok,
I everything you just described,
I feel like it's so obvious now that someone says it out loud
about funding this kind of foundational core technology and the maintenance of it.
And the thing I keep spinning in my brain
is the topic of the last couple of podcasts,
like critical infrastructure has been a part of it in
comparing a lot of open source to critical infrastructure.
And I feel like there's parallels here because
the government maintains roads and roads are kind of boring. Right.
There's, you don't see a lot of new and interesting hype around roads.
I have bad news for you.
So when we built our new Anthony Hee
ring road around the city,
they did one section using and using a new experimental concrete technique.
Yeah, it hasn't worked out. They're gonna pave it
but there is,
but that's
something
went
wrong.
It's just not suited for our climate
and that's, and that's like a lot of things is,
you know,
a technology that works well in one place may not work well in another place.
But so I would just strongly disagree. There is actually new, like,
uh go watch youtube on the new forms of concrete with the
enforcement stuff they're doing and the plasticizers and stuff.
-- It's actually kind of fascinating.
-- But
I'm sorry about that kind of crucified
that it's a niche
that
it's a niche
proving the
care about. Exactly.
So, I would say that there are amazing things going on in a lot of this stuff but it's,
it's so niche and crazy that like, nobody knows or cares or,
and back to what the last episode where Tomas was talking about,
like to even
to get involved to like, make a code, fix the level of expertise needed is just,
it's amazing, right? Like,
and, and I think
with your like, funding of these foundational things,
I assume it's going to the people that are already there.
And II,
I can't help but think that's a major part of what we need
to do is to kind of cultivate that existing talent and knowledge.
Absolutely. I mean,
just one thing I want to do to add what you said before.
So
what we're doing is for many people, incredibly boring. It,
it
doesn't matter to them and you know what it shouldn't.
But we keep saying
the most,
the biggest success story we can talk about
the work that we're doing is nothing happened.
I
found were
no luck for Jay happened. No, cbes for
zero days, one day, two days, you know, and I mean, this is about preventing
right in the way that our attention politics work usually, you don't get a lot
of,
you don't get a lot of props for preventive care, preventive work,
care, work in that regard.
So it's true that I think this is tricky and in addition to I think
those are really technical things that we are doing. Um
It's really technical stuff, it's really hard to people, for people to explain.
I mean, if you understand why OB GB D might be important or curl or a wire guard, then
when people understand that it makes total sense,
but you need a certain level of technical understanding and knowledge
to really be able to understand the importance of it,
then also make good decisions.
Yeah,
I want to follow up on what you just said though.
So you're talking about this is boring and obviously it's often
easy for us to fund exciting new cutting edge things.
But
how are you taking what we've just defined as boring foundational important work
and going to your funding sources and saying this is boring foundational work,
please give us more money to do more of this boring foundational work.
Like is that a receptive message or how are you wrapping this up in a way that, that
I guess piques the interest of the policymakers?
Yeah, that's a very good question and it's been tricky.
I'm actually surprised until today that this worked
that there have been people in the ministry and
the people that have been supporting us
that really understood what we're talking about.
But I think as soon as you start talking about the fact that
for everything that people care about these days, it may be innovation
may be disruptive innovation, science cars, I mean, Carl is built into cars and
so you know, that works well here, I guess.
So I think as soon as you're able to make the translation work, it works. But also
I think
as I said,
there was a very specific win of opportunity because um there was this
term digital sovereignty is being used in Europe a lot in a,
in a fundamentally different sense
than in the US from what I know. So here it really is now about enabling
yes companies but also administration,
the public individuals to make conscious and informed choices
and use open source.
Like open source is very much at the center of what we understand is the
sovereignty.
And it's not like let's build open source in Germany for Germany,
but it's actually about, you know,
creating a fruit tie and a good basis and
foundation for innovation to be actually even possible.
And yeah, I guess I really have to say that lock for J
like after
I think after lo
for J all those things happened, that should have happened after heart, please,
because back then people already understood
but
and some things happened and I want to give a lot of credit to that.
But I think on a more foundational level, on the state level administration level,
not even enough things have happened.
And I think those the mix of otf being almost trashed, then the
sovereignty presidency of Germany and the European Council.
And then also as you know, pushing for this concept and trying to lobby for that,
I think was,
yeah, lots of fortunate events happening
somewhat at the same time and also the election of course,
and I have to say two years ago, when we started working on this,
almost three years ago, we started drafting concepts,
writing the feasibility study asking like looking
around who's able to support this.
There weren't a lot of funders or anyone,
there were a couple of people that there was Ford Foundation doing great work.
There was otf um
there were a few other funders of the Sean Zuckerberg initiative,
a couple of that are supporting open source infrastructure,
but so much has happened since then.
So it's way more talk about it.
It's more on the agenda, like it's also on a state level, it's more on the agenda,
for example, for the uh for also for the US government in France,
it's becoming more of a thing in Germany.
We're definitely talking about it.
So I got to say Germany and our digital politics are
not really something we are renown for in the world.
Like why would be,
but I think it's kind of cool that now Germany is actually doing something where
like for once we're ahead of the wave, you know, and we're kind of surfing it.
So I think that's really cool. And
we always said the Southern
Tech Fund. So for this year, we have a total funding amount of 11.5 million
and we might get more next year, but it will never be the solution, right?
But what we'd rather like to see is that we
are pushing for a narrative and understanding for open source infrastructure
that will be copied by others. And that will rather lead to
a
different understanding of why this is important.
And we are strongly pushing for
the n
there's a term in Germany called
Dasso.
Interestingly, it doesn't really translate to English.
It's the understanding of the state being,
it's the job of the state to provide fundamental services that are important for
a society to work and for us to live a worthy life with each other
that is providing water, electricity, education, health infrastructure,
and that is called
Davao.
And we are pushing for open
source infrastructure as something as
digital.
Da
Di
Zaga.
And that doesn't translate because we still argue
if we should have that in the United
States,
that's what I thought a little bit
speak for the US.
So here in Canada, it's actually part of the British North American Act of 1867
Peace Order and good government
that is in Canada.
What we, that is our fundamental view of government so very different than the US.
Yeah, absolutely. I have to give props my co-founder,
Adriana go. She's definitely the policy expert here and she's been
working with political stakeholders for a long time. And we realize at some point
and you know, that's kind of the,
here's an interesting
thing to think about
the Sovereign tech Fund where we support open source infrastructure.
We are pushing money into a field and
an ecosystem that is inherently not sustainable.
What do we do about it? This I know I'm making a bold statement here, but
see, there are people out there who are taking care of open source components. Um
They do that often in their free time, they are not paid for it
and
they should be able
to say, fuck this, I'm out of here whenever they want to.
So what we can't do is just push the money into this field, give it to people.
We want to support people.
And I think volunteers are always going to be a part of a vital and healthy open
source ecosystem.
But we figured at some point, we have to think in a bigger sense and think about
what happens.
So funding is also inherently unsustainable where
we provide money and then we're gone,
we might provide a lot of money and then we're gone in five
years when the next or in three years when the next election happens.
So
what are we going to leave as an understanding and
more overarching narrative for the world when we leave?
And that is establishing that.
And as my co
founder,
Ariana always says it
that at one point, we are not going to talk about like with agriculture,
we don't discuss every year if, if we're giving money to
a to agriculture, but just how much
and the same should happen for
infrastructure. And that is sort of the overarching goal that we have by doing this.
No, I was actually um
I've never heard anybody say it explicitly that open source is not sustainable.
And I'm not sure I disagree because I, I know a friend of people literally, yeah,
carrying it on their backs in their spare time,
especially with a lot of this boring foundational stuff.
That is, it's, I mean,
like monetizing open source is hard and monetizing foundational
open source is damn near impossible in my experience.
But to this, that's, that's a
Yeah, like nobody says, let's cut the, you know,
do we have to spend money on defense this year?
Do we have to spend money on agricultural subsidies this year?
Do we have to spend money on health care or the roads?
Yeah, of course. I mean, unless the country goes to a very bad place,
the question is how much
um but
in line with that one thing you mentioned is,
and I was just thinking about this. So
and I don't know if you can answer this but are
different countries sort of needs around this foundational open source?
All that different because like for me looking at this
list like open B GP D and open MLS,
like you, you can't have internet without those period.
Like you just, you,
it just doesn't work literally uh same thing with
curl like you want to talk to the internet.
Well,
you need curl.
Is there actually that much of a difference?
Between say a Western European nation and an Asian nation and some, you know,
country in Africa like,
oh,
-- you mean in terms of who's using it
-- like as to what they would find important or need?
No, I
mean,
I kind of often might depend on like a
larger political philosophical framework they have and kind of the
decisions they make. But I would say no.
And that's the reason why we always said we are not funding open source
in Germany. We are funding
source
where it is being done because it is being used by everyone.
And it also benefits the Eu and Germany because it is being used worldwide.
I mean,
when you look at, for example, we are also supporting Ruby Gems and Bandler.
Yeah, you bet everyone's using it.
So we, so we are also not making any
sort of national statement about what kind of open source we're supporting.
And I think we know that this just doesn't make sense,
make more sense on the application level.
For example, what open sources the administration using um
hopefully not a different one than everyone else, but probably they are.
So it probably makes sense to focus on specific products. But since we're,
you know, supporting the foundations of that,
-- there's no point in saying we have a specific interest in this or that
-- that feels ungo
like to me, I feel like every time I see funding happening,
it's all about we're going to keep it in country, we're going to fund
German or us or
whatever people.
And
how did that go over when you went to
whoever's writing your checks and said we want
to fund people no matter where they live.
Well,
I guess we were able to successfully explain what this was about.
And, you know, the thing is with the pilot round, it was also hard for us to foresee
where the projects will be that we support. We weren't quite sure. And also with the
open application that we're launching next week,
I have no idea at this point how many applications we're going to
get from where I did a lot of contingency planning for five applications,
50 or 500 if you're up for reviews, let me know.
So
it's really hard to tell and I think we all know the problem,
but we all have such a limited view
of what's out there.
I could ask you right now,
what libraries do you know out there that are
really in need and you probably know they are,
but you might not be able to tell me exactly what it is because
not a lot, that's the thing. Not a lot of people know about these, right. Sometimes
libraries are even butted up in other libraries.
So even developers never know about the existence and importance of these.
So it's been hard for us to
identify this.
There's one thing that I want to note though we had nine projects on the P
round and I think it was six of them
or five of them actually had a fiscal host.
I want to state very,
very clearly that fiscal hosts or fiscal organizations are such a vital
puzzle piece of an,
of a healthy open
source ecosystem.
-- Explain what a fiscal host is.
-- Sure,
I'd love to um
fiscal wholesale organizations
that are basically doing the back office work for an open source project.
Many times,
they either hire people and employees and open source collective is
actually they are launching a program where they're able to just
hire developers for a certain amount of time so they can
be hired and work on things instead of being a freelancer.
So some fiscal hosts, they really just do the processing of invoices,
they're responsible contract partner who signed contracts with you
and who do all of the back office work. Because for a lot of open source projects,
it's not what they should be doing maintainers, right? They should be writing,
right? No, one of us wants to do it. So there are fiscal halls and organizations.
It's sometimes it's foundations. Um It could be a
sting in Netherlands can also be in a
in
Switzerland.
So sometimes it's people who are already working there but are
working on open source in their free time or something.
They really just hire people, they do sub
attracting.
Um and those are really, really important. I would love to see more of that.
And most of them I think are currently in the US
because I think
significant funding for
source technologies
that has traditionally been more present in North America than in Europe.
And other places, I would really love to see more of this because I think
it's sometimes a make or break decision that an open
source project can actually grow and receive funding
if they have an organization in their back
related to that. I'm curious because
there are projects obviously that have a lot of
people and are big and kind of healthy.
But
by the numbers, basically,
the majority of projects have less than a developer, right?
Like I've, I've met people who are like, oh,
I maintain like 400 ruby gems and I'm like, good God, like how,
you know, it's like those people that have 12 Children.
And I'm like, how do you even remember their names?
So I'm wondering like, what,
how again it kind of goes back to people are different and have different needs. But
I guess,
yeah, the scale issue of like there is
a completely different reality for an organization that has
10 people who can actually return your emails and
a
person who is maintaining 400 libraries and also has a full time job.
Like, how do you even begin to talk to them and let alone help them?
Like,
so for
experience, I can tell you
sometimes it's a large foundation that just never responds, sometimes it's
an individual that never responds. So uh that seems to be a common denominator here.
But
um you know,
that's kind of our job is when we identify technology um that fits our remit,
we get in touch with people.
And that sometimes means means to be just research, who's behind this,
look at the
github repository, we look
who had the most contributions. Um Sometimes there is for program languages.
For example,
there are sometimes foundations in the back that we can talk to
usually have a very good overview over the field in the community.
Um And then we get in touch with people and sometimes,
yeah, you have a conversation and they're like,
you know what I actually
um
the community is in a sorry state. I don't really have the time to do this.
This is too much work. I I would love to get your support but we can that has happened
um because things need to be figured out.
Then there are others who, you know,
can just be a contractor and actually really happy that they
can focus on this project for a certain amount of time.
And then there are others who say I can't do this right now, but
there's,
but we sometimes identify a suitable organization that could host
them for a while or just provide the sub grants.
Um
and something that we've been that I thought was found really,
really important and I wanted to make sure it is as the Sovereign Tech Fund
needs to cater to the diversity of actors in this field.
So we need to be able to support individuals. Um GMB Hag
501 C threes or companies limited in the US.
Um And we are currently able to do that because we commission work,
we don't provide grants.
So I
there's
I learned a lot about German procurement law that I, I never wanted to learn.
Big
surprise German procurement law. It's hard,
but
we were able to sort of find ways so we could
provide contracts to people in the most flexible way possible.
So no matter where they are, no matter what kind of organizational type.
And I think that's extremely important because
we,
you
and I,
we know there are very very diverse actors in this field that whoever
is a maintainer that can look very different who's responsible for technology.
So one thing you just mentioned that I hadn't really thought
about is so not only do you um essentially provide funding,
but
it sounds like you're also doing a bit of market making saying so for example,
you reach out to somebody and it's like, OK, maybe we're not a good fit for you.
But hey, Bob over here,
you know, they,
maybe they're a good like, is that something that you're actively doing?
-- You
-- mean as finding maintainers or people who want to work
-- on something or finding other funders,
-- for example,
if you reach out to somebody and you can't help them, but you know,
somebody that can help them, introducing them to each other, for example.
Yeah. And I think we would love to do that more in the future.
So what we're doing is sort of also a matchmaking, right?
We find a technology, I realize that
maybe the person who is working on this is the right
person we should support and provide a contract for her.
That's it.
But maybe it also makes sense for them to get some help from
someone who,
I don't know, a security art would be a classical thing to sponsor for.
But maybe in the future,
they might also need an agency or a company that's
actually using the stuff and who are able and willing
to, you know, fund this. And
I think
so I've been,
we keep pushing for this narrative that the
government needs to be part of the puzzle.
But at the same time, we're not saying that
there should be only the government or other actors should,
you know, be removed from this field.
But actually, we think there should be more actors in this field who are, you know,
commonly like um together taking care of this ecosystem.
So I think companies are an even bigger piece of the puzzle here.
Um And we would love to explore more ways so we can also work with companies, help them
to find a landing space and figure out models and support those,
maybe do match funding, maybe they can hire someone
to work on this because as you said before,
sometimes there's less than one person working on a
thing and that's definitely the worst case scenario.
And what do we do then? Right. And,
and just to close this, I personally think that,
yeah, we can try finding someone but
there's a lot of work, there's gradually more money,
but there's definitely not enough people.
And I think that's the big,
how would you say it in English, Achilles, Achilles
Heel,
Achilles
Heel, and the big breaking point of this entire thing
is the lack of people I would say slash community growth, health.
So I think that is one of the biggest security risks that we are facing in the future.
Your agency providing funding is important, but
like a lot of government agencies that help people do so by
matching them to community supports or programs or have you considered,
you know,
taking this two year tech degree so you can level up and
be a better person and pay more taxes and get a job.
Um And it seems to me like, and that's a especially in the open
source world, like I, I couldn't even begin to do that
effectively.
No way. No. How
and it seems to me like that would be some
that could be massively important and
impactful without requiring disbursement of money.
Right. Obviously you need a staff to do it. But
yeah, I've like, literally never thought of that.
And as far as I know,
like you're the only group I've ever heard that's officially really doing it.
Great. Yeah, we're trying to, because you also mentioned this earlier.
We're trying to,
um
when we have a little bit, we're currently a little bit busy,
but we're trying to write down a lot of
the learnings and communicating them and do some,
I don't know, maybe
let's call it funders exchange and education,
but also be more public and vocal about the things that we hear and see and learn
that are needed. I think,
you know, we can provide money, we will always provide money and contracts.
But there's,
I think a fund becomes interesting when you think beyond money and like,
what is it that we can provide besides the extra money?
Is it
upskilling? Is it connections?
Is it doing something, you know, changing political narrative?
So these things are being more seen and more folks are more aware
um
getting more funds
in the field. Um
You know, maybe also changing the way that companies are approaching this.
Um I think there are already so many interesting approaches out there
um with
Opos. But then also
I think,
and it's something that I hopefully in the future,
I can wrap my head around a little bit.
Um How do you create landing space for companies
in open source communities after anything that's happened.
And um
you know, I, I think that's, that's something to deal with.
And then there are a lot of companies that I think
there are developers or even managers who want to contribute to open source,
but they just don't know how or they just really can't
because the processes don't allow it. So I think there are a lot of
open
questions. I think generally the Sovereign tech Fund,
we are quite lucky in that sense that
we always said we are an iterative program. We're doing something new.
We are going to learn, we're going to iterate our programs, our offers our actions um
depending on what we hear and see.
Um
But currently we still definitely have more open questions than
answers and we're trying to tackle one after another.
That's awesome. I'm just going to end it there. I was going to let you,
well, we'll put show notes for links to all the things,
but I can think of no better way to end this show than that.
And I think the,
I can't say the word iterative change.
It's been Kurt's laughing at me.
It's been one of those weeks, but this is,
oh my goodness, Fiona, this is so amazing.
I mean, hats off to you and all your people for the work you're doing. This is,
it's not very often
I hear about a government program that I would say is going
to truly transform anything but especially open source where I think there's been
a historic lack of collaboration,
but this one feels different.
And so I want to just literally thank you
for the work you're doing because it is amazing.
Thank you so much. I'm so happy I got to talk about it.
And
yeah, I want to close with. If you hear something, you see something let us know.
We
are happy to, you
know,
we are open for recommendations.
There's also an application platform that's open for
everyone so we can't hear and see everything.
So if you do, please let us know.
Amazing. Absolutely amazing.
And,
and we'll have to have you back on in a couple of months
and you can tell us all about how the application process went.
Which II I can't wait, I can't wait. It's gonna be so exciting.
Ok. Thank you, everyone. Thank you, Fiona. Thank you, Kurt.
You go to open social security podcast.com. Head up the show notes, Su
Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag Do find us on social media.
I'll put a bunch of links in the show notes to all the things. Fiona talked about.
Fiona and Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- Thank you. You
-- too.
Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye,
the