Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in disparaging technology. Josh Pressers,
we disparage all technology. That's not a surprise.
Well, some more than others.
Like I think rocks are pretty good. I like rocks.
Rocks are dependable.
I'm not so sure about this bronze age thing.
Oh, I know. I know. Seriously. What was up with that coming out of the trees?
What was, didn't Douglas Adams have a joke about that with digital watches?
Yeah. Coming down from the trees.
Is it all went wrong
anyway? Anyway.
And then something about digital watches was included,
which I love how much he picks on digital watches.
He's not wrong.
One thing I love is when I go to the pool with my kids,
I go to the little toddler pool that just soak
in the hot water and splash around and have fun.
And I'm always reminded of like this is what being a sea otter must be like,
you know, like just, oh,
like when I see those videos of sea otters,
they just look so like relaxed and happy, you know, they got their little moss,
they got their favorite little rock.
They're smashing the moos
cope and they're eating it. They're feeding it to their young,
they're rafting together.
You know, they make those little rafts where they hook to each other.
-- Yeah,
-- that's because they don't have, they don't have internet.
That, that's why, that's where we went wrong anyway.
Yeah, we're going to talk about
c, I guess today.
Well, no, we're going to talk about memory, safe and memory, unsafe languages,
which means we're going to throw C under the bus because
we've been doing that for a decade now, I think.
But ok, so I'll, I'll set the stage for us here. The,
the NSA in the United States,
the National Security Agency released a document talking about memory safety.
They basically say stop using CN C++. That's like the TLDR. And
I thought this would be worth covering
because I know we've talked about most of this
stuff in the past at some point which we,
I mean, at this point, I love that we have what, like 300 some odd shows.
Like we've talked about most everything somewhere in that back catalog
don't go too far back because the quality is terrible.
But
I feel like
one hour
-- shows in the beginning. Oh my.
-- Oh man.
Yes.
Yes, we
don't.
And uh I, I, for some reason listened to episode one at some point, part of it for I was,
I was doing something and I'm like,
it's so bad. It's just terrible but whatever, it doesn't matter. OK,
I wanted to talk about this document partially because it, it's current.
So obviously that's interesting. But it also,
there's some things in this that I think are worth discussing
because not everyone knows it. Some people forget it.
And I think it's just fun to talk about because I love C,
I'm gonna just start with that C is
my favorite programming language in the whole world.
But I recognize
it is bad.
Like I know it's,
it, it, it pains me to say. And I also recognize
that even though I love C and even though I've been
doing memory management for like literally 30 years at this point,
I know I can't do it right. And anyone who says they can is lying.
Yeah. Like I remember reading the cow book back in what 98 or something and realizing
this is not for me, like I just,
I'm going to use Pearl and Bash and Python and I'm never going
to program and see because I just don't want to do this.
-- There was no Python back then.
-- Oh, it's true. Yeah. No, that was back enough.
Yeah, there was no, it was Pearl and Bash and I was like, that's it. That's for me.
I remember when Pearl Five came out and we were all very excited.
And the best part is even though I didn't want to do C,
I still had to do C because I downloaded software and to make it compiled,
you'd have to fix it.
That's right.
All right. So I want to kind of explain
why this, this memo from the NSA even exists
because,
and I'm going to focus on C specifically,
I know they say C and C++ and there's other memory managed languages and whatever
we're just gonna talk about C because I like it and I want to,
well, and by like by lines of code and by volume and by impact,
this is like talking about rope,
it's, you know. Yeah.
Yeah. Totally. Totally. OK.
So what does it mean that you have to do your own memory management in C? Right?
When we think of programming, like let's say we're doing Python.
If we have a string, we just have a string and we can
append stuff to it, we can manipulate it,
we can do whatever and we don't think twice about it.
Like
-- you take two strings, you stick them together, pop it
-- out of the stack, bend it,
insert it.
Yeah. And you don't have to think about like how big is it? What's it going into?
-- Do I need a N, do I need an extra bite for the null terminating
-- bite? Right.
And, and we don't even null terminating.
I don't even know like that's not even a topic in Python, right?
So what happens in, in the world of C
if you want to say, put a string in a variable,
you have to first allocate memory to hold the string
and you have to allocate the correct amount of memory.
And as Kurt said,
there's a thing called like a null terminator on many
data structures which is just a null byte of zero
but not all,
not all
I know. And that, I mean, that's part of the challenge, right?
Well, I think a big problem is there's a, there's no consistency,
right? Because if it was consistent,
consistently inconsistent, it's fine.
OK. So we've got our,
our, our bit of memory, we have to allocate
and then we do things to it.
And so let's say you have, I'm just gonna pick on strings a lot.
So I think they're easy to understand.
You have a string
and
you, you wanna add some characters to the string,
you can't just add them.
If you allocated the correct amount of memory,
you have to know how much memory you allocated,
which could be the amount of memory needed for the string.
Exactly. It could be more because sometimes you just allocate extra
for fun.
You know, knowing
you're pulling it out of a database, you're like, hey,
this table is, you know, a 1024 character field. So let's allocate 1024 characters
and then you do some reds
on that string.
Oh my goodness. Red
jack
is like the worst in sea.
But, but anyway, you've got your memory if you want to add something to it.
Now you have to do, it's called reallocate, which is where you say, OK.
Uh This memory is 10 bytes wide. I need 20 bites, right? Like give me 20 bites.
And then the compiler might hand you back the same memory address.
It might hand you a different memory address.
Like you have no idea, not the compiler, the system,
the cur
you have no idea what you're going to get back.
And so obviously, that's part of how it works. You do your stuff
and then you have to free it at the end because if
you have a long running application and you don't free the memory,
now,
you essentially will fill up all the memory space and the application will crash.
And so it's this kind of allocate,
use reallocate and free.
And to be clear, this is what actually the correct term memory leak is.
And a lot of people use memory leaks is like memory being disclosed.
But according to CWE and everything else,
a memory leak is where you basically use memory and fail to free it afterwards.
And also fun fact,
it's not just adding to strings where you have to potentially reallocate stuff.
But for example, when you remove stuff from a string, you can actually
things can still go wrong and that's you can have under reads,
-- you can have like there's yeah,
-- that's super corner case,
right. But the point is even even removing stuff from a string can be unsafe.
Strings are basically
anything to do with
any sort of data handling and memory
consequent memory handling and see
is put
potentially dangerous.
There's like literally nothing you can do safely and be like, no, this is fine,
this is safe.
Like literally everything can go wrong.
Right. Right. Because even reading, yes.
And now like, so here's an example, let's say I've got my string
and I forget to put the null terminating character on the app
the zero.
And now I go to read the string will all of the string manipulating functions.
They expect a null terminator.
So what they actually do is they will
read memory until they hit that null terminator.
So they'll read over the end of your string buffer.
See and like why the hell does the compiler and the system allow that?
Like, you know what I mean? That
-- makes
-- because it,
it has no idea how to figure this out because that's
just how C I mean C is a step above assembly,
right? When you're writing assembly code,
there is no concept of anything.
There's a string terminator is an artificial construct that we had to
create just as a way to know when the string was over.
Because there's no, when, when you're dealing with assembler,
you're just literally reading and writing to random locations and memory, right?
And that's fundamentally what C does
remember.
There's all those things writing about how when they had drum
memory and people would write their apps so that it would,
it would sequentially access drum memory because a physically spinning disk with
stuff on it like,
yeah. And they would purposely put things in locations where the head was going to be
when it finished the last operation to make it faster.
And it was, it's complete madness.
I'll look up, there's some funny stories in some of the hacker folklore
that talks about some of this stuff and why like,
like it was very clever programming, but obviously impossible to debug
if you didn't understand exactly what was going on. Like literally on the drum,
you couldn't do anything. It was madness.
Anyway. Anyway,
before we burn all our time talking about strings.
So basically in the world of sea there, it's easy to make these mistakes.
It's easy to like one of my favorites is, let's say you have a string.
Well, let's say you have memory allocate. It doesn't matter what it is, you free it,
right? The idea is when you free it, you tell the the comp
the colonel,
like I'm giving you this memory back, add it back to the pool, right?
But what happens if you free it again?
Because when, when you free memory, it doesn't like clear the memory to zeros,
it leaves whatever was there.
So when you free it again,
now weird things happen in the memory manager
and a double free is actually a, a pretty serious security vulnerability now.
Well, cwe 415.
There you go.
And it was funny because I remember there was
a time we thought double freeze were just crashes
and then solar designer figured out how to exploit it and we're like, well,
crap now we have to deal with this stuff.
Well, and there's also you're forgetting about use after free,
like you free the memory and then another part of your apps like, hey,
I still needed that.
Give, give it to me
and you know, things go sideways
yet again
with that.
I mean, this is
the problem with that.
So let's say you're,
you're using memory and what happens you have these pointers into the memory,
right?
So like different parts of your program can have pointers and be reading
and writing to different parts of memory and what will happen like this
after free. So if one part of it says I'm done with this memory, let's free it.
Another part still thinks you're using it.
So it might still be reading and writing to memory,
which the application is probably going to work just fine for the most part
because in the historic use of C while that memory wasn't technically allocated,
it was still accessible.
But now if another part of the application asks the memory manager, hey,
give me a block of memory and it hands that block of memory.
Now you have two different parts of the application using the same memory
and they're going to potentially trample
on each other and cause unpredictability.
-- And like this is, I'm just scratching the surface and
-- this is why I use Python.
Yeah.
Right. Right. We'll get to that.
And this is, and you have to think like you've got,
if statements you have control flow, there's so much going on
and if you can write to places in memory,
-- you're not supposed to concurrency
-- shared memory Numa.
Right. Right.
Right.
It's like there's so much complexity here and,
and we're just like we're not even that smart and we're just scratching the surface.
You can imagine the insane difficulty.
Did you read that Netflix Tech blog where they just sold
a um
using Java,
they basically scaled from one type of instance to an
instance that should have been about 2 to 3 times,
perform it.
But it wasn't, it was exactly the same.
And what they found out was is that essentially it was a cash miss.
So there was a one in eight chance the cash
would be correct and thus quick and fast and then
check up seven and eight chance the cash,
you know, because it's an eight core system with eight caches
essentially that it would miss and you know,
latency spikes all over the place. And it was crazy
and they literally added a 64 byte padding statement
and all the latencies and everything just poop
and they got something like 350% performance improvement by adding a 64 byte pad.
So that to force the cash
and the CPU to kind of be in alignment and everything to work out, right?
And it literally was like a 10 line code change.
Yeah, it's just,
and that's in Java where like you technically have memory management, but
even if you have memory management, you can still,
you know, stuff gets put in a cache
for a different CPU core and
now the time and latency is all over the place. So,
so one thing to point out is
like
even if you use a memory safe language,
you won't have maybe as many security problems,
but you will still have problems because
just this is an inherently difficult problem,
right?
And, and look, let's be clear,
you can use Python and Python still has security vulnerabilities.
It just doesn't have like buffer overflows. For example,
what's
different,
the kind of vulnerabilities it has typically are solved in Python.
And I don't have to do anything other than upgrade Python
in in some cases,
right?
That's a big part of it is like with C you know, I have to fix all that code.
OK? So let, let's talk about that.
So there's a note in this document from the
NSA which will of course be in the show notes
where they talk about Microsoft and Google.
They, they, if you look at their, they, there was a presentation
Oh, it just says.
So Microsoft revealed at a conference in 2019 that from 2006 to
2018 70% of their vulnerabilities were due to memory safety issues.
And then Google also found a similar percentage
over seven years in chrome.
And and I mean, you have to remember
that when you're dealing with something like chrome or
windows or internet explorer or edge or whatever,
these are applications that are essentially dealing with hostile code.
Well, hostile data, hostile code, everything
and not even intentionally hostile but just broken stuff. Like I've
stumbled across older web servers or web servers that are non conforming.
Or I remember literally, oh,
we had one provider that had an HSTS header that had an extra semicolon.
So technically,
it should be ignored because it was incorrect and
some browsers would ignore it correctly and some actually
listen to it, which is technically incorrect, but much safer,
right? But, but anyway, you get the point. There's,
there's all of the C code that has memory problems and a lot
of the bugs that we find in browsers and operating systems are fundamentally me
-- memory safety issues, especially
-- the exploitable security vulnerabilities
to be the
man
we've added some technologies over the years to try to mitigate some of this.
And they talk about this in this NSA document
where there's things like Microsoft has something called control flow guard,
which is meant to prevent an application from executing unexpected code.
Like one of the things that will happen
if I can write arbitrary things into random places in memory,
I can potentially overwrite a function pointer
or potentially a return address or something like that.
And so control flow guard is supposed to catch some of that. It won't catch it all.
Obviously,
we created address space layout randomization, which is a SLR
the idea behind this is when we used to write exploits. Back in the day,
every compiled application would use the same memory addresses for everything.
So you could say like I know the return address for
this function is going to be at this memory location.
If I can overwrite that memory location, I can take control of the program,
stuff like that.
And so we changed that. So now all of the addresses are random.
Fun fact, this was uh I think it was an IBM consultant,
gave a talk at a Linux users group like this is two de uh about a decade or well,
no two decades ago.
And he said that was one of his favorite reasons for using.
Oh jeez,
was it Gen two Linux where you basically
had compile everything yourself on your system?
Because every gen two system had different
-- return addresses.
-- That's right. That's right.
And, and when, well, usually when you compile something on two different systems,
you get two different
address layouts, you know, not always, but generally speaking, that is true
there is something we created called depth, which is data execution prevention.
One of the favorites from back in the day
is
you could write shell code into like stack memory or heat memory
and then just jump right to it and it would execute.
And so we we eventually we were like wait a minute.
There's no reason we should ever be executing
code from this piece of memory over here.
Like just say, not executable, right? Never execute.
It's only for reading and writing data.
If you want to blame somebody for that, you can blame John Von Newman.
Like literally,
this is how fundamentally architecturally this stuff
goes back in time because there are,
there were sort of theorized but never
really executed computer architectures where data and executable
memory and stuff was separate.
But
I I can't even imagine how you'd build that
system in the in to be modern performing system.
So actually
Itanium did this which has has garnered the name Itanic,
which this was the intel chip from hand
like 2000 give or take.
They they tried to create a different kind of 64 bit processor. It was
pretty banana is what it did.
I I did some research on it way back in the day
because I worked at a little start up called Progeny Linux systems.
And
it was, oh man, it was like,
I think HP maybe sent us a whole bunch of Itanium
to do development because obviously they wanted to sell them,
say looking for developers
who development was 89 to 2000.
Amazing.
It was one of those things where it started like it was kind
of one of those hail Marys to like fundamentally change the world.
And no, I'm sorry man, if it's not X 86 it's not happening.
I mean, and, and that's what happened.
But anyway,
the itanium had a special register stack because one of the things we would
do back in those days is if you could get a stack buffer overflow,
the return address for function calls was just stored on the stack.
And if you could overwrite that, that variable,
you could basically make the application jump to wherever you want your shell code.
Ideally
and Itanium put all the registers somewhere else.
That way you couldn't do that, right. You couldn't access the register stack
when you were in a function call. But we know how that worked out. Anyway,
there, there's also not mention in this,
there's things like stack canaries have been added.
There's
uh uh there, there's uh return oriented programming RP
protections that have been added.
There's, there's all this other technology that was added to C over the,
the countless decades.
And fundamentally, not just
-- but
-- also to the compilers to the operating system.
That's all, it's all compiler stuff.
It's not added to C I shouldn't, I shouldn't clarify that.
Yes, the compilers and operating systems and fundamentally like it's better,
it's harder to exploit.
But it's
like we haven't solved these problems.
This would be like trying to solve the
fundamental problems of cars and humans driving cars by
having humans continue to drive cars. Like we'll somehow make it
like, yeah, we can add airbags, we can add anti lock brakes,
we can make it safer and better.
But with fundamentally, this technology has limitations that just
humans,
that's exactly the right answer. Like
in terms of safety with automobiles, we've probably reached
about the limits of what we can do with humans driving.
Like if you buy a super high
end car now and have a super high
end trained driver,
there's,
are you gonna bet that they'll never have an accident? Would you bet your life? Of
-- course not, of
-- course not.
And it might not be their fault, right?
There's like so much that can happen and same thing with C
and then they also talk about in this, some of the,
there's like
Sat and DAST, which is static analysis and dynamic analysis.
And examples of this are you have like source code analyzers that
these applications will look at your source code and try to find bugs that
-- you might have put in which in
-- C fuzzing that scale like American fuzzy
loop and you know. Right.
Well,
and there's like Os S Fuzz doing this kind of work and that's
like gas where you're running the application and you're dumping garbage into it
and you're trying to crash it
and, and like, those have also helped make things better, but again,
we've kind of reached the limits of what all of
this technology can do in terms of making c better.
And so I think that's why
we're seeing some of this complaining and I think
the more important part of this a decade ago,
if I would have told you, we have to stop using c
people would probably nod their head.
Yeah. Well, we did, we,
well,
it's the same thing saying like a decade ago we have to stop using gasoline cars.
Well,
I agree with you in principle.
But
-- what
-- exactly. And now what was exactly it?
But now I think this is why we're going to see more of this is, I think the,
the technology has caught up with reality finally
and we have not that we didn't have Python or
Java or many of these other languages in the past.
I think the difference now is we have rust
and we have, I, I guess AAA paradigm shift. I just said paradigm shift.
Not ironically,
um,
in the world, did you?
I did, I can feel it. It's, it's in my bones
but
you know what I mean?
Like we're, we're moving a lot of workloads,
we're changing the way we do a lot of things.
And so I think that the purpose of this is, and they don't even talk about rust in this,
this document, right.
Actually, I should, I should do a search. I don't remember seeing Rust.
Uh oh, they do have Rust? No, that's Rust. Rust. Oh, they do.
They do list Rust as one of their languages.
-- I think
-- realistically,
Rust is one of the best options here for the simple reason that
it plays well with existing sea code and that's the thing to remember, right.
We've talked about this one
but like open SSL is a great example.
You will never rip and replace, well, even if you can rip and replace open SSL,
like TV,
vendors just aren't like it needs to be a perfect drop in
replacement where they like literally change two lines in a config file somewhere
and they might do that.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, there's, there's two ways, OK? There's two ways to look at this problem.
There's the,
we'll say the Linux kernel way where they're going to add the ability
to add Rust code to the Linux kernel with the obvious intent,
even though it's not spoken out loud very often.
The obvious intent is that eventually core functionality is going to
migrate its way into rust because that's a no brainer.
You don't have memory safety issues.
You gain all of the speed benefits and weirdness of sea without the memory problems.
Well,
more to the point using something like rust
means your device driver developer can now focus on
writing a device driver and not writing a
device driver and doing all their memory management,
that's fair.
And memory management in the kernel is extra weird because it's kernel
-- not like what we're used to
-- when you're dealing with network devices.
-- Oh man, like memory management is a next level
-- difficult.
Well, so here's the problem with, with like device drivers in the kernel.
If you have like a network driver,
you the the the goal is to get something off the network and get it to user space,
right?
And that transition from the kernel to user space is weird because
you can't just hand an application like a pointer into kernels frame
or like or here's an Ethernet frame
like no, the application is like what the hell is an Ethernet frame?
Well, ignoring that, I mean, even once you decode everything
like we we we've had bugs that do this
where where a device driver accidentally handed an application,
a writeable handle into kernel memory and you could, you could create a mess,
right? And like this is a problem.
Now
there's the other half of this I think which is where
if you are like drastically changing your application or let's
say you're migrating from one technology to a new technology,
there is no reason to start a new
product or project or service or whatever and
see like use one of these other languages.
It will be, you will develop faster, it might not be as performant,
-- but the benefits drastically outweigh
-- I'm so glad you said that because the,
the performance argument seems to be the most common.
Go to anti security argument
for memory safety.
Oh,
right.
And what's so, and, and let's be clear here.
I am not against performance because for example, there is a real world impact.
Like if you can make certain functions faster,
it actually has an impact on carbon footprint.
Like there's cloud providers now that are starting
to measure the carbon footprint of workloads.
And for the sake of argument, if you make a workload, 50% more efficient,
that can save tons of carbon emissions like that actually matters.
So,
let's assume like that's a good thing. I'm not against that.
But what I will point out is the vast majority of people have workloads
that are not worth optimizing. So a perfect example, the CS A website
like we're not amazon.com, we have a website, we serve quite a few hits actually.
But you know,
I'm not going to make my devs go spend weeks making it 10% more efficient, right?
It's written in rails, not the most performant language.
Well, perfect example, Mastodon right now, right?
People are discovering Mastodon is kind of a pain to scale
because it's written in Ruby on rails and you know,
like uh what was it, Ariadne
was like? Oh, I gave it bigger CP US,
don't do that. Give it more CP US, right?
And I'm like, yeah,
it's Rails app like you just like our scale plan at the CS A is pay Hiroko more money.
I think a lot of people think that the,
so the performance of your application does matter to some degree because
if your website takes like 60 seconds to return a web page.
Yeah, that's no good.
But fundamentally like when you get it down to say half a second or whatever,
unless you're doing like high frequency trading
or your Amazon running on Black Friday,
the vast majority of us,
something like rails or Python running in its pretty
much default state is more than good enough.
I have a great example for what you just described.
There are services where the performance is very important.
Discord has a blog post where they were using some go
to now go is a,
a memory managed language in the kind of way
Python does it where like garbage collection is go's problem
now it whereas in Rust, you have to basically say like I'm done using this thing.
It's just you can't screw anything up when you're doing it.
Now,
wait, Russ doesn't have built in GC like you have to trigger it.
You have to Yeah, you have to do it yourself,
which is,
which is the, that's the key.
So anyway, Discord was using go and there were these spikes every like two minutes,
right?
It was, it was rust doing garbage collection obviously.
And then they rewrote it or not rust it was go, sorry, go doing garbage collection.
Then
they rewrote it in rust
and it was very smooth because now they were controlling as things were being,
you know, allocated and de
allocated.
Yeah, there's a common problem with languages that have a GC sweep.
You hit that GC sweep and like system latency,
like,
and
there are applications where that is a huge problem.
And like in the case of discord, it was a huge problem.
This is why we now have languages that are capable of dealing with this,
that we didn't have a decade ago.
And so that's why I think like the time is right
to have this discussion and why the NSA is starting it.
Part of it is not just
it's a technology ecosystem, right?
So I don't know if you remember, but I had a slide deck when I worked at Red Hat,
like in the first month I worked there talking about why this cloud happen now.
And it's kind of like rocketry. We had all the ideas for rocketry back in the day,
but we didn't have the metallurgy to
make stuff that could withstand the temperatures
or the idea of like cryo pumps or the idea of like run the fuel around,
you know, the bell nozzle to pre heat it and cool the nozzle. And you know,
the whole thing from exploding.
And this is kind of where we are with
these memory managed safe languages is we also now have
mon,
like my desktop is a Ryzen 5 5600 X. It is a monster CPU
by any standard,
you know, with 48 gigs of ra M. Like, it's just my cheap little windows desktop,
you know,
like your, your
apple ecosystem with the M two chips. Those things are monsters
computationally.
And so part of it is,
it's this whole ecosystem like, like you could build the best Python ever.
But if you're stuck on P one hundreds, it doesn't matter.
It's going to be so terrible,
you know, and also you don't have the frameworks the,
the other bits because like no offense.
But
if you're using just Python, you're doing it wrong.
You want to be using the whole Python pi pie
world because like literally every time I write Python,
I'm like, oh, I have to,
oh I had to write code to like par C pe S. No, I don't import C pe,
right? And that's part of it is.
And this is part of where Rust and especially Python are
starting to take off is that and go is a good,
a great example of this is those standard libraries of like,
OK, people can't go write their own web service anymore.
Just no, you cannot do that, you have to import it.
And this is getting,
you know,
all the,
all the difficult things are being put into libraries by experts.
And
that's part of the power of this is, that's part of it.
You know, when we talked about, like, the open source, can we shut the door?
No, because you're already in the open source world and you can't go write your own.
You know, there's no way to stop. And that's part of this is like, if I give you Rust
and no web server,
well, that's like 90% of people can't use it.
Right. You know what I mean?
Like you need these libraries, you need these extra things like, oh,
it has safe string and like, yeah, I don't care, I need a web server that just works.
I need
all these other things that just work.
-- So
-- you, you raise a good point. So back in the early days when I would write a lot of C
like I,
one of my favorite stories is I was at uh progeny Linux systems and I had to,
I had to decode XML with C because
it was
holy cow.
That was the first job they gave me there because they were like,
we can't figure this out.
Can you figure it out?
They had a memory leak and, and yeah, that was the problem
when people look at XML and
JSON decoders, there are XML and
JSON decoders and there are stream decoders and people,
most people don't know what a stream decoder is because they've
never been on a system slow enough to need it.
We, we needed that. It had to be a stream decoder because we were looking for certain,
yeah, we, we were, it was, it was uh an application run.
It was called Discover Discover Two where it was meant to
do uh uh hardware identification during install of the Linux system.
And we did,
we didn't know we didn't have a lot of memory to work
with because you could potentially have a system with very little memory.
So we purposely had to make it stream and be very memory efficient.
But that also led to memory leaks
because
we were parsing XML. But anyway, anyway,
but,
oh my goodness. Anyway, anyway,
so I, I wanna,
I wanna tie this one up now and I know we've
done a lot of complaining about C because why not?
-- And, and I still
-- love it.
Well, the thing is C was an advancement for the time, but that was 20 well,
30 years ago, it's time to move on
our
-- tools and,
-- and, and I think that's part of it, right?
So,
like I remember in the early days we'd write C and the first thing you did was
you had to sit down and add a whole bunch of functionality for like allocating and de
allocating memory and doing some stuff like that. Like
no developer wants to do that. That's a waste of their time, right?
And these other languages don't necessarily have that.
And I think that's kind of the point of all this, the NSA puts out this, this guidance
-- and fundamentally at the end of the day, it's just stop using C like
-- that's it.
And what's interesting is there are some now anecdotal data points.
So NVIDIA has a slash shot posting that will put the notes.
But uh
but uh here we go back in 2008, a proof of concept exercise was conducted,
two low level security sensitive applications were converted from C to
Spark is this language? I don't know.
So OK, I actually didn't know what spark was. I looked it up.
Spark is a version of ADA that is verified. And in the world of computer science,
if you can verify a language is where you mathematically
prove the program is correct and doesn't contain issues.
There's been a lot of computer science work done in this space,
but generally speaking, it's never caught on because it's,
it's a little too wonky, we'll say. And I mean, wonky in the Wonkish regard,
I actually had a friend who did his phd in this.
But, but getting back to this and that's one of the things they talk about is
rather than having this sort of strategy of security through testing
and sort of hardening is a security strategy of well correctness,
which is interesting because like, for example,
that's what open BS D has always tried to do.
And to claim is like,
they don't care about
security vulnerabilities,
they care about correctness and everything needs to be as correct as possible.
And, you know, and based on the fact that they're using C, well,
there's still vulnerabilities in open SSH two decades later and they've been,
you know, they've been trying to clean that thing up forever.
So that's
the,
the first like,
what's interesting though is um uh here we go as a
result of the proof of concept validated the initial strategy,
the use of spark spread rapidly within NVIDIA.
There are now over 50 developers trained in numerous components implemented
in spark and many NVIDIA products are now shipping with spark components
so it can be done.
But it does,
I think the biggest problem is it requires like a
culture shift because this isn't just a technology change.
This is like going from like I think
before
we started recording the show was or maybe it was on the show,
-- the the whole rocks to bronze transition like that requires
-- just, yeah,
we talked about that at the beginning.
That's just
requires a very fundamental mental shift that not all companies can do
well and not just that if someone like you and I show up to corporate leadership,
we're like we should stop using C and we should the other languages,
-- they're gonna be like, yeah,
-- can security?
Can you have a escorted out? Right?
Where,
where the the people standing on the box preaching to the masses on the corner?
Who don't, don't care what I'm talking about,
right?
Whereas when the NSA and some of these other will say,
large security minded organizations start talking about this.
Now, I'm not just the sole voice of, of sanity.
Now, I can say, look,
these other smart people are saying the same things I've been saying
it's time to listen.
And so I'm hopeful that is what comes of this.
Well, part of it is just acknowledging that there's a problem because I,
I think a lot of people don't think there's a
problem because they've been living with this for so long.
It's just like cars crash, that's normal. What do you mean? Cars shouldn't crash?
Like what they do crash?
You, what are you saying? We should make cars that don't crash? Why, why would we do?
Like, what?
You know, and it's just,
there's so many things in life we live with that
are painful until somebody kind of makes it go away.
We're like,
like, wow, we lived with this horrible thing forever.
That was dumb.
Yeah,
I think we're at the point where, where people don't ask that question anymore.
I think everyone gets, we need to move on. And I think, I mean, this is
I'm hopeful in a couple of years.
Well, and then the next thing is how do we move on?
And we have an answer for that now.
Well, yeah, we do.
And it's not perfect.
I'm not saying like you can just, yeah, just go start writing with,
but we're at the point where it's actually realistically possible and
within, I'm guessing less than five years,
like the Rust standard library and, you know, the,
the training around it and the books around it and everything,
the ecosystem will have caught up enough
that you can actually take a junior Dev and get them
up to speed and rust in probably 3 to 6 months.
I hope so. I truly hope so.
All right, we're gonna find out we'll come back in five years and report back.
All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank everyone for listening. Go to open
our security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not Susie Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the.