Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in the Rock Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, what's new and exciting? Not much, actually. Well,
-- there's plenty new and exciting in the world.
-- I mean, the world,
like, literally there's a new CBC podcast called World on Fire.
And I just looked at him. I like, yeah, I don't, I don't need to listen to this.
-- I already know what it is.
-- You know, I kind of agree with that.
I, I stopped watching the, so in the mornings I used to make my coffee
and then go turn on the local news and, like, sit there and half listen to the news,
half read my newspaper and I've quit turning on the
news because it's just everything is such a tire fire.
At least with the newspaper I can hit next on the
stories that I don't want to read and it's just,
oh, man.
Yeah, it's, it's hard being a human
today
and that's related to what we're going to talk
about as well as just the world in general.
Yeah.
And I think most of us also have, like, enough weirdness going on in our lives with,
you know,
like just schedule disruptions and life disruptions like it,
you know, I love this whole,
oh, so this is what work from home is like. No, no, I've done this for 22 years.
-- Work from home is nothing like this.
-- It has been really hard to concentrate.
-- The
-- first
-- 21.5 years were ok. Then the last five months have been rough.
It's, it's been bananas for sure. And
it's,
it's always wild talking to people who have never
worked from home before and don't even like it.
Which
in my brain, I think, how could you not like it like that. But
at the same time
they're totally not working from home.
-- Well,
-- I mean, if this is your experience of working from home. Yeah.
-- No, I'm sorry, you're totally fair to hate this.
-- Yeah.
Yeah. Seriously. Anyway, anyway, humans insecurity.
I was going to
the show.
So, one of the things I was thinking about is so,
Kurt sends me a link to Schneier's blog
and there's what, what is it, the
security and human behavior,
security and human behavior is what it's about.
And it's a really interesting concept and it's something,
actually ironically I wrote a blog post about
unknowingly that this was going to be our topic
that is published now, you know,
link to it. It's about, I, I, what did I call it? The Ineffective
ciso? Maybe it's, it's Clickbait title. But anyway,
you know what I kept thinking of before we last night.
Well, I was, I was kind of, you know,
doing some research and everything for this episode
was if I could retitled this podcast,
which I would never do it just because it's too much work,
I would call it security philosophy, I think,
because I think that more accurately describes what we do then
than actually open source security,
which is our background.
But I feel like as security practitioners with the podcast,
we are definitely more philosophy than security. I think in most of these episodes.
Well, I mean, we lucked out.
Well, we didn't luck out, but we, we lucked out and that we chose open sources are,
you know, which, which is what one fundamentally.
-- So we got lucky there, Survivor
-- Bias, I knew it would win.
Well, hey, 20 years ago, man, that was not, that was not a clear outcome.
No, it kind of wasn't actually.
And you know,
that would be a fun show some time just to
talk about some of the crazy stories from the past.
You wonder,
I just installed visual studio code
and then looked at it and realized I also have visual studio already installed.
And I'm like, when did I do that?
Like I've literally at some point installed Microsoft development tools because
I guess I was investigating them and forgot about it.
-- And it's like, I guess Microsoft isn't the baddies anymore. They
-- run on Linux,
man. I mean, if you would have told me 20 years ago, visual studio would run on Linux.
I would have punched you in the face. Like I'd have been like, you're an idiot.
You have no idea what you're talking about.
Yeah. For your, for your own good and the good of the species we need to put you down.
That's right. That's right. You're an idiot. And,
yeah. Anyway, anyway, that's a topic for another day today.
We're going to talk about security and human behavior,
which I think is a super fascinating topic because one of the things, I guess,
ironically, well, a couple of things I always think about here is
you've got on one side,
people are people and
they're going to do people things
and then there's kind of this side of security where we'll tell people things like,
-- oh, don't click links and don't open on suspicious emails and
-- don't,
don't click links
that you don't trust. So somehow you're supposed to click
and know what they are and where they go, even though we all use URL shortener now.
Yeah, it's a lot of our advice is insane.
And we also often fail to just account for the fact
that people are people and they're going to do people things.
I don't even, I don't even know where I want to start with this one.
-- I
-- think the problem is it's so complicated because it's not just one question.
It's multiple questions. It's like a human can be fully security trained.
But there is a big difference
in a person between, they had eight hours of sleep and they had three hours of sleep.
There are differences.
They've done studies with parole boards and, you know,
you better be getting your parole hearing right after lunch, not before lunch,
but after lunch before.
Right, they're, you know, they've done all these studies with, you know,
how humans make decisions.
I've read into this a lot.
I remember one time the company I worked for one was talking about, hey, you know,
we need 24 7 coverage.
So we're going to like, make people work different shifts.
You'll work a bunch of day shifts and then a bunch of night shifts.
And my response is no, I'll quit.
And what was really interesting is I looked up
a whole bunch of studies and information on this
to basically prove what a terrible idea this was.
And one fascinating study was from the first Gulf War. So fighter pilots, right?
Fighter pilots need to basically go out and fly planes up all sorts of random times.
Right.
So, to help them with this, they give them drugs, you know,
and downers uppers to stimulate them and, you know, get going and downers
when they come back, they can crash and get some sleep.
And what was most interesting to me was the young pilots were taking
the uppers and the older pilots generally tended to take the sedatives,
the downers to get, you know, more rest.
So, even a truly professionally, like these guys cost millions of dollars to train.
And what was amazing to me is they had no
specific sort of doctrine or strategy for how to handle, you know,
medication to keep them awake.
-- It was kind of left up to the pilot.
-- I mean, that doesn't surprise me
-- and it kind of makes sense because everybody's different. Right.
-- Right. Right.
-- Right.
-- All these human things, you know? Ok.
So let's do this.
-- Let's start with Schneer and what he did
-- quick back story.
-- If you don't know who Sneer is, he wrote a book called,
-- everyone knows who Schneer
-- is, who's listening to this podcast.
-- I bet you a dollar.
Somebody listening to this show doesn't
because honestly applied cryptography has kind of been out of sight for a long time.
That's true. And it's even considered harmful in some places.
But it's still a cool book.
I would actively agree that it is now harmful, but 10 years ago it was 10,
but the world changed.
When did, when did it come out,
uh,
ages ago?
But I, I would say more to the point,
like crypto matured to the point now where you just, you use the cream, rub it on.
That's it. Just use it as, as specified on the tube,
make up your own cream.
So he wrote applied cryptography.
I don't remember if there's ever, I think there was a second volume, sort of ish,
but not really.
But anyways, he basically has become one of the, I guess,
grandfathers of information security, kind of the wise old man.
-- Yeah, we could, I'll buy that.
-- He's done a lot of thoughtful pieces.
He's, he's done a lot of,
I don't want to call it high level work but it's sort of
that really high level strategic where
there's nothing you can really actually specifically
immediately do with it, but you really should be reading it.
Yeah, I'll agree with that.
So, yeah, one of the things he's done is the security and human behavior conference,
which I, that's now in its 12th year.
Like I was looking at that and I'm like, man, this, we've been around for a while.
It's invite only
and, and in all seriousness, I think Schneier
was talking about human behavior
before most of us cared.
Well,
I feel like a lot of technologists get stuck in the
trap of trying to solve all problems with the same hammer,
the same technological hammer, right?
Like I've had so many people ask, how do I prevent X where X is?
Much more of a social problem than a technical problem.
Like people ask me how I secure my kids computers and I'm like, well simple.
It's up against the wall in the living room, in a public space.
Like they, you know, it's just high
visible
and when he's on it,
you know, like we keep an eye on him.
Right.
And that's probably far more effective than any technical
measure you can possibly because let's face it.
In most families,
the kids are smarter than the parents and they're going to get around
any sort of lockdown software you try to put on that computer.
Well,
the number of people I've had where they've tried to
lock down their kids' devices specifically so they can't,
like, view too much youtube videos.
Like, they only get half an hour an hour or whatever.
And the number of interesting and weird workarounds kids have found. It's amazing.
Yeah, the security and human behavior thing.
One thing I like about his conference is that it is small and they've structured
apparently so that, like,
everybody gets a few minutes to talk and kind of do their thing.
So there's, it sounds like there's a,
instead of like five or six people talking for an hour,
it's several dozen people each getting their five or 10 minutes.
-- So you get, it sounds like a lot more cross pollination
-- from what I've gathered.
There's seven minute talks
and then people break out and discuss facets of whatever the topic is,
which I love that.
That I'm not gonna lie.
When I go to a conference,
I'll, I'll go to a handful of talks, but generally speaking, the hallway,
hallway con, as people say is where it's at,
I've never enjoyed having someone talk at me for an hour.
In fact, I hate, like, I like giving talks.
-- I don't like giving talks for an hour
-- because my favorite
part is always the Q and A at the end,
especially when somebody asks a question. I'm like, holy crap.
I totally forgot to cover that or just that to
my mind.
Or my favorite thing. I always tell people when I'll start.
One of these talks is I love being interrupted and if you can derail me so bad,
we don't finish a slide deck.
I consider that a success.
And like I've, I've done talks before where I make it through two slides and we,
we're off the rails and I love it.
It's marvelous.
-- You want
-- to hear my ideal scenario, a person presents a talk,
they have their slides and they actually send out in
advance the slides with proper notes and an agenda,
but everybody acts,
he reads and pays attention to so that you can whip through the slides
in about four minutes and then get to the guts of the discussion.
That would be my ideal scenario in a perfect world.
Never going to happen. I get that.
But, you know, if we had spherical counts, that's what I would want to happen.
Yeah, I could agree with that. I do enjoy the conversations.
It's definitely more interesting for sure.
-- And
-- this leads to my biggest thing where, you know,
you and I are having that disagreement of whether or not
this sort of stuff is actually conferences in general are useful.
So I would argue
they are not useful for the reason people think they are
OK.
And
I would say so people envision you go to a conference,
you're going to learn new things and you can then take your knowledge back
to wherever it is you came from and apply it in some meaningful way.
And I'm going to argue that most of the conference content I've seen and even given,
I don't think is particularly useful.
-- I think a lot of the ideas are old and stuffy is
-- the word you want to use is actionable.
That's a fair word, I think. And yeah, there's rarely any actionable items.
A lot of this stuff is just thinly veiled
sales pitches for wherever somebody happens to be working.
And I find them frustrating and it's very flat.
I would, I was actually listening to Russell Brand's podcast the other day,
he had Conan o'brien on which was a marvelous episode.
And the thing Conan o'brien, he, how he described fame is a flavorless broth.
And I think that's what a lot of these conference talks feel like because it's,
it's like a flavorless broth.
-- You, you, you can consume it, but there's no sustenance in it
-- to actually,
I would agree generally with what you're saying. But I would add to that.
I think on the Dunning Kruger Curve, I remember every year going to RSA and, you know,
these people would be giving new talks on new attacks and I'm like, no,
I already heard about that, like, months ago.
My favorite is when the same people give the same talks every year on the same thing.
And it's like, this is insanity.
Well, I mean,
I'm talking about actually new stuff but I was working
for security information vendors at the time where it's like,
yeah.
no, we, we were told about that because we were part of the effort to deal with this.
And then it's like, oh, yeah. Right.
I'm not, I'm not having to fix printers or servers. Right.
I'm in the information security industry side of this,
not the actually making it work side industry.
And so one thing that I always have to keep in mind is for a lot of people,
this stuff is new.
A great example, you know, hands up who here
-- knows what Excel pivot tables are.
-- You can't say hands up on a podcast. Yeah.
Anyways point is how many people use Excel or a spreadsheet at
least once or twice in their life and have no idea.
Pivot tables exist. Cool.
But how many people use Excel, like on a weekly or daily basis and don't know,
-- pivot tables exist
-- probably lots.
I know what they are. I basically can't ever get them to work. So I don't care.
But the point is they're this hugely useful, easy to use. Tool.
Like literally,
you just need to spend 10 minutes on youtube watching
a tutorial video and you can start using them.
-- I've spent more than 10 minutes and I still can't figure
-- them
-- out.
-- Ok.
Well, in Google Sheets, they have a walk through example that makes it really easy.
Like it literally helps you select your data anyways. I tried it. I couldn't do it.
Ok.
Well, I literally, the last,
I literally set this up yesterday and I had
to re watch the tutorial because I forgot how,
and it took me three minutes.
But the point is it's this hugely useful tool
and it's not even that most people don't know
how to use it. It's that most people don't even know it exists.
And that's one of the things I do find useful for these conferences.
Like a great example.
Remember when I Ds and IP S was new and people were literally like,
it blew their mind like they, you know, wait,
I, OK. So I know what a firewall is and I can block incoming data to arbitrary ports.
Cool. Wait, you're saying I can like, actually filter for content and sort of
the bad stuff and let the good stuff through, you know what I mean?
And that was at one point that was new and again,
I bet you there's still people out there that don't really have
a good cognition of what this is and what it can do.
Yeah. You know, you're probably not wrong. I'm spinning this in my mind now of
what, what does that mean?
So the point is, is just knowing something exists, is a huge step forward,
knowing that there is a territory that is marked here, be dragons and going.
Huh?
I wonder what is actually there?
Well, and you know, you know, what else you just made me realize is
we were,
we had a conversation before I hit record where I had to remind Kurt that in no way,
are we comparable to normal people?
Because you're talking about dropping laptops
and Kurt and I don't drop laptops.
Like it's just an unwritten rule will say like, it's just don't do it.
Well, it's like people who break their phones and I'm like,
why did you break your phone?
We're not getting into.
My point is given
our, our how long we've been in the industry and we have a podcast.
So we obviously consume
vastly more information than I suspect most security people.
And, and let's face it. There are security people that it's a job.
Well, most people are busy
-- making stuff work so their boss doesn't yell at them. Yeah, that
-- too. That too.
And so it's a very different universe I think in that regard.
And so I'm spinning this in my brain and I don't think you're wrong in a lot of ways.
I, I always think back like basics there, there's so many basic fundamentals that,
where, where do you get them from?
And I think unfortunately, in a lot of cases, conferences might be it,
which is appalling now that I'm thinking about it.
Well, it's not just that it's the,
is having the time and space to actually, like,
breathe and learn something and not be.
I remember once when I was very young, you know,
looking locally for a job and this one place was like,
we expect you to work like 40 or whatever hours a week.
And I'm like, cool. And it's like, and we expect you to stay up to date in your own time.
And I'm like, well, I do that anyways, but I'm not cool with you.
Kind of expecting me to then
-- do 10 to 20 unpaid hours of work a week.
-- They had a term for this
in,
in a company I used to work for,
we called it church time where instead of going to church,
you spend that time doing something that is,
your company should be letting you do anyways.
It's just the way they structured it and kind of presented it.
I was like, ok, I'm, I do not want to work for you because it was pretty clear,
it was a sweatshop.
But that's the reality where a lot of people work is.
They don't have the time and space and support from their leadership
to actually get better.
I mean, and, and even when you do so, like, in all
seriousness.
I currently work, I work at Elastic and they're very generous with this concept.
We call it space time where we encourage people to take
like a week or two to go and do something that isn't your day to day job.
And it's not really, you know,
it's not vacation either but you go do something else and like,
I'm in a position where I just don't have time for space time,
which is super annoying.
And of course, it's easy to say, oh, just take your time.
But it's like, no, because if I don't do this,
my work is literally going to pile up because I don't have anyone to help,
do some of these tasks right now.
And I mean, one of the goals is like get Josh some help,
but that's also easier said than done in itself.
-- And so I get this, it's
-- the red queen. You have to run just to stay where you are.
Oh, absolutely. 100%. And it's super frustrating because I know I'm doing it.
And funny enough when I was younger,
-- I didn't realize that
-- so many people burn out of infosec
because they don't realize that in a lot of infosec,
you have to run to keep up.
And the problem is there are things that you can let fall by the wayside.
But to know what things you can actually let fall by the wayside and
not get like fired for requires a high degree of maturity and again,
some support from your leadership.
Right. So anyways back to the actual Shulk
topic,
I like conferences because
I don't want to call them normals because it, people even are not normal, but like,
even for it, people just to know that,
you know, products exist or to know that a new strategy exists.
Like how many people basically
know about Blockchain, but actually what they know is a little bit about Bitcoin.
And they think that that's what the Blockchain world is.
And when I start telling them what is actually not just possible in Blockchain
and distributed ledger technologies,
but what is actually out there in the form of like, things like, you know,
R three or hyper ledger or block one or whatever,
like things that are actually shipping where you can, like,
download an SDK and start building things.
-- It blows their mind
-- or what they, what they're good for.
I mean, I actually, so I had, uh, someone I work with, their daughter was
doing a report on security and she said,
can my daughter, you know, can we have a, like,
I want to take 15 minutes of your time or whatever?
And I said schedule an hour. Trust me.
That's what I said. I said schedule an hour.
She's like, I don't want to take that much time. I'm like, just trust me.
Schedule an hour. All right. Well, we'll take as much time as we need
and, yeah, I took an hour but,
and, and, yeah, at one point the, uh, this lady's daughter was like, you know,
what do you know about, like, Blockchain?
What is this Blockchain stuff? And I said, all right, we don't have a lot of time.
I've got, like, buckle up, I'm going to give it and,
and the thing is at first it was like, oh, magic money, whatever.
I don't get it. But then when I started talking about like lettuce, right?
How, how people are using,
let you know the Blockchain technology to track the lettuce supply chain.
And obviously, then when you have, let's say some sort of incident with,
let's say coli
and lettuce and all of a sudden now you
don't have suppliers that are like just accidentally,
you know, tipping that book into the garbage.
And no, we didn't have any lettuce come through here, you know, like, yeah, you did.
It's, it's right there anyway. Anyway, II, I do think you're right.
And I think so funny enough, we've, we've transitioned this, this talk from,
I guess, human behavior into conferences.
But I think that is an interesting point you raise is
they give certain people
and out, I guess almost.
But now here is the other side and I think the danger of conferences there are more
people I know than not who don't have budget or time to go to any conferences.
Well, I guess the good news there is a COVID.
-- It's all the conferences have a virtual component now
-- they do and
it is different for sure.
But I think even more importantly than COVID I would say has been. Besides
yes,
because I found the B size regional
conferences are substantially higher quality than anything
I've seen at like Black Hat or Rs A in the last decade.
And it is accessible
-- and fun.
-- I would say Bides has more variation.
The larger conferences tend to be very much a bell curve.
-- I think for content quality,
-- I agree with that 100%.
Partly because people are
-- so invested in trying to game the system.
-- They got to play it safe too. Right.
You can't bite a chicken's head off on stage
but you cannot be
-- sides.
-- You totally could. But not
that Rs A is a machine.
-- They can't afford to make people angry or to lose their sponsors.
-- True.
I mean, there's been talks that have been canceled or withheld or like lawyer
stuff got involved and
-- big controversies
-- and
Bides doesn't care.
Well, it
-- isn't big enough for anybody to care yet.
-- I don't know.
Yeah,
I don't know if they ever will be though because I think the whole point is to
keep it regional and if they start getting too
big now make two regions instead of one.
And I think that's part of the challenge too is that, you know,
it's these victims of their own success.
Like locally there's this guy who basically
started putting up Christmas lights in his,
like
on his farm and people started driving by to see it.
And then like 10 years later
guys got like eight C cans,
like 40 ft sea cans full of Christmas decorations that he has to put out every year.
And he's like, you know what? Just I, I quit, I'm done here. I get that
and everybody's like, oh, but we love it. We love it.
And he's like, cool, like y'all gonna pay 10 bucks to see it.
And of course, everyone is like,
you know, but this poor like,
or these music festivals like literally that start out with like, you know,
a couple dozen people and then 1020 years,
it's like, OK, you know, 5000 people show up and like,
we just don't have enough porta potties,
you know, and, and that's kind of what's happened with, well, by definition,
that's what happens with a good conference that runs yearly.
That is a good point.
And of course,
like the security and human behavior,
one looks like they intentionally keep it small,
but most conferences are run as a business and thus
the more the merrier and you know, and, and in fairness.
So I would say something like Rs A one thing I love about Rs A is
wandering around the vendor halls because I see at least five or 10 or 20.
Like just
I'm like, that is what? Oh that's actually really cool.
Like, I've never even considered that
-- and here it is as a product that I can actually buy.
-- No, I, I agree. I agree.
I do, I do love the vendor halls for that. That reason. Of course, it's also amusing
because there's always vendors there who clearly have no idea what's going on and
giving them a hard time can be fun.
-- There's
-- a lot of wackiness,
I'll still never forget.
One of my favorite things ever was, this was back in probably 2002, 2003,
going to Linux
World.
And it was one of the first times Microsoft had a booth there
and walking around. They're like, oh, do you use windows?
I'm like, no, I hate you guys.
And,
and they said, well, well, do you actually download the software and edit?
I'm like, yeah, I work for a Linux company, like, oh,
well, here's, here's a shirt, like, go away. Like, it was great because they were,
I was not their target audience at that show.
I mean, you know,
that's like communists and capitalists meeting at a World Bank forum.
Like, it's just
not that they're,
yeah, it's just, I think that conferences have the one thing too is like,
you just to get face to face as king for communication.
Like, I'm sorry, like we can, you know,
I've worked remotely for 22 years so I've learned how to write.
Well, and, you know, the phone and reach out to people and, you know,
kind of get up in their stuff so that I can get their attention.
But man, face to face wins. It's just so much easier and you get body language.
Oh, absolutely. There's huge advantages to it.
But again,
the most powerful aspect of that even isn't always the meetings you're
in during the day or the talks you're going to see.
It's, it's who you run into in the hallway and who you have dinner with at night.
Well, it's, I call it the, by the way, right?
Because in an email nobody ever types, oh, by the way,
we're going to be like burning down the
DC tomorrow night because we've got cockroaches,
right?
-- But they will say that face to face.
-- Yeah, that's true.
And if I ever saw an email that had, oh, and by the way,
I would stop reading at that point and just move on because it's like,
I don't even want to know.
Yeah. Whereas that's actually probably the most important critical thing.
Oh, by the way, you know, we're moving all the offices to
Mars for tax purposes tomorrow, pack your bags. Right.
And I mean,
then this is part of the human behavior piece is
just that humans are fickle and complicated and like,
I know my behavior and my kids' behavior changes from day to day.
Like, now that school's out, my one kid is kind of stressed and not happy about it.
And we are supposed to treat people like they're sort of this quasi
rational economic actor that actually behaves the same day in and day out.
No,
-- that's not how people work.
-- No, I agree.
I agree completely and kind of on that note if you, I'll put a link to it. But
so in Schneier's blog about his conference,
I'm really sad that there isn't more info,
someone did a little bit of kind of live blogging about it,
but it's not nearly as detailed as I would love to see.
It's fascinating, some of these topics and it also fascinated me that
a lot of these were less human focused than I expected as
well where I thought this was going to be very philosophical.
-- It's
-- sort
-- of that human machine interface part that
we get quite terribly wrong most of the time,
like all the time.
So many examples where, you know, clearly the people. Oh, a perfect example.
I'm at IKE
a yesterday trying, you know,
to buy some kitchen cabinets and we order a
custom countertop and she's got to print it out.
And a perfect example is she's scrolling through this list of like over 100
printers trying to find the printer that's like a foot in front of her.
Right? And I'm like, oh, can you set favors?
And she's like, yeah, we can,
but they keep changing and they change between the
apps and everything and they don't always stay put.
And I'm like, holy crap. You must hate your print setup and everything.
She's like, yeah, it's, it's like she literally, it took her two or three minutes
to find the printer she wanted to print to.
And like, I was just thinking, like, man, this is something that can be solved.
This is a solvable problem. But like, it just hasn't.
And, and that's kind of where I come to insecurity. There's
if you watch users for like five minutes, like going back to our talk before the show,
like
with laptops
back in the early days, people are like,
why do these laptops keep coming back broken?
What people do to these expensive things? And the answer is they're dropping them.
Why? Well, because they're people, people drop stuff on my kids' school.
They have chromebooks and they are taught a specific chromebook
hold where you cross your arms in front of you
and you kind of hug the chromebook to your chest.
-- Right?
-- Well, and they would, kids would break them.
It reminds me also of when I took science class in my younger days,
they taught you how to carry a microscope, right?
Like one hand on the base, nice and tight,
the other hand on the neck and you walk slowly to where you're
going because this thing is expensive and we don't want to replace them.
I get that here's where I want to end this and this is related
to everything that's going on and it is very human focused and this,
it ties back to the IKEA problem of, oh, you can fix this.
It's a matter of incentives and this was the focus of that blog post.
I wrote of, we often don't have incentives, especially in security.
And we think just complaining a lot is an incentive but it's not,
nobody cares if you want to see something fixed.
You have to actually have a reason to get it fixed.
-- Well, you have to align the incentives.
-- Well, right, exactly.
Just complaining isn't an incentive.
I mean,
so kind of the story I like to tell here that I've really kind of kicked it all off was
there was
a thread Mudge put on Twitter where he was basically
complaining about iot security and he's not wrong at all.
Sorry.
Every time somebody complains about iot security, I'm like, well,
what did you expect for a $5 like?
And so here's the thing though, right?
Is so the loft and cult of the dead cow and all these people back in the day,
they basically went to the public at large and they
shamed people like Microsoft into effectively caring about security.
And that worked. But that was a different problem. And
I think a lot of these people,
they think that bag of tricks still works and
shaming people is basically that that boat is gone.
It is sailed and especially in the world of iot
nobody cares. So, you have to think what is the incentive here, right.
Public shaming is no longer a valid incentive. So, what are we going to do next?
It's not effective.
It, it's probably, yeah,
and it might have been once and I have a feeling that was the planets aligned
and
it happened to work.
But,
yeah, like for real,
if you want someone to change behavior or you want to fix the system,
there has to be an incentive to do it.
Complaining and yelling at them isn't an incentive.
Yep,
I would agree.
And I think that's the hard part is especially as security people,
we often have misaligned incentives and we don't
understand what makes somebody care about something.
And
this is where kind of the point of the blog post I wrote was saying that, you know,
you have these csos screaming,
oh I have to report to the CEO and the reality is you're ineffective at your job.
And so the incentive
needs to be the CEO,
yelling at people on your behalf instead of being an
effective communicator and giving people a reason to care.
I just, I keep coming back to the, you know,
if you can't sell security to an organization,
maybe you don't actually really need it.
Yeah,
I agree because all these massive organizations have
had massive data breaches and you know,
what life goes on, man, like has anything
truly bad or terrible happened as a result of these breaches.
Yeah, there's, everybody had to, like, you know,
pay an extra 10 cents to get their credit cards replaced or whatever.
But fundamentally, you know,
-- I can't tell
-- sometimes there isn't an incentive and you have to be
-- able to recognize that and say there's no incentive
-- sometimes in life.
How do I put this nicely? Sometimes in life you're going to
step in dog poop
or there's potholes,
potholes are a better example. Potholes are just a thing
and, you know, we'll fill the big ones, but
that's it. Just if you want roads, you're going to have to live with potholes.
And if you want it, you're going to have to live with it.
-- Security problems
-- to a degree. Yeah, I agree with that. Absolutely.
But now at the same time,
you would make the argument that if we're going to use potholes as the analogy,
we'll ride this out on
-- you like a bridge shouldn't fall down when you go across
-- it.
That's a catastrophic failure. That has a larger impact.
-- Whereas a pothole,
-- but if a bridge fell down, people would
care, they tend to notice.
And I think that's part of the challenge we
have also is if you claim everything is critical,
nothing is,
-- and I think that's part of our problem is
-- alarm fatigue.
-- Yeah,
-- we claim everything is critical. So nothing's critical.
-- So no one listens to us because there's no incentive
-- and that's a challenge too.
Is like, literally, like, my DEV team came to me and they're like, oh,
we need to start tracking cvs.
And I'm like, no, no, you don't. And they're like, who cares? You're the CV guy.
I'm like, yeah. Yeah. Don't,
I'm like, they're like, but what do we do? What do we do?
And I'm like, well, you guys ship an update, like,
you guys refresh the software about every week or two.
And they're like, yeah, and I'm like, well, and you can push out an emergency update,
what, in about an afternoon?
-- They're like, yeah, and I'm like, ok, keep doing that. Yeah.
-- Right. Exactly.
-- That's way more valuable than tracking this crap.
-- And even better.
I'm like, do you keep all your, you know, your dependencies up to date?
And he's like, well, most of them we have a couple pin because of wonkiness.
I'm like, yeah, cool. Yeah. Right.
Keep an eye on those, like, just keep everything up to date and
keep pushing updates quickly and
because, I mean, that's what we're going to do if there's a CV flaw. Right.
He's like, yeah, I'm like, so,
yeah,
don't spend time tracking these things because
-- keep it up to date, man. Right.
-- There's,
and it's funny because I,
there,
there's almost a negative incentive to
doing something like tracking individual CV,
-- si
-- get for some people in some situations.
-- It matters and it does, but
-- there are instances, but I don't think they're the norm.
Well, and again,
part of that maturity piece of knowing when you actually need to do that and not do it.
Right. Right. Oh, yeah, definitely.
Banks need to make sure all accounts come out to within the penny.
Otherwise maybe there's fraud whereas, you know me,
I like fire up mint and I'm like the pie chart looks roughly correct,
whatever. You know, my kids probably aren't embezzling me.
-- So
-- I will, I will end this show
on, on, I have a story related to what you just talked about. So
I used to use good new cash to track my finances.
Yeah, like it was, I had a set up but I realized at one point
I was spending about four hours a month
on, on making sure everything worked out and anytime there's an inconsistency,
I'd have to go back through paperwork and figure out
and like 100% of the time it was because I forgot to put something into
one of the accounts. And I had many. And so anyway, I finally like, one day, I'm like,
II, I just, I don't want to do this anymore.
I'm,
this is driving me insane and it's taking tons and
tons of time and it just kept taking more,
more and more time.
And eventually I was like, I can't do it
and I quit. And that was,
I bet two years ago now it didn't matter.
The only thing that's different is I have four hours of my life
back and I'm not stressing out about why the numbers in Gnu cache
weren't matching up.
I used to have servers in my house and I got rid of all of them for the same reason.
Like running my own email was pointless. Right.
Sometimes. Just not doing something is vastly more effective.
And that's a perfect example of if it turns out you actually needed to do it,
you can go back in time and do it.
Exactly. I have, I keep the paperwork, I keep it in a file just so someday if I need it,
I can go get it,
but I don't need it and I haven't. So I win anyway.
All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
You can go to opens sources, Security podcast.com. Hit up the show
notes, U
Pound
Oss Podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.