Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in lacking an API, Josh Pressers.
Do I lack an API
for the
Os S podcast? There's no API,
there's kind of an API, I mean,
so we have an RSS feed for the podcast that
then
I guess it's an API. But then also, so the service we use
Liben,
they do have an API and I have, I have considered scripting everything I do.
Actually, we use uh Liben
host, the
audio
and wordpress host the blog
or the website, whatever you want to call it. It, it's just a blog,
but there are API S and I have considered automating all of this.
So instead of like manually fiddling with it,
I just like type make or something and it goes, but
see, there's how you're doing it wrong.
If you're gonna automate this,
I'll walk you through doing it in zap year in about 20 minutes.
Do I have to pay for ZAP year? Not at three level anyway.
Well, and you get like 700 zaps a month, which for us would be a lot enough. I need four
Yeah.
Well, no, but each zap would have multiple things because you'd want to have it,
like, upload the file, fire up the blog
press, do this, do that, do that. But like using something like Zapper
done in like minutes.
That sounds like more work than I care about. I have a process that works.
Ok.
Before we get to the topic,
which is api related as people have probably ascertained.
I have discovered the most amazing thing and I told you about it yesterday.
So mcdonald's the, the giant fast food company,
they have a character named Grimace who many
people may not know about because Grimace,
I'm glad you qualified that mcdonald's is giant
because I, I wasn't aware.
Look, look, man, I'm,
this is for the people thousands of years in the future who uncovered his podcast
and they're wondering like, what are these two idiots doing?
So, anyway, mcdonald's has all these characters and you don't,
-- you don't really hear about many of them anymore,
-- whatever happened to hamburglar.
-- Like, is he just doing time?
-- He's probably not a role model for Children anymore.
But anyway, there's a character named Grimace and he's a very strange character.
No one knows what he is. He's purple
and apparently it's his birthday.
And so mcdonald's because
is like, there's this meal you can get called Grimace's birthday,
which I actually went and got when I
learned about this and the milkshake is whatever,
like I've had worse I've had better.
Is it purple? It is purple. Apparently when you eat the fries it changes flavor.
But I, I couldn't really tell and it just tasted like sugar, like,
but
-- it
-- was
shocked
that a mcdonald's food product
that comes in a cup would taste like shrimp.
-- I,
-- I'm sure I got four days worth of calories from eating that meal.
But they, they actually have shakes that are over 3000 calories here.
-- I,
-- I
-- have
-- no doubt. Anyway. Anyway,
no, no, no, we're not, we're not discussing our terrible eating habits.
So, anyway, it's part of this, there's this website called Grimes's
Birthday and it looks like something out of the nineties because it,
it's amazing looking.
Also. Grimace is 52 apparently, which seems like a strange
age to make a big deal about on the website. There's this little game, right?
And
when you play the game, it looks like something from the nineties as the website is.
And it turns out the, the,
the game is literally a game boy color rom that they're emulating in the web browser.
You can extract the rom and play it on a real game boy color,
which is amazing to me.
And of course, the, the, the weirdos on youtube were,
were commenting how mcdonald's is now a game publisher apparently, but like I
was blown away by the fact that they hired a
company to make them a game for Game Boy color.
And then anyone can play it. It's like that is so amazing to me.
-- This
-- is
-- another show we need to do at some point.
But I think we're rapidly getting to the point where
OK.
It reminds me of back when I uh like this is 20 some years ago,
flood forecasting control had remote machines like remote data
collection equipment for like river levels and flow meters
with custom silicon chips to like
connect to a phone line and blah, blah blah.
And nowadays the answer would be like, no, just get like
a
AAA
system on a board computer and write some Python script
and like use about 6 million times more lines of code than is necessary.
But who cares? It's a Python script.
It's clear to me that web browsers are now at that point where it's like
I want to build like an A RVR thing that needs all these crazy capabilities.
Well, yeah,
the web browser will just do that and just
whack it through some framework in the web browser.
And so I bet every software project kind of goes to heck in a handbasket
schedule wise.
But
for example, using an old DEV kit where you're kind of, you know,
there's like strong guard, like think about color game boy, there's,
there's gonna be guardrails like you can only do XY and Z right.
You can really only make a game, you can't like,
you don't have to worry about a web browser you don't have to worry about this.
You don't have to worry about that. Like,
I'm guessing that, that
you could probably, like once you get the art
assets done and the basic gameplay figured out,
you can probably crank out a game boy game
in like a couple of weeks.
There's really good tools as well that help you along this path.
Well,
very mature tools.
Uh Yeah,
which is funny because like all of the hacker types did
all this work because Nintendo's not releasing a DEV kit for this
-- and
-- it kind
-- of
-- runs. Remember all the flash games that went by by
flash went bye bye. But like
this really speaks to, you know,
if I because if somebody tried to build this game using a modern framework,
it still wouldn't be done.
That's it.
-- And that kind of speaks to API S and power use.
-- It does.
Strangely enough, it's totally related to our topic, which is
API S and power users. OK?
What is an API?
And API is an application programming interface? And the idea is
you have a piece of software and typically pieces of software
have some sort of interface once they get complicated enough.
So we're, we're not talking about command line utilities anymore.
We're talking about like
a big Honkin
app that like like Microsoft Word or Excel or some web service thing or whatever.
Sure. And so
traditionally what happens?
Actually, Red Hat did this really well,
red hat when they would build something big and complicated,
would first of all build the command line tools.
And so
once you have command line tools, you have a working system and you can automate it.
And now you can stick a web front end on it
that calls the command line tools effectively. Right.
Yep, that's right.
And that web front end can be have a nice interface and it can, you know, like log in,
add a user whatever
and you can have like gated access and workflows and permissions and stuff.
But the problem becomes what happens when somebody needs
to do something that your interface does not support or
more likely needs to integrate it with another system. Well, they can't,
well, and that's where an API comes in.
You have an application programming interface where basically
you can touch all the knobs,
twiddle, all the knobs, get all the data in and out, do everything possible.
And now it's up to you to build something to do what you need it to do.
And I'm, I'm actually in this situation right now.
Uh The cloud security alliances has a uh we, we pay for this uh social platform
and I need to get the user's email address out of it so
that we can add them to the freaking Google groups as needed.
OK?
OK.
In the email that we send out to the group of men, you can add their first name,
their last name their company name.
There's like a whole mail merge with a list of variables that you can do.
Not their email address.
The reason API S are so critical
is it's your power users.
It's the people integrating this thing with another system.
It's the people building a tool that says, you know,
instead of clicking on each user profile and
cutting and paste the email address out,
we just want to automate that because
like seriously, right? Like that's our current workflows.
They click on the link, they cut and paste the email address into another thing.
And I'm like, that's no, we're, we're automating that. Like
that's ridiculous.
And so that's why API S are so critical because the majority of people will never
see an API most people will actually never interact with an
API because they'll use sort of the default website or the default
interface.
But the secret is the people who use power tools or third party clients,
they're the ones using API S
and if you take API S away from them,
you basically break life for all your power users
and all your third party apps and all your integrations.
That's right. And this is what Reddit did, which is why it's news at the moment.
-- But Twitter has done this as well.
-- They did it but Reddit did it in a way.
That is so unspeakably ridiculous because no,
no, because remember Reddit basically said we're gonna charge access to the API
OK. That sucks. But fair.
But then they like literally two or three days later realized and sent out.
They put that posting on the website at the top
saying moderator tools and bots will have free API access.
Like they literally forgot that their website
literally cannot work without these automated bots and moderation tools
to keep all the spam and horror show stuff out,
right?
They literally didn't think that through.
I think you could say they didn't think that through is pretty much the,
the the slogan for everything reddit has done for
the last two or three weeks at this point.
And it is amusing to me. So here's where I think this conversation gets very fun
is like Twitter locked out their API at one point where they started charging for it,
right?
I love that. I predicted that.
And so I'd written, I have a headless chrome browser that implements the full
javascript and everything to extract a single piece of text from your profile.
So I can validate your email address.
And,
and here's what's funny is most of the API S and these services exist
because they got sick of people scraping
their sites and like destroying their bandwidth.
Whereas
like you can make an API call that pulls in a couple of bytes or you can load
a website that like three megabytes of crap and puts a huge load on the back end.
And I hate to say it.
But from my perspective, I don't really care, I just need that email address.
Well, no,
the person on the receiving side doesn't care if they're scraping
or using an API API S were created for the services to
basically control their, their loading costs.
-- Well, originally,
-- not just that
but to allow
people to extend it because here's the thing.
-- Hold on,
-- stop. Not yet. Not yet. Let's, I wanna, I wanna cover something else first.
So
Twitter and Reddit kind of lock down these API S and they start charging for them.
They didn't lock them down, they turned them off.
Well, they, they didn't turn them off, they're charging for them, right?
And they're charging quite a lot of money.
-- That's functionally the same as turning it off. OK,
-- whatever.
And, but here's the thing,
the people who are using these API S are not the kind of people you often want to
kind of push out of your ecosystem.
-- Well,
-- they're the people that literally build the ecosystem
in social media. Yes. Without people, you don't have social media.
I mean, I think Reddit's learning that
the people that use the third party Twitter clients are literally the people
that are posting massive amounts of
content and moderating content and providing feedback
and especially on Reddit, like all the mods, you, you cannot use reddit
with the default client and website.
It's
not good. No,
no,
no, you can't. It is
impossible. There's stuff that's missing.
That's fair. That's fair.
But here's so, here's, here's what amuses me about all this though. Right?
Is those people they
have found it,
I guess, easy to pick up and leave,
which I love because if you look at Mastodon,
a lot of the people who migrated to Mastodon right away,
they were the heavy lifters on Twitter.
And Mastodon has like in, in the security space, especially
there,
like the whole community basically just picked up and left and it was phenomenal.
-- I loved it.
-- Well, and here's the trick is
you kind of have three main groups, you have the content producers,
the content
moderators and ma and community
managers effectively that enforce community norms
and the content consumers.
And they're broadly speaking, three separate groups of people.
Yes, obviously, there are people that are in all three groups, blah, blah, blah.
If one of those groups leaves or opts out largely,
then the whole thing just sort of falls apart
and especially
and OK, and if the, if the content creators leave, then obviously have a problem,
there's no new content, it's boring.
But
what's kind of insidious is the content moderators can leave and it,
it works for a few days or a few weeks until the not so nice people start coming in
and doing bad stuff to monetize community or to post
horrible stuff or to take advantage of it or whatever,
like apparently on Reddit, there's a whole bunch of companies that have already,
or,
you know, been using reddit essentially to do, for example, like market research,
like, apparently only fans was watching the various subs that post, you know,
where people post pictures of themselves to, you know, am I hot or not?
And then like the ones that are hot get
offered to become only fans content creator. Clever.
Right. Exactly. Well,
I mean,
yeah, like,
it's a no brainer, right? There's your market research
and, you know, they've already got a following.
So
what really the, the thing is
when you especially lose the sort of community content moderators,
the con the community
becomes very toxic and gross
nowadays. Very fast. It used to take months or years
now. It's like days or wish,
like I look at Twitter and like you read the studies of like the amount of
right wing and fascist stuff being posted there
and just being allowed and it's like,
well, I guess it's, that's how it is now,
right?
They're not taking stuff down anymore because, well,
they fired all the teams that did that.
No.
Right.
I know they did. Well, I mean, Reddit kind of just did too.
It's just theirs are volunteers and they got them for free.
So, anyway, anyway, OK. OK.
I want to, I want to back all this up because I think we're, we're too focused on,
on API S in this context.
And the other thing is API S
allow people to build something
new and interesting that
makes it better.
It maybe integrates with another service or it does spell check or whatever.
But it's subtle because sometimes the companies are like, oh,
that's a cool feature.
Let's make that part of the default and some of them do it nicely.
-- And ok,
-- there, right there. Stop.
That is the purpose of this discussion that I wanted to cover is that
when I am
the consumer of an API from a company like Twitter or Reddit or Facebook or anybody,
you are functionally at their mercy.
And this is what I think makes this whole universe so interesting.
Like from a from a risk perspective,
it is very risky basing what you do on their API
because like the Apollo app for Reddit is a great example,
right?
The Apollo app was I I know that the developer was
not making a living off of this by any means,
but it's an example of Reddit basically said,
if you're going to keep making this app, you have to pay us $20 million a year.
And the Apollo guy was like, I can't possibly do that.
We're not going to go into that, but it's actually worse than that because the,
the way people use Apollo pricing, it would have been a complete impossibility.
But anyways
to back it up a second,
it's not that basing your business on a company's API is dangerous.
It's basing your business
on another thing that a single company controls
is dangerous because let's back it up steps.
For example, if you sell through Amazon on their marketplace,
guess what happens if you have a really popular product?
All of a sudden, Amazon basics shows up.
Yeah. Right.
They've done that more than once or actually, I,
I heard a story on public radio here in the US.
Uh, it's been maybe a year or more
but,
you know, the people who deliver for Amazon, right.
Those Amazon vans and trucks you see driving around.
Do you mean the Amazon ones or the outsourced? Like in telecom ones?
Well, the, the, the outsource they're all outsourced, aren't they?
-- I think they're all outsourced.
-- Some are more outsourced than
ok.
Well, anyway,
they were basically talking about this person in Boston who created a
company basically to deliver Amazon stuff and for something happened that,
that Amazon got mad at him and they were like, you're done,
we're canceling your contract and like
that was it, there was no more.
This guy didn't have a business,
he only delivered for Amazon and when they cut him off with no warning because Amazon
-- like that was it, his company was over.
-- A lot of businesses
will cut suppliers off with no warning.
-- I
-- mean, that could be, I don't really understand that universe very well,
-- but part of
-- it is,
but Amazon scale.
Oh, we lost one
supplier, providing package delivery.
-- Oh,
-- they, they, they had, they probably had another one lined up
ready to go.
Well, they already have more.
See the thing to remember is Amazon is operating on a scale
where they use statistical modeling and forecasting.
Sure. It's,
it's nothing personal. It's not you. It's just a perfect example.
I remember 20 some years ago,
Suncor
and Syncrude, they're big oil companies locally, they had
massive spreadsheets for all of their equipment.
And essentially when this equipment starts breaking at this level and this rate
it's surplused.
And so for example, people were always like, oh man, Suncor and Syncrude,
they sell all these used pickup trucks so cheap.
And
like one of our I I was working for an electro like
an industrial electrical contractor back then that worked with these companies.
And they're like, yeah,
don't buy them because basically when sin crude or
Suncorp says that this equipment like we're selling it off
like
it's statistically, it's now into the nightmare mode of maintenance.
I have
no
doubt they've extracted
like they have literally extracted every drop of
value from that piece of equipment for sure,
for sure.
And now it's, it's
a, it's a negative thing
again, back to these API S that's
companies that are smart, provide API s realizing that OK,
Slack is a good example. Slack makes it easy to integrate stuff with Slack.
So what's happened?
Well, everybody uses Slack as their message bus with everything else tied in.
Same thing with Microsoft teams. Microsoft is trying to do this.
And this is for example,
um like what Zapp year does like they allow
you to integrate different services and smart services go
not only do we provide an API but we'll we'll set it up.
So it's easy to do in Zap year so that it just works and it's easy
because now for example, people like Kurt go, yes,
let's buy this service because this service will
integrate with all of our existing stuff.
So perfect example is
we use Zendesk for um help support,
right? Sure.
We're not going to use their api uh sorry, their A I for answering tickets
for one simple reason,
I can only use it in Zendesk
so I can put all this effort into learning how to
use their A I product and answer tickets and solve problems.
And I can only use it in Zendesk or
I can build an integration using ZAP here and open A is chat GP T
to answer our support tickets.
And now I can apply that knowledge and that system to do something else.
I mean, that's fair,
that's fair. See,
and
I'm of the mind where I would rather,
I would rather pick one vendor that solves multiple,
multiple problems than
you know, pay ZSK I and have that silo thing. And then,
oh, well, we want to use that knowledge and that training in another thing.
-- Uh We can't,
-- that's always the dream, right? Of, of one thing to, to rule them all.
If I end up using one A I provided by each service,
I'm going to have 20 different A is and that has a high cost
and this is where this is the whole point of API S is.
For example,
you can uh perfect example,
Red hat makes software management products that use API S in VM Ware, for example,
to control VM Ware through a single red hat product.
-- I want to back you up because you just said this is the point of API
-- S.
Well, it's one of the points
I have been thinking about this a lot and I think from the risk perspective,
so you hit your wagon to someone like Reddit or Twitter, we'll say,
and they're just good examples because they will say, behave badly recently.
And
I just keep thinking that the initial purpose of
those API S was kind of enablement and empowerment,
right to, to help people do better things.
And something happened
where they decided we're going to try to make
money off of this thing instead of viewing it as
a way to help people
do more and better with our product.
-- And I find that a fascinating occurrence. So
-- Corey Dr
has written extensively about this and it's the Ancid
education process and basically it boils down to a company
has something of value
that they realize.
Oh, we could
extract that value. We can keep that value, we can monetize that value.
Well, duh, let's do that.
So,
and also to back it up a second.
I,
it's not that Twitter has an api, it's that if you want to do social media,
your choices are Facebook, Twitter, Reddit.
What else? That's it.
I
-- mean, for the big companies, maybe linkedin, I don't know. Does that count?
-- No?
Well,
like if you want to actually like post pictures of cats
and somehow monetize that and make a business off that,
right?
You got to post it to Facebook or edit or Twitter.
That's fair. And so
it's more about you're not so much tied to the API you're tied to that company.
And so the FTA
is a good example of if you want to do Mastodon,
well, you can use somebody else's server,
you could set up your own server.
And as long as you're not a total jerk or using a total jerk servers,
you're probably not going to get defer
and blocked from everybody else's servers.
But it's biased nature. It's currently
mostly decentralized now.
It will centralized because simple economics says again,
there will be value there.
Companies will move in and try and capture it.
And then the coy
doctoral process of in shit
education will happen where
they intentionally
or unintentionally give away value, get people hooked in.
So, Amazon is a great example. Hey,
do you want to set up your own online store or just sell through us and have
delivery through us and prime delivery through us
and your customers will be so much happier.
Well, obviously, number two
and then Amazon
gets you in and start jacking up the fees.
What are you gonna do? Leave?
No, no, you're not. And worse if you're actually really successful.
Like, for example, I bought some uh gray bed sheets.
They were nice
and then I went to buy them a year later
and it recommended Amazon basics, exact same, basically description,
everything I ordered them.
And what's fascinating is they were exactly the same as the previous bedsheets.
However, the packaging was smaller, there was less packaging.
They'd basically been optimized.
They've been
optimized for cost and for pa and a whole bunch of like subtle things that probably
shaved a buck or two off the cost of producing this thing and shipping it,
which on a
-- matter at their
-- scale, a buck is a big deal. All right.
So here's the question, right.
I'm a company
and you can't exist anymore outside of
this whole ecosystem of everything around us.
Right?
How do I
make sure, like from a risk perspective,
how do I make sure I'm not
basically creating an unacceptable level of risk by being overly reliant
on one mega company's stuff.
-- You can't always do that.
-- I
-- don't
-- know if you can. I've been thinking about this a lot.
-- I've got nothing.
-- No, there, there's just industries where that's not possible.
Um If you build nuclear reactors for example,
you don't have a lot of customers if you're Lockheed Martin
and you build fighter jets.
Like
not only do you not have a lot of customers but the US government is gonna be like,
we don't care if you want to sell them to random country.
We said no,
like you can't sell the F-35 to
China.
Like you just can't, I don't care how many they want to buy.
Right.
And that's the thing like at some point, this is a business risk that you, you,
I'm a contractor.
I have a contract with the Cloud Security Alliance.
That's it.
I that's
if they cease to exist, I don't get to eat this month
until you get a new job. Right?
And
true.
So sometimes like
part of it is, for example,
some companies and suppliers will have very long term healthy relationships.
Like I heard examples that electrical contractor I work for,
they had been working for some of these country
uh companies for like over a decade or two
and essentially were on the preferred supplier list of essentially,
unless you bid some ridiculous number
will pay you to do it.
Or in some cases, they were so tightly enmeshed with the company,
they were just working on a cost plus basis of
essentially this plus 10% is what we pay you.
And it was such a massive amount of work.
We're talking like 2, 300 electricians on site
at
that scale again, you know, the company is like, yeah,
that plus 10% cool we can live with that.
Um
And
yeah, I mean, that's just a risk for a lot of companies. Like if you do delivery
for one company and that one company decides to fire you.
Yeah, that, that's unfortunate.
But part of it too, like if, for example,
if you make a product that manages virtual machine software environments
you're gonna support VM Ware,
maybe virtual box, maybe Red hat KVM. If you decide to be really nice.
And what are your other options?
Oh, Kubernetes, I guess,
I mean, for on Prem, you can also so a lot of those products now
-- and then cloud
-- stuff
will integrate. Yeah, with like cloud and on Prem
and they give you
kind of a nicer opportunity. But I mean, you, you do have a point like,
yeah,
and for whatever reason if Amazon or VM Ware really decided to
somehow legally lock you out or have a fight with you.
Well, tough.
Well, and, and I mean,
Amazon has done this more than once where there was a company
providing a service and they basically just built it themselves in Aws and
-- well, and
-- at some point though, like
that's
I'm sorry, but that's,
that's ok.
Like just because you just because you provide a service doesn't now you
get to own that forever and nobody else gets to provide that.
No, no, I, I get that. But I think so, what you're talking about there,
that's
functionally, I think competition in the market.
But I think Red Hat and t not Red
Reddit and Twitter.
-- That's a different story though.
-- So there's a great example of this is Walmart.
There's a, uh, we'll have to find the pickle story,
but there's basically Walmart as a vendor to work with is apparently
a nightmare because they basically will squeeze every penny out of you
and then fire you randomly at some point. And so I've heard that before.
So the Walmart Pickle story.
Yeah. Anyways, wow, it's 20 years old now. Holy cow that goes back away.
But the point is
there are vendors that are
mature enough,
I guess that when Walmart comes to them and says we really want to buy your product,
they go,
no,
like just no, because we know how this will end.
And it's kind of the scorpion and the frog in that.
It's not personal.
It's just, this is how big business is you're going to try and extract all that value.
Ok.
But,
but in the case of Twitter and Reddit,
they're hurting themselves.
They've done.
But here's, here's what I wonder though.
And here's maybe the closing discussion point is,
I'm pretty sure Reddit did what they did because they're
hoping to suck money out of the A I people.
Well, actually, no, it's more the IP O thing.
They're trying to IP O and they're trying to juice the numbers.
I know they wanted to IP 00. And you think that the, the, it was strictly about
revenue?
Yeah.
-- Got to show recurring revenue. Got that, that line got to go up into the
-- right.
I mean, maybe that it could be that simple. That seems overly dumb to me.
But that might be it.
I mean,
because
overly dumb,
well, no company would ever do something overly
fair.
And I think, I think in the case of, of Twitter from everything I've heard, they,
they, they got a huge hit from their revenue and they thought
they could just raise prices on the API S and,
and recover that and it doesn't look like that's true either.
Traditionally, large companies
had a board of directors
and
A CEO
that essentially wouldn't do irrational things.
They would be somewhat rational and predictable and sane
and that
is,
and then perfect example, apparently
Elon Musk and Mark Zuckerberg are having a little Twitter thing about a cage fight.
You, you sent me that story there
and it's on the BBC. So because when I first saw this pop up, I was like, what? No.
And then I'm like it links to the BBC. Oh my goodness. It might be real. Not the onion.
Yeah. And then it links to the tweets where they're like going at each other.
I hope they do.
And the last, and I'm just going to remind you the last time Elon Musk started
basically talking big on Twitter.
He ended up having to buy it at an absurdly inflated price.
Yeah. And it's worth pennies on the dollar now. Like,
I part of me hopes this happens because it's going
to be the most amusing event of the decade.
Zuckerberg has been training jujitsu. Like he's actually,
yeah, they, they said that on,
-- on the BBC article
-- that I've seen video of him fighting.
-- He's, he's reasonably competent.
-- Is he? Well,
Musk has no training in the space. So
year old out of shape guy.
Uh, yes. Right. He's 52 I think he said, and Zuckerberg is in his thirties, 39
or something. Ok.
That's
as an, as an aged gentleman.
There's a big difference between 10 years
-- and
-- somebody who's been training and somebody who's not.
That's true too. That's very true.
I've seen some scary looking 70 year olds when I was doing.
-- That's a good
-- point.
That's a good point.
-- Like that's fair. That's fair.
-- Anyways, no, this whole thing, the problem is
the API is a technical thing that will always be beholden to the business interests.
So there is no amount of technical protection or like, oh, well,
very cleverly include a Blockchain.
So blah, blah, blah. No, it doesn't matter.
There will always be the business interests
assuming that API is done through a site being run by a business
and those business interests will always say something like, hey,
remember how open a I said that they grabbed all our data and used it to
train an A I model that they then managed to get $10 billion of funding for.
I would like some of that cake, please.
Well, now here's actually, here's the ending thought on this.
If you look at what's happening at Reddit,
all Reddit has to do is shut up
and they can't, they can't.
-- And that's what I think makes it the most amusing.
-- Again.
The problem is you're saying Reddit when you should be saying SPZ
because Spz
is at the helm driving the boat and apparently he's not listening to reason,
just like Elon Musk with Twitter.
That, that, yeah, that's, and that's part of the thing, right?
Like a normal large company, the CEO,
the board would directly call the CEO or have legal,
call the CEO or the CFO would talk to the CEO or say something and be like, you know,
like,
and they'd be like, oh, right. Oops.
Or be like, you don't work here anymore because you're obviously an idiot.
Well, no, no, no, he's just, he's decided to take more time with his family.
-- That
-- right. Yes, of course,
nobody ever does that. No. Cor
by definition, if you're a CEO, you don't like your family.
-- I
-- mean, that's probably fair. They probably don't like you. But
-- that's not true. I know some CEO S that have lovely families.
-- But,
well, I'm talking to like mega CEO.
-- Si get what you're saying. That's probably fair
-- CEO s of these
like,
and that's part of the thing is,
I think part of it to become the CEO and stay
the CEO of some of these like large start up,
you kind of have to be a villain because
there's 100 people that would love to have your job
and we will cheerfully put you in a tree chipper to get it.
Yeah.
And I guess at this point if Reddit could, like,
just shut up and stop burning down the house, they would have done it weeks ago
and they obviously can't and won't.
And
I, the,
the,
-- the IP O ship just keep sailing further away.
-- I predict what will happen is
the mods won't back down. So Reddit will replace a bunch of mods,
-- which they've replaced a ton of them already
-- and things like our
picks will sort of soldier along. But
the people who will want to become mods are not becoming mods because they're
nice kind altruistic people who want to see a better ARP picks community,
they're going to do it to try and monetize or somehow push other agendas. Right.
Right.
I imagine
there's a bunch of countries with a bunch of disinformation
efforts right now that are working hard to be moderators,
you know, and steer those conversations and steer those, you know,
public opinion things
and, um, Reddit's not going to die,
but it's going to become kind of a grosser and grosser place like Twitter did.
Yeah, for sure.
The thing is though,
the people that are the users of it,
they won't know what to do.
Like,
it's not like dig to Reddit where there
was a clear transition from one coming to another
because the Reddit to Mastodon transition
is so fundamentally different and weird.
-- Not
-- Mastodon Cavin or Lemmy are the two options.
Sorry. Yeah. Sorry. I meant, yeah, that's what I meant.
It is a lot different and like I, I won't lie. I'm loving it, but it's different.
-- I can't
-- even remember the names,
let alone how to get there and log in and get an account.
That's my point
and I have an account
and I can't even remember.
So like a normal person is gonna be like, where's the app for this?
But here's the thing, here's the thing that I,
I think of it and I want to close on this point is
the,
the people who are most likely to run and moderate a community
are the people most capable of leaving and going somewhere else,
right?
The users who can't leave, they'll stick around for a while,
but they'll eventually turn it off because it's
going to turn into like the toxic trashy
about
Facebook and
Facebook
is different. Facebook
has a, a community aspect for planning and stuff. Look at Twitter, right?
How many people do you know? Still on Twitter?
Well, and more to the point nobody, you can't.
Facebook does have the family aspect where all your
old people are on Facebook and like you said,
the, the community kind of planning events,
-- I'll give you that. That is different.
-- I think that's its power
because Twitter, I think lost its power because it lost a lot of the people who,
who did the good work of making Twitter.
Interesting. I'm
-- actually
-- having to go back to Twitter because there's
still people that will only post stuff on Twitter
-- that's still quite high quality and interesting. I have,
-- I have not found any of them
-- a
-- bunch. Like, and they just, they're not un mastered on Tooting away
and that they aren't going to come to Mastodon at this point.
-- If you haven't moved to Mastodon, I don't think they
-- will.
They're gonna lose their,
their follower account is gonna go from like six
figure.
I
think
that's what keeps a lot of people like on Twitter is they,
they're obsessed with that follower count and they, they don't want to start over
it. It's, it's gonna be similar with Reddit, right?
Where moving from a, a Reddit, a subreddit that had 3 million people.
And now the equivalent on Cain
has 2000.
Like that's a huge difference. But
again,
it's a different thing and I don't think
-- it's necessarily comparable
-- and that's another thing.
Maybe another show. But like
some of these subreddits,
bird examples are slash picks. It's got a community of 30 million people.
That's a large country.
Yeah. It's ridiculous.
That's not a community anymore really. In the sense of,
like,
30 million people, man.
Right. Oh, for sure. Yeah.
Like, there aren't 30 million people on all of Mastodon, I don't think.
-- Well, more to
-- the 0.30 million people can't really coordinate or talk to each other.
Like, that's way past your dunbar number.
Right
by a couple zeros.
So, and that's part of what I also wonder is, again, we're, we're,
we're lumping all these subreddits into sort of the Reddit bucket.
But
I mean, there are subreddits with 100 people and there are subreddits with
well, 30 million people. I think, I don't know what the biggest one is.
It's number nine ranked by size if I click that
one
R slash 2050 million users. So there are,
there are two subreddits that are bigger than Canada
and then a bunch that are about as big as Canada
-- anyway
-- anyway.
Yeah. Yeah. I don't know.
It'll be,
it's funny because I have a suspicion from the time
we recorded until I hit publish on this episode.
There will be
many more ridiculous happenings in the Twitter or in the, in the Reddit saga.
-- But I guess we
-- shall see.
And here's and one note also that we ignored that I want to mention explicitly just
API S are also really needed by people with disabilities like the
blind.
And that is one thing that really
does upset me and hurts me is that
Reddit is
largely unusable
through the default app and website,
even if you are fully cited and fully capable. Like I,
yeah, I use it through the default apps and stuff
and it's kind of garbage and I cannot imagine how terrible it
would be to try and use it if you were blind.
And that's the other thing is API S
allow people with disabilities to interact with the site
in ways that unless you are really committed to usability
and most tech companies are not,
they're just not.
I won't disagree with that.
And that's, I kind of hope at some point.
Somebody fires up like an ad, a suit in the US about this.
Uh Yeah,
I would not be sad to see that because we've already got ad a guidelines for websites
that are
-- largely ignored by a lot of sites like alt takes for text or images. Sorry.
-- Right.
Alt text takes for images.
I, I, yes, I agree that that's a,
that's a very good point and I hadn't even considered that aspect of it.
All right. I'm gonna call it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com.
Find the show, not Tuesday Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.