Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 126 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers,
or we could call it like 100 and 25.5.
Sort of, I don't know. Yeah,
that's fair.
So anyway, anyone who picked up here, uh this is, this is kind of part two of episode,
100 and 25.
So if this is the first episode you're ever
listening to uh go back and listen to 125 1st
because it'll make a lot more sense.
All everything we talked about there is going
to be really important for this conversation.
So, so anyway, anyway, picking up where we left off
is we kind of covered a lot of the open source security dependency, just,
just nature of the world.
And, and we kind of said at this point in time, like there's,
there's nothing we can do to fix a problem of like
a nefarious actor inserting a back door into open source.
And so that
may not be fixable,
but there are some things going on and I think
there's some things we could do in the future.
And so kind of well and to be clear though open source
does have a reasonable reactive model for getting these things fixed quickly.
Right. We have a community panic and it's the immune system, right.
We should call it the open source immune system, right.
Where, where,
like your immune system generally doesn't do anything before
you get sick and then it kicks in and,
and everything magic happens.
But anyway,
yeah, and I'm sure doctors can send us hate mail.
Well, and actually I love this because this is a great example because this one,
so this thing happened and, and somebody on github
did a ton of really good in depth analysis and posted it to the issue.
It's great for like free, right?
And this is like, this is the kind of level of analysis where I look at this.
And I'm like, yeah, I'd hire this guy, right?
Like, literally looking at this one analysis. He did.
No, this dude's
like he is really quite competent and cares and good enough. Well,
we don't know if it's a he just for the record. But
yeah,
well, his, his github
account
says his name and it's
anyways, that's anyway, whatever, whatever it does, right?
But, you know, and that's what I love. There's a, there's a ton of smart people who,
you know, they don't have the time to do this every single day, all the time.
But, you know, once in a while when we need to panic, we can do that and it works. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Ok. Ok. So, so let's,
let's talk about the future.
Here's where some of this is going to be real and some of it's going to be made up crap.
And so here's, here's the stage I want to set.
So
we know where we are today. We know most of the scanners don't work all that.
Well, there's some solutions, some are getting better, some are worse.
There's, there's not enough people to do the kind of work we need to do. And so
I think we can, can I interrupt for a moment, please?
I would say it's, it's not so much about the scanners, not working or working well.
It's
the fundamental technologies that we currently have available
that is fair. A lot of them don't
scale. A lot of them
aren't smart like they're, they're really,
if you look, if you scratch the surface,
you know, it's basically people doing the work,
putting it into a system and then the
kind of replicates that,
you know what I would compare it to
is, is the space race in the sixties is where
we went to the like humanity.
And I'm, I'm not going to say the United States did this because that annoys me.
But we'll say humanity went to the moon and
we didn't really have the technology to get there.
We had the ability to get there where I would say
we still aren't even to the point where we really have
the technology to actually go to the moon correctly. Right.
And, and it's the same thing with this, like the whole, you have,
we solved the three body problem.
My understanding is it's still a tough one. I have no idea.
I
don't,
it doesn't matter either because the point is that
the technology we actually need doesn't exist yet.
And that's,
I think where we should start with before the technology even exists.
We need to imagine crazy things. Half of which will turn out to be garbage,
the other half of which will five years later. Well, of course, it was self evident.
Everybody would carry smartphones with them, right.
You know, now in 2018 it's like, of course,
everybody has a smartphone in their pocket.
You're not going to walk around with a calculator in your pocket all the time.
Yes, I am. Ha
take that math
teacher.
Well, you know,
I keep telling my parents and everybody it's like we no longer have an excuse
not to know something because we have all of the world's information in our pocket.
Yeah. But bar conversations are way less fun. Right?
It would be way more exciting. Like, like discussing
what, what something may or may not be.
Right.
But anyway, anyway, so, so here is,
here's kind of let's set some ground rules for ourselves.
Uh Number one,
I think whatever we see in the future is going
to have to be 100% automated humans need not apply.
Can we agree on that?
Yeah, because even if it's, you know, a millionth of a percent of effort by the human
times a billion lines of code, you're going to run out of parking and washroom space.
Exactly.
We have the law of large numbers is against us.
Well,
I think where you can have people involved is people can
be meta involved in the sense of setting policy or setting.
You know, here's our risk appetite,
here's what we're willing to deal with or here's what we're not willing to deal with.
So very high level decision making, that's fair. But actual like actual,
like basically people can be involved in the strategic component of this,
but they absolutely cannot be involved in the tactical component of this.
Yes, exactly. 100% agree.
And, and I think the second point
that I think will be important is we need to
be in a place where you can do your updates in
minutes
because today a lot of organizations and systems can take hours to days, two weeks,
two months.
I want to make sure I understand what you mean by updates because for example,
are we talking strictly pushing the update out and getting it deployed
and making sure that it's been deployed or are we actually talking about
building an update,
testing the update to make sure the update solves the problem
and doesn't break other stuff and pushing it out as well.
Both of those things.
Ok. So now we're talking about essentially from
a problem has been identified.
We go from a problem identified to having a software or whatever workaround patch
or change is needed to the system or to the software or to the service
and that change is implemented tested so that we don't like break everything
and deployed and,
and this is the thing that really gets me tested that it was deployed.
Right.
Because how many people, like, for example, well, no, for example, my,
my partner works for the government.
A lot of people don't shut their computers off
at night so they don't get the updates overnight.
And I, I guess they're like, and I was like,
why can't they just forcibly reboot the systems?
Oh, yeah. Right.
Because these people leave documents open and they would lose
work and they would complain and it would be under,
you know, it would be like anytime there's a computer problem,
they would blame that for it.
So
don't do, like, they're not going to do that. So,
you know, she has coworkers who are weeks out of date for updates,
you know,
95 machine don't ever touch that. Yeah, exactly.
So,
I, I would agree that on the continuum of when we say an update,
I would say in the ideal continuum,
it's from the point of a problem being identified to the point of the problem,
not only being solved
but
confirmed solve.
Like we updated all the servers and rebooted them as
necessary or whatever it is that needed to happen,
you know, and that's fine.
It's a minor data point in a much less,
it's a massive data point because for example, this one cloud vendor, it's a
data point in our story today.
I understand big picture, hugely important.
Yeah. All right. So anyway, anyway, anyway,
so, OK, so here's, here's what, what I, I guess I see
is we're talking about massive automation, also safe automation.
I think that's the biggest thing, right? Is we can automate this.
But then we're, you know, I've seen a lot of people automate things like
I have automated server updates
and they may or may not work. I have no freaking clue. I just hope that they do
now. Could I automate it in a way that's
provably very safe. Yes. Am I going to? No, because it almost never fails
again. That's part going back to that risk thing.
And I think that's part of it is that this,
we need to also sort of acknowledge that
different people will have different
abilities
or, or capabilities or risk profiles where you know what? Oh, yeah.
If we, if we update that system and it breaks, that's cool.
We can, we can have a human poke it and fix it versus,
you know, this system runs the national debt. We can't have it break.
Yeah, I mean that, that's fair. OK. That's fair.
So, so anyway, anyway, here's, here's what I,
I think we're going to see and there are people working on this today
where
you can include uh a
dependency in your,
your product or service or whatever.
And like there are scanners today that will say, all right,
you're bringing in this dependency and
this dependency brings in these dependencies.
And now like here's the license on them
and here are known security flaws.
Now, the the biggest problem today with most of those scanners is they're,
they're generally overly conservative and so they miss lots of things
and ironically, the false positive rate is typically very high as well.
Well, it can be right, you have one or the other,
you either have way too many false positives or you fail.
And so I, I have no doubt we're going to see systems at some point
that are going to be,
we'll say 80 plus percent correct where you include a dependency and it will say
this dependency has these security problems and you might be able to look at them.
And then you're also going to have to have the ability to say
I care about these kind of security flaws. I don't care about those kind.
And then you have a system that can basically say you're ok or nope, we can't do this.
Well, and here's the corrective action.
See, that's the other thing. Right? Is these systems can't just be gatekeepers
because telling somebody no or yes,
there's a bit of value there but there's far more value in.
No, but here's what we can do to make it a yes,
it can. It always has to be no.
But, and, and actually this is something I was,
I was arguing with someone the other day about is that, you know,
when security is a gatekeeper, people just come on the fence,
right?
And it's the same thing with a tool like this. If, if, if you just tell people no,
they will find a way,
they will find a way. Well, they have to, because they have to ship their product.
You know,
like every project manager I've met the sacred thing is
the schedule and the features that were promised to clients.
And if you get in the way of that,
they're going to run over you with a steamroller
and, and kind of as they should because like if you're not shipping,
yeah. Well, it's their job. That's literally their job,
right? Why are people paying you if you're not giving them what they want?
You know, that's
kind of how it works.
Ok.
So anyway,
you include your dependency step one,
we have a system that gates it and says yes or no.
And if it says no, it's going to give you reasonable alternatives
and they could be something like use this version
instead or they could be upgrade to this version
because you're trying to pull in an old version or it could even be this thing sucks.
Use this other thing over here because it's better
and, and that happens a lot.
I see that a lot where someone will use some sort of dependency.
Not because it's the best because it's what they know
and there might be a better alternative.
People
grossly underestimate integration cost.
Uh Yeah, it's, it's hugely expensive, right? When you pull in a dependency
at a minimum,
you need to add a line import law or whatever your language equivalent is.
And then you need to have at least,
I guess one line of code that somehow calls it and uses it
and
usually it's a lot more than one line of code
almost certainly,
you know. And so yeah. No, the, the the cost, I mean, the cost of building yourself is
quite often higher than integrating way higher. Yes. Although not always.
Yeah, people,
I think that's part of the problem is people
vastly underestimate the cost of pulling a dependency and
maintaining that dependency because that dependency may
change or something may go away or a new
features added that behaves differently ah in this narrative,
uh
maintaining it goes away because we have to automate maintaining it. Right.
Well, yeah.
Yeah, that's, that's handled by the automated system to some degree, I mean, right,
the automated system has to be able to deal with that and, and I think it will be,
I think it's coming and I think we're going to
see that at some point in the future because it's,
let's face it.
It's like someone is holding a giant bag of money
and they're saying someone come catch this giant bag of money.
Oh, if somebody came to me and said, look,
here's the thing that will help you handle your dependencies and make sure that they
don't break your core application because we've had that happen at the CS A,
right.
We've had
a library that was used
the uh the HTML, I think it was the uh file type or object type or whatever it's called,
it was returned was different.
And so of course, it broke
and, you know, once we figured out what was broken and what had changed,
it was really quick and easy to fix.
But man, I mean, if we had some sort of,
you know, massive dependency checker that ran, like,
say some sort of testing to say, hey, wow,
this dependency actually changed the way it's going to work with your code.
Ignoring the security side of that, man. I would love to buy that.
Yeah, seriously. It'd be huge. I think. I, I have no doubt. All right. All right. So
let's assume
for the moment
we have the dependency problem mostly solved. Right.
So now
we, we get to a point where we're writing our application
And today
you hear of manual code reviews and you hear of static analysis, code reviews,
right?
And
I'm gonna say they both have their,
yeah, it's funny
they both have their own set of problems.
And I think we can say manual code reviews need to go over human
rights,
go away.
Should be doing architectural reviews.
Yes,
that's a very good point.
And an architectural review would have happened long before we get to where we are.
Right. So we'll just ignore that for now.
But I, I do think humans doing architecture of these matters.
This is part of what I love about all these conversations
is we have this massive technical debt.
Like I once unpacked all of R seven,
all the base packages for redhead and Prize Linux seven,
you know, unpacked all the RP MS deleted all like the J PGS, images, text files,
like basically got rid of everything I could that
didn't appear to be code
and I was left with like 50 or 60 gigs of stuff.
Yeah, it's enormous
like we,
I'm not sure if like all of the programmers in humanity stopped
doing what they're doing for a week and spent time reviewing that,
that we could even effectively do that. No, no, just no. The answer is no.
And,
and actually there have been studies done that a human
being can actually only do a code review for two hours
after two hours. You're, you're wasting time.
Well, and even worse than that. Do they understand the software they're reviewing?
Right. That's the first step. What is this an image library? A web library?
Uh freaking A I neural net.
Can you or I review an A I neural net? No, no, we could
just won't be very useful.
Yeah.
OK. So anyway, humans go away. No humans, right?
So we know now we're dealt with essentially what is a static analysis tool to look at
your code commits to look at the code to look at the application as a whole. Because
one of the other complaints I always have
is if all you're doing is reviewing commits,
like sometimes you need to look at the big picture because you can't just look
at this one commit and what it's doing because it can affect other things.
And so this is where you're going to have things
like you need the ability to check API S.
You need to be able to verify that we're not breaking things.
We have to be able to run like static tests against
one file or one feature.
And then also like giant functional testing across the application.
And this has to be automated and it also has to run fast.
The other dirty secret is you actually now need
integration testing against say cloud providers because for example,
we ran into a thing where
this um
this library generated essentially generated magic S3 URL S.
So you can, you can have an S3 bucket that's sort of quasi
public private in that it's
the, the data is publicly accessible if you have a magic URL that has like a,
essentially it's assigned,
it's like a, it's a, it's a URL with a non and a crypto string in it that
authenticates you as being able to grab that object publicly, right?
And
the default time out that it was setting for these objects was five minutes.
And cloud flare sets,
the smallest time out you can set assuming
you don't go to some crazy enterprise package.
It's 30 minutes.
So essentially downloads would work for five minutes and then break for
25 minutes and then work again for five minutes break for.
So, you know, this is these are like
the this integration testing is becoming a bit
of a challenge.
The other thing I was just, I had the thought kind of back to the Linux kernel.
Why are we doing this just for security bugs? Why not all bugs? No. Right.
And and yes, actually, that's a really good point
I think because quite honestly if you're building,
you know, in my perfect ideal world, we have a system that essentially
runs these code tests and runs these function and
integration and all the tests possible and looks for
wonky or bad or like definitely bad behavior like
system core dumps that probably shouldn't do that,
right. You know, because you can have a static code analyzer.
And who cares if it's security.
Right. Right. Yes, it doesn't matter if it's security.
I've seen flaws that are worse than security flaws in the, for example, it's a memory
usage issue where it's slowly,
you know, memory,
memory usage builds up over time and then you
have to reboot the system and it was like,
the system will run for a max of like, eight hours and then you have to reboot it.
Well,
that's arguably worse than a denial of service because
it's going to happen every eight hours without fail.
No. Absolutely. And in fact, I'll, I'll argue here
where, let's say you're a database vendor
and you have a bug that corrupts all the data on disk
and you have another bug that's a denial of service, right?
Which one are you going to fix first? Not the denial of service.
You have a bug that randomly mangles a little bit of data once in a while.
Yeah,
those are the worst actually because then you don't
even know what's going on till it's too late
because if you mingle all the data cool, we know it broke.
If everything breaks cool, it broke, we saw that we fix it.
But if it only mangles one in a million records randomly
and you found it after a year and now all you back
are broke
anyway. Anyway. All right. So yes, so we can agree unquestionably
that there's going to be some sort of like what,
what we would call human code review today needs to be dumped off on a machine.
And part of that review is going to be
things like testing and making sure that the code
you'll have different, uh was it styles you use whatever?
So, so we're going to make sure that's all good. And so now we've got
our committed application, right. We've got our, our, everything's checked in
now it's time to start thinking about a release.
Right.
And now, historically, when someone does a release,
this is when a lot of organizations would really kick in the security work and say,
all right, now it's time to take a look at things.
And I'm telling you, if you're doing it that way,
that's too late. It's way too late. Yeah. Exactly.
Because I'm, you know, we're like, I see
to put it bluntly
the people who move towards continuous development win and it's,
I think it's less about continuous development and more about the fact that
they are so much faster and more agile than the people not doing it.
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
So, so anyway, however, I will say
so you're, you're getting ready for release and at this point,
you shouldn't be running a bunch of new
tests because you should have already run them.
Right. That's, that's the universe we need to be in.
You shouldn't have to worry about, am I shipping ban dependencies?
Because at this point
you almost certainly have done all your testing.
The
other problem too is when you do the testing of that
time frame
backing out is hugely costly.
Yes. And in a lot of cases, I
just don't
say
it,
you know. Yeah, I mean, we can't not ship this product.
It's been six months since the last release.
And I think that's the other benefit of continuous development and rapid
releases is making the cost of a release smaller that too.
Right. If you do it a lot, you're good at it.
Well, you have to get good at it or you go bankrupt. Yep. Yep.
Well, and, and you have to write you.
That's true.
You make it easy. I've seen people do it. They're not good at it. They go bankrupt. Ok.
Ok. So, anyway, let's keep moving on. So now we've made it to release, right?
And this is where I think we need to start putting some serious effort into
how we run a lot of these systems because the vast majority of systems out there,
if you can break through an application, let's say you, you know,
you go to a website and you,
you send some bad command and now you've got a root shell or not a shell,
we'll just say a shell in the system.
Yeah. Well, here's about Rooney Mar.
If you're running as the web application,
you control everything that web application does.
That's all I care about. Roots are relevant. I agree. Roots are relevant.
And, and here's the thing though, like in, in so many systems,
if you can get to that point, like it's done,
right? There are almost no protections,
there's you can do almost anything you want, you can probably move laterally
and,
and that's something that really needs to change.
And this is actually this is happening now
with
kind of kubernetes and
sto and some of the things I see there is where people are able
to run a container and say like this container can only connect to the database
end of story, right?
Like that is all it can do and that kind of stuff is hugely powerful.
If you can say like this application should never run bash,
right? That's cool.
Well, even more to the point,
I'm looking at things like state uh serverless computing
where a request comes in handle the request.
You are allowed to for example, talk to the database back end, return a reply,
then you die.
And if you don't die,
the system kills you because you get X 100 milliseconds
of compute time or whatever like those cloud flare works.
And then so and actually the the there was a
really good presentation by AC CC Chaos Computer Conference guy.
I want to say last year or the year before their Christmas conference
where he talked about how all the different ways you could, for example,
exfiltrate data from a serverless thing in a in Amazon, I remember that.
Yeah. And man, it was, it was. But you know, I hope some of those got fixed by Amazon.
But more of the point, it was way harder than a traditional
super convoluted.
Now, at the same time, this means a lot, a lot of systems and a lot of,
I guess solutions will say need to be re
architected because most things don't work like that.
And the beauty is once you get to true
Serverless and really understand where your state is.
You're sort of inherently building continuous delivery in
the sense of how does an upgrade work?
Well, I provide a newer version of the software and the next time a request comes in,
it uses it mic drop.
We're done here. Right.
Yeah. Right. Right.
You know,
and, and that's the kind of thing, you know,
I'm looking at these things in the context of, for example,
I'm working on some Blockchain projects
and obviously a lot of these watching projects
will probably have a web based front end.
OK.
Well,
I don't want you breaking into the web based front end
and camping out there and looking at other people's data,
for example.
Right. So how can we do that?
Well, like serverless is a good example of you come in,
you break into the serverless state machine
and a couple 100 milliseconds goes by and you get the boot
and more to the point, you can't easily look at somebody else's request
or their data. Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly. Right.
Because in theory, it's a different process for every request.
So you just can't get to it if you wanted to. Different server, I suppose. Yeah.
Different server in some cases.
Yeah.
You know, looking at like the cloud flare thing and,
and the point is can I architect that in a traditional system?
Absolutely. But it is really hard
now, you can't just just say no, it's no. All right.
So anyway, we, we're running out of time. We got to keep moving.
So now we've made it to a point
where we've essentially released our product or service.
And this is where things like our traditional compliance comes into play.
And I'm going to be very specific. Compliance and security are not the same thing.
Right? You can, you can have a compliant insecure application, you can have a secure
unlit application.
Every major PC I data breach has happened at a place that was PC I compliant.
That's correct.
So, so anyway, but here's, here's kind of my point on compliance is
uh whether you love it or hate it. I don't care because you need it
because it's just kind of where we are.
And, and I will say as well, I view compliance is washing your hands.
If you go to a doctor that doesn't wash their hands, the answer is no.
Right.
If my doctor doesn't wash his hands, I'm not going to that guy.
And and it's the same deal with compliance like it just because
my doctor washes his hands doesn't mean my doctor is any good.
It just means they wash your hands.
But I know if they don't wash their hands, they're probably really, really bad.
Right.
That much I can say, well, it's, it's these signals,
I look at places like with the star registry, you know, this, this,
I'm not going to say basic but these, you know, massive list of questions
and yeah,
if a provider can't answer things like we do
do we do background checks on our employees?
Ok, thanks. Bye.
Right. That's right. Yes, let me give you my personal data. Please
take it.
So anyway, anyway, so here's the thing with, with compliance,
there are ways to do like continuous compliance skin and generally speaking,
the way it works is you bring your auditor in,
you get everything done once a year and then you're like, hey,
we're compliant and then you stop carrying till next year.
And that's totally the wrong way to be doing this stuff.
I think we're going to see a world very soon where
compliance reports and scans are literally happening all the time every day
and there's going to be no way around it.
And so you're not going to be able to get away from it every day is not fast enough.
It has to happen when there are changes.
Yes, that's true. Actually, that's the ultimate thing. Is it
when there is a material or even not a very material change to the system,
the system has now changed. Is it still in compliance? Right.
And if you're doing continuous updating and you're updating your system
five times a day or 10 times a day or whatever,
you're right,
you kind of need to scan it on a regular basis or you change business process or
you open up an office in another country,
another data center in another country. Those are, those are really good points.
Yes. And this is where actually the world of compliance needs to catch up as well.
But how, how much can I advertise the cloud security lines here?
You can pimp it all you want.
Well, because, I mean, that's what we're moving to, with the star registry.
We're moving to the continuous
compliance model with the star registry. You know, it's,
it's,
it's happening because it has to,
you should get someone who's doing that on the show and we can,
we can hassle them about this because that's, that's really cool.
Actually, I, I think, I think it's going to be huge because like,
I look at the way compliance works today
and you sit down for like a week with the auditor and you answer like,
10 million questions and they're just, they're writing pro,
it's not like they're even like, you know, using some sort of
machine. Understandable. Oh, it's Excel spreadsheets all the way down. Right.
It's a mess. And I'm like, this is insane.
This is madness. Like why is it working like this? And, and so,
and, and not only that, the thing that really ticks me off
is at the end, you can have an auditor will say, oh, you need to do that
and then you can more often than not, you can talk your way completely out of it.
It's like that is not OK.
That's not how this is supposed to work. Well, my favorite thing was like with the,
you know, with the PC I and the TLS, it's like you have to get rid of this.
Well, except for these cases, like old point of sale systems or whatever.
And if you're like, promised double square
keeps
to like, deal with it at some point in the future, then you can keep doing this.
Right. I know. I know it's anyway, well, here's the thing. What's the alternative?
You can't actually like if compliance actually shut things down,
half the banks wouldn't be running.
It's very true. It's very true. Alright. So, anyway, I guess that kind of,
that's what I think the future is going to look like. And, and I guess,
well,
the simple reality is the people that are able to do
this and capable of doing this will clobber the people that
can't,
I mean, look at software releases.
Like,
I remember a world where getting a new piece of software
on floppy disk every couple of years was totally acceptable,
you know,
and then C DS every year and then maybe, you know, oh, windows with service pack,
one service pack two
totally acceptable. New Linux distro every six months,
you know, and now I expect essentially if you're not shipping the updates as
needed.
Yeah, I'm not going to use you
and, and I do get some constraints like Microsoft Tuesday, you know, like,
like I do appreciate that Microsoft made it a schedule because I remember when it
wasn't Microsoft Tuesday and when we would
literally like literally just uh you know,
an email would go around like everybody goes to work now to start processing this,
you know, like literally drop whatever it is you're doing
and
you know, Microsoft just dropped a pile of updates panic now
could be,
you know,
you remember those, it was terrible.
So I'm actually really happy they put it on a schedule.
So I guess here's the question for you and here's how we'll end it is
if you were going to guess
on timelines of how far away we are from kind of this, this world that works.
Are we talking about
a single digit years,
tens of digits or do you think it's like
we'll be dead before this happens?
Well, I, I know it's happening in, in the next single digits of months.
It's, it's no,
it's not because we're not going to have like dependency scanners that work right,
like some of this stuff maybe.
But I'm saying what I think what will happen is
it'll start at the higher level and then filter down
because the high level will drive the lower level like the high level.
I bet you're right people, for example, will have continuous stars,
you know, entries.
Cool. Now, what are you doing about your software? Why is that not continuous?
And not only that if you have stars doing continuous scanning, you can,
you can slowly turn the knob up, like boil the frog as they say, where once you,
once you get them hooked, you can really drive some real change in that.
Yeah.
And I think it has to kind of be top down because
I think this fundamentally has to be driven by the business.
I, this isn't one of those things like, oh, definitely,
definitely a great example is TLS SSL that can totally be in many cases driven
by the techies
because you can just sort of do it and get away with it.
But a great example is um I think was it the BBC or the Guardian or one of
those big British news organizations had a really good
posting about how they went to HTTP S everywhere,
whatever and like it took them a good year or two because, you know,
all the third party stuff, the ad networks that just
all of that
to do this properly without breaking their site and making life, you know,
miserable for users
was a very nontrivial matter.
And I think that's part of the reality too, is smaller shops
in some ways have an easier time of doing this.
I mean, for, well, one thing they just have less code to deal with,
they have less technical debt.
Right.
Like a start up has a lot less technical debt than say,
and I'm not going to pick an IBM but I'm going to say IBM because I know they have a lot of
is, is writing the checks for technical debt. Exactly.
It's the big companies that have to cash them.
Yeah, well, they own, they own technical debt bonds that are, you know,
20 years old at this point,
you know, they're going to be mature
technical debt.
Yeah, exactly.
So, you know, a company like IBM, the,
I can't even imagine how many lines of code they
have that they've written and have to maintain and I'm not
about just products they've released but like under contract and stuff,
I guarantee they have no idea
in
part
of the
problem.
We have no idea of what the US federal code is, you know, for the laws.
Yes, that's true too. Right. We have an estimate of how many like pages it is.
So I suspect like I said, this will come from top down,
especially in the larger organizations.
Alright. Alright. So let's take it from the top down then.
So something like continuous compliance.
You're saying that's probably we'll say in the single digit years,
easily within single digits years.
It's something that is actually reasonably achievable.
Alright, so let's move down now.
So we get to kind of the, the whole universe of lots of magic. Uh uh
we'll say hardened systems running like Kubernetes Isio
style things, which is going to be a very serverless like universe.
I think we were really close there.
I think I would say mid single digits kind of a 3 to 5 year time frame. All right.
So let's move down. We're kind of at, at magic
uh integration style testing slash C I slash coder view all that stuff.
So I think that will happen, you know, again, single digit,
mid single digit years because
ignoring the security side of things, if you can say, hey, look,
we can basically guarantee that this code and service we're writing kind of,
we never break it for users again.
I think something like automated code reviews are
five plus years.
Well,
we've discussed this before,
but I don't think necessarily you need automated code reviews because for example,
automated code
it
the big.
No, no, no, no. Let me finish.
I think,
I think automated code health would be a good enough start.
Hey, this project is sickly.
It has three committers and two commits over five years.
So chances are there will be a a,
you know,
a problem with it at some point that you have to panic about
versus this other library that is equivalent and much healthier and much newer.
Uh, no, you're, you're, we're a level above that conversation.
But anyway, all right.
So, so I'm saying when I,
when I do a check in and I think once you get that then you'll get code reviews.
Ok. And that's fair. That's fair. So, I guess next. Ok.
So, so let's, let's go one more level down and say
the, the question of
kind of managing your dependence
and I'm going to guess that's 5 to 10 years to do that.
I guess here's let's sum it up because we're, we're totally out of time.
Is,
it sounds like
this isn't quite as dire as, as maybe, maybe I thought it was
in the last episode. Here's the Dirty Secret and I the Cloud will enable a lot of this.
A lot of this can't really be done on premises easily, but the cloud
with that.
Ok. No, that's fair. I, I agree.
I, I guess I,
I feel more hopeful after this part of the conversation
than I did at the end of the last one.
So I guess thank you for that. If nothing else. All right, cool.
Well, thank you everyone for putting up with us for
this crazy episode.
If you want the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com,
you can hit us up with the Pound
Os podcast hashtag on social media
And yeah, I guess everyone. Thank you for listening.
Have a great day and Kurt, I'll talk to you soon. Thank you
the.