Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast number 23 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Pressers.
-- Hey, Kurt, how are you
-- doing?
I am doing awesome.
I actually had a really interesting experience during breakfast this morning
-- that
-- this story sounds like it could be really funny or, or really disturbing.
-- Uh,
-- a bit
-- of
-- both.
Um, so I, I tend to eat breakfast upstairs and, uh, sometimes I like to watch,
you know, a little youtube while I'm eating my breakfast.
So I, uh, fired up the, uh, the computer.
It's a Mac mini hooked up to the TV, because it's basically the cheapest,
quietest computer I could find for a TV.
I accidentally logged in as my own account because, um, well, not accidentally,
I had to do a backup of it.
Like I had to run time machine and change the settings.
So I had to log in as myself and not the kids account. Right. Normally the, uh,
that machine is logged in as the kids account, which, you know,
they can't break stuff.
Right.
So I,
I logged in as myself because I had to fiddle with
some time machine settings and make sure time machine was running
-- and uh I forgot to log out and I of course, fired up chrome and um as
-- yourself,
not the Children,
-- well
-- as myself and all the Children and this is the one copy of chrome I
have where I don't like log into chrome and I don't have an ad blocker installed.
Oh man.
So it's funny, right? Because I typed in like why
like normally on my browser if you hit the Y
key youtube, you hit the A key Amazon.
Do you know like there's just,
you know, that's just how it is.
So I typed in uh yout hit enter,
right? Because without thinking, right?
Just like, you know, because I'll end up youtube, right? Of course.
So I actually ended up doing a Google search for Yout, which,
you know, conveniently enough showed me uh 33 ads, the text ads for youtube, which I
then I kind of thought it was a little weird because I
just assumed Google would have bought like one ad for themselves,
but maybe they bought a couple.
So it like shows the screen, right? What do I know? So, whatever, right? Obviously
this ad at the top it says like youtube, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
wwww.youtube.com blah, blah, blah.
And I'm like whatever, click on that, right?
And immediately the TV starts belting out your computer is infected with a
virus and you've got a virus and it shows me on Microsoft,
is it actually saying these words?
It was audio, right?
And it was like a Microsoft skinned website,
you know, like it was the micro, like it looked like a Microsoft knowledge,
like, whatever
saying, like, blah, blah, blah. And, um, I'm talking
to
you just like the real
microsoft.com does. Right.
Exactly. And of course, I'm like, what, you know, because, like,
you know, I haven't eaten breakfast yet.
I haven't had my coffee yet, so I'm not 100% with it. But I'm like, wait,
this is a Mac,
you know.
Right.
So that's my first clue.
And then I, like, I wake up a little bit more and I'm like,
I probably don't have a virus because like,
this account has never done anything other than like
run time machine and like fiddle the settings.
And, um, so it was a call 1 800 some phone number, your computers infected by a virus
than that
if you don't give out the phone number, Kurt.
Uh, but even better than that, there was also.
So I was like, ok, obviously this is like a malware scam type deal, right?
And so I, I took a screenshot and hit back
and then clicked on the second link because, hey, I'm kind of curious now
and it was the same site,
but a slightly different link instead of saying
like your computer is infected with malware,
blah, blah, blah.
It was like something something, something Facebook
and, but these looked like youtube ads.
They were the Google,
-- they were Google ads at the top.
-- It
-- was
-- like
-- the
-- Google text based
-- ad. But what did the ad say? What was the text?
-- It
literally just said www.youtube.com, an online site for videos. And
so it looked like a youtube ad. You clicked it and you clearly went to
-- this thing,
-- uh,
some hacked website because now if you go to the website dyvry.com or whatever,
the, uh, somebody was kind enough to remove all the files,
uh,
it's now blank. There's not even an error page.
The website itself is actually, was quite nicely done.
Uh, there were no spelling errors. Uh, it actually was in like, proper English.
If that's the bar, I think we've got problems.
Well,
come on. Have you read the spam email in your spam folder?
Have you read any of the email you get from most people
in
full of spelling mistakes in van grammar?
Yeah. Well, any grammar would be good at this point.
But anyway, so, yeah, it was interesting because,
ok, the part where, like, people hack somebody else's website and use it to serve,
you know, whatever wonky stuff.
Yeah, that's, that's normal. That's just how the internet works now. Right.
But the fact that they had
Google ads that redirected to their thing and it was based on typos, right?
-- Like yout, not like typing in youtube or
-- y you know, it's really funny you,
you mentioned this and
when, when I was a buddy, we
lad
working as a Cetin at
an ISP,
we had a customer that would register like all kinds of misspelled domain names.
And like this was, this was a company that sold chairs
and they
literally had like 1000 misspellings and they would call us
at least three or four times a day and say,
hey, buy this domain for us, buy this domain for us.
And it was just, it was kind of bonkers honestly and they just,
they kept registering these domains traffic
though,
you know, I don't know, I have no idea.
In hindsight,
I kind of wish I would have crunched some of
the numbers to understand if like this made sense.
Like because back in the day when like you could get ads for click
or not through, click throughs, but for just page views and stuff, right?
People would do that kind of stuff all the time,
you know.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And I mean,
I know that there's also the people um I don't know
if you remember this from last year or this year,
I guess still this year
people
squatting on domains that are like one bite off of a regular domain.
So like basically,
you know, so so apparently the deal is when you make a DNS request,
like a packet can get mangled
and like, so let's say for the
no,
-- no,
it's not, it's not even just that it's about like,
-- it is
-- a
bit.
Right. Exactly.
You can have various hardware errors and it, it's not a lot and I'll link to the story.
I forget what the number is but
it, it's, it's nonzero.
Um, anyways, yeah, things like that.
Like,
so it's interesting to me because on the one hand
are these bad guys actually buying Google apps for like,
you know, yout
search results because let's face it, right?
Like you're going to get search results for like a ma a ma Z am Ezo, right?
For Amazon, right?
And you send those people to something that looks like amazon.com,
they may not pay attention to the address bar and
they might type in their credit card number again.
-- I mean,
-- nobody pays attention to the address bar
because I know like traditionally,
one thing everybody does is the defense of DNS registrations,
right? Like
bob.com Bob with
an O, Bob with a zero Bob with a Q because hey,
there's sort of
kind of circles.
And so, you know, I'm familiar with the idea of DNS defensive DNS registrations,
but the idea of like defensive ad registrations because here's the change, right?
Like
I remember what was it about 5, 10 years ago?
That's when all the web browsers, the address bar turned into also the search bar,
right? That's the thing to remember, right? Folks is that
it used to be that address bar, you type something in it.
Better be a valid DNS or URL or you get an error.
Now, it's like it'll do the DNS look up and if that works great,
it'll send you there and
it doesn't work, it'll send you like Google and do a search.
Um Which is really fascinating because I know, um, apparently columbia.co was uh
well, but here's the really cool part, right?
Because Google Chrome, for example,
and some other browsers in an attempt to be faster
will do things. Like if you type in like google.co, it'll be like, oh,
you're probably going to like
that domain. I'm going to look it up right away.
Right?
And so of course, because people type like.com dot You know,
you type.com Columbia was basically typo squatting all of.com,
right? There's, there's articles but it, it was, it was unreal, right?
Because, you know,
and especially now because we have how many new top level domains that are actually,
there's
an infinite number now. It's completely crazy.
Apparently,
I there was some discussion about like should local host be a
reserved top level domain or should they be allowed to sell it?
-- I like,
-- didn't they end up selling it?
Which is freaking nuts
dot local host? Yeah. Um It's reserved, apparently, still reserved. Thank God.
But I know my like my current ISP back in the
day when they started out with high speed uh cable modems.
This is like, oh my goodness, this is like 9899.
So long ago anyways,
they would let you pick a host name like Bob or Dave or whatever dot ISP dot C A.
And so me being a smart ass, I picked local host
and then my modem just like lit up,
you know, because here's the thing, right?
When your, when your computer system looks for a name, uh for example,
when it looks for local host, it actually looks for local host dot
whatever you put in as your default search domain first that
either fails or ideally,
a lot of places do list an actual explicit like local host dot Like
cried.org is 1 27.0 0.0 0.1 right?
So you end up at the right place.
Um And if that fails, then it tries like just local host and goes, oh yeah,
I know what to do with that now.
But uh yeah, so I basically set my host name to local host and then my,
my cable modem lit up and I was able to log into
the web page to change my host name back to something else.
So I had to phone the, the is the uh one of the uh cis
AINS there and I was like, uh Kevin. Yeah.
Uh Remember that thing where you let people choose a host name.
He's like, yeah, and I'm like
it, let me choose local host
because the funny thing is they actually had a black list of stuff like a men male,
like host names that they used
and then they actually started adding a black list of names that were like,
sort of official looking
-- and, and apparently local host, eventually
-- you should add local host to that
because I just did. And well, yeah, now my, my internet connection is melting.
That is awesome. And you totally got what you deserved.
Well, but, you know, it was fun.
I should have really been running a sniffer though.
Oh my goodness, man, you, no, no,
no, no.
-- You
-- know,
-- violating all kinds of laws.
-- I remember hearing stories about stuff like this where
I haven't heard any recently. I'm sure this still happens. But
there, there's a story I heard of this,
this an old Geezer hacker one time was doing some testing and he was basically,
this was pen testing before it was called pen testing, right?
And, and he essentially sends an exploit into the NTP server of this ISP
and he had it set up a reverse shell
because he wanted to prove to them. It's a problem, right? And, and here he sets it up.
So the,
the, the use net post shouldn't leave this one server
and lo and behold, they screwed up their, their NTP server, NNTNNTP.
It was called, right? Yeah, NNNNTP server
and then put it out on all of use net.
And so this, this dude had like reverse shells coming in from all over the place I was,
like, what do you even?
I
guess he unplugged his internet connection because he's like,
I don't even know what to do with this.
-- Like, it's like
-- that guy with the excess or whatever on Facebook that, like,
turned into.
Right. Right. Like, yeah, like that.
It was just like, all of a sudden it's like, boom, I have a million friends.
And then did they? I think they, they killed his account, didn't they?
Oh,
yeah, they're, they're not going to be nice about that
-- anyway.
-- Anyway, so back to your fake site.
I took a screenshot of it and yeah, it was just, it was really fascinating. Right.
Because I understand,
you know, like, it's just, I've never encountered,
I've never encountered malware and whatnot through advertising because
I always have U block origin and, um, the Efeffs, uh, the effs
privacy badger thing installed, which privacy badger is super awesome, by the way,
kind of a bit of ac pu hog comparatively, but
like, super awesome for, well, privacy and blocking ads, you know,
it basically doesn't allow third party sites to do dumb stuff.
And so, you know, it's funny. Right, because
I'm just not used to seeing ads on the internet.
Right. So when I do accidentally browse
-- with a browser that doesn't have ad blocking, I'm kind of like, oh, what's
-- that?
You know, it's really funny. So I, I did that. I was,
I've got my ad blockers and
I was, I was at somebody's house and they had loaded,
I think it was Facebook and I looked, and I'm like, what's wrong with your Facebook?
It's like, but seriously, you don't have an ad blocker.
It has so much garbage on the screen. It's unusable.
I mean, it's not even recognizable. Honestly.
You're, yeah. Right. Exactly. You are totally the product.
You are not the customer.
But,
so anyway, but here's the deal with, with you finding the, the,
the ad that's obviously, I, I think
I'm comfortable calling this malware.
Right? Is
definitely
I'm guessing they would have had me either give them my credit card number or,
-- you know, install this like teamviewer dot exe, not
-- ransomware dot exe.
Yeah,
totally legit. Don't
panic. Do.
But here's the deal when I think about all of this stuff is
the bad guys. They're fitting into society in amazing ways.
And this reminds me sometimes of
during prohibition in the United States,
the mob was essentially a business
and you even look at organized crime today.
You hear these stories about like they operate like a
business and that's what these guys are starting to do,
which is just crazy.
I mean,
they're, they're basically,
they figured out what the rules are that everyone else uses and they're,
they're just bending them in their own way.
It's, it's crazy.
Well, what gets me here is, um, I mean,
this stuff works because here's a great example.
It's on the register.co.uk.
Uh and it's talking about and this is what uh Los Angeles to
extradite bloke from Nigeria after scores of city workers fall for fish scam.
So apparently some Nigerian scammer actually emailed like
everybody who works for Los Angeles.
But here's the thing. So
the L A District Attorney's office claimed in May that
uh sorry claimed on Friday that in May of this year 2016,
last name O Ona
Ginor,
I'm butchering that
sent the emails to more than 1000 Los Angeles counties, 100 and 20,000 employees.
So basically he had up like less than 1% or roughly 1% of the
total employees
of the 1000 employees.
100 and eight of the messages tricked
users into handing over their login credentials to
service portals.
Now this isn't
like,
like
that's
a
-- 10% success rate for like, please give me your password.
-- That's
right. Actually is there have been a lot of studies done on fishing and it's
like 10 to 30% is about what you can expect
for
when you have 100 and 20,000 people working for you. I mean,
you're up to like you, you're done,
right? And so this is exactly the point right is
we will never stop fishing.
Fishing is
it it, it exploits the human, we can't patch people.
And so there is no way to fix,
you know what,
-- I'm gonna have to disagree for you for one moment because it just came across
-- my
anti
fishing.
Uh No. Uh Uber runs their own email I DS, system
engineering security through Uber's custom email I DS
and it starts off with fishing is one of the
largest and most difficult challenges for any enterprise security team.
It's the greatest equalizer of security. We all have to deal with it.
Well executed fishing attacks can trick people
into making simple yet costly mistakes.
One way companies go blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah at Uber, we decided to build our own email ideas for a couple of reasons.
Number one to drive operational benefits
and price extensibility and performance.
Number two to exercise full control over features and alerts
so we can adjust to evolving threats in real time.
And number three
to capture advanced insight for debugging intrusion alerts
and email processing at Uber in general.
Anyways,
um we'll obviously post a link to it in the
show notes but like seriously this thing is really interesting.
It does,
it sounds awesome and it sounds like something that everyone should be doing.
But again,
we're not.
Well, the reality is we can't fix the people, right?
There's a certain subset of people where you, you,
you ask them nicely for money and they'll just give it to you,
right?
And part of that is because humans
and large are nice people.
-- That's
-- why they like as seen on TV section exists in the, in the,
-- you
-- know,
struggling with those Tupperware, man. That thing can be tough.
Um,
I, I
hate to say, I love that subreddit where they, they take those, uh,
those I've seen on TV, like the,
the bits of the video where the people are struggling
with whatever product they're trying to sell a solution for,
you know, and they like me subtitle it and it's just, it makes me laugh.
But,
um, no, but the reality is, here's the reality, right?
Like I, I don't have the expertise to build like an anti fish ID system for my family.
You know,
like I'm sure my kids would be more than happy to go find daddy's wallet
and hand over his credit card number to get like some online game or something.
Yes, you're probably unfortunately correct.
Um, which I believe you had brought, uh, you mentioned something earlier
-- that you maybe want to mention on the show.
-- Which particular thing would that be,
-- uh
-- the Mario thing? Oh,
the Mario Run.
Right. Right. So, so
who don't know is I,
I unfortunately don't have it because I don't have an Apple device.
But
so Nintendo, who I am a huge Nintendo Fanboy.
Nintendo creates an app called Super Mario run, which is one,
just one of those endless runner type games with all the Mario characters,
which of course,
I'm, I'm the person that like you could, they, they could like,
put poop in a box and call it Mario or Zelda and like I'm gonna get it right.
I'm gonna get it and I'm gonna show it to everyone. I know and talk about how cool it is.
So, anyway, Super Mario run it. It's like 10 bucks on I OS
and there is nothing for Android. And of course I hear about Mario run.
I'm like, the first thing I do is I type it into the Play store.
I got bad news for you, buddy. It's free on Apple.
I thought it was. No, no, you can download it for free.
But no, no, no, like you get,
I guess like a crap demo level and then to actually play the game,
you have to give them 10 bucks.
Right.
Right. Right. So, anyway,
anyway,
I, of course, type it in the play store. Nothing there.
And then I type it into Google and there are plenty of Super Mario run
A PK si can download and install on my phone and I'm like, yeah, I'm not doing that.
But so there's, there's a
story. It's an awesome
dude.
Right.
So I hear,
no,
no, I hate, I hate malware.
But, but so, so here's the thing, right? Is,
is, this is a,
this is totally related to people not knowing really what they're doing and,
and this even kind of goes around fishing and it is very related to your, your, I guess
yute search is that, is y out a word? I hope it's a word.
But anyway,
So, so here's the point though. So yut is not in the dictionary, unfortunately,
but we'll fix it.
So,
so anyway, but, but here's the deal, right is when
there is a hole
in the universe for some reason, I if, if the good guys don't fill it, the bad guys do.
And this Mario run is a perfect example of that where
the good guys don't make it for Android.
-- So of course, there are copies of it for Android. The
-- ever classic.
What is it like lonely Singles in your area? Wanna talk
-- to you?
-- Right.
-- No, no,
-- they
won't.
Right. Right.
-- It's
-- human nature. Just
wait till we've got A I bots powering that stuff.
You build it for like five bucks from Amazon.
You be able to start up your own only singles. 900 service.
Um Well, you can already do that. Remember.
Um, Amazon announced, what was it, Amazon Parrot, which does the text to speech
in um,
what was it like two dozen languages and 40 some accents.
Yeah, but I'm sure, you know, it's a computer.
Well, I, I figure it's like probably like my Apple, my iphone,
I actually set it to the male British accent so that I can pretend it's my butler.
Ok. So the way the Apple phone uh works is you can select a variety.
I think it's about four or five different uh, voices and either male or female.
And you have a choice of like um, like American English, British English,
Australian English
and the way they pronounce things, especially names,
like my last name is way different.
And so I have the British male voice set because then I
-- get to pretend it's my butler because he's like calling Melanie
-- Smith.
Your English accent is top
notch.
Well, you know,
the best part though about English English is they pronounce aluminum
aluminum,
which is like the greatest thing ever.
I just, I remember finding out that in Australia they actually spell tire, like,
like the thing on your car tyre.
-- And I'm like,
-- they do that in the UK too, don't they? It's tire,
tire
tire.
I'm just trying to think of top gear and I've never seen them spell it.
-- So
-- you
-- want
-- to know what's really funny is, so, I,
I worked for an Englishman for, like, 10 years
-- and
-- I don't even,
I don't, whatever,
a gentleman from the UK will say that.
And
I say so many English iss
like, like UK iss
that the people in here in America, they laugh at me constantly.
I don't even know I'm doing it. And so,
like, yeah, I, I'll read words written in, in the Queen's English
and, like, my brain doesn't even register it.
And everyone else is like, ah, look at those idiots spelled tyre wrong.
I'm like, what? No, they didn't.
I've actually, yeah, for Color Center and a variety of different words
when I write them in
emails to my family.
I spell them in Canadian English, which is essentially British English.
-- But when it's a work related it's American English.
-- God bless English.
The greatest language ever.
But, yeah, I know.
It's, um, well, I've actually had a related thing with, uh, to the Mario speed run.
So,
one of my kids loves this youtube thing called boba
-- boob A and it's totally safe for work. It's like
-- a little
computer
-- is a
-- little,
it's a little computer generated um,
like cartoon essentially. Um
But is like the sort of little like Russian troll thing.
-- It's like
-- a little hairy guy
who's like
horrifying.
Look at this face.
It's like,
it's a head
with legs and arms. This is like, what
little kids
anyways, he loves this guy
and there's like, you know,
he gets into all sorts of adventures like where
Aruba tries to attack him or he sets the kitchen
on fire or he breaks into a bakery and
needs all the packaging and not the cake anyways,
my kid loves this thing and I accidentally found out that there's like
there's two BBA apps.
Oh, and uh so people know Bubba is a of Russian origin, but it's not verbal.
It's just like there's no talking in these things.
So anyways, of course, he wants these two apps. So I install them
and the first thing they do
is they install and then I load them up and they say downloading content
and it's like 60 megs of stuff from somewhere in Russia
bear.ru.
Well, so the good news is as far as I can tell, it's only ad based spam.
So at the top of the app it shows like a little banner with like,
-- click here to buy a car or click here to, like, learn about
-- it all in Russia.
Uh, no, it's in English because, you know, they know the target market.
But it got me thinking, I'm like, I really hope this Russian software is not like,
just
using my
phone,
whatever.
And, um, yeah, you know, it's just, and all this and the one app just does not work,
right?
Like, it just doesn't work properly at all.
And my son's like, wow, you know, I'm like, well,
because it just doesn't work like we tried turning it off and on.
I don't know,
I got nothing but they love this app and
it's so frustrating because I don't trust this app.
I don't trust the people that wrote it.
This creature is clearly untrustworthy
the attic episode where he like, it's actually pretty well done and amusing.
Like with the little voodoo doll and the Snow Globe and stuff, it's,
you're not convincing me.
This is what,
you know, it gets me like is realistically like what happens
if halfway through playing a game or something, the ads, the, the,
the game says something like,
you know, you can unlock everything in this app.
All you gotta do, go find your dad's wallet and, like,
put his credit card in front of the thing and we'll take, you know,
we'll verify your identity and what they're really doing is like,
taking a picture of it and sending it somewhere
and it, like, takes a picture of the front and back of your credit card and send it to,
you know, sends it to somewhere.
But why even do that?
There's probably easier ways to get people on a device
to hand over something of value actually on the device.
Well, but a six year old,
yeah, but
I mean,
because I've got their devices locked down and more
to the point there's nothing on their devices.
They can do like, they don't
have
the
card
and
do the same thing. My kids
like, yeah, he did, I'm gonna buy this app. Nope.
Even the people I know that aren't savvy are using like the uh, you know,
the apple uh family plan and stuff to like lock down their devices because,
you know, there's been those cases where those kids spent like, you know,
like $6000 on one game like
rubies or whatever to like buy
rainbow ponies or Lord knows what.
But I live in fear because like what happens if my kids snake
my wallet and go to Amazon and set up a new account.
But
here's ok. So first of all, that's why you have a credit card
because it's, it's the credit card company's money and even if your kids steal it,
I'm sure there's rules going on here. Right.
If somebody steals a credit card because of an action your Children take,
you're still not going to be liable for those purchases because it's still fraud.
Right.
Now. If they go to Amazon and they order a whole pile of crap,
you just send it back.
Right.
Assuming you can't get it canceled,
your
account gets blocked or canceled.
Amazon might do that. I mean, rightly so, but whatever, whatever, right.
The point is that
what you're talking about is
I would say a, if I was going to do a threat model of my concerns of, of,
we'll say malware type or, or, or organized crime attacking like my Children.
That's
not on the list.
Right.
It's unlikely. But, you know, it's just me being paranoid. Right.
Yes,
because my kids are becoming smart enough to understand that there's,
they understand that the credit card is a thing that, for example, if they had one,
they could get skins in Minecraft.
Uh, you know what though?
Like you're right and, and I, I remember that age when my Children were that age,
but they've also reached a point now
where they understand that's not how it works.
And,
and so part of it is I've spent a
significant amount of time already trying to teach my Children
about money.
Ok. That's fair. But then that's their own fault.
But again,
that's why you have a credit card and it's not your problem because the liability.
But I mean, so, so seriously, actually let's talk about that. Right.
We're talking about this, this malware and fake things and what's going on.
And if we look at the credit card industry,
they've solved some of this problem by shifting the
risk from the consumer to the card issuer.
Right. Like that's a model that works
because the people don't really have to care if
someone steals your credit card and they buy,
you know, $10,000 worth of chocolate.
It's not your problem.
I mean, yeah, you might have to deal with a little bit of crap to get it dealt with. But
-- fundamentally
-- what frustrates me fundamentally though is ultimately,
do these people build security systems or do they just pass the cost on?
Well, that's,
yes. Yes, that's an excellent point. And that's kind of where I was going with.
This is, it's not about
building insecurity necessarily.
It's about understanding where your risk is,
but it's about ensuring that the
correct organization carries the appropriate risk
because if we expect an end user and this is, again,
we'll tie this into the fishing conversation if
we expect an end user to have the knowledge
to avoid dealing with this stuff.
I, we fail every time. Right.
Well, it's, it's actually part of my, uh, security economics course.
They specifically talked about how in the UK financial system,
the banks were able to hand
the risk over to customers. So, guess what happened for online banking security.
Right.
Well,
if the customers got,
you know, whacked on
this until some laws were changed,
you know.
No, I agree.
I mean,
part of it is we want to create
an environment where bad behavior is dis incentivized,
which is a fancy economic term for, we're going to smack you
a two by four if you do it.
And that good behavior is incentivized,
which is again a fancy term for saying if you do the right thing,
we'll give you a hug and a cookie.
You know,
so, you know, like with my kids, for example, right?
I'm trying to teach them like, yeah, we can, you know,
we can spend money online but we have to do so carefully and we
have to make sure we actually want this and that it's like legitimate.
And I, for example, been trying to teach my kids that like,
and I've had some success with one of them that like,
advertising is theft of your time,
right?
And he actually seems to understand this a bit. But,
you know, I'm like, oh, this ad, it has
a, this app has ads in it. I'm like, it's stealing your time. He's like, what?
And I'm like, you're spending time getting rid of that ad.
That's time you can't spend playing the game.
-- He's like, oh, I'm like, yeah, it's bad. Huh?
-- I have a great story.
This is so my, my daughter has this game on her app.
This, this podcast episode is like the parenting extravaganza that's in it.
But, but my,
so my daughter has this app and,
and she kept setting the tablet down on the couch and going over and
getting a piece of candy
out of the candy dish. Like a very small piece. Right? And I'm like,
what's going on?
He's like, oh, they keep playing these videos as ads and I don't want to watch them.
So I just go eat candy. I'm like, that's awesome. That is so cool.
I just remember when youtube started introducing mandatory ads
and I showed my kids the skip ad button and they would
just sit there going ba
ba,
you know,
because it's like you have to watch five seconds
of the ad before it'll let you skip it.
And they would just sit there like smacking away
on that skip ad button until you know,
the five seconds elapsed.
And I was like, ok, you can just, just wait for the button to, you know, like sit down.
It's more fun
doing something.
Yeah. But uh yeah,
I am really curious because this whole, let's face it,
micro payments for content will never happen, right.
It's just too much hassle,
-- too much decision
-- making would never say never,
ok, fair enough.
Um But the advertising model is between the people like you and me who
you know,
will only ever surf the web with ad blocking enabled
and our Children as well and their friends and whatnot
and combined with the fact that, you know,
we're teaching them explicitly like that.
Yeah.
Like, advertising is stealing your life, like,
it's stealing minutes out of your life.
So, it's evil and sorry to all the advertisers out there.
I guess that means we can't have advertisers on the show. Hey,
uh, I think I'm comfortable saying that won't happen. But
-- if somebody came to us with a million bucks, we'd
-- take it.
I would do almost anything for a million dollars,
you know,
audience that you heard it here.
But, but ok, so, so here's the deal is I read a story the other day that was claiming
there's something like $7 billion in, in ad fraud
in
this was, this was a story about, I think it was on Krebs site about this.
Yeah,
-- that's right. That,
-- that it was $5 million usa
a day
because they were basically,
they built like this whole fake infrastructure to essentially load ads and,
and have just computer
pretending to be people
-- and they were
-- collected
-- load ads for the
-- right.
Here's the deal, right? Is you read this and they said something like $7 billion
in ad fraud a year.
You're talking, that's like 10% of the whole online ad industry.
Is there any other industry out
there?
It's that low
to be honest with the online ad
because I remember back in the,
remember those things where you got like paid to surf.
This is a long time ago folks.
So the concept was like, literally,
I think it was part of it was just pure old market research.
So they'd install like a browser plug in or something that would
like basically watch you web surf and the more so you surf,
the more you got paid and you could actually make like a few bucks
a day doing this.
So people would basically just set up like farms of
cheap P CS with scripts to like grind through websites
and make, you know, a couple 1000 bucks a month. Like it was insane. Like,
I remember places where we got paid per 1000 click and we got
-- paid upwards in some cases of like 20 or $30 for
-- 1000 clicks
worth
seven cents now.
Maybe
so. But here's the thing, right? So what happens?
Well, I got really good at getting my stuff on slash dot
Because you get 100,000 click throughs on
slash dot which means 100,000 impressions at
20 or 30 bucks per 1000 impressions. And it's like, I basically just,
I've justified my existence for the next three months
with one article,
you know,
like Clickbait, Clickbait has always been a thing, folks, let's face it, right?
Like it works, you know.
And I remember, yeah, this one thing on slash it was the death of open ssh and open SSL.
Right. And it got so much traffic and death threats and everything
and it literally basically paid my salary for four months.
That's awesome. Right.
And, you know, it was a decent article actually it wasn't total garbage.
Um, but the reality is like that, that kind of thing has always worked
and, you know, it's just, it's a matter of, well,
especially now that these clicks are worth less.
-- It's, it's escalating,
-- you know, I guess you're right is,
it's just that now the,
the bad guys have figured out how to start gaming the
system as opposed to the players in the game itself.
-- I
-- mean, well, you know, there's money there,
right. That's why, what was it, uh,
that famous us Bank Robber. They're like, why do you rob banks?
And he's like, well, because that's where the money is and it's like, oh,
-- good
-- answer.
Who knew?
-- So,
-- yeah. Yeah, I mean, it,
but I guess here's, here's, here's the deal is
when I think about things like the, the scare wear
and the ad fraud
and, and even just living with ads in general
is
there's clearly a
very human element that's being abused here
and
we don't have a way to stop it because like a
great example is your ad that looks like a youtube ad
that should
Google shouldn't let that happen.
And I'm sure when they find it they will pull it,
but you need some sort of automation to stop that from the beginning.
Right.
Well,
I just would have assumed that an ad displaying like
www.youtube.com but going somewhere else wouldn't have been allowed,
which is why I clicked on it.
Right. Otherwise I would have scrolled down to the actual,
was the ad,
-- is it a graphic or is it all?
-- It was a, it was a Google, um, text ad.
So, it was, wow. Yeah, they should,
they should catch.
It's weird.
I, well, or maybe, I don't know, it was weird. Right?
Because I, I was just so shocked because I clicked on
a,
you know, in my experience. Right? What little experience I have with ads,
the Google text based ads, the URL that you're shown is like where you end up going?
I thought
apparently I'm wrong.
I don't know.
I mean, I, I,
what's funny though is I've been seeing other Google spam and fishing like I got
a Google. Um
let's see if we can find it uh Google account.
So I got a thing for um ah here we go.
Hello as discussed.
Here's a link to your G Suite contract for those of you don't know,
Google apps has been renamed uh G suite Google Suite or whatever.
Please make sure to sign out of your current Gmail account and
sign back in with your admin credentials to accept the offer.
Click here to view your contract and accept your new offer view contract.
And it's weird because it actually goes to google.com. But here's the thing
they sent this to me on December 13th and they
said the contract will expire on December the 16th.
If you have any questions about this contract,
please email me at blank at google.com.
Now, II,
I was unable to believe that this was real because Google as
silly and crazy as they are emailed me on December 13th,
which is uh that was a um a uh Tuesday
saying essentially you have until Friday to accept this
new contract is kind of weird and insane,
but maybe it's legit as it turns out.
I don't know, but
-- it struck me as fake and I certainly didn't click the link.
-- Wow,
that's when you set up a VM man.
See what it is.
Yeah.
But um you know, like, uh that reminds me I need to send the,
the full email headers to somebody at Google who asked for them
um because I tweeted about this and you know, yeah, it's just like
here's my concern, right?
My bank TD, Canada Trust I'm naming you guys because I'm not happy with you guys.
They,
they phoned me one time and they were like, hi, is this Kurt Seaford?
And I'm like, yeah, and they're like, this is blah, blah from TD and I'm like, really?
He's like, yeah, I'm like,
how do I verify that? And he's like, what? And I'm like, how do I verify it from TD?
And he's like,
he's like, well,
I'm gonna ask you some security questions to verify you and I'm like,
that's not how this works.
Yeah, I've,
I've done the same thing to my bank and they
clearly are not used to that happening to them.
So, like TD Canada Trust again, naming and shaming phones customers and says, hi.
Is this Curtsey Fried? Yeah, we'd like to verify your
granny. What's your date of birth? What's your postal code?
What's like blah, blah, blah,
right?
Not something like what was really interesting with my corporate um credit card?
I was buying some stuff on Expedia.
The first one went through, the second one got blocked
and then I got a phone call from them and they were like to verify your identity.
We wanna ask you what um the last transaction on your card was like for how much,
which you know, is a little less scary, right?
It's not a personal information, but TD Canada trust naming you guys
asked me for like my date of birth, my postal code and um
uh what was it my address or whatever?
And I'm like, no, like I'm not having this because this is like, no,
you know, and, and yeah, I mean
the my concern is that we have these companies that
do things that are training people to get ripped off.
I don't think it's
like this,
if this Google thing is legit
you know, it's like as discussed, here's a tight time frame.
You have to act now, you have to click this link,
you have to put in your administrative credentials.
-- Like what
-- now? But, but why would people, why would they not trust
organization to give them solid advice
-- on
-- that? Actually is an actual Google email. It's
for real.
-- It's accounts.google.com. That's
-- horrifying.
So they're bad.
This email is legit and they're like training their
people to be like here's a time sensitive thing.
-- Click on this link and enter your password. Here's the
-- deal, right is. So
there's a bunch of layers here
at the top.
There's Google
that has groups internally that know better that were clearly not consulted,
right?
Oh, there's actually a reply to the email saying hi Kurt.
I, because I replied, I said phishing email supposedly from Google,
your account is being impersonated.
I I replied to abuse and the supposed google.com account came from
and I didn't see this because I like marked the thread like go away
and it says hi Kurt, thanks for your reply and sorry for causing you any concerns.
You can always call us to confirm this email at our support
line and we will be happy to provide you more details.
Uh Trick question,
-- what's the Google support line?
-- I hope they included it in the email to you.
No, of course not.
-- They didn't.
-- Thankfully.
That's
good.
Yeah.
Well, it's like every time somebody shows up behind the door and they're like, hi,
I'm from Energy Company
X and I'm like, really? And they're like, yeah, look at my ID and I'm like,
-- yeah.
-- Right. Of
course, you are.
Ok. Right. But, so here's my point though. Right. Here's my point is
you have
organizations
that don't always have the right people helping them make smart decisions.
And why would a normal person know
that doing? This is a bad idea and let's face it.
This is someone at Google with good intentions that is trying to do the right thing.
Well, whatever, we won't
argue,
we won't argue the philosophical
intentions. We'll just say they have intentions. OK? We, we'll leave in there,
but here's the deal, right? So
when, when you're a user of Google, they're an organization that you trust
and
I,
in a way you look up to them, we'll say, right?
Because they're providing you something of value and important. Right. Exactly.
Exactly.
And now it's human nature to trust organizations and
even people to a degree that we kind of
-- my kids think Santa Claus is real because apparently we said
-- so.
Exactly. As a parent, this is very, very parent child, right?
And, and that's kind of the relationship. There is
people trust Google because they see Google as a giant
amazing
entity
that has their best interest in mind. And we won't talk about that either today. OK?
We'll just say
that's what people think.
OK,
and So you've got that angle and I mean, this is even true of,
of banks and department stores and,
and whatever grocery stores pick an organization
and people think like this, it's just being a person.
But then the bad guys, they know this too
and they take advantage of it. And the problem is
this has been happening like throughout human history
and it isn't going to go away. This is the way people are
and the bad guys are always going to find a way
to use one organization's good name
to fraud another person.
It is just unfortunately,
it, it is the way of the world.
Well, I remember like reading about fraud back in the day when you know,
this is before computers and laser printers and everything
and like just possessing the letterhead of an organization like so stationary with
Bob's mining company established 19 whatever
with, you know, this address and phone number on it, typing something out on that.
Like, you know, uh
this is Bob in accounting,
give the bearer of this letter like $500 would be like enough to get $500 or whatever,
you know, it was insane.
It's
crazy, but I mean, it hasn't changed, right?
We, we have that whole spearfishing of CEO S and C level executives for, you know,
bank uh transfer fraud where
it's like please pay this invoice of like
$200,000. Thank you or you know, hey, this is supplier X.
Our banking details have changed,
you know. So in future, please pay us here
and apparently companies do this, you know, like it's with minimal
oversight. It's,
it's bonkers,
it's people, man, it's not bonkers. This is how people work and this is where
I guess
you don't
because the same people, if you said like this cup of coffee is $7 they'd be like, no,
-- absolutely not.
-- I bet if you slapped a Google logo on that sucker,
they'd pay it.
And I'm, I'm only half kidding.
But
actually, no, you're right. Like Starbucks does sell $7.
Isn't that like Apple's entire business model?
Anyway. Anyway, let's bring it all back though.
Is we come back to what you talked about with, with the Uber, I guess, anti
fishing
spam, whatever the heck, email server thing they have, right.
And
that's really what it's about is it's the job of
the security people to understand what the bad guys are doing
and to make their lives very, very difficult.
And if you look at
like, literally everything that happens in the financial universe today
in the way that normal people handle transactions.
It has been designed to make fraud difficult. I won't say impossible,
but it's difficult.
Well,
what's always funny to me is you hear about
these places that suffer fraud and it's like they,
they violated very basic standards, like, um, and we'll look it up in the show notes,
but
I don't know if you remember about a decade or two ago,
there was that large bank that cratered out because the, um
there was a trader who was trading and I believe it was copper derivatives
and the oversight was being provided by his wife.
That's totally legit, right.
It was, it was a British bank.
It is up to the security people and, and really, it's up to everybody,
but I'm gonna pick on security folks just because I can
on this podcast is we come back to the point that,
that
I, I'm, I'm feeling like the internet
and electronics and everything we interact with today is
still too new and we don't totally understand.
And so
the problem we have is we don't fully understand the problems,
which means we can't really work on the solutions yet.
And so
it's, it's so hard and I feel like as security people,
we love to try to solve problems that aren't real or don't exist
yet and we ignore real problems that are causing real issues today.
Uh You know, I just ran into this. I had to pay somebody a large amount of money.
So I was like, oh, you know, I'm gonna use in track uh
e transfer.
So a debit essentially over email hit a daily limit
and so it took three days to pay this person
because I had to break the transaction up into three transactions of
small enough amounts so that I could send this person the money,
you know.
Um, and I'm, I'm kind of glad that in a sense of so I, I, I'm assuming the idea is
we limit your transaction amount and actually then step it down the next day by half.
Um, so somebody tries to clean out your account,
it's gonna take them a few days and maybe hopefully notice,
but I legitimately had to pay this person
on time.
It's a lawyer, you know, you got to pay your lawyer, you know,
and it was really annoying but the funny thing is he's like, oh yeah, yeah, yeah,
we I forgot to mention that to you, right?
Because he, you know, he of course runs into this all the time, you know,
because the transaction limit by default is so low,
it's like 1000 bucks which like if you've ever dealt with a lawyer,
1000 bucks doesn't go very
far,
right?
Uh ok, so, so here's the deal though is there are ways to get that man, his money,
you just didn't use them. I mean, I just,
I, I in
a
paper bag full of twenties.
-- No, no,
-- no, there are, you can do wire transfers and there's
various,
he's a freaking
lawyer,
doesn't he have
a,
he gives me his wire transfer details.
In theory I could do a demand debit and clean out his account.
If you give me a blank check for your account,
I can do a demand debit
from your account and clean it out.
You can, but he's your freaking lawyer, dude, he's going to sue you.
Like, don't do that to your lawyer,
obviously. Yeah. No, don't mess with your accountant or
-- lawyer.
-- And so you can even,
there are ways around this though.
Is there are clearing houses whose job is to be the middle man?
My accountant flat out. It was funny because he sent me an invoice
and I'm like, what? There's like a link to square. What the heck I phoned him.
He's like, yeah, we're accountants. We're not like we don't do
invoicing and pain.
Why we
just
pass our money.
You know, he's like, and I know half of you don't have checks anymore.
So we're using square, it's like 3% but we don't have to chase you. I'm like, awesome.
Thank you.
Seriously. It's, it's phenomenal.
The annoyance is I can't pay my taxes with a credit card
that's
on purpose, I'm sure.
But then it's Visa's problem and not the tax people's problem.
Right.
Anyway.
But, but, so here's the deal at the end of the day, right?
Is, is we keep laughing about all this stuff.
We keep making up these silly jokes and reasons and whatnot. But,
I mean, fundamentally
the financial sector I think has solved a lot of these problems and they get
what their threats are.
Right. You don't understand our threats today to the degree we need to.
Well, one thing I haven't seen is actual, what's the cost of these things? You know,
uh, in some cases, we have a very clear cost, like they paid a
million dollars in false invoices, you know, obviously that's a problem but
here's what I'm seeing, like,
especially with the leaks of personally identifiable information.
What's the problem there? Like, how does this actually end up costing money? I mean,
obviously
the people whose information gets leaked,
they have to eat costs and deal with hassles and whatever.
But the
-- like lost it all,
-- do they? I mean, I'm not gonna, I'm not gonna argue about it today
but like in, in all seriousness,
even if someone steals your pi i
it's not
a huge deal.
Why do you think people are buying that
medical information there and especially in America,
they're buying it
-- so they can use it to get medical treatment?
-- Sure.
-- But does that
-- skip out on the bill
damage me? Really? I mean, that's the,
-- when you get a bill for $20,000
-- then I don't pay it because it's not me.
Right. It creates some issues for me, but
it is and that's probably a discussion for another day. But I mean,
I think this is part of our issue is we don't have a way
to put value on this information or the problems. And so we struggle to say
yes, this is an issue or no, it's not.
I mean, as security people, we've always defaulted to. Holy crap.
Biggest problem in the world, which is never true.
Well, here's my real concern is even if we put value on that information,
we're still able to externalize the cost. So, it's not my problem and
that.
Right.
It shouldn't be my problem as a consumer.
It should be.
I mean, as the person who dropped the ball and made the security mistake,
it's not their problem and
-- that's where things fall down. Yes,
-- I agree with that.
And that's a topic for another day, I think.
But you're, you're dead on.
It's, oh, man, everything is a mess.
Like,
well, you know, the good news is, I mean, we're seeing more regulation,
try with good intentions. Now, I don't know if it's gonna work or not,
but let me add that.
Yeah. Well, you know, I, I'm a realist, not a hopeful person
and I am hopeful in that we're hopefully, you know, I,
I do see people becoming generally more aware and I don't know if it's because
they're becoming more aware or it's because the pool of suckers has been like,
sucked dry.
Oh, dude, there, the pool of suckers will never run dry.
Well, I mean, for simple, you know, scams, like I, I would like to think that like, um,
you know, I,
I have $50 million I'm trying to move out of the
country and I was given your email address by a friend.
-- Don't ask any questions.
-- Just help me out. No, man, those are never going to end
-- well. True.
-- But I would like to think that it's,
-- they've depleted the
-- pool. No way.
No way.
You know, they have it.
I
-- had hope, please let me have
-- my hope.
Hope,
hope is dead.
Well, it was funny. Right.
Because you would have thought like the, the,
the younger people are more digitally aware and apparently they've done
some studies with like fishing and fake news and stuff like that
where everybody's just as terrible as everybody else
or
whatever,
the person,
we will never patch the person.
Yeah. Unfortunately, I'm calling it Kirk.
There's, this is, this is like the most depressing conversation we've ever.
-- The reality
-- is like some, just some simple stuff.
Like if it looks too good to be true, it probably is.
Or in the case of this Google thing,
like this is so weird because it's like you have three days to like,
accept a new contract and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
But I'm pretty sure if I don't,
they'll just keep billing me and keep giving me service,
-- you know, they will
-- like, yeah, I mean, yeah, I'm well, please Google,
don't cut me off.
I need my email. Thanks.
Please Google, don't cut me off.
All right. So thanks for listening. Everybody.
If you want the show notes, you can go to open source security,
podcast.com and all of the interesting news stories and various
other bits and pieces we've discussed will be linked there.
You can hit us up on Twitter with the Pound
Os S podcast. Hashtag
That's an easy way to get a hold of Kurt and myself and discuss the,
the issues of the day.
And if nothing else, thank you everyone for listening, we certainly appreciate it.
And until next time, take care.
Thanks, folks.