Hello.
And welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 114 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime Josh Pressers.
-- So,
-- we're gonna review a book today. Have we reviewed a book before?
I don't remember.
I don't know that I've ever read a book before
anyway.
No, honestly, well, in the context of computer security,
I haven't bothered to read any of the books
in ages because they, well, has there been any good ones?
Uh, there was, uh, there will be cybercrime, I think it's called
or will, there will be Cyber War or it's Mark Goodman's book?
It's actually pretty good. I read that one some time ago. I, I've read a handful.
I need to actually look back at my,
-- I've
-- looked at most of them
and the synopsis,
synopsis. I don't know the plural, uh, of those and, and just not been terribly
impressed and more to the point.
So, what, like, what's the actionable advice?
Uh, they never like
advice. Exactly.
Um,
you know, and, and I can totally see reading them for relaxation and fun, but, like,
this is my daily life.
So it's not really fun.
It's all I know.
I, I'm pretty much Stockholm Syndrome for the security industry.
So, anyway, we want to talk about Schneier's new book,
which is titled Click Here To Kill Everybody.
And then the subtitle is Security and Survival in a hyper connected world.
And it just came out not long ago.
So it, it's kind of exciting to read it quickly and then,
and then have a quick chat about it.
Well, in fairness, it's not a big book. It's 200 pages
with 100 pages of references.
Yeah, 244 I think is what it came, came at
on my Ereader. So, so let's do this.
What are your like, like, what's your two minute thoughts
-- on this book?
-- My, well, my, my 32nd thought on this book is quite simply that
we've attached everything to computers
and all of those computers are on the internet
and
all of those computers are not very secure.
So we've gone from a situation where, you know, if you wanna go mess around, say,
uh, well, let's say you want to turn the gas off at a power plant.
Well, it used to be that you had to like, slop down there and turn a valve physically,
you know, and, well, that, that's expensive, right?
Why not attach a motor to that valve and, you know,
let somebody remotely press a button.
Cool. That's, that's
nice.
Well, why not have that button pushing attached to a computer so,
you know, some central control room can do it.
That's a long 30 seconds.
Yeah.
But basically, I mean, that's the premise of the book is we've done all this stuff.
We've connected all this crap up. And, uh,
well, security is like today, you know, I was driving my kids to school and
somebody is, you know,
holding their phone up in front of their face while they're driving,
we make things safe only because we have to. Right. We don't do safety first.
Yes. And, and that's kind of touched on here as well.
There's, I mean, I mean, so the beginning of the book is
kind of you are here
where,
and there's nothing,
I don't think there's anything that, that's super new
if you're paying attention in this,
in, in the beginning part.
-- Well,
-- I think part of it is just how it's, it, it,
it's one of those things that's crept up like everybody has a cell phone now.
So, for example, I just bought some Amazon Dots because
I give up like I, I carry a device that can record me 24 7 anyways.
So I'm just gonna scatter some more of them around my house and at least I'll be able to
tell it to add stuff to my grocery list without
having to haul my phone out of my pocket.
Sure. Sure.
The degree of computer control is
somewhat new and, and especially around, you know,
well, it's not new. If you've been paying
cars
and, and hang on, let's, let's,
we're getting way in the weeds too fast. Let's, let's cover the book.
The beginning talks about kind of where we are today.
And if you've been paying attention,
you aren't going to necessarily learn anything new.
However, I will say Schneier
has a very nice writing style. That's easy to read and easy to understand his, his,
his superpower other than growing an awesome beard
is explaining things in a way. Most anyone could understand.
I could give this book to my parents.
Well, you can explain to normal people
exactly.
Like I would feel comfortable giving this book
-- to my parents
-- and even to politicians.
That's, that's the key right? Is
I feel like this book,
-- every policymaker needs to read this book,
-- there's like 100 and 50 books,
every policymaker needs to read.
And that's,
you know, that's part of the problem where we are, right?
Is the world is just so hideously complicated.
My guess is we're lucky if most of them read the comics
on Sunday.
-- Uh
-- I'd be, I would, I would say we'd be lucky if they read it all anyway.
And then kind of the second half of this book talks about some
of the what are some possible solutions to all of these horrendous problems?
And fundamentally,
I think what it comes down to is Schneier
says
we have to regulate
-- everything. Well,
-- all the economic incentives are against being secure.
They totally are.
And he's actually quite clear and honest about that,
which makes me really happy because I think people always pretend,
oh, if you're not secure
then you're going to lose money. And the reality is no, you're not.
I'll stop using Equifax. Oh, wait, I can't opt out of Equifax.
Right.
And in fact, he, even,
he Equifax comes up in the book of the fact that there were all these
hearings on it and the only law that was passed about Equifax was one that,
that makes it so you can't sue them.
Like what,
-- what just happened?
-- Well, they have good lobbyists and regulatory
count. Exactly.
Exactly. Now, now I have one serious complaint
about this book that we should get out of the way immediately
and I'm going, this is a huge spoiler.
So if you haven't read it and you want to, and you want me to write the book for you,
you should stop,
stop listening right now.
He only uses the word Blockchain once
in the whole book on page 233 I think it is. So, it's almost to the end.
So, what's your specific complaint that he only used it once? That's all.
No, I'm just being an idiot.
I would sort of agree in the sense of I,
I feel like Blockchain is going to be one of those just
underlying technologies that we'll all take for granted in 5 to 10 years
and obviously I'm biased because my job title is Chief Blockchain Officer.
But, you know, I feel like it's like the web, right?
I feel like Blockchain is where the web was in 95. And that, yeah, we,
we, we, we can talk about Blockchain some other day actually, in all seriousness.
I'm, I'm pleased by how UN
this book is
where he could have like, tore it off all about hackers and Blockchain and A I and,
and big data and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
It doesn't matter what technology we do because
the economic incentives remain the same and,
-- and
-- right, and I, I think that's, that's what I like about this.
Right? It's not
like Equifax is going to move to a Blockchain
and somehow be incentivized to protect our data.
They literally got a law passed so that they don't have to. It's just that simple.
-- Like I, I don't know how else to say it.
-- It is. It is, it's
all in all,
I guess my, my kind of
what my suggestion here is,
it, it is worth reading if you haven't been paying a lot of attention,
even if you haven't.
I think it's worth reading just as a way to better understand
how to talk about some of these things to normal people.
And I think most importantly is,
uh we should all buy a copy of this and mail it to our senators and,
and hope somebody who works for them,
reads the freaking book because I think it could do them a lot of good.
Now, now,
II, I must say though,
and here's the thing I realized while reading all about this because,
because Bruce spends a lot of time talking about regulation
and kind of how regulation works and what's going on.
And, and the thing I think I'm, I'm starting to disagree with is he,
he keeps talking about having like,
one central regulating body for all of computer security.
And, and I don't think I agree with that anymore. II, I did.
I used to but I feel like we've reached a point where, for example, like,
let the FAA regulate computer security of airplanes,
let the Department of Transportation regulate the security
of automobiles. Right? Like, why should we have one central authority?
-- What about the
-- things across boundaries, like drones?
Well, in, in what do we do about things like that today?
Are drones an FAA problem or a privacy problem? Like, are they a local
problem with respect to privacy or are they an FAA problem?
Because we've actually had cases now in Canada and
the US where, you know, drones have been up of up,
there was a drone apparently reported here at about
four or 5000 ft in the air that almost,
you know, the west jet plane had to, like,
yeah, they, they saw a drone at like four or 5000 ft up in the air.
And so the uh the National Transport Safety Board is, um, is investigating, I mean,
but good luck with that.
Well, and there's always going to be some level of overlap. Right?
There's all of these regulating bodies always like the FDA, for example, I'm,
I'm sure is involved with the EPA on certain things.
-- I
-- would
-- hope so.
And, and I was going to say, I think, I,
I don't know that we necessarily need one
central regulatory body for all things computer,
but we do need a high degree of cooper operation,
you know, because like,
you know, I have experience of this within the CV board,
we're trying to federate and make hierarchies to control, you know,
like for example,
ideally medical devices, you know, cars, aerospace, open source,
but these things all overlap
oftentimes quite a lot
and the and the concerns overlap, for example, self driving car,
there's clear safety concerns, right?
If somebody can remotely hijack that self driving
car and drive into a crowd of people,
that's, that's a law and order, you know,
that's a terrorism related thing potentially
and not just public safety anymore.
But then there's also on the sort of softer side, there's like, well,
the self driving car has a bunch of sensors and cameras.
What about the privacy of that data? Right?
Does it drive down the street recording your face
and uploading that to Google?
Is that allowed, is that blocked?
-- So
-- today privacy isn't regulated in the United States very well.
It's not regulated very well anywhere and we've just gone through GDPR.
-- I think
-- GDPR might have potential.
And, and this is something that, that one of the chapters, I think chapter 1010,
9 or 10
talks about GDPR a bit in this book
and
it, it's still too early, I think to, to answer a lot of questions.
But I feel like if, if you look at something like GDPR,
GDPR is an overarching piece of legislation
that affects
everybody,
-- all all industries, all businesses,
-- right? Anybody interacting with Europe,
either in Europe or from outside of Europe.
-- And
-- I feel like in there are certain things
like like privacy is an easy one to pick on
where you can say this just this affects everybody,
right?
Because this is really about the people.
But then if we start talking about something like securing automobiles,
now we're getting fairly specific and, and the thing I keep thinking of is
the problems that you're going to have,
securing computers in cars are different than
the problems you're going to have securing
light bulbs
and that's different than securing my phone
and, and there is some overlap,
but I think the fundamentals are going to be different enough,
trying to lump them together is going to make us fail.
I'm going to disagree a bit
for two reasons. Number one on the technology side,
most of these things are running the same software they're pretty much the
whole IOT at this point is running Linux with some busy box.
So from a technology perspective, they're,
they're a lot more similar than they are different, right?
You have this thing, it has a Linux kernel, it
has a bunch of IO devices that it controls and takes data from.
And it also typically is attached to the internet so it can
at a minimum,
send data and also accept commands like turn the light switch on and off.
And then for more of a sort of a, I guess a procedural or like a process point of view,
these things are essentially as much as we like to pretend they're not,
they are a general purpose computer running a specific app,
like all those ATM S running Windows 95 or XP.
And they just happen to be running an ATM app and be hooked up to a, you know,
a little cash dispenser machine thing
inside the machine that, you know, will spit out $20 bills if you have it,
-- send the right IO commands
-- it.
It, it is true.
And, and so here's, here's what I'm,
I'm fighting with myself with my brain right now and
I haven't landed necessarily on one side or the other,
but I'm, I'm still leaning towards
uh not being too general.
But like
if, if you look at say engines, right? Gasoline engines,
you can find them in everything from small RC
cars to lawn mowers to automobiles to even,
well, we won't say gasoline because we could, let's lump in, you know, locomotives,
right?
-- Like locomotives have diesel engines,
-- let's say hydrocarbons. Sure.
And even airplanes in that respect could, could fall under that if we, if we wanted to
and
we don't have like
AAA Hydrocarbon Engine administration or something. Right.
We, we basically say airplanes, you figure it out, train people,
you figure your problems out car people,
you figure your problems out lawnmower guys, we don't care, whatever,
partly agree with you in the sense of there's,
there's some vastly different failure scenarios.
Um So for example,
between a light bulb and a self driving car, right?
A self driving car can clearly and simply be used to run over people.
That that's a problem, right? Because,
well, let's face it.
People already do that with their own driving cars because they suck at driving
or, you know, they're bad people conversely with a light bulb,
I can definitely create a
not totally unreasonable corner case where not having
it work could potentially be life threatening,
but it's a corner, you know, you got to work at it, right?
It's not like a self driving car where to
create a scenario where it kills somebody who's like,
yeah, no, that's like that's a normal thing today, right?
Cars do that
and, and so I think there's a bit of a difference there.
Well, a great example being there's that lovely video of, um,
this ferry that like lost propulsion as they were pulling in
and, you know, it slams into this concrete quay,
you know.
You know, well,
you lost power so you can't throw it into reverse
so you can't stop because it's not like ships have,
you know, brakes while they do have a brake.
It's called, put the engine into a verse,
you know, but it's, it's an active thing.
It's not like a passive thing, you know, like in a car for the brakes to fail,
you got to work at it,
like you have to work at it and, and in trucks,
they're designed so that if they do fail, they,
they go on same in trains, right?
Because we were, you know, large, heavy objects
moving with no brakes or it's bad,
it's just bad that, that's what I hear.
For example, a scenario where, ok, well, I can turn the engine off.
Well, like in a car.
Yeah.
You know, you do that to somebody on the highway that's, uh,
you could really cause some problems but you do that to
like an oil tanker coming into an oil processing facility and,
you know, uh I hope they have enough tugboats to
it, right. So
what I'm saying is, there's, there's
sort of the ease of creating a failure scenario that is like really,
really expensive and impacts quality of life and, or, you know,
kills a pile of people.
There's a big difference between your IOT light bulb
and your IOT car and your IOT super tanker.
Right. Exactly. But at the same time, like I said, fundamentally,
the Dirty Secret is they're all running the same software by and large.
It's just sort of, the application running on top is a little bit,
you know, bespoken, custom tailored and,
and that's kind of on the one hand why I think,
you know,
when I read these things like carrier grade
Linux and automotive grade Linux and I'm like,
well, fundamentally what they want is they want Magic Linux that just doesn't fail,
you know, like they need their five nines of reliability because, you know,
they need the phones to work for 911 or they need the car to work because you're,
you're on the highway doing 100 miles an hour.
Right. Right.
And, and ok, so I'm going to tie this conversation kind of back into the, we, we, we,
we're approaching book territory again
and,
oh,
yeah, book review. Right.
Right. We're, we're talking about a book. That's right. Well done.
Uh, so one of, one of the things
that that's talked about in chapter nine is, is, you know,
finding and fixing vulnerabilities.
And I feel like this is kind of related is
you are correct that all of the software is basically the same at this point.
-- Well, open
-- source one man,
it totally did.
And that's great
because now we only have one thing to fix thankfully by and large, like we have a linen
and not 17 different things
-- and,
-- but I guess here's, here's the way I keep thinking about this is
you can lump, say,
fixing vulnerabilities and let's say open SSL all together
and say we should care about open SSL,
you know, and we should,
but I, I feel like
that's, that's like caring about the supply chain. Right.
-- It very much is. Yes. it's like steel quality. Right.
-- Exactly. Exactly. That
you want to make sure you're getting what was advertised because otherwise that,
that's exactly what I was going to talk about is the fact that, like,
let's say the government is ordering military vehicles,
they're going to say the steel has to look like this
and then it's really up to the suppliers to figure that out.
Right.
You're not, we don't have, like the national steel board saying, well,
there might be,
but, you know, saying all steel must be of this quality.
It's like, no, there's, there's different levels.
-- Well, there's, there's standards, there's different standards.
-- Right. Right.
And, and, and much like steel, there's different,
there's people that want software that,
you know, moves fast breaks things and,
and that's cool because they're a service provider
and then there's, there's vendors like,
we're guaranteeing that this will work for 13 years with API and A B I Compatibility.
So you can build an accounting system that sits on top of this
and
we promise it won't break for 13 years and if it does break,
you can yell at us and we'll fix it and, and those are both valid use cases.
Right. Right. E exactly.
You know, some people need brittle steel and some people need very ductile steel.
-- Right.
Exactly. And I, and I feel like this book is trying to,
it's trying to put everything in the same bucket.
Well, I think from a procedural point of view, it kind of does because we, you know,
as much as we'd like things to be different fundamentally,
we from a minimum perspective, all this iot stuff,
we really want it to work otherwise.
Well,
-- that's a cost if it stops working and either it gets bricked or denial of service
-- and,
and ok, but here's,
here's what, what I think makes it all different is insecurity.
We have historically had the attitude of perfect or nothing
and, and perfect just means it's a fancy word for nothing.
So nothing wins and we basically fix nothing.
And we say, oh, if we can't do that exactly correct,
we just shouldn't do it or we end up
blocking projects because we can't get them completely correct.
And I feel like trying to put all of this stuff
together in the same bucket is saying perfect or nothing,
right? We already have nothing like,
and, and this is where I feel like if we say automakers go figure this freaking out
in and some of them might fix some of the open source,
some of them might write their own stuff.
Some of them might go completely off reservation and do something crazy. Who knows?
Well, here's a thought.
Maybe we should, for example, have a regulation saying that you have to do
attack modeling of your product
-- and release that
-- publicly. Are they doing that in meds?
No.
Oh Lord. No,
no dude, there's no problems in meds.
And if you say otherwise, what do you
uh No, I feel like the meds
people are actually starting to move in the right direction.
-- Yeah,
-- some of them are coming around but it's going to be wild. But
for example, let's hypothetically say
you have to release as part of your like ul Well, so we have the idea of, you know,
underwriters laboratory and like the uh the CS A,
the Canadian Standards Association, not the CS A I work for.
Um
you know, we're basically like, for example, they, they,
they audit things and check things to, you know, for example,
if you plug this into your house, they ain't gonna burn your house down,
which is a nice quality to have an electrical equipment.
But for example, let's say you need to attack or threat model your device. And
a great example being remember the nest thermostats that require internet access
to like make your house hot and I think they change that.
I'm not sure, but
I will never buy a nest thermostat unless I know
for guaranteed 100% certain that if my internet goes out,
I still get to have heat in winter.
Right, because I live in Canada. So that's, that's a bit of a concern.
And so, for example, having a, having that threat model would at a minimum,
let me make a slightly better decision as to, you know.
Ok. So what happens when this device loses internet access? Can it,
does it still have basic functionality,
you know, or does it completely crap itself and stop working?
Uh And that's actually, that's something that, that's in this book as well,
is a refrigerator, right?
If your refrigerator loses internet access,
like it shouldn't spoil your food and that
one's really easy to understand or the thermostat
if internet goes out, don't let the house freeze and also don't make it, you know,
a billion degrees inside that would kill people.
Like
a example is I'm pretty sure my Amazon Echo is useless without internet
because doesn't it send all the voice commands back to Amazon for processing?
I'm pretty sure it does. I think it has hardware in it to listen for. What is it?
Hey, Alexa
or whatever,
but beyond that
it doesn't do.
So if I don't have light switches and I'm depending
on that thing to turn my lights on and off
could be a problem.
-- If you don't have light switches, you totally deserve what you're going to get,
-- uh,
I'm a paraplegic in a wheelchair.
That's fair. Ok. So, no, I don't have light switches and I have this Amazon Alexa
with this IOT lighting system that now lets me control my house.
That is cool.
You know,
and that's something we often forget about is
there's a lot of people legitimately in this world that have, you know,
very different abilities than we do.
Like,
um, you know,
one of my sons is high functioning autistic and I have no idea
how I'm going to teach him about password security because it just,
he doesn't care.
He just flat out like
he just, I don't think he knows what a secret is.
It's just
not, no, like straight up, it's, it's in a way, it's beautiful, but at the same time,
like,
I, I worry about people taking advantage of him, you know,
because he just doesn't kind of get
privacy or secrecy to the world and his brain is an open book, you know,
that, that's fair.
You know, as I get older, I like the idea of being able to tell my house or better yet.
I don't want to have to tell my house.
I want my house to sort of vaguely know where I am and turn the damn lights on.
So I don't fall down the stairs.
I, you know, I think that's a reasonable thing to
now we have a threat model while just walking down the stairs. Turn the lights off.
Now, now,
now we accidentally murdered Kurt over the internet.
Right. Generally murder doesn't imply accidentally that would be manslaughter.
But yeah,
but no, I mean, that's, that's an example of where, you know,
for a normal bodied person.
Yeah, whatever deal with it, turn the lights off and on,
but not everybody can do those things and not everybody's given that choice.
What if you're renting? And that's just how that place is. You know,
that's true.
I'm using Airbnb more now
because quite often it's a lot cheaper than a hotel.
And it's more interesting, you know, we stayed in this new
condo. It's a, it was a round condo kind of built on stilts next to a freeway.
So that way you didn't have to like, stare at the side of the freeway,
but you actually had a view
and it was like each condo apartment, whatever was kind of like a large slice of pie.
Very cool design.
And, you know,
it had an internet connected door lock thing because
that way they can just send you the code
and you go into your airbnb now. Am I a fan of that? No, God, no.
But you know,
like every hotel I've ever stayed at that door lock is centrally managed by the hotel
and they can create cards to access it for anybody housekeeping, who knows?
And that's just the way the world is.
You know,
I can no longer rely on these door locks being
-- secure in the sense of like I trust that's
-- fair.
So I, I guess there,
there's one other important point in the book that I want
to mention and I want us to discuss a bit is
uh uh there is a chapter about when policy can go wrong.
And a lot of it is dedicated to the encryption backdoor debate.
And of course, the book takes a very hardline stance.
-- Oh God.
-- And we're going through that
again, it never, it'll never end.
Uh So the book takes a really nice stance of this is a bad idea and it can't be done.
And I do appreciate that Bruce doesn't try to be like,
maybe this isn't something that we could do.
But, and to be clear when we say it can't be done,
we mean it physically can't be done without
completely compromising the security of all the encryption,
right?
That's
so we're not saying it can't be done like, oh, you know, like
racism is bad. We shouldn't do racism.
No, we're saying like,
physically you can't do this without completely compromising
this version of reality and how encryption works.
-- Like it's just
-- physics and stuff.
Yeah. Math, I
guess
-- that Pesky, math physics
-- is math.
You know, maybe we should just legislate math to be different. I don't know.
Yeah. And, and,
and a lot of,
but the problem is a lot of lawmakers, you know, don't
seem to know or care about that.
And, uh, well, and this, you know, a lot of things like environmental law and stuff.
I've seen some environmental law where it's kind of like, but
that's not how rivers work. You know,
water flows downhill. Yeah.
Or like things where they've legislated and, uh, yeah, whoops,
we kind of screwed that up.
Well, and I guess this is where I want to end it and is
kind of, you kind of hit on it about legislation is
there's two ways legislation happens.
You have lobbyists and companies
that write it,
give it to the legislatures and say pass this bill
and half the time these guys probably don't even
know what's in it because these things are phone books
or
there's some sort of public outcry because something is happening and,
and the example I'll use there is like OSHA, the, the worker safety in factories.
Right?
Well, worker safety everywhere where people work, I mean,
and put links to Reddit OSHA because that, that's a gong show.
Oh, man, that
-- is crazy.
-- It makes me
so grateful to work indoors.
Right. Seriously.
But anyway,
the point is that's an example where
actually the lobbyists didn't want these changes.
And there was, there were enough humans who said, like this is nuts,
we need to fix this.
And, and I guess this is the problem with,
with computer security
is
until something horrible happens to make people care.
And I don't mean horrible, like your bank account got stolen.
It's gonna have to be endemic.
-- I mean,
-- like, like,
like a building fell down or a bunch of people were killed sort of thing here.
-- Right. Or
-- like
-- a dying from self driving cars. Right.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
It's going to have to be crazy
to make people care and let's face it. The companies behind this stuff,
they don't want to fix this, they don't have any incentive,
they want to keep it the same.
So they aren't going to write anything to get this done.
And so fundamentally,
the only way we're going to see this change coming through government regulation
is when the people get mad enough to say fix it now.
And I think we are a long way from that happening.
So I on the radio this morning, there was an ad for
like before you dig uh call us to locate the underground power lines. Please.
You know, this is a message from the Alberta. Uh what was it?
The Alberta Electrical Transmission Council. And it's,
yeah, like just we don't care, we do it for free,
but just for the love of God before you start putting holes in the ground,
like let us come out and make sure there's no big power lines there because
it happens, right?
We, we had an outage uh like two weeks ago where yeah,
somebody was digging and hit a high,
a high voltage power line, you know, downtown
because well, yeah,
that's what happens when you just start randomly digging holes.
So, you know, simple stuff like that where it's,
we have a solution and a framework to deal with it and people still mess it up.
So, yeah, I know you're right until things get like literally,
I'm not sure even 100 people a day being killed by self driving cars would be enough
because I think that's about the death rate from regular cars in the US right now.
Higher than that even.
I feel like I looked this up and it was, it was scary how many it was.
Oh, actually, uh, ok. So in 2010, in the US, 5.4 million
collisions crashes,
30,000, 296 of them with fatalities killing 32,999 people.
So, yeah, just that's about what, 9085 a day,
about 100 a day. That's
and injuring 2.2 million.
That's a,
that's when, and, and, you know, and you know, we're not talking to stub toe
in a lot of cases, you know, we're talking some pretty serious injuries
and that's not enough to make people care.
And I think that's the standard,
you have to realize basically what whatever is going on is going to
have to kill more than 100 people a day before people care.
Something like over
a,
I think it's a half now in Canada of all
car collisions now or because people are on their phone.
I, I have no doubt.
And it was probably something else before that.
Right. It's,
anyway, I guess
I, I'm, I'm happy to close with this. It, it's a good book.
I, I would suggest anyone could gain value from reading it
and I would highly suggest if you are a manager
type who maybe doesn't follow the news as closely as,
as you could
read this book because I think you gain value of it
and we should all buy a copy for our senators.
And yeah, when you're done with it, I give it to your parents.
They, they'll like it too. I bet.
So,
II I think realistically the only,
like you said, things have to get so bad that they get bad enough for people to care
or we need like a Ralph Nader style champion to maybe get this,
-- you know, head us off at the pass before it gets so terrible
-- because maybe, maybe,
I mean, I, I attribute Ralph Nader to stunt hacking and
it,
but, but he was, he was riding a wave of disaster. It's not like he, he didn't create a
problem and let's face it.
A lot of stunt hacking is creating a problem and then trying to
kind of do something with it.
Whereas Ralph Nader didn't have to do that.
-- I,
-- I disagree because with stun hacking that,
that you're just the messenger with the bad news.
That that was it
a Cherokee or whatever was always could be hacked and monkeyed with to, to drive,
you know.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Yeah. All right.
Well, we'll, we'll talk about stun hacking another day.
We're, we're out of time, so. All right, cool. Well, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, get a link to the show notes.
I don't know if we'll have show notes uh, linked to the book at least.
And if something you can use the Pound Os S podcast,
-- hashtag to hit us up on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of
-- your day.
-- You too, thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everybody. Bye bye.
So the bank now has like a voice security thing and I'm like, no,
I absolutely don't want that.
And she's like, I'm like,
because there's like hundreds of hours of recordings of my voice on the internet
because I do a podcast
and I'm absolutely certain somebody can chop them up to be like, hello, my name is
and I authorize you to send all my money to Russia. Thank you. Goodbye.
Right. Like for sure, all those words are there.