Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 100 and
25 which by the way is a perfect cube with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
-- And
-- what's a perfect cube
-- five to the power of three,
-- five to the power of three?
Ok. That's fair. So, five times, five times five equals 100 and 25. And, and
actually,
right.
Does it. Yeah, I guess, I don't know. I can't do math in my head.
-- If
-- it doesn't, then maybe check your computer.
I, I do have a calculator. Actually, let me look it up. So funny enough. I, uh,
I opened up, I was cleaning up my desk the other day and I found my old T I 82 calculator.
So I've been, I've been using it. I wrote some programs on it. Yes.
Five times, five times 5, 125.
Thank you. T I
it's, uh, the whole calculator industry amuses me because like this calculator,
you can still buy it today pretty much
for the same
price. Like it's, the new ones are just as crappy.
-- Is it
-- the T I 85 that's actually required
by pretty much all the schools in North America
or T I 82 or one of those models.
82 or no. I'm sorry, I've got, let me, let me look again. I have the, this is the 82
-- and so when I
-- discontinued in 2004,
probably it was really, it's a long time ago,
but when I was in, in school they required the T I 81
and I bought the, the better one
because why not?
And yeah, so anyway,
oh, here we go, Texas Instruments. T I 8383 plus or T I 84.
So the 83 is like the new, I guess, crappy model and it probably costs what,
$200 and it has 32 K of RA M, right?
Uh
-- No
-- discontinued in 2004.
Ok.
So, so what's the current one? And how much ra M does it have? Because mine has 32 K,
the T I plus blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Discontinued
when not, doesn't say
I, I do know that the tis are still required
-- and, and they still cost like 100 bucks or whatever ridiculous amount,
-- right? Ok.
So let's see here.
I just typed in T I graphing calculator into
uh Google shop shopping or whatever they call it.
-- And it looks like uh T I 84 is 100 and $50
-- introduced in 2004. Still being made.
And like, as I understand it,
one of the biggest reasons is because you
can essentially provably clear the memory on it.
There's, there's very little way
when you do the memory, clear
uh commands, it's like what three or four buttons you mash in sequence.
Uh Yes.
As I understand it, there's like, absolutely no way short of like rooting the thing.
There's, there's,
I, I don't know. OK. So actually this has 100 and 54 kilobytes of ra M.
So I guess good job. T I
like
what the WTM it does come with three megabytes of RA M,
which is embarrassing but whatever.
And,
and I remember that where teachers would make you clear the memory and you could get.
So, so one of the advantages I had with my calculator was
you could, uh, like program it with,
with a little cable where you plug it into your computer,
then you plugged into the calculator and you could upload like assembly programs.
Someone figured out how to basically route the thing.
-- And there were, there were programs you could get that when the teacher,
-- like,
I doubt it has a trusted boot chain.
They might now,
but they didn't then, right?
And you could actually install an application that would like,
make it look like you cleared the memory even though you didn't.
And, and now I, I remember I never did this because it's like, I was,
I was always fairly good at, like, if I can use a calculator and write down,
I was always good at math.
So I never worried about it. But
I remember thinking like, that's interesting
because, I mean,
that's one of those things like teachers are
counting on the security of this calculator and,
and obviously that was not the case.
Well, realistically, from what I've seen, I mean,
in high school there were definitely kids who cheated
because either they managed to get grades that there's
no way they could have gotten that grade or.
Right. You know, you could see like they, they, they admitted to or they,
they both stood about, or claimed about cheating later.
And I'm,
I know when I went to school there was no honor code and I'm
guessing when you went to high school there was probably no honor code.
-- I don't know if that's a thing
-- now, not in high school. I had one in college
and, and it was, it was
nice.
I enjoyed having,
I think it makes sense when you're getting into more of a professional setting.
But, you know, at the same time, like having high school kids ride each other out.
Like, yeah, what, what problems could that possibly cause?
Exactly. Exactly. But, yeah.
No, it's, I, I do, I,
I really do utterly despise that whole t I series of calculators because, yeah,
they still cost over 100 bucks.
-- I
-- mean, let's face it, it's like $5 worth of technology. Is it even
$5?
-- Probably? I mean, the plastic case probably costs more than a chip.
-- Like,
I
think
you
buy Zylosteum order is like a shipping container's worth.
Well, in T I manufactures them. Right.
So they, they're probably getting them, like, for nothing.
They're probably using the same fab line they've been using for 20 years.
-- It,
-- it would not shock me at all anyways
in related news, I guess,
is the N PM thing this week.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
So we're going to kind of call an audible on this one and, and let's talk about kind of,
I,
I don't want to focus on the specific N PM problem itself
because I think that's less interesting than some of the bigger questions about
open source security and kind of the dependencies and, and what do we do with this?
-- To
-- be blunt, this also affects
closed source security. It's just they do it behind closed doors.
-- It,
-- it totally does
-- and we never find
-- out. We, we have no idea. Absolutely. Absolutely.
And so let's kind of let me set the stage here so we can understand what's going on.
And I, I'm not going to go into specifics because I don't think they're important.
So
essentially there was an open source project hosted on github.
Somebody essentially helped out and said,
can I become the maintainer of this project?
I want to take it on
the author said, sure, why not?
-- They became the maintainer, they inserted a back door,
-- quick piece of context.
The original author apparently had several 100 packages he was managing.
So, like, it's not like this guy was lazy or something, like,
legitimately,
he probably could get rid of a few of these and still have a lot of work to do.
Yeah.
Right. Right.
And, and then essentially whoever took it over, eventually kind of went rogue
and, and, I mean, you could even make the question, you know, ask the question.
Did, was it even the original kind of owner of the package who went rogue, you know,
with his account taken over?
We'll never know,
doesn't matter, doesn't matter.
Or was this whole thing a false flag narrative from the original author?
No, you're never allowed to use the word false flag.
Like never say that
what it boils down to is we don't really know who did this?
Does it really matter?
-- Not really,
-- doesn't matter, doesn't matter because here's the point is so
in the open source universe,
there are
probably millions of projects. I would, I would bet.
I, I think that's a safe guess at this point.
And so what happens is
if I'm a project maintainer, people can send me patches,
right. That's like how open source works. It's the whole point.
So I get a patch.
I, I, we call them pull requests and github right back in the day.
It was email or whatever, doesn't matter. Doesn't matter, it's irrelevant.
So, anyway, I get a pull request
and I might look at it and say, wow,
this is great and then I accept it and then I
might get a few more from the person and I'm like,
that's great.
I'll accept those.
And after like the fourth or fifth, I'm just going to say, uh
can I just make you a committer? Because I'm tired of approving your pull quest.
And like, I've done this more than once. In fact,
I have a handful of crappy projects I maintain and,
and this exact thing has happened to me
recently where it's like I'm tired of committing,
of, of approving your pull request.
I'm just going to make you a committer, right? And now, boom, this guy hasn't.
-- Well, and
-- this is one of the classic
problems in that, you know, we always talk about, oh, you know,
all code should have a code review and go through C I
and CD and blah, blah, blah. And the reality is nah, humans are lazy man.
Well, it's not even that they're lazy. Like when you're a guy
who's, you're not going to review everything, I mean, a large project, right?
Something like the Linux kernel or the Apache web server, whatever,
those have the manpower to do approvals and reviews.
But the reality is if you're like one guy
you're not gonna approve or review patches,
I would point out that despite the Linux kernel and Apache doing, like,
having a lot of manpower and a lot of smart people and a lot of committed people, like,
they still let things through that are problems.
Oh, totally. Right. Right.
Right.
And I don't mean just from a security point of view but from a point of view of like, oh,
you know, this makes the system crash or this eats data or,
you know,
there's been some truly horrific nonsecurity flaws
in software where it's kind of like,
oh yeah, don't use this version because then all your data is gone.
I'm like, what do you mean gone? They're like, there's like a file system bug.
Don't use it.
Whoops. You know,
-- sorry
-- guys.
Right. Right.
It happens all the time and,
and in this instance though we're focusing on a nefarious act.
Right.
And now like this guy, if he was smart,
he could have done it in a way that no one would ever see
but he wasn't.
And well, I shouldn't say that I, I think
the likelihood of being caught is, is
a,
well, even if you're caught, there's no consequence.
What the police are going to capture this guy.
No, no, no,
I,
I'm ignoring the consequences for the perpetrator here because I
think that's irrelevant as well in this conversation because there,
we
probably can't find them.
-- Yeah. Right. I, I don't, is that even, is it illegal? I don't
-- know.
I'm sure somewhere it's illegal, but
good luck getting that jurisdiction to find prosecute or sorry, find,
build a case extradite and prosecute this person.
I mean, in, in all seriousness, I bet,
like in the US with the computer fraud and abuse act,
which is what's generally used to prosecute like hackers.
I, I bet
it would be a stretch to convict someone who did this under the C FAA.
I, I would be, I, I guess if they, if they were found guilty, I wouldn't be shocked.
But if they were found innocent, I would be as equally Unho
-- written to deal with it.
-- There's a specific law that will
actually allow you to, to prosecute under this as a criminal matter.
Now, as a civil matter, you could definitely pursue this person,
sue them into oblivion, but good luck finding them.
-- Right. Right.
-- So, anyway, anyway, here's the point.
So I've heard a lot of wailing and gnashing of teeth where there's people saying,
oh N PM is such a tire fire and, you know,
you shouldn't use open source dependencies and you should vet all
your source code and there's been a million things and I guess
I want to break this down in a way that is practical insane
because I think the security people have done their usual light,
their hair on fire and run around like crazy
and that's not helpful to anybody because this is weird and this is hard and,
and I'm going to be quite frank here.
Uh, most security people probably don't know how open source works and, and
some do,
-- but a lot of them don't,
-- well, more to the point,
most people don't know how soft works.
Like, whenever anybody's, like, I've literally had people say to me,
what are you going to do for a work when all the software, like,
security flaws are fixed?
I'm kind of like, excuse me. What now?
-- Yeah,
-- I'll be dead before that
happens. The universe will be dead before that happens.
But fundamentally, you know,
we can't prevent people who want to make the best software possible
from making flaws and making security vulnerabilities.
And you expect us to somehow prevent
a malicious actor from doing this.
Now, granted it is possible in some very, you know, constrained, confined well
understood environments.
You know, for example,
um my understanding is like the space shuttle
software was one of those pieces where essentially it's
like we have all the money in the world to build this thing and we're going to,
you know,
document every line of code and what the intent was and who did it and
why we did it in which committee meetings were related to it and everything.
-- And you can absolutely
-- do airplanes,
airplanes,
airplanes work like that too,
to a degree,
except
for the flight control systems,
the really, really important stuff.
I I, yes,
because I was working with the FAA actually at
one point and they were very clear about this that
anything that like flies the plane, every line of source
-- needs to
-- be
done.
For example, the new anti
stall stuff in the Boeings that apparently was at fault for that crash in Malay.
Was it Malaysia? I want to say
that recent
Antall
Boeing crash.
Um and that was, yeah, here we go. Sorry, Indonesia, my apologies.
The problem here is that they added new features in the form of an anti
stall system for the, yeah, for the new 737 max
and apparently the pilots didn't get any training on it.
And so again, I'm not, I'm not gonna completely blitz,
but it's related in the sense of
they made changes to the software that had a
very real and material impact on the system.
Yeah, whatever run with it and, and that's kind of what happened here. Right.
Somebody made real and material changes to the software.
Um, but,
you know, could very much potentially impact you if you're using it in a certain way.
Right.
And my understanding is it only affected you if you're running one specific uh
uh
wallet or coin type, I forget what it is.
Uh Right. Right. It was, it was to steal
kind of CIN
but um,
but even so I'm,
I'm what I'm just trying to point out though is even the airline industry with all its
money and care and regulations still gets it wrong in the sense of, oh,
we added a new software feature that materially affects how the plane flies.
I'm sure the pilots will figure it out.
Right.
So,
and that's the problem
software.
It's not just about the, like, good or bad code,
but people have to know how to use this stuff correctly and safely,
you know, open SSL being a classic example of that. Right. How
open SSL reasonably well built piece of software, how many people use it wrong?
Basically, all of us,
all of them.
Right. Right. So, OK. OK. Anyway, let's, let's get back on track here.
So
there's
is open source secure. And, and how do we deal with, with this sort of problem
in a very open universe where anybody can contribute, anyone can deal with it.
And here's my answer that I know not everybody likes and,
and some people don't like at all
is uh we don't deal with it because this is how open source works.
And that's just, that's the answer I have and I wrote a blog post about this actually.
And, and here's kind of my summary of it all is in the TLDR, this is like public health,
we will never stop all disease.
Our goal is to stop epidemics.
And it's the same thing with like open source.
We're never going to stop incidents like this.
In fact, there's almost certainly another one happening right now.
But what happens is
somebody's going to notice it and they're going to raise the
red flags and it's going to get dealt with as needed,
which is exactly what happened this time
and, and yes, some people are, are going to have a problem and they're running this,
this bad code but people get sick and it's just the way it has to be.
There isn't a way to fix this.
Well,
fundamentally what I see it boiling down to is
there's a lot of software out there that,
uh, is sort of on that, on that part of the distribution curve where,
you know, it's not a billion downloads but it is over a million or over 100,000
-- easily.
-- This thing was like 2 million a week. Yeah,
exactly.
-- And which
-- is, that's a
lot, not really by current standards.
That's kind of what's amazing.
Like, I remember many years, I remember about 1015 years ago,
uh or not 1015 years ago, but no, this is even shorter, five years ago.
I think it was, uh, I forget, I think it was a ruby thing.
This, this basically this kid had literally gotten involved in ruby writing,
you know, helping with the documentation
and from there leveled up to like,
you know, helping with the code and stuff.
Uh, and sorry, not ruby but various ruby gems,
you know, the modules
and, you know, he leveled up and got competent at it.
So they're like, cool, like this one isn't very well maintained.
Uh Do you want to take ownership of it? And he's like her dip.
I'm not smart enough to say no. So I'll say yes.
So this guy takes on ownership of it does a pretty good job
and then there's a major security flaw in it
and this poor guy's freaking out because he's like,
we've had 10 million downloads of it.
Somebody's going to sue my ass into the dirt.
And I'm like, nah, they probably won't, it'll be fine,
you know, we'll get this fixed
and this poor
guy was,
he was
and I'm like, no, trust me, it'll be fine. Nobody's going to sue you,
right?
And kind of talk to him off the ledge because he was pretty like he really wanted,
like, he was really worried and freaked out and like,
really wanted to do the right thing and protect everybody
and,
you know, with all that. Yeah, we still have security flaws.
So yeah, you introduce a malicious actor
but more to the point what it boils down to for me is with the open source world.
There's so much code out there that is
very
good useful code. A lot of people use it.
It, you know, it sits there churning away dates or doing, you know,
whatever it is that it does.
Right.
And you know, there's like, maybe if we're lucky one,
slightly not dead maintainer of it, like straight up, right?
Like, I,
I know of major like image libraries that
literally are one person working on the weekends
and these are libraries used like industry wide,
you know, like the time zone guy.
That is a sad story.
Everybody wants to be the cap but, ok, great.
Who's going to step up and actually do it?
Nobody's gonna step up and do it. And that's the problem.
And I don't think they should.
It's, it's, it is a problem I will say in, in a certain respect,
but I also don't think it's a big enough problem to
necessitate any sort of drastic actions because like what happened here
where people noticed they,
they ra they rang the bell and then everyone came and helped out.
-- Like that's how it's supposed to work.
-- Well.
And I was going to say that's the thing though is we do have
sort of an emergency procedure.
We have a generic emergency procedure and open source to deal with this,
which is called, let's have a small panic and fix it
and, and we do,
and then like 12 hours or 24 hours later,
we've fixed it
and
just pull a new version.
There's nothing more we can really do. Like we fix the problem.
You need to go consume the fix.
Ok. We're, we're done for now
and while it's not very pretty or maybe super efficient,
it's, you know, it's essentially the, the,
the spot fires that flare up or are generally when they're seen they're put out
well, and, and let's face it. I mean, let's, let's think about here for a minute,
how you're going to fix this? And I've heard a multitude of,
-- of possibilities here.
-- Well, how about I propose some solutions?
And then, you know, we, you,
you let us know or we figure out why they won't or maybe why they will work.
So OK, let's go with the classic one
code review. Let's let's have every single piece of commit
coming in to a project properly, code reviewed before it goes into that project.
So essentially only good trusted code is going to make it in,
right?
So
how many, how many? Right? So
this one's even
so some, I guess here's the deal.
If you have a large project, you can do this.
And for example, the Linux kernel reviews every, every commit.
Uh I I work for elastic,
we have elastic search and that's an open
source project and every commit is reviewed,
right?
Because that's
we, we have the resource
to do that.
Now, if we think about a project, for example, I, I maintain a project called
Yarn, which is a very old text based dungeon crawler game.
I am literally one person and I think there's two other committers who I
added because I was tired of approving their pr s at one point.
If they commit something,
I, I don't have time or care enough to view it like let's just face it, right?
If, if I'm one person,
I, I can't do that. I don't have the resources.
And so now we're in a position where if you think that is a,
something that has to be legitimately done by humans
who's going to pay for it and who's going to find the resources.
And what's interesting, I mean, to me is that
a lot of these large companies will do this internally and then consume
open source and a lot of them will basically not give any,
uh, work or resources or help back, not even bug reports.
Right. Right. So, OK, so that probably, OK.
Well, then, OK, well, let's, let's maybe move that up the chain a bit.
So the people who consume this
can do code reviews of all the code that they're consuming.
Why, why can't that work?
So how many packages are in a Linux distribution? Uh Tens of thousands,
Kubernetes
-- has
-- billions of,
between one and 2000 dependencies. Now, something along those lines,
I, I would be shocked if it's only that and,
and it's probably when you look at the system as a whole,
my guess is Kubernetes is probably a million lines of code
and that's probably a, a conservative estimate is my suspicion.
And so the, so here's the deal.
Uh if you're going to review your code, here's what you've got, you've got a human
could do it.
Humans don't scale,
they're really bad at it and they're going to miss a lot
of things because nobody can review a million lines of code.
Right.
So maybe they could grip around for a couple of things and, and whatever,
there are some automated tools, there are things that do like static analysis,
there's things that do like dependency analysis and,
and some of them are pretty good.
I'm not going to say they're, they're, they're all bad,
but the reality is the vast majority of them will produce a 13,000 page report.
And what do you do with that? Right. Like of those 13,000, maybe 10% are real.
Well, you run into the human scale problem. Again.
That's true because a human has to consume the report. Absolutely.
And so what are your options now? Right. You, you can't let humans do it.
We don't have the automated tools to do it.
So what I know, let, let's have the security,
every new package we add. Right.
Right.
And, and again,
we're back to who's going to pay for this because
are you going to hire 100 and 20 security?
Could you find 100 and 20 security people?
I was just about to say,
like the problem is you can't even by definition anybody capable of doing this kind
of code review and security work probably has a job and they're probably very busy.
Right.
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And so where are you going to find, even, find people ignoring the fact that,
that no one's gonna hire 100 and 20 people to do
it like you can't even find him if you wanted to.
And, and not only that this kind of work sucks.
So nobody really wants to do it, like, all the time, all day,
every day for like garbage, right?
You want to work on fun?
Interesting, cool things that when you find security problems in them,
you can make some noise and be like, look at this cool thing I did as opposed to saying,
look,
I found a security flaw in this no name N
PM package that like nobody uses and has two maintainers
and, and I'm going to send them a patch and nobody's going to care.
Right. Like that's
so, so anyway, we're kind of back to that whole resourcing issue here and,
and there isn't,
there isn't a solution to this.
-- You know
-- what this kind of reminds me of is
forest fires and that we've essentially got this technical debt,
this fuel load building up.
Right. We've got
how many tens and hundreds and billions of lines of code now in the open source world.
But most of it's probably reasonably ok. But,
you know, we're, we're probably adding
thousands or tens of thousands of security flaws a day across the
whole ecosystem just because of the amount of code being committed.
Right.
So, here, here, here's a question.
What do you think is the rate we're adding security flaws
as opposed to fixing them 100 to 1000 to 1?
I bet it's at least 100 to 1.
I would say it depends slightly because there are some projects like,
say open BS D where when they find a flaw, they'll try and act,
get rid of that entire class of law,
either through code audits or re architecting it or whatever.
But
ignoring,
ignoring them, there is statistical anomaly.
They're the like seven standard deviations out of normal
anomaly, right? They're like space aliens in disguise.
Uh the the the more typical like looking say at the Linux kernel, right,
the amount of code being added versus the number of security flaws
being identified.
And, and to be clear, also the Linux kernel, I kind of liken that they're basically a
bug is a bug.
We don't care if it's security related,
it's a bug and we need to fix it because this is a kernel and it can't
be like randomly trashing people's data or locking
up their video card can't have that right.
It might be a hospital system.
So I kind of like that theory.
The problem is then our data becomes skewed because we have no idea how many of those
flaws that they fixed are have a security impact because their take on it sort of is,
you know, we fixed the flaw, we made sure the flaw is fixed, you know,
maybe it has a security impact in some way,
but we're not going to bother investigating, right?
We just, we fixed it, we're moving along.
But I would suspect the rate at which security bugs
are knowingly being fixed is obviously probably a lot lower than
what they are actually being fixed because, you know, people rearchitect stuff,
they get rid of old code,
they refactor things cleanly, you know, and that probably
hopefully gets rid of more security flaws than it introduces.
But
I, I would say
I would probably say about 10 or 100 to 1 somewhere in that neighborhood.
So, uh for your, your long answer you just gave you had me thinking, I,
I suspect the major projects are probably 10 to 1 or less.
But I bet if you looked at open source or just software as a whole, I won't even,
I won't pick an open source in general here.
But
-- I bet if we like lumped all the software together, the Bell
-- Curves, Microsoft
like no straight up, right.
You know, like, I mean,
Microsoft has been doing a lot of good security work for a long time.
Patch. Tuesday is still a thing.
It, it's true. All right. So anyway, we're,
let's keep this
going. So what, what are some of the other ways to fix this?
I guess we've talked about reviewing commits, reviewing our dependencies.
00, oh, I know a classic one for you.
And I let's take a quote unquote, known good version of the software.
Freeze it in time and just back
to the fixes and updates and things that we specifically need,
that's so much work.
-- I'm so glad I don't have to do this.
-- That is,
I know it's a horrible job like that is
a potential solution to this because for example,
if you were running an older version of this N PM package,
you,
you don't have the problem because you didn't upgrade into the bad version. Right?
But at, at the same side, it's a ton of work to do.
You need like huge teams dedicated to this.
Well, and conversely now you've created the risk of
we have a frozen in time version and there are known security flaws in it
that we don't know about because for example,
the project doesn't get CV numbers or they don't do security really, they just,
they fix bugs and move along and
you know, their response to security as well,
just run current because that's the one with the most bugs fixed that we know about,
which I think is actually kind of a fair answer.
Yeah, I I would not suggest that as a solution to anybody unless again,
-- you have a massive team of people who can deal with this issue
-- or, or for example,
maybe you're using the software in a way
where that particular version of that functionality is,
is good enough and
maybe it's more of a constraint.
So for example, I remember looking at one piece of software,
all it did was convert dates from IO format to uh American format, which is,
what month, day, year
-- and that's all it did
-- the dumbest format ever.
-- And I'm guessing it
-- had, although I, I hate the European format too. Everyone use. I
o,
yeah, I agree. So, did that thing have a security flaw? Yeah, probably did.
But, you know, it was used in a constrained enough way where the, you know,
the dates being generated were never fed by the user.
It was created by the system and fed by the system.
So they would always be a correct iso
date.
-- And I was like, so,
-- so I couldn't give it a date of
potato. Exactly.
Or like 1000 years in the future,
1000 years in the past or that day that doesn't exist in the Julian calendar or,
you know, whatever.
Right.
And so I basically looked at this because I looked at what I did basically is I
downloaded all the dependencies and looked at when
the last commit was and in some cases,
like it was four years ago,
like, they, they haven't, you know,
when a piece of software is being used and it hasn't actually had an, a
commit or a version or anything happened in four years. It's basically dead.
I, I would agree with that. Yes.
Right. And if it has a security flaw, you're gonna have to fix it.
And in this case, I was like, yeah, whatever, fine by me, like the risk is so low,
you know, somebody can actually exploit this cool, good for them.
Maybe that's a problem that we can manage scale wise,
which is at least review your dependencies
and, and make sure you don't have anything truly unhealthy in there.
But again, for something, but the problem is,
well, if you pull in something like Kubernetes, then boom,
it's like one or 2000 of those things.
What do you do then? Right.
And, and I would argue if you're running Kubernetes,
don't worry about the dependencies.
Kubernetes has just worry about Kubernetes.
It's up to Kubernetes to take care of the dependencies in all seriousness.
-- Well,
-- and a healthy project will do that.
And, and maybe that's part of the solution too is,
is accepting dependency.
Hell and saying essentially we're going to abstract
it away by allowing a healthy project like Kuber
to deal with it.
-- That is absolutely correct
-- because realistically, what else are you going to do?
Let's face it, right.
Uh Yeah, nothing. That's what you're gonna do. You're gonna do nothing.
Um All right. So, so what are the other, what, what else can we do here? So you've got
source control, we've got managing dependencies.
There is back porting,
freeze it in time and back port, which none of these are good solutions.
-- I mean, let's face it. They all suck for their own reasons.
-- You could.
Well, and a related one would be you fork the software
which I think is the same as freezing it in time.
Well,
it's actually, I think it's worse. It's a combination of freezing it in time and
to keep all the commits because now you have to also generate all the commits.
That's true. Actually. That's fair.
Yeah, it's actually the worst of both worlds in a way. I'm
trying to think what else can we do? Not use it?
Uh, that's also, I mean,
don't laugh that that is a possibility where you could just not,
not do something if you know, it's questionable functionality
and, and that's not unreasonable at all.
There, there, actually, there, there is a solution but I'll,
I'll wait to save it until you, you think you're out of ideas.
Uh, well, it's not that I'm out of ideas.
-- I just can't think of anything realistic that
-- there's one realistic option.
Ok.
Nothing.
-- Oh, just business as usual.
-- Do nothing.
That is the only realistic
and, and I, I jest, but,
well, that's basically the fire drill option. No, no, no.
That's the fire drill option. Right.
Every time we have a forest fire we rush to put it out
and, but we don't do forest management. You know, we don't call dead trees.
We just put out the spot fires and,
and hope the fuel load doesn't get so large
-- that eventually the whole damn thing burns down
-- and,
and
that's probably a bad analogy because like there was a,
a terrible fire in California just now.
Yep. Same here. Which was like, super devastating. Right. That's true.
You guys had one in Canada. I forgot about that.
Well, and, and that's a direct, I mean,
and I think that's one of the fears we have is, you know,
what happens if some bad guy collects up,
say 1000 really good vulnerabilities and uses them to like,
pone everything or break everything.
I, I think that's definitely a possibility and, and I guess, II I say,
do nothing in half jest because I think there's some,
some real options here for how, how this should be managed moving forward.
And so here's actually what I think we should do.
So we're, we're pretty much out of time for this show. So why don't we cut here
and we'll come back with kind of like a part two talking about like,
well, well, let's look into the future
and say, what are the things you need to do to deal with this kind of stuff?
Because there actually there are some cool things going on
and I think there's some real possibilities as to where,
where we can go with some of this.
And so let's cut it here.
So you can go to open source security podcast.com, grab the,
not a lot of show notes today but whatever can use a
Podos podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on Twitter
and I guess, yeah, stay tuned for part two, which will come out.
Um Unfortunately, probably sometime after this but yes, I think,
I think there are things we can do, but it's not super simple.
-- So, all right, Kurt, have a great day. Thanks everyone for listening.
-- You too.
Thanks everybody.