Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 21
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
We're legal to drink now in the United States, right?
Yeah,
that's uh 21 podcasts.
And we hit a major milestone today in the infosec industry,
-- a huge
-- milestone.
Kurt,
possibly one of the biggest ever and something we've
been warning about for longer than I can recall.
And it finally came true.
You were right,
five years,
-- at least, man, at least.
-- So today, actually, uh just a few hours ago,
uh Open SSH 7.4 was released
and somebody noticed it has several
security updates including a remote code execution
in the SSH agent code.
And
Mir
has assigned four CV S
uh to Open SSH one which in and of itself is quite exciting,
but more importantly, these are CV
over 10,000.
So we now have CV E 2016, 10,009, 10,010, 10,011 and 10,012.
And this affects a pro a product obviously that, you know, open SSH is in everything
I actually can't think of a network device that doesn't have it.
No, no, I mean there's alternatives,
there's things like drop your ssh and whatnot but, but
I don't know if people understand the significance of a CV E ID having five digits
is that has never happened. CV E I DS. Ok. Right. We're not gonna count that,
but practically speaking
in all of history, every CV E ID has had four digits after the year
and we've been
concerned for a long time that we would hit
10-K and this year in 2016, the year that just keeps on giving,
we legitimately crossed 10,000 CV E I DS being issued, which is
a mind boggling number.
Oh,
yeah. No, it's,
uh,
when the DWF assigned, we, we assigned some CV ES that are longer than
10-K.
But, you know,
a lot of the DWF project isn't really completely live and on stream yet.
But even when we did that, we discovered internally, you know,
that there are some system,
like there was one system that broke that wasn't
ready to handle CV S over four digits long.
And today, I mean, I can only imagine how many things are breaking right now.
It's awesome.
And this doesn't. Miter has
actually Miter already assigned a CV E
10-K a
few days ago,
um,
and put it in the database today publicly, uh CV, 2016, 10,005 for Web
in Pro and Sap Solomon. I have no, it's an SAP related thing, I guess.
Um, and that is now in the database live,
which means if you consume those CS V files automatically, uh,
you better hope that you prepped for CV
10-K. Now, now the reality is CV.
10-K has been, I think we've been warning people and dealing with it for,
I wanna say, five or six or seven years ago.
Long time. Yeah, it's been so long. I don't even remember anymore.
I think it's, I'm pretty sure it's older than my kids.
Well, we should also talk about the fact that
meer
officially updated the CV E format, what three years ago, maybe
to accommodate this, this because originally the,
the CV E data format was pegged at four digits and obviously any
reasonable person realized that was going to be a problem at some point
as it would have been today. Had they not fixed it? So what's the new format?
-- Kurt, explain it to us.
-- So the new format is very simple CV ES between 0001 and
9909. Stay the same. They're four digits,
then they add 1/5 digit for 10,000 through 99,999.
And then for six and up, we we just, you just keep adding digits.
So there's basically what it boils down to is there's no leading zero.
And the beauty of this is, it means we now have, well,
we're just using integers straight up, starting at four digits long.
Uh So when I said there's no padding zeros, what I should have said is
there are padding zeros for single digit CV, S,
double digit CV S and obviously triple digit CV S and then CV, 1000 through 9009,
have no padding. And above also has no padding.
And personally, I think that kind of makes sense because quite honestly, like CV,
2016-1
would look,
you know,
a bit strange.
Yeah,
but no, essentially we've now embraced integers and the sky is literally the limit.
It's gonna be awesome.
And I mean, the other great news is in 2016,
Miter has minted a whole new pile of CV numbering authorities.
You know, we have the Apache Foundation,
we have JP uh cert Japanese cert
including a private individual. We also now have Larry
Kaller minted as AC N A enlisted officially on the CN A web page.
Larry is his own CNA. I had no
idea
that
-- C
-- N A web page. He is now his own CN A
quite
well back in the day, Stephen Christie actually did
uh presentation on CV and specifically called it Larry Cash
Dollar. I was completely hosing all the statistics for one year
because he found, you know, several 100 remote code execution vulnerabilities.
And um I wanna say Ruby Jim's uh
applications,
you know, so this one guy single handedly, like,
totally skewed the bell curve for the rest of us.
So, I mean, you know, to me that says, uh, yeah, he's probably ready to PSCN A,
we'll, we'll let it go. Right.
So, well, and the, the problem too is he, you know,
he came to me and he needed CV S and I was like, how many he's like, well,
probably about 1000 of them.
I was like,
you maybe want to consider just being ac N A
at that point. It's like
you
don't go to the store and ask for 1000 turkeys.
You could
but they might. No, no, it's not even that though. It's not.
This isn't going to the store to ask for 1000 turkeys.
This is going to the store and saying I need 1000 slices of cheese, please.
And the person at the deli looks at you like, no,
absolutely not. Here's, here's five pounds of
uns,
somebody
do that at the Italian Center.
She wanted something like five pounds of sliced ham.
-- Well,
-- there's nothing
wrong with it.
No, no, five pounds of sliced ham is doable. But if you said I need 1005 slices of ham,
they're gonna be like, no,
I'm,
I will slice five pounds of ham or I will s give
you five pounds of ham and you may slice it too.
But I am not counting 1005 slices of ham.
Yeah.
Yeah. So, no, this is a, this is a great auspicious occasion. Uh
It also really drives home.
It drives me nuts that some open source projects just don't do
CV S.
-- Are there still some, I guess I don't
-- Linux
kernel,
the kernel is weird other than that one.
Open SSH and all of the open BS D stuff.
Oh,
that's true because they released this advisory here with no
CV E I DS which is kind of bonkers and
I
agree
with
-- that.
-- It's a cultural thing which I kind of agree and disagree with in that
the Linux kernel and the Open BS D guys, essentially, they,
they profess to only care about code
quality and code correctness and to them,
it doesn't matter if it's has a security implication or doesn't it
is incorrect. Code needs to be fixed end of story. And more importantly,
they,
the Linux kernel community and the Open BS D community
generally expects people to be running whatever the latest,
you know, effectively nightly build of the code is.
The Linux guys
are kind of a different story here. But, but if we pick on the open SSH guys,
they had a special security section in this advisory. So they can't claim
that they have no,
I,
I guess they don't care whether it's a security issue or not
since it's all about code quality because if they didn't care,
they wouldn't have a security section in their advisory.
Right?
II I can't speak as to their, what they're sort of
doing.
But
I just, all I know historically is that's what they've said. And,
you know, I understand that argument. It, it kind of makes sense. You know what?
No, I'm gonna say no,
because this is 2016.
And
basically all of this code is used all over the place and everybody knows it
and CD E is the standard, love it or hate it. It won guys.
It's what everyone uses and you can get on board or you can be
like the guy trying to ride his horse down the interstate where you're just,
everyone's looking at you and shaking their head and they're waiting for the, the,
the 18 wheeler to come and plow you over.
This is true.
The problem is,
and it's funny because I've actually been looking
at CV E usage from an economic perspective.
There's not a lot of
incentive for these open source projects to actually use CV.
Other than to be, you know, good members of the community,
you know, open SSH, not using CV E doesn't really impact them
all that much, you know, it,
it certainly impacts the world and everybody else is shipping open SSH and using it.
But that's part of the challenge and, and I'm trying, I've actually,
I've got some ideas on how to make CV E more of a benefit to people who use it
so that more people will want to you know,
make sure that their issues have CV S assigned as soon as possible.
It's interesting you say that
because
you might not be wrong.
But I think you can make the same argument just with bugs in
general of what's the purpose of having a bug tracker with I DS.
Why don't we just do everything in g,
well,
the one advantage of having a bug tracker is it
actually does have an economic benefit to the project,
right?
It makes it cheaper and easier for them to track and manage their own, you know,
internally found things.
So there is a real,
you know, in economic terms, there's a real benefit
to having this, you know, you don't have to spend time figuring out.
Did we already fix this? Did we, was this already reported?
Was this already dealt with, is somebody else working on this?
-- But
-- you can make the same argument with CV E I DS is someone could say,
did you,
did you fix the security issue?
True.
But for example, the open SSH and Open BS D communities have historically been uh uh
not as user friendly maybe.
Yeah,
you know, and, and they quite frankly don't, like they flat out said they don't care,
you know, kind of about that kind of that, that
part of the problem.
So essentially what it boils down to is yes, there is a real benefit for using TV.
I mean, the biggest one being is that,
you know, whenever Red Hat finds an issue
and we have to talk with other people about it, you know,
especially if there's multiple issues in something,
you know, then CV E provides a huge benefit in that we can actually
uh
identify what it is we're talking about with these other vendors,
especially when there's, you know, more than say, 10 or 20 vendors involved,
you know,
but um there's something to remember is open SSH doesn't have that right.
Open SSH development largely happens within the open SSH community
and they essentially push out
versions publicly, you know. Um As far as I know, they've never given anybody
-- a heads up or, you know, embargo notification ever.
-- Sure.
And, well, so, you know, what this really comes down to, I guess,
is kind of putting the open source hat on is
Open BS D
is quite free to say, I don't want to use this thing.
But
given the fact that other organizations do care about it,
we're able to get involved and basically make these I DS
work in this context just because that's kind of the,
the magic of open source is
a,
the project doesn't have to care about something.
But if someone else does and they're willing to do the work now, it's a real thing.
-- And I guess that's exactly what this is
-- and that's
part of what the DWF solves is long term.
Once the DWF has, you know, our technology stack, stand up, standing up to, uh,
you know, make CV assignments happen a lot more, uh, less painlessly.
We'll be taking on all the open source assignments. And one thing I'll be definitely
doing is, you know, the DWF will act as sort of the insurer of last resort. Right.
If you need an open source CV. And the project doesn't do CV S,
you can come to the DWF to get a CV.
And one thing I will be doing is, you know,
with the CV mentor program is there will be people with sort of specialties,
you know,
and no doubt,
I will hopefully have one or more people whose
specialty is the whole open BS D open SSH ecosystem
so that we can get good
coverage of them.
Um, because I've actually looked through and, you know,
there's historical bugs that,
you know,
sometimes what happens is a flaw gets fixed and it doesn't get known as
a security flaw for weeks or months or even years in some case,
you know,
and especially with people who run sort of stable versions
of the software and back part of the security fixes.
That's a very important thing to find out about,
you know, because there's, there's been Linux flaws where uh they were fixed
23 years ago
and it's only recently somebody's looking through that code commit and being like,
oh, you know, this plus this equals a security flaw this,
you know,
and
as it was not identified as a security flaw back in the day.
You know, anybody doing the backboard thing
doesn't have this fix.
You know, but the minute you assign it a CV, it pops up on the radar of everybody.
I mean, that's very true.
So, and that's one of my biggest goals. Right.
I wanna make CV S so easy to request and so easy to assign
that. It,
it's like using a bug tracker. Like, why would you do it any other way?
It's, you know, source control, right?
The only people not doing it are, are essentially determined to be backwards,
you know,
and we're not quite at that point yet, but hopefully within 2 to 3 years we will be,
-- that's awesome. And then we'll have millions of CV I DS instead of 10,000,
-- right?
Yeah.
Well, especially when you consider we have almost, well,
really no coverage of non-english software.
-- Uh Didn't you just say JP Cert is AC N A
-- now?
They are AC N A? But I mean, obviously it's gonna take
time for them to come online and bring, you know, all of Japan
and quite a bit of Japan is already pretty good about it.
You know, Hitachi and some other vendors are pretty good about their CV S.
Uh But obviously with it being easier, I'm guessing that, you know,
there will be more issues that get CV S because, well,
small things that in the past were sort of not given CV S because it was too much hassle
or a few years ago prior to CV,
10-K,
you know, miter
and other groups kind of actually had to cut back a bit on CV assignments to make
sure they didn't run out in case something
important happened towards the end of the year.
You know, literally. Right, because it was artificial scarcity.
That's true.
If you look at CV assignments,
-- we ran
-- out of
integers.
Yeah.
Well, exactly. You know,
uh but we solved that problem now, we have an infinite number of CV S
and
researchers. That's a challenge.
-- You
-- know,
it's, it's going to happen.
I mean,
Google announced what two weeks ago now that they are open source fuzzing project,
they were taking candidates
uh for open
source projects that they're going to fuzz and find security flaws in
which is kind of crazy to think about because the day is coming
where we're going to have a computer that finds a security issue,
classifies it, probably writes a patch for it
and sends the patch away without human beings even being involved at all.
Yeah, there's already experimental work with that.
Uh And one of the best ones I saw was not only that,
but it actually came up with exploit code
like a built a test case which
I know it's incredibly useful, right?
Because you need to know that this patch works and that there's no regression later.
In life when you, you know, modify something else. Right.
So, it, it's coming, it's
fundamentally it's one of those things. It's like self driving cars. Yeah.
It's not an easy problem. And snow will definitely make it even harder.
You know, there's a lot of security flaws that are quite subtle. But fundamentally
we don't need to be
very good to be better than most humans.
Right.
That's the thing to remember too is to make a
self driving car that is better than the average human.
You really?
Yeah.
You know, we just finished a new season of Canada's Worst Driver, uh, season 12.
And I mean, you know, for some of these people it was like,
well, I only drink when I drive because I'm so tense.
I drive, I need to be a bit more relaxed.
So I have a few drinks before I drive and, you know, I know, and the,
the people running the show were kind of like, wait, what, like
you, what, you know, you, you, that's drinking and driving.
He's like, well, yeah, but I only do it so that I drive better and they're like that.
No,
you, you know, so there's people that do those things let alone, you know,
turn signals.
So the reality is, you know, with a lot of the security flaws.
I mean, the fact that somebody like Larry Cash
Doer can essentially script this and find thousands of security flaws.
You know, we, we can find a lot,
millions of security flaws with not very sophisticated automated systems.
-- So
-- here's the deal too. Ok.
And this is a complaint I've had for a long time
is finding security issues is quite honestly not difficult to do.
I mean, buzzers have come out and are doing
a marvelous job
of this work. And I remember back in the day
when
someone would fuzz like a font library and then say, oh, look,
here's 1000 font files that crashed this library.
And
it's like, that's not,
I'm not giving you any credit for this because this isn't work.
The real work is the poor samp.
So we have to figure this out and of course, it ended up being, you know,
three or four real bugs and the rest are garbage.
But
that's the thing, right? Is just finding the issues isn't the challenge.
The challenge is working with the groups and getting this stuff fixed correctly.
-- And like those guys are the heroes
-- even identifying that it is or is not an issue.
You know, I had somebody come to me with exactly that 1000 or 100 or so
test cases for, um,
it was a utility that converted file formats for like office file formats and um,
ok, great. Yeah, I, I definitely agree. You found bugs that crash it
and he's like, can you please, uh,
essentially investigate them and assign c visas as necessary?
My response was no, no I can't,
but, you know, you can come back to me with minimized test cases
and we'll talk and literally four days later he came back and he was like, oh yeah,
these all just crash it.
None of them are exploitable at all.
And I'm like, well, you know, I, that's awesome.
And you're not getting any CV S because, you know, generally speaking,
crasher bugs and command line utilities.
Unless it's something that, you know, typically used by servers to,
to mangle data being passed from the internet, like,
say an image library or whatever,
we generally don't bother giving those CV S because
especially with crasher bugs, the response would be, well, just, you know,
you opened a file, it crashed, well, don't open it again.
Like don't sit there hitting
repeat until you die of old age.
-- It's like
-- I want, I want a CV E because when I hit my laptop with a hammer, it,
it stops working.
Well, now,
if the laptop manufacturer made a security claim that it was hammer proof,
then we would consider giving it a CV.
Although we technically don't do CV S for hardware issues that although again,
that line is incredibly blurred because for example FPG eight, you know,
field programmable gator rays
or, you know, TCP/IP in silicon,
right? Is that hardware? Is that software? Well, software in hardware?
That's
an interesting question. And
what about CPU micro
code?
Right.
Right. Right. Well, that's magic.
And we don't know anything about those, but there, there are
so, so I know, I don't know how this works anymore since I've,
I've not paid attention to the industry for a long time.
But I know
there were actually applications at one point that you would write C code for,
say like an MP3 decoder
and you would run this application on the C code and it would essentially output
the layout for a chip and then you incorporate that into your designs.
And of course, the C code had bugs.
And so
that, I don't know, I mean,
if you found say a buffer overflow and something like that,
that let you do crazy things in hardware is that a security issue?
Well, here's a simple example that becomes very non simple.
You have a hardware random number generator.
These, these do exist in hardware, you know, there's ones based on, you know,
thermal noise in the CPU whatever.
And let's say, for example, every once in a while,
uh let's say it also makes the claim that
it is a cryptographically secure random number generator,
right?
Which means it has special properties like it won't spit out a stream of zeros for,
you know, two days,
right?
Because if you, if you generate encryption keys based on that, you're,
you're gonna have a bad time.
And let's say it does do that
randomly well, may you know, should it, for example,
let's say for the sake of argument it's caused by cosmic rays,
you know, something you just can't block and deal with reasonably. Right.
But should it have maybe had some sort of test
on the output to make sure the output's not garbage?
Right. Where do you draw those, this line?
I mean, clearly you have a problem when,
say your random number generator spits out zeros for two days straight.
Right?
Or, you know, say after a period of, uh, what is it, uh um
4 billion seconds it runs out or goes wonky and starts spitting out zeros or,
you know, different cases like this, right.
What is it
Boeing?
What, what plane is it,
-- the Boeing plane that has to be turned off and on every 32
-- and a half
hours, it's their Dreamliner,
the 787, right? Yeah, the new one.
And the best part is though,
actually you can't turn it off and on
too often because that apparently also causes problems.
Of course it does. So,
yeah, so it's as part of the maintenance thing now,
you're supposed to turn the plane off and on every uh 31 days or something like that.
So, I guess that you don't, you know, mid flight have the system,
you know, go bonkers, right.
Uh But, you know, clearly there are,
-- there is the potential for hardware based flaws to some degree and
-- as miter
prepared
-- to issue CV ID for those,
-- not at this
time,
uh although it's something the board is discussing and we're working on and
obviously a lot of us are pushing for it because the reality is,
you know,
TCP, offload.
That, that's a big thing nowadays, you know,
and the reality is that's going to become
the default in TCP/IP stacks because especially with internet of things,
you know,
as a manufacturer,
you don't have a lot of power and you don't have a lot of software and CPU to play with.
So, you know, if you can buy a chip that's the same cost that has TCP offload,
you're going to do that.
-- Well,
-- what about like some of these enclave processors now where you've got your,
essentially the idea, I mean,
like the Apple iphone and most of these phones
use it where they have like the special secure processor
that's designed to hold,
you know, key material and, and login material and things like that. So
the line gets really fuzzy there
as to what is hardware problems and what is a software problem.
And fundamentally, I mean, the reality is just,
I think it's going to happen because there's value in it, right?
I need to know if this stuff works or not.
You know,
even if I can't fix it, I can at a minimum, say for example,
buy new hardware and replace it or stop using it,
you know.
Yeah.
-- Yeah, that makes sense.
-- But at least as a consumer, I need to know that it is a problem.
You know, the, it's like product safety recalls. Right.
A lot of product safety recalls consist of, go take this thing back and get a refund.
Sure. Right. Because it's not economically viable to fix this thing.
It would cost 50 bucks to fix a $5 device or whatever, you know,
but as a consumer you need to know that there's a problem so that, you know,
you can get rid of this thing or replace it or whatever.
And, and is CV E
the way we want to deal with things like that?
Well, I, you know,
and then part of the challenge there becomes what exactly is a security flaw, right?
So traditionally,
we've talked about, say, for example, denial of service.
Well,
what if I have a remote flaw that lets me
brick your IOT device into a completely unrecoverable state?
Well,
let's, I personally would say that that's a security issue.
We can even back it up from there though. Is
we ask questions like, what's a security issue? What happens when
we have sand boxing technology
around
an application
and you can maybe take over a certain
amount of the application's ability to do things,
but it's stuck in the sandbox.
Is that a security issue?
It would depend on what you're able to do and not do.
I mean, it would be, is there a trust boundary being crossed?
You know, is the attacker able to get additional access, you know,
for example, maybe the application is only supposed to turn the light
on and off,
but maybe I can also then cause it to dim or something or I can, you know,
do other things.
Um,
I think a lot of what's gonna have to happen is we're gonna have to
become
ideally a bit more concise about what the security properties of these systems are.
So that we know when they're being violated,
which of course is not going to work at
all for cheap devices because they just don't care,
right?
They're not going to send out a security assertion
document with this thing. You know,
I mean, a perfect example that like is FS
testing, right?
The federal information protection standard stuff, you know, for encryption,
right?
Where
you have hardware certification
of, yeah, you, you no doubt are familiar.
So you have hardware uh
that does encryption and decryption and is,
you know, some of it is uh tamper resistance, some of it is just tamper evidence.
Some of it is,
you know,
uh I think it will basically commit suicide if you look at it funny
so that it can't be decrypted or whatever.
So there's also different
pips levels where some are very hardware focused,
some are software focused and some are where you mix the two
is what makes a difference.
And Phipps is, is a really interesting one actually because
fundamentally and, and I guess this is sort of true in general for CV E is,
the intent isn't to deceive or to necessarily
prove absolutes in one direction or the other.
It's, it's more along the lines of
we're, we're showing that we've put in an honest effort here
and this is as good as we think it can be.
Yeah.
Well, the reality is, you know,
a lot of stuff based on Open SSL has been FIP certified and of course,
open SSL keeps fixing security flaws.
Yes. You know, that's just the nature of our reality.
It's complicated though because Phipps focuses very much on the,
the cryptographic math,
not all the other stuff.
And Open SSL actually doesn't touch the algorithms very often.
It's all the other crap surrounding it
that gets all the attention.
And so, I mean, this is part of what makes Pips so confusing and bizarre is
like TLS isn't covered by FIS but the, the ciphers
that are used with TLS are,
-- and
-- this is, it's
just only covering the low
-- level,
-- very,
very low level. Yes.
And actually this is one of the things that the,
the nist folks have been talking about is the fact that
you can have,
you know, super secured, validated ciphers
and you can have a TLS layer that's absolute garbage.
And so you could have a Phipps validated product
that is essentially a huge piece of crap.
And that's a problem. Right.
Well,
I think a lot of that boils down to is truly
testing the software and giving it assurance either way is,
is impossible.
And
I personally think I would rather look at it more from an operational standpoint of,
you know, we know that this, so we know that all software has flaws,
for example, what is the vendor capable of doing response wise? Right.
How fast can they get a security update out? Do they have a security team?
Do they have just one guy or is it like 20 people?
You know, do they? I, I've dealt with companies where they,
they absolutely don't work except between 9 to 5.
Right.
So, out of hours and on the weekends there's, there's literally nobody home,
-- it's impossible to deal with and,
-- and there's a huge holiday coming up.
How many organizations are going to basically shut down for an entire week?
Yeah.
So personally, my take on it with security is,
and this is kind of where I'm hoping to move CV.
Economically speaking is
right now CV, is seen as a, as a bad thing. Right. You have a CV, you're bad. Right.
You've got four CV s and open,
bad, bad, bad
to me. It's actually the opposite. It's good. Right.
I, it means people are identifying and fixing security flaws.
I,
I agree with you completely and I feel like we may have mentioned this in the past and
I might, I, I've written this down.
I know many times in many different places is the fact that
if you have a product and there are zero CV E I DS for that product
that is a product no one cares about.
Nobody is looking because every single piece of software on the planet,
no matter what it does has security issues.
Well, and it actually,
it's a bit worse than that now because there's a lot of stuff with embedded software,
like every network device is probably running Linux
by large,
you know,
and so there are definitely flaws in it.
It's just they haven't been explicitly identified in that
whatever that vendors shipping what version they're using,
you know,
uh
and the,
and the problem is you don't have to look that hard to find them, right? You can use
old attacks, you know, in metas
or, you know, various security scanners to very easily, you know,
poke at a device and find out whether or not it's flawed
with very minimal effort. Uh The challenge then being is, you know,
for example, let's say you did some research into
IP cameras, you know, IP based cameras
and you found a whole bunch of them running outdated software. What would you do?
I would join them to my botnet.
-- You
-- know, currently there's no easy way to say,
update the CV descriptions and information to say what's vulnerable.
And fortunately that is changing, you know,
that's something we're working on currently
uh in the CV world.
Wait, wait. So you want to let
normal people
basically say this particular product or application is vulnerable,
that's hugely valuable. Look at that.
I mean, it comes back to that, that Google guy who was reviewing uh USB C cables.
Remember on Amazon and finding cables that like fried his laptop or pixel that
you know what that is incredibly valuable work and data, right?
Because I I don't want to fry my stuff by buying like a cheap cable.
I agree with you.
So let's think about this for a minute. And, and I'm very much in favor of this
idea.
The secret is, is that you have
within a CV, different classes of data, you have sort of the,
the the really trusted high quality data like
the description or
the CV number itself
and that, you know, we restrict access to who can monkey with that to some degree.
But for example, with, with the, with the DWF and with the new CV stuff,
we're looking at a
JSON format
that for example,
has a vendor section so that specific vendors
and products can have claims made against them
-- without sort of polluting the global description.
-- I love that idea. In fact, we
NVD used to do that.
I don't know if they still do,
-- but they would let vendors essentially add commentary to every CV E
-- ID.
And for example,
I've had some vendors bring up the case of where they
want to have CV SS scoring specific to their product because
for example, they maybe have better se Linux policies to harden it.
-- So it's not quite as bad
-- or CV SS scoring is very
environment dependent
where if you're using an application in this way,
it would drastically change the score versus using it in another way.
Exactly.
And some vendor ship things that are actually secure by default
or, you know,
default or
choice,
it's slowly happening very slowly. But yeah.
So anyways, the,
the reality is what I'm gonna do is there's gonna be essentially
the the data that is traditionally seen as high quality and good,
you know, which basically is the CV description text itself.
You know, this
product has this vulnerability and this version resulting in this impact,
you know, like buffer overflow, resulting in code execution, remotely whatever.
But yeah, then for specific vendors
and I don't mean just like for example, Red Hat and souza and Debian and Open BS D.
But I mean, like,
you know, this Chinese digital video recorder built by this company, you know,
is running a
web server with, you know, this vulnerable version of PHP.
So I want to add that information to, you know, that CV E about PHP,
right?
That's,
that's so crazy. I mean, I love this, I love this so much
but it's,
-- it's,
-- it's a, it's a problem space, you know, remarkably similar to, you know,
online ratings of, well, anything,
right?
It's, it's not an easy problem, but it is basically a solved problem. And
the beauty is, the reality is in the security industry,
the majority of people who behave rationally insanely are, you know,
reasonably well known.
They're not hard to identify, you know, when somebody comes to me and says,
I want to add this description,
I look at their email address of their Twitter handle and I'm like,
chances are I either know who they are or I can find out very quickly if they're,
you know, saying and rational
cyber
troll 1375.
Don't
listen
to that guy.
Yeah. So,
and you know, part of it is this distributive trust property, right?
So the way I'm, I'm really trying to set up the DWF with the CV mentor program is
I will be minting CV mentors like such as yourself and you in turn, for example,
when you go to SMU
on or whatever can actually start minting
other CV mentors that have specialties and
assigning CV S or maybe uh specialties in making assertions, you know, because
uh what was it?
Oh, remember back in the day,
there was that one developer for the Linux kernel who had like
one copy of what was it like every USB video camera ever made
and he wrote
all the drivers for them. Remember that
it was, I don't even know if he was an official Linux
developer. I
think
-- it was for
-- the longest time
was just this dude in France that,
-- that made everything work
-- and that's a perfect example of like,
as ridiculous as that is, it totally worked.
People.
I remember he had a web page and he was, he had this huge list of all the web cameras,
all the USB cameras he had.
And then it was basically was like, if you have a camera that is not on this list,
mail it to this address
and, and like, I'll write a driver for it if I can.
I remember this was similar back in the late nineties
with Ethernet cards as well where there was some,
yeah, the NASA guy
because I remember,
I remember emailing him.
-- Right. Right.
-- I remember,
well, well, so when I went to college,
like
Ethernet was a big deal and I remember like, I had a network at home and stuff,
so I didn't care, but they would only let you plug in
an Ethernet card you purchased from the university.
And I remember, I'm like, this is insane. I have a box full of these things over here.
Just let me use one of mine. Like, no, no,
you need yours. And I'm like, can I run Linux?
And they're like, their heads exploded.
And I thought all right, I'm going to, in fact,
I installed windows on my Linux machine.
So, and I had to bring it to them and I, like, I watched them do it because I,
I was very insistent.
I'd be there when they touch my computer because I,
my assumption was they were morons and I'm pretty sure that's not wrong.
But anyway, they,
they put in their special Ethernet card, which I had to use and they even had it.
So when you connect it to the network, it would verify the Mac address. So it was,
and it did a bunch of monkeying and I thought, you know, what,
use a stupid card and, yeah. Yeah, like getting it to work was in Linux
back then.
Yeah, Donald Becker, that's the guy.
He, I wonder whatever happened to him.
But yeah, no,
I literally would only buy cards that he
wrote drivers for because everything else was garbage
and it was crazy back then. It was, oh my goodness.
Why are we even talking about this anymore?
Well, because the reality is we're back in that situation, right? Like I need to buy
cables.
I and, and you know,
I'm plugging devices that cost 1000 bucks into these
cables and these cables cost like a dollar.
-- All right.
-- So let me ask, this is a cable that is known bad and will cook your laptop.
Should that get a CV E ID?
Is that
that?
Well, no, it's, it's, it's a violation of a state
property, right?
They stated that this cable is a USB C compliant, which means it has,
I think what is it like a 51?
Ohm resistor or something on PN seven or something,
you know, specific like that, right? To prevent it from cooking stuff
and, you know,
they're finding these things with like smaller resistors or whatever it is.
You know, I'm totally wrong on this,
but it's some detail like that that causes the physical damage
to me.
That is, you know,
obviously if you say that this cable meets a certain specification and
in failing to meet that specification, it causes actual, like physical damage.
Yeah, that's a problem. That's something I need to know about is, and I,
you know what happens if your local university purchases
1000 of these cables and hands them out.
All right. Well, here's
a
million
dollars and
let's make it even weirder
is what if the manufacturer of the cable
doesn't make claims about its USB C compatibility?
There are specific and implied claims.
So for example,
you can make a specific claim like you can imply or you can make a specific claim,
this product ships with the firewall that has these properties.
And if it doesn't clearly a CV is needed,
there's also implied claims. For example,
uh
like products not having a back door,
even if it's somewhat documented, that's still a problem,
right?
Because we expect products not to have back doors just
like I expect to be able to buy cables,
plug stuff in and not have it fry.
But if, if a cable doesn't claim to be USB C compatible,
but it has a USB C plug on the end is that implied,
I would say, yeah,
I
would kind of agree with you there.
You know what I mean?
Well, for example, I make a USB extension cable which has like
a signal booster into it, except that signal booster.
I, I sort of missed a couple zeros and it puts out the signal to say 1000 volts.
I think you can buy one of those for $50 now. So
clearly, like if, you know,
I have a cable that say boost the signal
and boost it way too much causing physical damage.
Even if I don't
make specific claims. Obviously, again, that's,
you know, that's a huge problem.
Um
You know, and then it gets into sort of what's intentional, what's not intentional.
Like
you have a power supply that catches fire one in 1000 times, is that a CV worthy issue?
I, I don't know,
you know, but if it, what if there's a specific flaw?
Like I, I've been watching a lot of these airline disaster films
and there are a great example was, um,
on this one model of plane, the, when the flaps come down and extend,
they could overextend. So they, the fix was to install a bolt
with some washers and nuts on it to prevent the flat from overextending.
But if during the installation of this process,
you didn't put the washer on properly,
the bolt is now small enough that it could actually go through the hole
and essentially go into the space where the sort of the, the action for the flaps is.
And so if it falls off into this space when the
flaps are extended and then pushed back in all the way,
it would actually push the bolt in and puncture the fuel tank.
And that's what caused that China Air
uh
airplane to catch fire on the ground a few months ago. Remember, or a few years ago,
it was a China airline flight that landed, they, they land safely, right?
Everything's fine. They're taxing off the runway
and all of a sudden,
you know,
it catches fire on the wing because it's like
spraying fuel out from a punctured fuel tank.
And luckily everybody got off, nobody died.
Uh
and it was a 737 which, yeah,
it was a 737 which is why this is such a problem because
this is like one of the most common planes on the planet.
You know,
I've been on many,
-- many 737
-- so
uh whatever
and maybe it wasn't at 737 but I remember it was boring.
But anyways, so, you know, does something like that deserve a CV,
where the process of fixing this flaw,
there's a documented process that's easy to mess up.
And you know, if you have this washer missing, you, you have a big problem like you,
you're going to puncture your fuel tank at some point.
-- So
-- I wonder if the FAA has a similar identification system where you
directives, right? Maintenance directives. OK.
So, so that's the same basic idea as CV E, right?
Do this or your plane will break right? In a, in
a really bad.
-- And
-- I guess though CV E is less direct than that where we don't say do this or else,
but rather here's what's going on.
Well, we kind of say we try to say what the impact is, you know,
or else you will suffer a buffer overflow that allows
a remote attacker to take control of your system.
But we don't have the authority to
see. Part of the challenge is the FAA
and the N TSB are separate entities, right?
The N TSB does the investigations and recommendations
but the FAA does the actual enforcement,
which I think makes sense because you need separated.
But the N TSB can only make recommendations. They can't make law or rules. The FAA
is,
has to do that.
So there's been cases where the N TSB made recommendations that were not taken
and then you know, the problem crops up again later.
So eventually FAA is like, OK, yeah, we need to do that,
but that's totally like the current CBE universe where
issues are found, researchers find things,
they might suggest things and then it's up to the vendors and
developers to decide should I listen to this person or not?
True?
And what I'm hoping to do is make that data more
available so that customers can start pressuring people to make those.
And I totally agree with that because let's face it.
If, if there is a problem making airplanes explode
and the N TSB said,
you know, fix this or things explode. N fa was like, yeah, screw you guys.
I don't want to do that.
There would be like
a peasant.
No, no, that's happened before.
Uh, the DC, the one with three engines, the, uh, the cargo bay door wasn't
designed correctly and it had a latching mechanism where
you could forcibly close it and latch it,
but the pins were not engaged properly.
So the door would like blow out when you got to altitude.
And it basically happened once and the guy,
they managed to land the plane good for them.
You know, nobody died. There was a huge,
like it, it was so violent
that it actually, uh the, the floor inside the plane, you know,
broke and part of it got uh moved.
And so obviously, you know, once they figured out what happened,
they made these recommendations.
Uh The two main recommendations were to change the latching system so that,
you know, you could not engage the pins without the door being latched correctly.
And the second one was to have vents in the floor of the plane inside the plane.
So that if there is an explosive depression, the floor, it can vent.
It doesn't, the floor doesn't get wrecked, like, you know,
in this case the floor was pulled like one or 2 ft out of
space
and there was a huge hole in it. Right.
They showed it and the pictures are insane like it.
You know,
this poor flight attendant had to jump over the hole to get to
the front of the plane where it was safer when they were landing.
And then the same thing happens two years later.
So,
you know, we've, we've sort of, well, look at the Challenger
Oing disaster. We knew that they were a problem.
Yeah. Yeah, they, well, some people knew.
Yeah. So I, you know, there's been cases. Um,
you know, this is a, well, I mean, back to your, you know,
industrial safety presentation, things have to get really bad
before people notice and start to take action.
You know, uh, Ralph Nader's unsafe at any speed. You know, how long did it take?
How long did it take for the car industry to put three point safety belts in
or airbags?
Totally, man. I mean, it, it took a long time and
it wasn't easy either.
Yeah.
So one of my goals of CV is twofold is to get better CV coverage.
So we have an idea of the scope of the problem
and two to change it from being such a negative thing to being, you know, yay,
this vendor has 100 TV S that they all fixed within a reasonable time frame.
That's awesome. That's the product I want
or more to the point, this vendor is responsible and, you know,
is maybe not fixing these things, but, uh,
is giving guidance about it or at least letting
me know so that I can take maybe action.
Yeah, I agree completely. I think that is
the future man and, and
this part of me is intrigued by this and part of me is terrified by this because I,
if it's done wrong,
it could go very badly, but I'm hopeful it will go. Right.
Well, ok, that's fair.
You know,
information security economics course. And
uh
I forget the guy's name, but it's the law of lemons.
And it basically posits that when you have information asymmetry,
that is the customers don't really know or can't know about the quality of a product.
You can't actually build a high quality product and
get people to pay for it because they can't
verify that it is a high quality product.
So they give the example of used cars, right?
Used cars, generally speaking, don't get their value
that they should,
even if it's a high quality used car because people are simply not willing to pay
because,
you know, they have a belief that used cars, especially used car sales, people are,
you know, kind of scummy and gonna rip them off.
So even if, uh, you know, you could have a used car lot, which has, you know,
uh super awesome mechanical inspection and only sells top of the quality used cars
is that gonna work? Probably not.
Right. Because the perception is that, you know, you're getting,
you're getting ripped off on these things and, you know,
and that's where we are with a lot of computer security software,
especially not even just computer software but computer security software.
For example, being antivirus vendors, there's, uh,
what 56 of them on virus total.
So there's at least 56 major antivirus vendors globally,
which of these ones are good and bad.
You know, if you look at Tavis, one of these work into antivirus scanners, right?
-- He's finding horrendous flaws in
-- these things.
I think, I think Tavis would tell you they're, they're all bad.
Seems to be the consensus.
Yeah. You know,
so as a consumer, how do I choose a good antivirus product?
-- I'm, well,
-- the answer is I actually cannot. It is basically impossible.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Yeah, for us.
But with better CV coverage, maybe we can fix this.
I don't know, but we gotta do something.
I,
I agree and I guess stay tuned everyone for
the upcoming awesome changes to CV E for now.
Just bask in your CV E
10-K I DS
that are going to be assigned for the next week or two
for a few more weeks.
Because, you know, as soon as like once January 1st hits, people are still
bringing up issues from the previous year,
about a
month, maybe two months. Usually and then it basically Peters out.
Oh,
man,
I can't wait.
How exciting.
Yeah.
All right. Happy CV E
10-K. Everyone.
I guess if you have any questions or comments, be sure to tweet us at hash Os S podcast,
check the show notes at open source security podcast.com
where I'll put links to all the fun things we talked about
and if nothing else until next time.