Hello and welcome to the Open source Security podcast episode 185 with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
-- So,
-- what's new?
I think spring is almost here.
-- I hope so, man. I need it. Yeah.
-- No, it's, uh,
yeah,
exactly. So funny enough. I was watching the news this morning.
One of the things I do in my mornings is I turn on the news,
I read the newspaper and I drink coffee and the people
on the news said that we have received 20 inches more
of snow than is average at this point already in the year.
And that's not enjoyable. Right.
It's a lot of shoveling. It is a lot of shoveling and I'm, I'm done with snow now.
So if it never snows again, I'm cool with that.
-- Well,
-- except for them, the widespread crop failures would be a problem.
I feel it seems like a small price to
-- pay for my personal convenience
-- for not shoveling.
I, I'm not going to disagree with you
anyway.
So we are going to discuss the Linux Foundation today.
There's a news story that just came out
when, at the time of recording.
But why don't you explain it to the listeners and we'll go from there.
So, the Linux Foundation has done something that I think is actually quite useful.
It's called the Census. And so the basic premise is they look at the open source
ecosystem and look at sort of
what software really matters, right?
And some of it's, you know, we know it's obvious like open SSL, basically,
if something does crypto
in the open source world, it's what 98 let's say, percent chance.
-- It's probably using open SSL
-- without question.
Yes,
-- but
-- they're looking at things that are maybe a little
less obvious but widely used or widely relied upon.
You know, my favorite example being what was that thing?
It was called like Left shift. And the guy, what did he do?
He like took it off of no Js or whatever. And it broke like every website on the planet,
right? And all it did was like justify text to the left or something.
-- It
-- removed spaces,
I think before text and the actually
the metadata in that package was magnitudes larger
than the actual code because it was like three or four lines of code.
-- Yeah,
-- I remember it was like four lines of code.
And I was kind of wondering like, as much as I, I, you know, we,
we a lot of people say the classic, you know, you should use a library,
not cut and paste code, but in this case,
you probably should cut and paste the code because,
you know, it's like
string stripping.
That's not the node way though. No
N PM is all about having millions of dependencies that all do one obscure thing.
And I've even seen ones that are like a configuration thing,
like they set up their configuration as libraries because,
well, that's kind of the only way they know how to pull stuff in. But anyway,
so the census two report, I forget when they did the first one.
But I'm, oh, here it says, uh in 2015.
So it's been a while. Well, every five years, isn't that?
-- How often the US does a census,
-- 10 years, every 10 years we're due this year,
actually.
Oh, interesting.
Yeah, I mean, they basically look at this and
there's a lot of software that isn't widely known but is widely used.
There's also a lot of software that
probably has more vulnerabilities than it should for how much it's used
and relied upon.
That's fair. I mean, what's amusing to me is that
we're still sort of trotting up this line that, you know,
somehow open sources is still growing.
It's not folks, it's, it's one like it's what,
80% of the world's software or something.
Now
that's actually in use or something.
In the, in the
article we will link in the show notes.
Apparently Red Hat did a study and it's somewhere between 80
90%. And I believe that 100% because I know in, in the
elastic universe we've done a bunch of analysis of our source code
and it is about 80% dependencies and 20% stuff we wrote.
-- And
-- I kind of wonder how much of that skews
because a lot of these dependencies are huge in that.
This isn't like a small package that does one tiny little specific thing.
It started out that way, but then it started doing other things. And you know, they,
the thing I always love about pulling these libraries is a bunch of
other people spent five years chasing down all the corner cases for me.
Right. Well, and there's an unusual aspect of this and I'm actually still,
I'm writing a bunch of blog posts to try to help explain what's going on here.
When you use a dependency, a
library you pull in.
Like you said, there's all these corner cases,
there's often a lot of features that it uses.
It's not just one little thing in many cases. And this is actually where I think no,
like it actually handles more than one currency,
right? For example, and
most people are only using one small portion of it.
And so, well, yes, let's say it pulls in 10,000 lines of code. I might only be using
a
and lines of that code in my project.
But then it also creates issues because now I
have 10,000 lines of code I'm technically not using
and some of it will have security issues and
like the problem is crazy and very difficult.
Well, and then there's even like the lower level bits where they pull in XML or G
zip so that it'll compile natively on windows.
You know, I remember with the XML hash
do stuff way back in the day when I started at
Red Hat and looking at all this stuff and I'm like,
why is this stuff
pulling in G zip and you know XML,
it's like we provide libraries for that and then I start reading all these, you know,
packages and it's like, oh so,
so it'll compile on windows cleanly because on windows you
don't have like G zip dot So or whatever.
And even in, I mean, depending upon your environment now,
like with the universe of containers where it's
all about let's run the smallest possible container.
It's becoming common practice again to just kind
of pull in all these binary objects.
-- And that's how you deploy your software now.
-- Well,
the reality is a statically compiled binary with, you know,
containers being like the extreme example of that work, you turn them on, they run,
right.
And you rarely have problems where the version of the library you have on the system.
Windows 95 DLL hell, I mean,
-- right. You and I have both been through that
-- even on Linux
man, I mean,
I remember
this, I mean, this is a million years ago, but
I worked at an ISP and we bought like a binary
application that was designed to run on Red Hat.
It was Red Hat Linux back then, probably version four or five.
It was long, long ago and we installed it and nothing worked
because it was expecting certain libraries in certain places.
And I remember we ended up just like,
manually putting things in weird places just to make this stupid thing work.
-- And it was, that was terrible. I mean, it was so obnoxious. It
-- wasn't Se Linux
that I used, but I used something, I think it was like, I notify or something.
I basically, I would like, run the program
and like, see what binary or library was looking for and what location and then like,
yeah, copy it there,
simlink it there and then run the program again and
it would get like one step further and fail.
-- Uh
-- There's,
you know, there's something called LDD,
which is the linker and if you run the linker against a binary,
it will tell you what libraries it's looking for.
That'll let you cheat. True.
But some of these, I remember having software that was so broken and brittle that,
you know, it needed the libraries in a specific location or,
or be ever infamous
one where it needed something totally different from the system.
-- That yeah, that happens all the time. It was terrible.
-- Do I see a truth?
This thing, you know, run it in a jail, like, or do I just like,
right? S
-- link and just document it and pray it never breaks.
-- Yep. Yep.
No, I remember those days.
So, so anyway, anyway, we're talking about the Linux Foundation and their,
their census,
they did and all these applications and I feel like
I'm going to take a somewhat controversial stance here and
we get to argue which is fun.
But
so the Linux Foundation did this work
and they identified these problems and I think that's wonderful,
but then they start talking about what they're doing to make it better.
And I feel like the Linux Foundation should be doing more.
I think they are in a position to
accomplish great things.
And I feel like they have squandered what they have
attempted and I'm sure not a super popular view.
Every time I look at what they, what I feel like they could or should be doing.
I feel like they are not living up to my expectations.
Well, I'm not going to 100% disagree with you.
But at the same time having kind of lived through similar efforts like the DWF, it's,
it's more complicated than that.
I, I won't disagree with you and it is hard
and I think there's a other side of the coin even
where there's the angle of what, what they could or should do.
And then there's the angle of this is the world we have,
how do we make it better or rather how do we exist in it versus saying, oh, we should,
you know, the, this software is owned by a dude in his basement.
-- So how do we, how do we fix that? It's
-- like the Coronavirus thing.
Just have everybody self isolate for 14 days and the plague will burn itself out.
That's totally reasonable. Yes,
that's my dream, my dream, Kurt,
I'll isolate myself forever and then I'll never get sick.
It's wonderful. But
no, I say that, I,
I bet after 14 days I would be climbing the
walls like I would talk to anybody at that point.
But anyway, anyway,
so kind of, here's, here's the example I want to give.
So I'll, we'll pick on Low Dash because we picked on them a couple of episodes ago.
-- So Lo Dash is a project that's literally owned by a person.
-- I think they didn't, it
-- finally open
-- up?
Uh Not, not that I know of. That was not Lo Dash. That was the, what
a
web
that was.
Yeah.
They hit rock bottom.
Like,
-- isn't there yet? I believe
-- they had an intervention and it's working itself.
So it's a person
and they own it
and they're obviously busy and this isn't their job or anything like that.
And so we have the universe of saying
and, and we did this where we're like, oh,
you should open this up to the community. You should accept help.
There's all these things you can do and there's nothing wrong with saying that.
And I feel like that's what the Linux foundation is doing also.
But at the same time,
how do we look at this and say, OK, so I have a piece of code
that's literally maintained by a guy in his basement.
How do we make sure that it's secure and it's something I can
run safely because I understand that this is the world we live in.
-- So be it
-- one step, for example,
would be committing some resources to it and say
submitting some patches that improve it or fix bugs.
People have done that and the author isn't accepting them.
And then that's kind of where we go to step two, right?
So if the author does accept your patches and things move on, then it's, you know,
reasonably healthy, right?
But if it's, if the author is not accepting your patches or not talking,
then, well, by definition, that's not super healthy.
And, you know, maybe they're busy, maybe they're sick, maybe they have a real job,
maybe, you know,
I remember one case the person went on was on vacation
for like months like they were off in Asia or something.
-- You know, when one of those big kerfuffles hit it
-- can happen. And
that's an instance where
nothing
is a different message than a no,
I won't take your patch because I don't want to or I won't take it now because I'm busy,
I'll look at it again later someday
and, and part of my thinking would be so if you try to submit good patches
and that's the thing too. A lot of people think they're submitting good patches and,
well,
you know,
there's a lot of emails from Lynes Torvalds
on this topic that's
hilariously bad.
Well, but he's not always wrong.
Sometimes he's wrong, but usually he's not completely wrong.
He could be a bit nicer about it though. So in that case, no offense.
But one of the real significant freedoms of open source is you can fork
it and go take your ball and play in your own yard with it.
Yeah, but we, we talked about this a couple of episodes ago like forking.
Well, but I mean, if it's,
if it's that critical for you and you really need
it to work and you really need these patches then,
well, suck it up.
-- Buttercup.
-- I mean, no, no, it doesn't work like that anymore
because if you're using, say N PM
as part of your node project,
you're going to be pulling in dependencies and those
dependencies are going to pull in other things.
-- That's an unrealistic expectation
-- card.
It is, I think an unrealistic expectation.
But then it also speaks to what these people expect from
the ecosystem to get sort of for free as it were.
This is exactly where, where I think we wanted to go with this is.
So,
you have the Linux Foundation talking about the way the world should
work and they've dedicated resources into
various projects and in all seriousness,
I don't think they've been runaway successes.
-- I think you could argue.
-- They're trying to boil the ocean. Yes. Right.
Like, like it's like trying to get CV, coverage for all of the world's software.
-- Right. The answer is it's not going to happen.
-- Exactly. You're exactly right.
The Linux Foundation cast their net wide
-- and they've missed everything.
-- Well, part of the problem too is there's
like this, how do I put this nicely?
The software industry is so fundamentally broken
that quote unquote.
The first lesson learned from this report is the
need for a standardized naming scheme for software components.
And that's never happening.
You know,
number two, the increasing importance of individual developer account security,
right?
Yeah, easy. We'll just get all the developers to, you know, go turn on two fa
github
super
easy.
And then, oh, and this is my favorite,
the persistence of legacy software in the open source space.
I've worked for Red Hat. So, you know, I'm kind of guilty of this one.
-- I I was part of the problem here.
-- These problems are never going to go away.
These are problems like saying, oh, the problem with crime is people steal stuff.
So, you know, if, if everybody just stopped stealing stuff or
you know, nobody ever lost a house key or left their left the door unlocked or uh well,
yeah, perfect example, if nobody ever left a door or a window unlock
open,
you know,
there'd be a bit less crime because like there are literally people
go around jiggling door handles and then if the door is open,
they, you know, clear out your glove box or whatever.
Sure. Uh Yeah, that would help reduce crime of it.
But, well, like the Coronavirus, if everybody would just for the love of Pete,
just wash your hands once in a while with soap.
No, like seriously, dude, how often have you been in a bathroom with other adults?
And one of them uses the toilet or in case the
journal
-- and then walks out of the room,
-- we discussed this
a couple of I think last it was two episodes ago.
Whenever we talk about the Coronavirus,
we can't get people to wash their hands reliably.
I know, man, you're proving all of my points for me, I think.
Well,
I guess the point then is maybe the lungs foundation
isn't doing so bad given these insane constraints of reality,
they're collecting and spending a lot of money.
So if that's a goal, they're doing great.
But,
but
the point is
there's all these realities and
you're never going to change many of them. And so we have to exist in that universe.
Like I'll give you a great example of at restaurants.
There is a 100% chance that some of the staff
don't wash their hands when they use the toilet.
Otherwise there wouldn't be signs
that's true.
But there are other controls in place where you
expect them to wear gloves and wear other material.
And there's expectations around handling of certain things, right?
Like this is all related where the people who are creating these rules around food,
health and safety know that part of the story means there are people using
the toilet and not washing their hands even though there's a sign that says
-- they must do it.
-- Yeah. And so this is lovely.
The CDC in America estimates one in six
Americans are affected by foodborne illnesses annually.
I have no doubt. I'm shocked it's that low.
-- I would expect it to be much, much higher.
-- One in six is a lot.
Yeah, it is a lot.
That's like more than, that's more people, that's more than people that get the flu.
I believe that though because people go out
to eat a lot.
Well, this also counts as like food that, you know, like the,
remember when all the spinach was contaminated by wild pig poop?
Yes. Yes, I do.
So, actually my wife caught a parasite eating lettuce one time.
-- It was some, like, you've got to cook
-- your lettuce, man. You've got to boil that.
Exactly.
And it was funny because she got like all these
phone calls from the county Health Department and they're like,
no.
And she was in Indiana
and caught it and then came back to Wisconsin and, yeah,
like everyone was freaking out.
It was beautiful. It was some little, uh,
one of the single cell parasite
Deos.
And then, yeah, like you take some medicine, you're fine after a couple of days.
-- Well, let's assume
-- you identify what it is and have the medicine available. Uh.
Right.
-- And it did take a week to figure it out
-- and that's
something we sort of take for granted in the western world.
We can go to a doctor,
see a doctor relatively quickly and then get medicine from the pharmacy.
-- Right. Usually all in a period of less than half a day.
-- That's right. Actually.
So, it's funny you say that to us.
So, my,
my daughter has what they call Colonial Day at school today when we're recording
and they, like, go dress up, they pretend they're old timey and they,
they do all this old timey stuff.
Are they allowed to use bandaids if they get hurt?
I, I probably,
but they,
she was talking about how, oh, everyone was probably sick all the time.
And I just, I remember I was, I was working on my computer.
I looked up, I said everyone had worms,
all of them had worms all the time and they had lice and she's like,
-- like,
-- well, yeah, what was it, the whole thing in the Southern Us with,
with toilets and privy and ringworm, you know,
because people were walking around in bare feet all the time.
-- No one
-- wore shoes. Exactly. Everyone had no hookworms.
Hookworms are what you get in the toilet.
Yes.
Yeah. Things we take for granted in the morning.
Seriously. Like no one has worms anymore. It's one. Well, we don't. But
anyway, why are we talking about worms? We're talking
about software.
Well, I, I think the,
it's kind of a very close analogy to sort of the current health state of the open
source ecosystem.
You know, actually, you're right. I, I agree.
-- It's
-- this low level of parasite that's not going to kill you.
But, you know, is there an ex ss in your web framework?
Yes. Yes, there is. And what was that Cryptocurrency place
-- that just had to shut down because of an ex ss?
-- Right?
-- I don't remember the name but I know what you mean.
-- Yeah.
So, you know, sometimes these little parasites are well,
if you're not healthy then, then they're really, really bad.
And so I guess let's stay on this topic for a minute because if you think about it,
from the health perspective, you have,
there are certain things you can do for prevention.
But even if you do everything you could possibly do for prevention, like,
let's say you wash your hands and you make sure your
food is clean and you're getting it from a good source,
whatever you can still get sick
there is, there's nothing that says you won't, you will get sick.
You will. But you might not get worms. Right.
Like, to my knowledge, I've never had worms.
-- I'm sure part of that is because I take certain precautions.
-- Right.
Well, but we also live in the western world where we've got, you know,
massive controls at scale.
So that,
you know, we don't have to worry about things like cholera because the, you know,
the vast majority of North Americans use toilets.
They don't go in the street, thank goodness anymore.
So, I think like a lot of things, you know,
when 99% of people do a reasonably sane behavior,
like washing their hands after they go to the bathroom and before they handle food,
then you can sort of start to nip this
stuff in the bud and prevent widespread outbreaks.
You'll, you'll still have outbreaks but they're very localized.
They, they sort of, they don't transmit,
they don't kind of break out of the one
restaurant that had one person doing one bad thing.
Right. Right. Right. But now let's compare it to software.
And I feel like we're at the point where people are
dumping the chamber pots out the window into the street right now
and there's little, there's not a lot of good hygiene.
No. Well, and it's hard though, like, even something.
And I say a simple with giant air quotes here,
continuous integration and continuous delivery,
like having a good testing framework or not even having a good testing framework.
But having a
framework for testing,
you can actually write test, right? Remember when we had the guy on the show
and they're talking about, that's one of the big problems,
a lot of these projects have, they, they don't even have a testing framework,
let alone test.
And even having like a blank testing framework would be
a massive step forward because now you have the possibility of
writing tests and
actually running them once in a while.
And yeah, the majority of software, well, I mean,
whenever you see a really simplistic regression, well,
obviously there's something a bit deeper missing
there because that should not have happened.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Yeah. No, I
I agree. I agree completely.
And it's, it's part of, it's part of the larger story,
right is where you have this way to test and to understand
what's happening in your environment.
But even with that, right,
there's still going to be instances where things get missed, bad things get in,
right?
-- It's again like going back to health
-- also new things.
Remember when you know, buffer overflows were Black magic.
I mean, remember when return oriented programming first came along and it was like,
who
is this?
-- And now it's just a thing, it's a Wikipedia page like whatever
-- again,
like if we compare this to public health,
there are new diseases happening all the time,
right? Like Coronavirus is a brand new disease that we've never seen before.
And now we have to figure out what to do with it. And this is
this exactly parallels
world of security where new techniques are found, new problems are found.
And now you have to figure out what to do with it.
And I feel like we still have that attitude of we can fix this instead of saying,
all right, we got a new problem.
How do we like, stop everyone from dying and like 10% of people dying is,
is the best we're going to get.
Well,
I mean, the one real thing I see in the infosec industry is that whole,
the perfect be the enemy of the good, you know,
so many infosec people want it perfect.
And it's like, well, number one ain't gonna happen.
I got bad news for you but it's just like like fishing and what is,
what do they call S MS fishing attack?
I think they call it smashing and fishing and spear fishing and all that stuff.
That degree of social engineering will never go away because it will always work.
Exactly.
And so part of it is not solving it, but it's, you know,
a
great example is this, I noticed in gmail now
I use the Marcus spam button maybe once or twice a week.
-- Remember what it was like 10 or 20 years ago?
-- It, it used to be bad, in fact.
So I, I look, I was digging through my spam folder,
the other day because I was expecting a message and I didn't see it.
And so I was like, maybe it's in spam and it actually was,
but I was looking in there in my spam folder is almost all sales.
Now, I'm like, this is awesome.
This is the dream.
The spam email I do get is actually typically directly emailed to me. And it's
like, it's I didn't ask for it.
So it's spam but it's not like spam spam, you know, it's actually somewhat targeted.
And yeah. Yeah, whenever I do look through my, my folder, it's just like, oh,
you know. Yeah. No, that, that is clearly not stuff I want,
you know, what else amazes me is.
Some of these companies are emailing me like three and four
times a day and I think, do they know they're going in the spam folder?
-- And they're hoping one of the mail sneaks out
-- well,
but it's cheaper to do that than to clean their email list,
-- I guess.
-- Yeah,
it's, but it's not the same mail. They're like all different. It's, it's terrible.
Well, my favorite is too is like, I'll look for the unsubscribe link now, you know,
hit control f unsubscribe and a lot of emails still don't have it.
They'll have like reply with removed or whatever.
And I'm like, oh, those I mar a spam and hope to never see again.
Right.
But back to the public health kind of thing is I think part of the problem is, is that
with these online epidemics of, you know,
some virus or Trojan or some attack goes through.
I don't want to say we have good visibility into how bad it is, but it's kind of,
it does tend to be, especially if it's like a major site.
We do tend to be,
we, we think it's really bad,
usually a lot worse than it is a great example being like that
iot attack that bled over and they had to shut down a major,
I think it was a natural gas pipeline or something.
So, you know, information security people always kind of want perfect like,
you know, like spam filtering.
Oh, I want 100% of spam filter and no,
the reality is like one or two spams getting through to your inbox a week.
That's acceptable. It's annoying.
But, you know, it's only a few minutes a year of your time. Right.
I think the problem becomes when we're looking at global scale, you know,
one or two minutes per person across the entire world.
Yeah, that, that is actually kind of terrible.
The reality is I don't think we're ever going to get
to these perfect solutions of like blocking all phishing emails or
-- blocking all viruses or
-- fixing all of the open source software.
-- Everyone uses,
-- getting all the XSS fixed,
even ignoring Xs si think things like getting,
expecting every developer to secure their account.
It's not a realistic expectation.
-- It's never going to happen. Yeah.
-- And I mean, should we push developers to do it?
Absolutely.
I mean, I, you know,
am heavily encouraging people to use two factor authentication.
Right. Right. You know, it,
it's frustrating to me that a lot of these websites allow credential stuffing.
It's like, why, why are you allowing somebody to try and log into my account?
You know, a million times over the span of 24 hours?
-- Like,
-- well, they don't try your account,
they use the same password on all the accounts,
-- right? It's the reverse of that,
-- right?
And well, and I feel like that, you know,
-- the bank it system should be somewhat smart enough to detect that
-- you'd think
like, except they're not,
but it's also an
-- externalized cost for like them, for example.
-- Oh,
yeah.
Yeah, it's not their problem.
But I guess, ok, so I'm,
I'm formulating some ideas in my mind at this point and I feel like there's,
there's the stance the Linux foundation has that says this is
what we should do and there's nothing wrong with saying that,
but I think expecting it is unrealistic
and this is where you have to say, ok, so let's assume,
let's say 80% of open source developers are using two factor authentication,
that means 20% of them aren't.
So what am I going to do for the fact that 20% of the open source I'm running
doesn't have strong authentication for developers and
could acquire malicious code because of it.
How do I defend against that scenario?
-- And I never hear anyone actually say that
-- part
of the problem is you can't because we just,
we can't have that depth of data to know that like
this project has these people with two fa enabled or not.
No, no, we don't.
No and we never will.
And so this is we're doing things like segmenting services
-- and running code in sandboxes
-- providers like github could,
for example, put a little mark on the web page saying, you know, because in github,
you can require an organization to use two of a, it is true.
And so for example,
github could maybe publicly start showing that or allow it
to be publicly shown so that people could advertise,
let's become the Apache Foundation because they're usually pretty competent.
I'm guessing the Apache Foundation probably
has reasonable two factor authentication policies across all their stuff.
I would hope so.
And if they could show, you know, if they could have like a little flag in their github
page that says, you know, look, yeah, we, we have two of a turned on across the board,
it's enforced.
So this is an interesting concept you speak of.
And I think you're right because so like I'll pick on the Linux Foundation again.
They have their ci I badges, which is the core.
In fact, we talked to David Wheeler years ago now about CIA
and I still think it's a cool idea, but the reality is,
it's not widely deployed and I think it's
because it's voluntary and anytime anything is voluntary,
you're just not going to have a large uptake.
I bet you have something like 20 to 25% uptake max in an instance like that.
Whereas github doesn't need to ask you,
it doesn't have to make it voluntary or they can just do it because they
actually have the information you need to say
this project has two factor often enabled.
This project is using our security advisory. This, you know what I mean?
Do they say when a project is using their security advisories or not?
Not that I know of,
I haven't seen anything.
-- I feel like that would be a really good, I'm guessing it's a really good sign.
-- I agree.
No. Absolutely.
Because I feel like if you publish security advisories,
if you get C vs that shows a certain amount of understanding of security
versus
-- like I have no idea what I'm doing. Well.
-- Most well and
problem too is it's always, it's not just an understanding of security,
but it's actually brushing your teeth every day,
wash your hands, brush your teeth,
90% of problems
and
look man flossing, I think is a bridge too far for most people.
I think if everyone just brushes their teeth in the morning and at night,
that would be a huge first step.
But I mean, you just did it right.
This is what everyone does where we think, ok, here's an easy thing you could do.
Oh, but also you should do this hard thing that no one else wants to do. Right.
No, just start
-- easy. Make it easy. That's how we have to do it.
-- I'm
-- also
-- hesitant to have github
just start publishing this information about projects without their,
I guess I want to say consent.
You have to boil the frog, right? You can't just flip a switch.
You start by letting people opt in and then you talk about how neat it is and you show
how powerful it is and you just slowly turn on
one feature here and there and here and there.
And before you know it, you've done it all. In fact,
this, this topic came up, there's, there's a new type of shoe, I guess that the,
like some
athletic association has banned because they decided the shoe gives the runners
too many advantages over people without the shoe.
Anyway, this art, I'll see if I can find it. I don't know if I can.
It was, it was very obscure. I remember when I read it.
But anyway, it was basically the author was talking about how
in the world of athletics,
you can't turn the knob up too fast or people notice and your product gets banned.
But if you turn it up nice and slow after a couple of years, you're actually exactly
where you would have been two years earlier.
But by turning it up slow, you can get there. If you turn it up too fast, then you get,
you know, the rules are changed and your products are banned.
And that's exactly what
Github's situation is where if they turn the knob too fast, people will be like,
whoa, I hate this.
This is, you know, nonsense.
I'm moving my project over here to whatever so they can do it.
They just have to do it slow.
Yeah, it sounds fair.
I'm just looking through this and it's not even,
yeah, like I'm just clicking around on this and there's all these,
they have zero security advisories.
There's, and, oh, and so you can see if they have a policy or not. So that's good.
And you can see if they've published advisories or not,
but there's no easy way to kind of scrape this data.
-- I, I would imagine. Yeah, it'd be great
-- if there was a big button
or is there?
-- Maybe, I don't
-- know, there's an api, I bet you could get it,
but it'd be a pain in the butt.
But it would be nice to be able to say, for example, you know, well,
in my C I or CD system again,
assuming I have my magic C I Canon to shoot me out into magic C I land,
you know, having a, having a flag saying, you know,
check all these dependencies to make sure they have a security policy or make sure
they have published a security advisory at least
once because they've all had security flaw.
Right. Right.
-- No, I agree. Those would
-- be indicators.
Here's the thing.
What, what do you do with that because you're not going to not use the dependency.
You know, as we were talking about earlier,
what you're gonna,
you're gonna rewrite all the code you pull in to use some other dependency.
-- No,
-- you're
-- going
-- to use it because working is more important than security.
And again, though, this is where step two comes in.
So let's assume they didn't wash their hands.
So now what do we do to add another layer of protection?
And we don't have a the answer for that today
and nor should we honestly,
the one thing I keep coming back to with
this is having the ability to push updates quickly,
full stop because you're going to need that anyways.
You're going to want that anyways.
-- All right, man,
-- we should, we should call this one.
I think we've, we've rambled on for long enough and I guess if I was going to sum it up,
it's just
a matter of, I think these discussions are good to have,
but I think we need to be more realistic in our expectations and say,
expecting to change the world in the ways like
the Linux Foundation is looking for right now is not
-- realistic. So like, what is the bar? I don't
-- know.
I'm going to gently disagree on that. I think Github
is starting to do more good and I hope they turn up the heat and
boil the frog a bit faster because looking at some of the work they're doing,
they clearly have good intentions around security.
I hope they move a bit faster because I suspect that wouldn't be a bad thing.
-- Well, we will
-- see it would make people uncomfortable,
but we don't have 50 years to fix the software industry.
Right?
We have zero years
or maybe it doesn't matter and we have infinite years. I have no idea. All right.
Anyway, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open
source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show note,
UZ Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on
social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.