Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 170 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
How are you doing?
Good. Uh I
-- thought I would open up a bank account today. Oh my
-- goodness.
We just argued about not talking about this.
So basically the story is this bank in Canada
and in Canada, you can rather easily open up an account online.
You know, you don't have to go into the branch.
Um And this is actually kind of handy because we have a
couple of banks in Canada that are basically online only or,
you know, heavily regional.
Like they, they,
there's a couple of major banks that just don't have like
they have like a branch in Edmonton, right?
Ok.
So anyways, this bank
was as part of their process to validate.
You was asking for your bank account details
including your pin number at a different institution,
which is really dumb.
I don't approve of that.
And then they also refused. They basically said no, no, it's secure.
We scrub the data,
they didn't say what they do with the data, but they said,
and they were very clear that they scrub the data.
I'm, I'm sure they're using military
grade encryption.
It's
scrubbing,
right. Everything's
military grade scrubbing. I'm sure that's fine too.
Right. Yeah, whatever.
It's all good.
So
yeah, see it asked for all my personal details and everything.
As for my tax info, my sin number, identity verification,
which is, that's all you need.
You don't need my banking information at another bank and more
to the point what if I don't have another bank account?
-- Because I'm, this is my first bank account. Here
-- is my suspicion
is why you need to do this. And I recently helped my Children open bank accounts.
So it's been a couple of years a year or two now.
But basically when you open a bank account, at least in the United States,
you need to present certain identifying information.
And in our case,
it was basically passports is what we showed up with
and the banks were happy because passports are hard to get
and they assume if you have one that you went through all the crazy hoops you need.
Otherwise my suspicion is this bank
wants to say, well, if you already have a bank account at another bank,
we're going to assume you already jumped through all these
crazy hoops and we're going to use this as proof.
You are who you say you are.
And I don't think I'm not saying it's right.
I just have a suspicion that is their thinking here.
Yeah.
I, I don't know,
regardless the fact that they won't come clean on how they use
the data or how they process it where they store it.
And they just simply say this, we scrub it
like, you know, no, like it goes to the web server, it ends up in memory,
it might be written to disk in a temporary file, you know, ends up in,
it's going to go to a database somewhere.
Most likely do they scrub the database securely.
I bet whoever wrote that doesn't even know what that means.
That's like, I'll never forget when
there was the whole Hillary Clinton snafu in the US
email server. And a reporter asked her, did you scrub the server?
-- No. Did you wipe the server or
-- no? Did you wipe the server? She
like with a rag?
Oh my goodness.
And that's what I feel like here like you scrub the data.
You have no idea what that means.
You,
you probably delete it and you don't realize it's stored on 30
disks because of all the systems it's been transferred through anyway.
Uh It, it's stupid
and I think this is one of those marvelous examples of people.
-- Well,
-- what's interesting is the banking industry of Canada said no, this is fine,
like the, the spokesman for the bank, whatever thing of Canada was like, no, this is,
this is ok.
And of course the privacy. Uh Well, this is what annoys me.
They had a farmer, a former privacy commissioner that of course is like,
this is absolutely not ok.
And this is highly questionable and needs to be explained in detail.
You know,
because we have spent all this time and effort teaching people your bank will
never ask you for your password or your pin number unless it's your bank,
right?
You shouldn't give that information to other banks or other people.
How much time have we spent telling people, you know,
your ISP is not going to be calling you and be like, hey Mr Bresser,
uh I need to reset your account.
So can I get your password, please?
Sure, sign me up, you know, or Google,
Google is not going to call you and ask
you for your email password nor will Microsoft.
I have a funny thing I can tell you about is I remember there
was a long time ago we were changing cell phone providers and we,
I, I use T mobile now and my, my wife is actually doing most of the work because I was,
I was working at the time
and,
and I couldn't get off, I don't even remember the details.
But anyway, she calls me and says we need your password.
I said, oh, I'll just email it to you.
And she's like, ok,
and it was,
I think about 50 characters long
and
I, I emailed it to her
and basically the, the T mobile person
insisted on like they typed it in, they for whatever reason.
And I remember I told them, I said, here's like, you know, whatever transfer,
whatever you need, there was a bunch of information.
I forget all the details. Now it was special pins and stuff
and they were insistent on having this password like, ok.
And then I remember they said, can you make it shorter? And I said no,
like if you won't listen to me and take this stuff I gave
you you actually need instead this BS you can type this in.
-- It was
-- beautiful. So interesting. I just got to the screen where it asked me for this.
So it says identity verification,
your login,
sorry, it's not my PIN. It's my login credentials from a financial institution.
Help us confirm that it is. In fact, you completing the application
and they are, I'm going to click on this
and they actually want
my user name or access card, not my pin number. They want my online password to my
my other bank.
-- That's marvelous.
-- I am taking a screenshot of this.
This is no, I, I mean,
I thought it was bad enough that it was like the pin number and stuff,
but they actually want my online account number
-- and the password to access it.
-- That's bananas.
Wow, that's
ok. And if I click my bank is not on the list,
uh what happens here.
So they list basically and the thing is they
only list like seven banks which granted in Canada,
those seven banks cover
the majority of people but they don't cover
like they don't have the Canadian Western Bank.
They don't have a TB, you know,
Alberta Treasury Branch, they just have a couple of national ones. Um,
and if I click, my bank is not in the list,
I get sent to
enter my personal information yet again. Like my name and phone number and stuff.
Ok.
What in the heck? Salutation Mr
or Miss Weird.
So this is like this is hysterically terrible.
I'm not even a little surprised. I don't know what to tell you. Kurt. I think you have
your, your expectations don't match reality, the vast majority.
Oh, they're forcing you to make an appointment.
They, they will not let you complete an all online account set up without giving them
the login details to another live bank account that you own
or you can go see them and show them your documents, which is acceptable.
But I think giving online information is bananas.
Yeah,
I am.
-- Wow. I mean,
-- anyway,
wow,
this is,
I didn't expect it to actually like the,
I,
I kind of want to set up an online bank now and just
apparently this is acceptable.
No, your, your plan of defrauding your customers is illegal.
-- They're not
-- my customers yet. Nope, they're not my customers though.
These people are just dumb.
There's a difference, right. Fraud and stupidity
aren't the same thing.
See, here's what gets me is how many people did this before this one guy spoke up
and raised a ruckus about it. Right. That a lot did unreal.
Well, so to the guy who spoke up, I'm not going to say, well, you know, you,
you're in the news.
Ok.
So, uh, to Paul
Kaminsky, good on you, buddy, like straight up,
good on you for going to the press and raising a stink about this.
That, that was the correct thing to do.
You know if you see something really weird, say something.
Yeah, except do you think anyone's going to care enough here,
here's how this is going to go down.
If the Canadian banking regulators decide this is bad, they will shut this down
if it's just up to the press,
nothing's going to happen because enough people don't understand this.
I don't think you're going to see a high enough level
of outrage from the public to actually drive any change.
Hopefully.
Well, hopefully this piece of, uh, can be an educational opportunity to, um,
you know, like no, really,
when we say you shouldn't be giving your user name and password to other people,
you really shouldn't even if it is a bank or something,
but an educational opportunity for who, who is going to learn from this.
-- Well,
-- hopefully people who read the CBC article,
-- how many people do you think that is? I mean,
-- honestly
it's on the front page of the local news online.
And how many people do you think that is of the,
we'll assume you have a population of people.
Like, literally everybody I know in my age group reads the CBC news. That's
where we get the news.
Where can we get our news from the sun? The Facebooks.
You forget that the CBC has a special relationship here in Canada. Right.
It's the Canadian Broadcast Corporation and it's,
it's similar to the BBC in stature in that. It's a scene as a,
not a fully neutral news organization,
but reasonably neutral and reasonably truthful
-- and honest and reasonably
-- correct.
No, no, I understand.
And actually that's probably fair in Canada, it might be different.
But I know like in the United States, the number of people who actually
read the news is laughable at best and even then of them,
I wouldn't expect most people to read or understand this sort of article.
I, I'd be shocked if the reach in the United States,
if a similar story was published on any, let's say, on a national level
to hit more than 10% of, of people.
Yeah.
And even then of them, you have to figure,
I bet at least half won't have a freaking clue what's going on.
-- Well,
-- I, I think part of the problem here is so, for example,
here we go sharing sign and access with another Canadian
financial Institution for a legitimate purpose such as opening an account
online is acceptable and this is from the uh CB A,
the Canadian Banking Association spokesperson.
On the flip side,
we have the Canadian anti fraud Center which
collects information on internet fraud and identification theft complaints
and funnily enough.
They don't recommend people sharing the login details with anyone
which is fair.
Yeah, so which is it? See, my concern is
um I've now had the occasion where my bank or one of my
banks rather actually called me out of the blue and was like,
hey Mr Siefried bla
bla and I'm thinking it's a sales call, right?
So no big deal annoying but not the end of the world.
And they're like, can I verify that you are Kurt?
And I'm like,
yeah, and they're like, ok, I just need to ask some personal details.
I'm like, ok and they're like, can you share, you know your um was it like your,
your name and address and stuff with us?
And I'm like, no,
he's like what I'm like,
I need you to prove that you're calling from my bank first and he's like, well
uh caller ID and I'm like, yeah, that can be faked.
I'm like, prove to me that you're calling from my bank and they can't, they won't.
And what annoys me is
I have
a
pin number with my bank for, for online like for phone banking.
Can't they have a pin number with me to validate themselves to
-- me
-- because everyone's going to lose the pin and forget about it.
Well, they already have their pin, they have to keep their pin for their themselves.
So, they're already doing this
if they do online.
No, no, no one's going to do this because nobody cares enough to do it.
How many times do you think the bank has
ever entered into this sort of Mexican standoff situation?
-- You're probably the first.
-- Oh, absolutely.
I'm the first one that's ever happened because they, they literally were like,
I need to talk to my supervisor and then he's like, I don't know what to say or do.
And I'm like, well, thanks. Bye. You know, but I mean, this is part of my frustration.
This is why phishing and, you know, scams work so well is because even the companies
behave like fishers and scammers.
Right. Exactly. Exactly. It's, and it's never going to change, man.
And it's people, this is how people act.
Yeah.
I mean, well,
at least maybe people can get better educated because the reality is like,
if you teach people it's ok to do this,
-- going to do it. No,
-- people are, you can't educate this away.
-- This has to be solved with technology. I agree
-- that you can't educate it away.
But this is like telling kids it's ok to run across the street
-- without looking. It's
-- not.
-- And you tell them not
-- to, like,
this is actively teaching them to do something dangerous.
But thousands of Children are killed each year running across the street
without looking and we can tell them all we want and some,
some will listen and some will learn.
Most don't care and some are actually going to get killed.
Right.
But my point is if somebody was telling
Children to run across the street without looking,
I suspect most people would not be ok with that.
Ok. That point I will accept.
However, people understand why running across the street is bad.
People don't understand why sharing your user
-- name and password for the bank is bad.
-- Simple. They can go clean up your account.
You're insured. I'm sure it's probably fine.
You're only insured up to a certain amount.
And more interestingly in Canada, especially with online
e
people who've had their like email accounts and stuff hacked.
The banks have said well, too bad.
No, no, no, there's,
this has been an ongoing thing over the last few
months where there's been lots of cases where people,
you know, paid thousands of dollars and the company is like,
we didn't get the money turns out, you know,
their account got hacked and the banks like, well,
you should have kept your account more secure.
Too bad.
I, yeah, I don't know.
I, anyway,
anyway,
I,
I, I think it's time for a transition.
So I'm going to do the worst transition in the history of podcasts and just say so
quantum Supremacy,
-- you heard about that?
-- I assume that was a good bond film?
-- Was there a bond film called quantum supremacy
-- quantum of
solace?
Was it
the one where they blow that
hotel in Peru or something stupid?
I
don't know. I
don't watch a lot of movies and
I've seen a handful of James Bond films, but that one doesn't ring a bell.
So I don't know if I've seen it or not.
I don't know.
Anyway,
the whole quantum computing thing strikes me a lot like Blockchain and that
cool technology
not super useful yet.
And I suspect part of the problem is that
quantum is so fundamentally different from classical computing much
like Blockchain is very fundamentally different from classic,
you know, data storage and
processing techniques.
It, it doesn't map well to existing problems that we do understand and want to solve.
But given five or 10 years, we will find problems that it's good at solving and,
and use it for that.
Uh I want to add an important point before we actually get to.
The reason I brought it up is
the other,
I think unique and difficult problem that
both Blockchain and quantum computing have in common
is a nontrivial number of people have significantly over
prosed and comically under delivered
the um the, the classic um oh what is it the
oh the the the curve of, you know, the hype peak hype and then the, the, the,
the
the trough of disillusionment and then the plateau of productivity.
I don't remember the name of that, but I know what you mean. I know the picture.
We'll put it in the show
notes,
-- the
-- hope the hype cycle. Here we go. The hype.
It's literally called the hype cycle. I thought it had a fancier name than that.
Anyway,
so, so anyway, here is the reason
we bring I,
I bring this up is so Google recently claimed quantum supremacy by
solving some problem that would take traditional computers 10,000 years to solve.
And they did it in a couple of minutes.
It's always suspicious to me that it's such a round perfectly
zero filled number,
like not 9000, 927 but no 10,000
whatever. It's an, it's an estimate. They don't know.
Actually, we do know, we do know
we know the answer because actually IBM basically came back.
It was like, uh we can solve that and it takes 2.5 days on our supercomputer.
It's like, oh,
well, that's not 10,000 years
and maybe, maybe Raspberry Pi or something.
-- Well, on a, on my desktop, maybe
-- probably something like that. I imagine their
measuring stick of a computer was
not good.
And,
but, but
the, the thing I love about this
is, it's,
there was all this hype and everyone's like,
holy cow like it's real now it's the real thing.
And then finally IBM is like, no, it's not really yet.
And it's like, oh, my goodness.
Come on guys, this is so bad for the industry because yet it,
it feels like water on Mars, right?
How many times have we discovered water on Mars?
Or how many times has Voyager left the solar system? And it's like, holy crap.
I don't care
anymore. Like I just saw a story maybe a month ago.
They're like, oh Voyager left the solar or what Voyager one left the solar system.
I'm like, again, like how many freaking times this is gonna happen?
And it's the same thing with quantum supremacy is it's that constant. Oh Look at us.
Oh Look at us. Oh Look at us. And it's like I don't even care anymore.
Like unless you're cracking Rs A keys, I don't care. Shut up.
Well, it's,
that's literally part of the hype cycle
from what I understand of quantum computing.
It's
like I said,
it's probably not going to be especially great at solving
the problems we currently understand and want to solve.
But
at some point, we will find useful things.
Like, I mean, I look at web servers right back in the day,
web servers with little static content cool
turns out what web servers are actually good at is application to,
right? You know, I wouldn't have guessed that in 99.
Actually, the web server is still delivering relatively static content. It's just
there's some magic in front of it and behind it now that we didn't have.
Yeah, well, and javascript now. So the client side plus the backside
back end or whatever. And, um,
but, yeah, I mean, like, given that in 99 I wouldn't have guessed that, you know,
I'd be doing what I'm like,
I would not have guessed in 99 that I would
be doing my word processing in a web browser.
I
-- would agree with you. I feel like that was not necessarily expected.
-- Yeah.
-- No, emacs life forever.
-- Oh You're an emacs user. I still am.
You still use emacs. You're so you're the one.
-- It's
-- because I had eight megs of ra M in my second computer. So it actually worked.
I wasn't memory constrained like all the V I users.
That's right.
Uh That's why actually I remember when I worked at the, the ISP,
we would uninstall emacs because it used so much memory that we couldn't leave it on.
And in fact, I mean, we didn't have like V I, this was like V I from Sun.
That sucked.
But man, those are the days I don't want to ever go back to those.
But
anyway,
uh
Right.
So
this, I, so the reason I bring all this up and kind of the point of this story is
sometimes I feel like this even ties into
your bank discussion from a little while ago.
So look at me tying everything back in a nice bow.
But I think
security is notorious for this where we kind of, we, we have historically
and not so much promising fixing things but, like,
like portraying the threats of the industry
is we are constantly over hyping this stuff
and it never shows up and then people are like, well, now what?
And I think you end up in this cycle.
Well, it's not that it doesn't show up, it's worse, it shows up but it's not useful.
It's like a car with 17 wheels that goes half a mile per hour.
No, not just that.
I mean, how many times and I,
I haven't done this in years and years but I remember where someone
would build like something super insecure and you'd say you'll be sorry someday
and they never were, the only thing they were sorry about was tying to talk to me.
You know?
And
I think that's part of this kind of hype madness.
And this is probably where security got itself into trouble is.
We were all about, oh, everything is on fire. Everything is gonna burn down.
It's like, no, it really isn't.
I mean, things are mostly ok and, yeah, there's some problems but whatever.
-- Yeah. No life goes on. Right.
-- Right. And
I always, I always think of this and when people get, like, shocked and appalled
when they learn things like,
you know.
Yeah, I have a, my,
my Wi Fi password is terrible and I just connect everything to my Wi Fi network and
I use a password manager.
And I have an Android phone and they're like,
I thought you were a security guy and it's like, I'm a reformed security guy,
you know, I'm,
I'm not,
I'm not the way I used to be.
So I, I suspect in five or 10 years quantum will start doing some more useful things.
But
yeah, for now, honestly,
it's not that I don't care.
It's, that, it reminds me of speech recognition 20 years ago.
You know, it's just around the corner. We promise.
-- Oh, no,
-- it wasn't. It was 20 years away from not sucking from not being terrible.
So I don't, I don't remember if I've ever told this story on the podcast,
but I remember when
dragon dictate came out this way I paid
for that.
Yeah. Right. I, I was so excited about it and I wanted it right.
So, like I got it, I bought it for my computer. I installed it.
And the first thing you had to do though was train
where I spent,
I bet 10 hours training this stupid thing to
recognize my voice because every time it failed,
I'm like, oh, I just need to train it more.
And then I spent a couple of hours training it
which,
and I'll never forget,
like I actually got it to the point where I would say it was usable.
I won't say it was good, but it was usable
-- and then I'll never
-- forget. Got to that point.
It wasn't good, but it did stop.
But then I remember my brother started using it one day when I was gone
and he did some training and like it ruined everything and I was so mad.
I never used it again.
-- So
-- best thing the other day,
the insurance guy was over here after my garage got clobbered
and um he's Australian and we were talking about uh the,
the whole voice thing came up, you know,
and so he as an Australian actually found that on the Apple iphone, you can.
So Siri can be changed
to have either the like American British Australian and I
think one or two other sort of versions of English
and
Canadian Siri. No, I don't think so. But anyways,
I thought it was just the output was modified, right?
Because for a while I set mine to a male British voice because, you know,
pretended it was my butler.
Um
And uh
you got a better use for voice technology.
So funny enough, my,
I use ways on my phone and I have ways set to the British voice because I enjoy it more.
But anyway, so I knew that it affected the output,
but I didn't realize it apparently also affects the input.
So he has his set to Australian and it understands him better.
But then the problem is when Siri processes
his voicemail because it's all Canadians leaving voicemail,
it mangles it.
That's interesting.
So basically he has to, he had to make the choice of, like,
having mangled voicemails or being able to talk to his phone,
you know. And,
yeah. So I, I, it strikes me as, I mean, there's a great example of,
can you,
to me?
At least it doesn't seem that hard to, like, I hear an Australian accent and I hear
a Canadian
accent
and I can tell which is, which pretty much right away.
Yeah.
But that's because we're bags of meat that have
evolved to do this for thousands of years.
So, but it's weird to me, like, you,
you think the voice recognition people would be working on that because
especially something like Alexa,
you know, wouldn't, like,
I assume it's better if you understand somebody's accent because
you can then more easily parse what they're saying.
Like
a great example of this is I,
I understand English with a German accent very well because of my mother.
And so there's a lot of cases where, you know, I,
I'll listen to some German speaking in mangled English and I'm like, yeah,
I understand that.
No problem,
you know, and everybody else is like, what did they just say?
And I'm like, oh, they want to go to the bathroom or whatever, you know.
-- So
-- I have a great example for you. Is
there the
Scottish people talking to computers is mar,
because
their accent is not only very Scottish,
they have a particular,
very Scottish way of speaking
where they're vernacular and just words in general
are, I will say on the borderline of the Queen's English
and there's actually youtube videos of people doing this and
I, I get it and even I think a lot of Americans would struggle to understand
-- someone who's
-- really Scottish
and I did not understand
a thing they were saying.
It's
so, you know, it's really funny. Actually I love is, I'll never forget
the first time I ever went to London
and
I was out having some beers at the pub
and it got late. It's like, all right time to go. Right.
I go back to my room and I turn on the TV.
And it was a Gaelic station or
it was a Welsh TV station.
But the noi that like the sounds in Welsh are very English sounding.
I remember I'm saying them like, how much beer did I drink? Like I,
I was
II, I did not know what was happening.
It took longer than I want to admit to realize they were not speaking English and no,
you didn't drink too much at the pub.
Like everything is fine, but
we're, we're horribly off topic as we tend to get.
Well, I think this is a great example of like,
it strikes me as a classic case of like,
how is this not a technology somebody's working on because it feels
like it would make things a whole lot more useful and better.
No, no
people are working on it. It's just really hard to solve.
It's kind of like, let's pick on security in general.
We talk about how security is a tire fire all the time. And in many aspects it is
and there are people working on it
but it's too hard to solve.
And this is one of those places and I'm sure it's the same thing in voice recognition.
Well, I, I would disagree a little bit because one interesting thing is
the majority of the voice recognition that is currently kind
of available and being widely used at the consumer end,
not the business end,
like not medical transcription software but things like Siri and Alexa,
they can roll out an update to everybody in two minutes because they just do.
-- Right. Yeah. But I don't think that matters security.
-- However, let me put this,
I could come out with the best open source security appliance that does DS ID P,
firewall
threat, intelligence, everything.
-- Oh,
-- dude, if you go to RS A, they're selling those, everyone's got one.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
But I'm just what I'm saying is even if I had one that was
free or even if I had one where not only do you install it,
but I pay you $1000 to install it.
Would I be able to get more than one or 2% market share?
No, whereas
Amazon improves Alexa
and Bam Alexa is better for everybody.
You know, Apple improves Siri and as soon as they do an OS update,
Siri is locally better for everybody.
And um,
my understanding is Siri still does ship some stuff
off to the back end mothership for processing,
you know, same thing with the Google voice is, is,
is it does most of the stuff locally but does ship stuff back to the mothership.
But I'm going to bring this back. We talked about
incremental change a couple of episodes ago if you
call.
And I think that's what this is though,
is in voice recognition and security for that matter.
We are seeing very tiny incremental changes along the way
when the reality is and this is kind of part of the quantum discussion as well. Is
there needs to be a new breakthrough in research to actually make this stuff better?
I think just slowly improving, it's kind of like,
-- well,
-- it'll get there but in like 20 or 40 years,
but it's not, it's not slow improvements.
All right, we need breakthroughs and quantum is probably a breakthrough.
I I don't know what kind we're going to find out someday.
-- I'm sure, I
-- mean, one challenge with quantum as, as I understand it quantum is great,
but you're going to need more than like eight cubits to do something useful.
Well,
I I think I read an article that Google or somebody's claiming they should be up to,
I think IBM has 40
they're expecting hundreds in the next couple of years.
Which maybe, maybe not. I mean, it's, it's complicated and hard to understand it.
I'm not going to pretend
I'm an expert at all in any of this stuff.
We'll link to a, uh,
there's a good comic strip off S NBC from this week that explains quantum.
-- Yeah,
-- that's really, really good. I really enjoyed that one.
Yeah, we'll put that in the show notes. Definitely.
But it's,
it's hard,
not many people understand it. I definitely don't, I won't even pretend I do.
-- You
-- know what? Actually? No, I'd say it's worse.
It's a lot like Blockchain and, but a lot of people think they understand it.
-- Yeah,
-- that's probably true. That's like security also. Yeah.
If we just apply more A V to, you know, it rubs the A V on its skin or it gets the hose.
That's right.
I, I know, man, there's, you know,
what's funny is I used to read these security articles
and I would like,
actually contact the authors and the people in that would be like you got this wrong,
you got this wrong, you got this wrong now that I'm older.
I'm like,
I don't even care. This article is terrible. It doesn't really matter, you know,
and it doesn't because no one's reading it anyway. So it's fine
anyway. Anyway. So,
yeah, I don't know. I guess my, my take on quantum computing is
until that thing is cracking Rs A keys.
Like, shut up. I don't want to hear it.
-- That's kind of where I sit right now. I think I'm
-- guessing in five years
we have pretty much the exact conversation, word for word.
I suspect we will.
And now I, I would bet a pint on that. I wouldn't bet my house,
but
I feel like
quantum has been
so slow
-- and we
-- were
-- so
-- much
some of these problems like cold fusion, speech recognition.
-- They're just a lot harder than we thought they were self
-- driving cars, man.
I mean, do you remember what self driving cars came up probably about five years ago?
And it was looking like holy crap.
We're going to have self driving cars in a couple of years.
And at this point given what I've seen, I bet we're still a decade away,
which makes me sad because I hate driving and I really want a self driving car,
but
I, I have a suspicion. It's,
it's like anything right
that it's the 8020 rule where that,
that 80%
doesn't take long to get to,
but the last 20% really matters and it takes a lot of effort to get that.
Well,
and self driving cars are a great example of
where you have an even more difficult problem of.
So the car is self driving, but if it ever has to fail back to the human,
the human has to be paying attention and has to be on the ball,
which kind of defeats the whole point of a self driving car.
Right.
All those people in their Tesla when the
Tesla slams into the back of something stationary,
you know, when it's supposed to change lanes.
And doesn't I, you know, if I'm in a Tesla self driving car,
my understanding is that I can kind of zone out of it.
Not, I have to be hyper vigilant because if I have to be hyper vigilant,
I might as well just drive the darn thing.
Yep. I agree. I agree completely.
The whole point is that I can fall asleep or read a book and I don't have to care.
No, I gotta say I'm on Google's side with this where the, the car has a button.
-- That's it. Yeah.
-- Serious. I, I agree 100%.
Actually, I learned, I,
I read something really cool on Twitter the other day and this is,
we can end on this marvelous piece of advice.
They said when you're stuck in traffic,
uh, just cut off a Tesla
because they have all the right.
They have like all the special computery autopilot stuff in it.
So basically as soon as you start to cut it off,
it will get out of your way and you don't have to worry about getting in an accident.
So
there you go. If you need to merge into traffic, find the Tesla.
I've actually been wondering about that.
Can I just like these, these protests where, you know,
can one person just walk out onto a highway and
snarl it up without fear of being run over.
Uh, if there was all self driving cars.
Yeah.
I, I would assume so. I mean, the cars aren't going to hit people.
Yeah, I believe that's a car don't.
Right. I mean, that's, that's the idea. And is that a way you could protest?
-- I mean, yeah, you can do that now, even,
-- well, we've already seen that.
You know, we've already seen that with the, with various protests, you know,
sitting camping out in a bridge or a busy intersection or whatever
because most people thankfully are not willing to drive over protesters yet.
You know, even if they are late for work,
I'm not, we're going to end this because this conversation could
take a little bad turn for the worse.
So,
thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com,
hit up the show
notes so you can use the P
and Os podcast. Hashtag You hit us
Pao
-- Kurt. Have a fantastic rest of your day. You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.