Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in thinking about things, Josh Pressers,
didn't you do?
Thinking about things just the other day?
I
think you did.
I'm gonna be honest with you about an hour after we record the podcast,
like somebody like Mel or Felix might ask me like, hey, what did you talk about?
And I'm like,
stop.
Actually,
I can attest to this because there's been more than one time I've told her, oh,
remember we talked about this on the podcast?
He's like, no, I don't remember it at all.
But I'm the same thing with emails.
Like I'll write an email and like an hour later you expect me to remember an email.
-- That's the
-- point of writing. But
-- yeah, whatever, like
-- same thing with the podcast because like,
if we'd done 10 or 20 of these, yeah, it'd be amazing and special.
And now it's 400 later,
here's what makes it even more exciting
is. So you said partner and thinking about things
and I'm pretty sure you said that in the last couple of weeks.
But we also have some podcasts.
We're like building up in the hopper because we've
got some vacation time and things coming up.
So, you probably said it.
But I don't remember when, and I don't remember when that episode will come out.
So you got to love it. It's all good.
I really got to automate the transcription of these things.
It's on the list. So, I've, I've done
a lot of research into that. I, OK. So I, I just, we kind of tangent on that note.
I found a LLM model
from the open A I people. I think they called it Whisper or something like that.
Yeah, whisper will do it.
The challenge is, it's like a lot of LLM things.
A good foundational model is nice and all.
But what you want is something like me geek where it's like speaker identification
-- and all that other stuff.
-- It didn't do speaker identification, but it got
a lot right, because I tried a couple of things.
-- So
-- whisper and speaker identification is one
-- of those things where it
-- doesn't exist.
It doesn't do it. Well,
whisper technically, doesn't do it,
but you can do it in a prestage actually relatively easily because like
the tone of your voice and the tone of my voice are like, it's like,
remember when that guy released the uh the vuvuzela
filter notch
for the World Cup and it's just like this one
and like, oh, the Vuze Zs are
gone. Thank God,
I miss them.
I miss them every day anyway. All right, we have a real topic I don't want to talk about
and stuff right now and, and, and transcriptions. It's on the list.
Anyway, there have been two very interesting and we say
not at all similar documents released from Cisa in
the White House in the last couple of weeks.
And I'm actually really excited because I've been like,
bugging the heck out of Kurt to talk about this Cissa document,
which I think is terrible.
And then like,
I, I don't know, a couple of days ago from the time we're recording now,
the White House releases a thing.
And I'm like, oh, holy crap. Thank goodness. We didn't record before this because,
because
I
CIA was July 8th and the White House was July 10th.
-- Ok.
-- And, but I didn't find the White House one, I think until the 12th,
so I missed it.
Yeah, it's, uh, well, I mean, do you want to, you're the American,
you should talk about your own government.
I want to start with the CIA document because I think it's, it's terrible.
-- So,
-- yes
and not. And, and what I love is, it's terrible on
sort of such a deeply fundamental level. It actually takes a bit of explaining.
Well, no, no, it's not just terrible.
Like, like a hamburger with pickles and hot sauce and like,
fig jam would be terrible.
-- That would just be terrible.
-- I've never had that. I don't know.
Well, now I want to try this.
But you know what I'm saying? It's not like simple, terrible. It's complicated.
It's complicated. I agree. I agree. OK, so let's just start, they, they
put out a blog post that says continued progress towards a secure open
-- source ecosystem.
-- Is it a blog post? It's in their news section.
So I thought it was more official than a blog
and it says blog on the top of the page. I don't know
who
cares.
It doesn't matter,
it doesn't matter. That's the thing.
Like when the federal government releases a thing, this is true.
It's not like when you and I write a blog post, this was,
-- this probably took three months
-- and
mine goes
like they get,
they get
well, my work work ones, not
the stuff I write is me like
that's
coherent,
-- but
-- you don't have a domain ending in.gov.
That's right. That's right.
So anyway, they basically publish this, this post.
And I would say the fundamental message behind it is
you should measure the goodness in your open source.
Yes
and
well, sort of let's skip to. So they have this the idea of a framework
because,
well, but before that,
I want to literally read this one sentence that I think captures the essence of it.
All the task of assessing the trustworthiness of Os S that is in use or
that is being considered for use is more
complex for Os S than for proprietary software
because there is generally speaking,
no direct relationship between the authors of
software and those who use the software.
That's so cute because, you know,
I was just talking to Bob at Microsoft the other day about my Windows.
11 problems. Oh, hang on a second. I don't have a relationship with Microsoft.
Beyond giving them money to use Windows.
You don't, I mean, if you're a huge company,
you do because you're probably in some sort of weird contractual agreement.
I love this whole pretending that somehow
I can go to like Google and be like, hey, Google, I,
I deleted a file and could you please fix it for me?
They would laugh at you except they can't even get your message,
right.
Like I remember, I remember I was speaking with somebody I know who works at Google,
who I was like, I want to report a, like a weird bug and they're like,
I don't think you can do that.
There's no way
and, and, and, but he was also like, he's like, I don't think I can do that either.
-- Like he couldn't even do it internally.
-- It wouldn't surprise me at all. Right.
Here's so, here's what I think is the important part of this.
They have a framework which we can look at. I don't, it's, it's kind of unimportant.
The point is this sort of message around trustworthy, open source
I think is flawed fundamentally from two different sides.
And actually the the the document from the White House
gets part of this right? And we're going to read that, I'll read that in just a minute.
But there's the stop trying to measure open source quality.
That's not the point of open source.
The point is open source is a thing that exists that you can become a part of.
Not like let's measure open source and figure out which open source is the best,
which leads to the second half of that, which is in the vast majority of cases.
If you measure open source you're using and it scores a zero,
you're still gonna use it because there's nothing else to use.
So what's the point of this stupid measuring in the first place?
It's not that there's nothing else to use. It's worse than that.
It's you're already using it. And the cost of switching will be
quite significant.
Like even if they're perfect example, Apache and engine X,
they are actually quite comparable pieces of software, web servers that
given an Apache configuration and set up, you could actually with not too long,
probably tens of minutes to hours, replace it with engine
X.
OK? Try doing that with Kubernetes.
-- What exactly are you going to replace Kubernetes with
-- Docker
-- Swarm?
-- Right?
Or like maybe Terraform except
-- Terraform went off the deep end and it went to some weird open source name
-- but
Terraform isn't
Kubernetes. That's not.
But I'm saying like the things that are like comparable
like there is Lib J peg.
That's it. Like that's,
-- that's
-- all folks and any framework lib J peg is going to score zero.
And then the other thing that really gets me is I always come
back to this thing with the open source versus closed source again,
like I just love how we sort of pretend like having a contractual relationship with
an entity that is typically on several
orders of magnitude larger than the customer.
Microsoft, Apple Amazon, those are all
-- basically trillion dollar companies at this point.
-- OK?
-- I have a theory about this actually.
-- But my point is
even if you're the US government and you're huge,
if you said Microsoft, we really want the default windows background to be read.
-- They'd be like, no,
-- probably not,
they might listen to you a little bit if you have a big enough contract,
but odds are not good.
Well, but here, here's my theory about this though
and, and this is true of the open SSF scorecard as well.
I know we've harped about that many times in the past.
And I think this is a very similar problem is
people who often work on these sort of frameworks and frame these problems.
They're always framing it in this context of,
I need to make sure the thing I'm taking in is trustworthy.
And I think that feels like a very big company security attitude to me, right?
Where these big companies are all about, like,
we're going to create these frameworks, we're going to create these rules,
we're going to control our risk that's coming in.
-- Right. Like that is what they do.
-- Well, it, it's,
they want like,
sure we want to accept the risk or refuse the
risk or ensure the risk or compensate for the risk.
And we're a big company and blah, blah, blah,
they operate in a world that most of us don't
-- because
-- they can because they're spending sometimes millions of dollars.
-- But
-- because they have to, so without going into
detail, the CS A just has a new member,
which is a large bank and sometimes we sign up new members and they're like, cool,
whatever we pay you, we're a member.
Great.
And then we have other members like this bank
that is asking us for,
it was eight different kinds of insurance to prove that we have it
right.
And like most of these,
I actually know about most of these insurances
because I've been in the business long enough,
like some of it was like, you know,
just standard business insurance and then it was like,
there's some other insurances that they wanted to make sure that we had and if not,
why not?
And blah, blah, blah.
And
that's the like this is like asking the US like
the US government lives in the US government world,
they don't live in the world that the most of us, the rest of us live in.
No, I agree. I agree. And so their view of reality
is
different than our view of reality because their reality is actually different.
-- But
-- I,
I don't think that counts because we're going to read a
thing from the White House here in just a minute.
I'm just going to read it now because it's, it's good.
-- Well,
-- but some people are clever enough to actually accept a
more, let's say, broadly accepted version of reality versus the one they live in.
Maybe.
Sure,
look, here's, here's what I think is so good.
So the White House released a memorandum. Um
Does it have a title
memorandum for the heads of executive departments and agencies
subject, administrative
uh sorry, administration, cybersecurity priorities for the fy 2026 budget. Ok.
-- That must be it.
-- It's boring. So, you know, it's actually kind of interesting.
-- It's very
-- boring and it covers a wide variety of topics.
It's not focused on open source by any means.
But no,
they have a paragraph about open source that I'm just going
to read the whole paragraph because it's so freaking good.
And it says improve open source software security and sustainability.
-- That's like the paragraph header,
-- the fact that they used the word sustainability.
Yes, we'll get to that. I
know
that's the point. That's the point, right. That's the key.
And this is where I read this.
And I'm like, there's no way this is from the government, but anyway.
It says recognizing the many benefits of open source software
departments and agencies should ensure secure use of open source
software and contributing to maintaining open source code to help
sustain components depended on by the agency contribute to maintaining.
I love that. Right. And that's the point. Ok. Well, I'm going to keep going.
Then it says maintenance activities
could include developing mechanisms that enable
and encourage employees and contractors to
contribute to open source software components
including security related contributions,
monitoring changes to code tracking and correcting potential error
and flaws in the code and other related activities.
Agencies should integrate open source software
considerations including process to review,
approve inventory and centralize open source consumption into agency.
It and cybersecurity governance structures,
agencies are encouraged to study the
benefits that could be gained through establishment
of a governance function modeled after private sector,
open source program offices that defines roles,
responsibilities and methods of engagement.
This is remarkably sane.
Well, it's like that Swiss thing that came out where it's kind of like, yeah,
there's this the boat sized hole of, you know,
you must uh this this one Swiss government thing is like you you need
to start using open source with the
exception of pre-existing third party licensing,
blah, blah, blah.
So like Microsoft and all, but the fact that people are saying this out loud now
is yeah, like this whole sustainability thing
that's
so big because they're no longer saying
you have to use open source securely. It's,
you have to participate in using open source securely.
Yes. Well, and that's the thing, right. That's the key
is there's no, we'll put quotes around secure,
but there's no secure usage of open source where
you are strictly a consumer of that open source.
That's not a thing.
And this is where I think there's like such
a stark contrast where sis is basically pulling the,
you should be afraid of this thing.
So we built a tool that lets you be more afraid versus the White House.
That's basically saying
-- get involved, you chumps like come on.
-- So sis a though, so that's the thing.
The White House is different in that they are in theory
like kind of the highest level of policy and strategy.
I mean, in theory, the
government
and SISA is much more down in the dirt. And a perfect example of where CIA
where their framework is beyond terrible
is I I'll just read it first for the project.
The number of active contributors are unexpected changes in account ownership
for the product, the presence of known vulnerabilities or out of date dependencies
for protections,
whether the project requires two factor authentication on developer accounts.
Sorry, I don't mean to laugh at that, but it is so ridiculous uh for policies,
whether the project requires code review
or has responsible vulnerability disclosure process.
So there's two problems with this number one, these are all sort of like policy,
things, not actual security, things like
-- a project can require code reviews, but do they actually get done or not?
-- Right.
Right.
My favorite is when I have code reviews on my repo and then I code review my code.
-- This
-- leads to the second subtle thing of
why this these four things are beyond uselessly
terrible is because they are building a framework
on what they can measure easily today.
That is true. I'll agree with that statement. These can be measured.
No,
no, easily. Because for example, I have actually done this. It's kind of a jerk move.
I have
like when we're evaluating SAS
suppliers,
I literally will look for what their security contact is and email them and say
I need to report a security vulnerability.
What do we do?
Oh, that's not bad.
And then I see if they actually respond or not and I kind of go like, sorry,
this was a test
-- but like I need to make sure you respond.
-- I mean, that's fair. That's fair.
And, and, and some of them, you know,
I get like an auto responder five minutes later and then I
get like a human response a day later and I'm like,
totally acceptable. Yeah. Yeah, for
sure.
-- And some of them I never hear back and I'm like, oh, ok then yeah,
-- that went,
that went to a black hole
and some of them I can't find a way to, to do it.
Yeah, for Sure.
Or I finally or my favorite is I'll email their sales department because sales like
-- they will reply to your
-- email. Yeah, sales and legal always reply.
Yeah.
Yeah. But the point is none of this is anything that requires work to measure.
It's just passive, they're measuring passive things.
Well, and thank goodness that that's one thing I will say.
Thank goodness it's passive because goodness
know,
we don't need every company on the planet
emailing every open source maintainer asking them questions.
That would be ridiculous.
-- Well, we did that with log for J It was awesome.
-- That's true.
And, well, and so, you know what stuck out to me when I, when I saw this at first was
the very first one. It says a number of active contributors.
-- It's one, it's always one. Well, they,
-- they want more than one
in their framework thing that might have built them.
It's got something about checking
the number of maintainers and my first thought was Man XZ almost had two,
but now they're back down to one.
Well,
every project
I use statistically is there's one person who has done like 80% of the commands and,
you know, it's,
it's a perfect statistical
patto distribution across every project I've ever looked, you know,
with the exceptions of the ones that have a robot,
it, with all the commits in the robot. Oh, I know. Depend
aot or whatever. Oh, that thing is really, yeah. Here. OK.
Not to go too tangential but does depend a
bot
count as a good contributor.
I mean,
I would argue, depend
aot can't approve pr s.
-- So I would argue, no,
-- I would argue if a project is using,
depend a bot and actually rapidly updating their dependencies.
I
mean, that,
that's what they
keep
saying
they want.
Yeah, that's good behavior. I agree.
I mean, I think you get into a weird discussion about
what is a maintainer and things like that.
-- And I don't want to do that today, but I
-- think more it boils down to.
Ok,
here's the world that all these people want is I want all my dependencies up to date
but nothing to break.
That's it. That's what they want.
And, and every project should have 15 maintainers that way if anyone gets hurt
and all
containers are contributing equally.
So, like there isn't one core maintainer we can't afford to lose.
And ironically, this is exactly.
Red Hat's business model of, we will take all this software
and if like, the maintainer isn't available or
isn't, he's on vacation this week or she's not
responding,
we will ship a patch
hopefully in a reasonable amount of time and
you can consume it and pay us for it.
-- Well, that doesn't
-- scale. Right. I mean, we're, we're so far past that now.
Right. There's like, how many millions of N PM packages
-- for
-- sure. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Well, and that's the thing.
Like when Red Hat started that business, there were what,
1000 open source projects on the planet,
-- like,
-- maybe, but we're in wide use. Yeah, probably. I mean,
that's the thing that blows my mind is like, you look at those NP MS and wow,
$10 million a week, like, even if 90% of them are automated bots,
-- that's still
-- a lot.
Yeah, for sure. Well, and not only that,
when
one of the pieces of signal people look for,
when they're looking at a project is they will go to the N PM page, for example,
and be like, how many downloads does this thing get a week?
And it's 10 million, you're going to say it must be a good project.
Everything is fine here.
But what choice do I have?
Like I, you and I have actually spent time investigating and, and,
and like trying to, you know, pick open source and like
yada yada yada
and to this date, like essentially it boils down to,
I can occasionally find a good signal
and I can occasionally find a terrible signal. Yeah.
And so there's once in a while where I can say, wow, like this project clearly cares.
This is great.
Like a good example would be Korda,
Korda had their own in house built Java Applet server.
And then one version they're like,
we got rid of it and replaced it with an open source component
that probably has a lot less vulnerabilities than the crap we wrote.
And then another time they're like, oh,
this dependency we track had a vulnerability.
Doesn't have a CV or anything,
but we caught it and we fixed it like we updated it great.
And then there's the, the, the opposite side where, you know, you see a,
-- a project where,
-- no, I don't think there's an opposite side.
-- I don't think there are
-- projects that refuse.
But for example, are they haven't shipped an update in eight years
-- and it's dead.
-- That doesn't make it bad. It might make it dead.
But that's a different thing. There's so here's the thing.
I think this is where I'm going to split
hairs over this one because I think it's important.
There is projects, I think all projects try to do the right thing.
I don't think any open source project is going to purposely try to be bad, right?
I don't think that is a thing. I think there are projects that are dead.
I think there are projects that react negatively
to, we'll say misbehaving community members.
But I fundamentally don't think any project is necessarily bad.
And I think that's part of what makes this discussion so weird
is
tools like what, what
Sisa has built,
they're trying to create two buckets, good and bad
and there isn't a bad bucket, right?
There's good and there might be better, but I don't think bad is a thing.
I would argue there is a bad bucket, but it's very small.
And in my experience of looking at hundreds,
probably less than 1000 but more than 500 projects,
there's like,
literally a handful where it's like they have outstanding vulnerabilities,
no maintainers or anything going on.
And it's just like,
-- like it's a combination of dead and has known flaws
-- that's just dead.
That's ok.
Well, but it has known flaws.
Like there's so there's dead but not known flaws and that's,
you can probably use that safely
-- but stuff that has known flaws,
-- no dead is dead.
I would say it's dead and you know about some of the vulnerabilities
or it's dead and you don't know about some of the vulnerabilities,
-- but there's still a crap load of vulnerabilities back
-- to this.
None of that matters
because it's in my dependency chain. I can't change it easily.
-- Yeah, you're not changing it or
-- I'm using it and replacing it is like, either, well,
I could stop using it and if I could stop using it then, well,
I should just do that with all the stuff I can stop using
and
reduce my risk.
But obviously I'm using it because it does something
that I needed it to do at some point.
And so
what gets me like, I think the problem is a lot of this software is infrastructure.
It's not a nice to have Solitaire or mobile game. It's infrastructure
and we don't have infrastructure unless we need it.
-- Because it's expensive.
-- I will agree with that.
And I think there's a second piece to that, which is,
let's say we do stand up some sort of brand new Greenfield thing
that has no vulnerabilities in any of the stuff we're using.
How many days do you think it'll take before you start having vulnerabilities?
-- I bet three or
-- less.
And the other thing is like by definition,
anything the government does is pretty much almost
always infrastructure and boring life have to happen.
-- That's good. We
-- need
boring. Like they do occasionally mobile games.
Like there's a mobile waste management game and was
-- part of my waste management app from
-- the government.
Seriously,
it was the city of Edmonton has waste
management app that basically does two useful things.
One it tells you when your garbage day is and two, it's got a little,
it tells you how to sort your garbage because I guess some people are not so
good at that and it's got a little built in game to sort your garbage.
I
want to play this game.
It's, you just throw like the bottle in the right thing.
It's the same thing as curious George.
Uh
Anyway,
and that's the thing by definition, what
Cisa is dealing with is the government, by definition,
what the government is doing is infrastructure and that is always complicated.
-- It
-- doesn't matter though. I don't, I think that point is moot. I think you've got
an example here. We have two agencies, right?
-- But I don't know if the White House counts as an agency.
-- Well, no, no, no.
The White House is non agency.
-- All right,
-- whatever you've got the CIA you have, the White House
is saying you need, you should measure open source and be afraid.
And the White House is saying get involved.
My hope is that the White House Guidance trickles its way around
and we see these agencies because it's not even just
Cisa I've seen this come from more than one agency,
especially lots of big companies that I've seen.
But I'm hopeful this guidance will trickle around
and we will seem less of a, we should measure our open source
and that turns into something like
we need to be like good shepherds of open source, not just like
a, a some sort of lamprey sucking all of the blood we can find out of this ecosystem.
I'm going to say something a little mean, which is
the CIA Guidance is both wrong and useless in that. Even if you follow the
CSA Guidance, implement it to A T it's not helpful.
The White House advice is look, you need to use OS S so get involved and get good.
The CIA advice is be afraid, make it measurement,
pick a good one except we're just, there's not good ones like there's, or, or,
or there are good ones like the Linux kernel
or curl or whatever like big nice mature projects.
But, like, when you're looking for a bunch of N PM node stuff,
there's nothing like that in that space.
Right.
Like when I'm in my Python pip little world and I'm looking for a thing, like, ok.
Yeah, there's pandas and numpy and psych and NLTK. They're freaking awesome.
But when I'm looking for, like, a thing to convert, like, html to markdown,
it's like, yeah, I'm, I'm just picking kind of whatever works.
Right.
Exactly.
And there's like 17 of them,
you know, and three of them have not been updated in this.
I was going to say this decade actually also the last decade.
And in some cases though, it's, that's ok because I was, I,
I was looking at some file conversion utility
and it was like last done in like 2008,
but it's like that file format is so simple and so done that.
No, that's it. Like it, this is it, it's done,
you know,
there's a security vulnerability in it.
There's also some funny examples of this where
I remember I wrote a tool one time that I,
people kept mailing me these spreadsheets and they
were spreadsheets produced by some other tool.
And so they had a completely known format.
I had to extract all of the CV E ss out of them.
I had to parse the CV ES and then
add back in
our basically justifications for these.
And I wrote a, I, I basically just looked,
I typed in the stack overflow like I need to parse an Excel file with Python.
And of course, there was an example and I took it and
I copied and pasted it
and then
I needed to basically there was a bug in the, in the library.
It wasn't doing something the right way. I forget what it even was.
And so I go to the project and
it hadn't been updated in like seven years. I'm like, oh boy,
like this is literally critical infrastructure now
and then. But anyway, that led me on the path of, oh, this project is dead.
This other project
is maintained and proper and it took me a day and I, I converted everything.
But yeah, like that's one of those instances. I,
I had no idea because I was just like sucking down some open source and using it,
you know,
and you were lucky though you're in the Python world where quite
often there is more than one option for reading Excel files or
PDF to
HTML.
There's
only one option.
-- Well,
-- now there's, there's one best of breed all
dead.
One in the
Alive.
Yeah.
But I mean, a lot of people don't even have that option with their software.
You know,
there's a lot of things where somebody wrote one of
it and why would anybody else write another one?
So that I, like I said, I think it boils down to the
CSA guidance is just it's like talking about how to
breed horses better when we're entering the 19 forties.
-- And it's like the car era.
-- I mean,
yeah,
I agree.
If you're, let's say you, you run their framework and then they call it t
check, I tried to run it. I couldn't get it to work. Right.
-- And I gave up because I couldn't be bothered just
-- looking at this,
everything I use would fail it because everything I use has like one developer
and that's my point, right? That's my point. Let's say
you run this
and a bunch of your software scores zero.
What are you, what, what's step two like, well, just don't run it again.
Yeah,
like
I love that. I'm using this Leper Chat A I front end and it uses a post Gras
docker container that's like kind of really out of date, but like who cares?
It only talks to
it through one internal service and like,
I'm not gonna ask the developer to update it because it's
like who cares pointless?
-- Or
-- you could update it for them Kurt,
but it doesn't matter,
then stop complaining.
Well,
but or I could spend that time writing
backup documentation that would actually benefit people.
It's fair.
I have a good example of this actually.
So a long time ago I worked at a little
ISP and I'm pretty sure I've told this story before,
but I decided I was like, starting my security journey
and I thought I'm gonna run,
I think it was just called crack back in, back then
crack. Yeah, I know what you're talking about.
I'm going to run crack against the password file and we're going to tell
all the people who have terrible passwords that they should change their password.
-- Why
-- would
-- you do that?
-- Why?
-- Because I was a burgeoning security nerd. It felt like something we should do.
And honestly, back in the olden days, there was no two of a,
there was no M fa there was none of that.
-- So,
-- no, no. Right. Right.
And so anyway, we had 9000 user accounts at
this ISP
and we had, I think, like 1500 hits in the first day.
That's it in a day on like crappy hardware.
But anyway, we got all these hits
and then I'm like, what do we do now?
And this is, and I was like, turn it off, delete the data. We're never doing this again
because it was like,
this is the company knew they could not handle the support burden,
asking 1500 people to change their passwords.
And so the solution was to stick our head in the sand and not do anything about it,
not even the support burden, but you would just piss them all off.
That's true. You'd probably lose some of those customers.
-- Why
-- did you look at my password? I thought you said my password was secure.
That's true. That's a good point.
I didn't even think of that angle and, but anyway, here's my point. Right.
And I think this is how I'm going to sum up my final thoughts on this whole thing.
I think the guidance Sisa created
is we'll say what feels like doing something.
And I think in the world of security sometimes
we do things to feel like we're doing something,
-- but sometimes that is actually worse than nothing.
-- The goalkeeper's dilemma.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah, exactly.
So, statistically
what's the best thing to do as a goalkeeper
in soccer is to basically stand your ground?
Yeah, stand still.
But if you do that, the crowd will set you on fire and you'll lose your job.
Well, I I'm less worried about that if I'm on fire
and not a hypothetical example, right?
Like some countries take this very seriously.
That's fair.
I would say it's actually,
I think for me it's a very subtle thing of SISA is looking
at open source from the perspective of there's all this negative stuff,
do stuff so that you can avoid the negative.
And the White House is looking at this saying there's all
this open source and there's a whole bunch of positive stuff.
Embrace that and lean into it.
Yeah, I think that's fair. A basic fact of life is no amount of avoiding the bad stuff.
Like no amount of not doing something will get
you in shape or a happier human being like,
yeah, not smoking is a good thing, but like you have to exercise,
you have to eat better, you have to make actual positive engagement.
Like no amount of avoiding bad air codes, bad open source
will result in me participating and helping build better open source. That's it.
And I mean,
honestly, here's the thing.
Imagine if 10,000 people across the federal government, which is not a lot.
Right. The federal government in the US is pretty big.
I don't know, let's look us federal government employees.
It's about 2 to 3 million,
it says about two and a quarter million civilian personnel,
civilian.
So you've also got the dod, you've got all the law enforcement,
it says two and a quarter million military personnel.
Well, regardless, 10,000 people is
-- a doable number. Yeah,
-- 10 1000 is a rounding error.
And imagine if those 10,000 people each spent 10 hours a year, not a month,
not a week a year
-- helping improve an open source project.
-- That would be remarkable for sure.
And, and not just the government, here's the thing.
Yeah,
if the White House releases this sort of guidance,
the private sector is also going to pay attention,
right?
And I think that's part of this is we also need
these big companies to stop treating open source like a liability
and start trying to get involved in some meaningful way.
Like I said, embracing the positive and engaging and doing something positive,
like no amount of not littering is going to help build a new park in your city.
You know, like
if
I, I think it's starting to shift because quite frankly,
one thing I've noticed and you've probably noticed this but never thought about it
is the companies and organizations and especially the start
ups that really engage actively with open source.
Quite often do a lot better than the ones that don't.
And obviously there are ones that just strip mind the
heck out of open source and do just fine.
That happens
one caveat to that.
I would also point out is those things are often big enough that they
sort of do the engagement internally and don't return it to the public.
So they do get the benefit of internal
like that synergy well or whatever the firm is like where
I improve something 1% he improved something 1% you know,
stone soup and we get this thing that's massively better.
And like Amazon Apple, Microsoft all do this
internally
and some of them like Microsoft are also starting to return
it back to the community with some pretty good results.
-- I
-- think if you look at
a number of large companies, I mean, there's a lot of organizations
doing a lot of really good public work.
I mean, Google and Microsoft, even Amazon to a degree has been doing quite a bit.
There's a bunch of banks that have been doing a lot. I mean,
there are plenty of companies you can look at for
good examples of how to do this right now.
Granted, I also recognize that like any big company,
I'm sure for every person doing it right.
There's one or more people screwing it up.
I would have never guessed this guess. Ok. So there's two sites of data for the Linux
uh 6.1 kernel. There's the by chain sets and bylines changed.
So looking at by change sets, not lines, but by chain sets.
-- What is the top company
-- if I had to guess right now?
-- I bet. Is it, is it arm or Intel? Not
-- even close? Huawei.
Huawei.
-- Oh, yeah. Ok. I buy
-- that
but
-- 9.2% Intel at nine unknown at
-- eight. OK. I was close. I was close. You said way off.
-- Come on. Uh well,
-- Google Lena
A MD Red Hat, Meta and video souza oracle
NXP semiconductor at 2%. That's, I've never even heard of them.
That does not surprise me in any way. They're probably building socks.
And, and if you look at my lines changed, it's oracle A MD, Google Intel. Unknown.
Real tech. Yeah. Real tech has a lot of drivers, I bet. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
But yeah, like
it's, it's
big companies like big boring.
-- We make stuff companies because
-- like the Linux kernel is the best.
I mean, Linux won.
Yeah.
All right, we need to end this one. So
I, like I said, I think all of this
and I think this is true for security.
All of this security that boils down to trying to slap people
on the wrist and make them not do the bad thing.
Like the whole phishing email training thing.
No,
make it so that like their computer works properly and clicking a link doesn't
result in all of your money being sent to some random person in Macau
and make sure they're not afraid to come tell you if they do make a mistake.
That's a huge other part of that.
Or
to ask even because I think some places they're so
hostile that even just asking you get in trouble for,
right?
Which is the correct thing to do.
You don't punish somebody for saying, hey, this invoice looks a little
like we get that all the time where we get these wonky invoices.
-- And I'm like, I google it and I'm like, oh, this is totally a scam.
-- So it's very funny.
I, I make our, our awareness training every year at, at Anor
because I hate, I've, I've tried to find something that's like appallingly bad.
And I would say 80% of the training,
I think just boils down to just please come and ask me
if something seems weird like the end of every slide is that.
And I think 90% of that is just like pause, take a breath and think for a moment.
But on the other side, lots of people come and ask me questions now.
And I'm like, and I even tell them, I don't care how
dumb you think it is.
-- Yep.
-- Come to me with it. Oh,
the same thing with security reports.
-- Like I would rather 100 false positives.
-- That's awesome.
All right, I'm ending the show. All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Quote from
our security podcast.com. Hit up the show
at Susy Podos
-- says podcast. Hashtag I Mastodon Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You
-- too.
-- Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.