Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner knowing what a pager is.
Josh Pressers. I do know what a pager is.
I had to explain what a pager was twice yesterday,
why
it came up just talking about tech and old tech and
old cell phones and like, yeah, like my, I wasn't even a cell phone.
-- My first thing was a alphanumeric pager.
-- I, I do remember that.
-- Of
-- course, anybody under the age of 40 doesn't know what that.
Thank goodness they were terrible.
They're still used because the frequency they're on penetrates buildings,
parking structures, basements.
-- So that's why hospitals still use them.
-- That's true. I can hate them though.
I do not miss owning a pager at all
so
well. And then I had to explain to the waitress, the thing is
you would call your answer service and an answer service
was this person that would take a message for you.
And
like,
obviously you have to call them because they can't call you
because if they could call you and knew where you were,
then the person calling to leave you a message could have just done that.
And
that's right. And you couldn't push a message to somebody.
And she's like, oh, yeah, she's like, texts are better and I'm like, uh huh.
-- Yes, they are
-- for sure.
-- I don't think anyone would disagree.
-- That thing. I will never pine for the olden days
anyway. All right. This is not a topic I have any desire to dwell on.
Well, it's this forward March of progress, which is good because things are better
and
well better.
And
once in a while
I'll take texting over a voicemail any day,
I'll agree
with that. And like the new voicemail interface in Iowa 17. I'm sorry.
But having it pop up and I can just hit the play button.
I don't have to dial my voicemail, punch in the code and blah, blah, blah.
-- I love that.
-- My phone has been doing that for a long time.
I don't think it's an I OS 17 feature. I think you're, it's a phone provider feature.
Uh uh
I am with a uh
I'm with Tell us which is a Canadian phone provider. So by definition, they suck.
That's fair.
But this goes back to like, for example. So, um unity is a game engine.
It's very widely used.
All right, our topic is uncertainty for anyone who's thinking about it.
Changing
to a new podcast right now, it's gonna be good.
So unity
-- wants to make more money
-- as does everybody.
Yeah, that's fair. I get that
but
-- they did two things.
-- Only two,
well, two main things.
They did lots of little things, but two main things is number one,
they decided to
alter the terms of the deal.
-- Pray we don't alter it further,
-- right.
In a, in a way that's pretty ugly. And actually
see, here's the thing,
like Microsoft's is a good example of this Microsoft
will absolutely bend you over to make money.
And like,
especially if you're like the mouse story where
they saw the mouse at a meeting and then
came out with their own mouse that looks
suspiciously identical six months later or whatever.
But in
general, if you're an actual partner of Microsoft, they'll bend you over,
but they won't kill you
typically because they understand that they can extract a lot of
money in the long term by having a bigger healthier ecosystem.
I don't know if I would agree with that.
There's a whole embrace extend and extinguish concept.
They're a bad example, probably.
-- Look, I think we can, we look, we don't need to give examples.
-- Unity went too far
with
altering the deal and hurting their developers to the point where
the,
the new terms of the deal because it was paper install and
if somebody buys your game and installs it on five systems,
now you have to pay five times as much to unity.
OK? We should clarify what, what is even going on.
So unity is a game engine used by mostly
independent developers and it's a very nice game engine.
If you've done any game development, ever,
you understand the importance of an engine that takes care of your
physics and drawing the sprites and collisions and tons of stuff,
right?
And unity had a really nice model where for not a lot of money,
you could get a really nice game engine
and
recently they altered how the game engine was priced.
So they want a cut of every sale after a certain point.
So I think you need to get like a million installs or a million revenue.
I forget what the number is exactly.
-- So
-- that was part of the problem is it was based on installs.
So if you're getting like a lot of people trying trials and stuff,
ok.
Basically what it boiled down to is a lot of small developers are like,
hang on a second.
This might bankrupt to me. Sure,
not, this might cost me money or I might make a lot less money, but
this might actually bankrupt me. Sure. Sure.
Like I will end up owing more money than I've made.
And, and so here's what happened though.
So unity does this, there's enormous backlash
-- there,
-- but there's the second part is
they were going to make this post facto.
So what unity had traditionally done has said has said
we have a game engine version X basically they did it by year
and
that game engine X year has terms. And if you agree to those terms,
that's the deal moving forwards. If we alter the engine and the deal,
you can move to that. And if you don't like it,
you can stay on the old one,
which is not
super great, but it's better than nothing.
But in this case, they said no, no, no,
this is post facto like this is altering
all the deals for all time.
You don't have an option.
You don't have an out and to add insult or injury previously, they,
they had had a github
repo
that tracked their terms of service and changes to it
and it just sort of got deleted
because no one was reading it, we were told. So it's fine,
but that's the real problem is and this is
very specifically
not how contract law works. Sure
contract law is pretty specific around the world.
But if you agree to a contract, that's the contract.
And if you want to alter the contract,
that either has to be a provision in the contract for that alteration,
like we reserve the right to change the terms and conditions at any time,
we feel without warning,
but that's generally not how actual proper business contracts work.
And so unity had that out, but they, they joined it.
They so they
like every single lawyer that saw this unity thing was like what?
Like
you can't do that.
Ok? Anyway, anyway, it doesn't matter. It's less important. I think.
Well, it does matter because it,
-- oh no, no,
-- no, just it's the, the overall problem.
So anyway, unity does all these shenanigans, right?
And an enormous number of people are now saying we're going to move to Godot,
which is go dot Which is an open source gaming engine
and unity has walked back. Some of these changes.
I won't say they walked them all back,
but they realized they kind of made a mistake.
But an enormous number of developers are like,
we're not going back because they're gonna just do it again.
Well, and that's the problem is they can't go back because now unity has introduced,
not only did they do a terrible thing,
but they then walked it back and they were like, oh blah, blah, blah, we,
we hear your concerns.
We, we understand that you don't like this
and now they've not only done a bad thing, but they've also done an uncertain thing.
That's right. Exactly.
Ok. So, hypothetically speaking,
they could march forward and never do a bad
thing again and be a good company that this is
theoretically possible. It's, it's a possibility, it's unlikely.
-- And most of us are mostly game devs are not really,
-- we've seen this dance before.
Exactly
what is more likely as we've seen many companies and legislatures and things
do is introduce a terrible piece of legislation or a terrible change.
Walk it back and then just sort of keep hammering that
wedge home until they get it all the way in.
That does happen a lot.
And that's kind of what people expect to
happen because that's kind of what usually happens.
But I, I think the uncertainty is
the, the key pivot here because as security people,
uncertainty is
the single most dangerous thing we have to deal with on a regular basis.
And I think there's a couple of
how severe is this vulnerability?
Yeah, like, if not knowing is worse than anything. And this is where like
I give, I mean,
remember when we were at Red Hat and Red Hat marks vulnerabilities won't fix.
And a lot of people are like, oh, you shouldn't do that, but it's like, no, no, no.
And,
and,
and in an intermediate limbo state of uncertainty
is worse than saying we're never fixing this
because what does the customer do?
Oh,
maybe they're going to fix it and we don't have to worry
about it or maybe they don't fix it but we don't know,
you know, whereas, oh, you're not going to fix it. Ok. Now we have a choice.
We can stop using the product.
We can yell at Red Hat, we can tell them no, you really do need to fix this.
We can find a compensating control. We can
and just say, look, it's a moderate, it's cross site scripting.
Just don't log into the admin screen
after clicking links and email. That's
right. That's right. Exactly.
And that's the right.
And that's the thing is uncertainty increases the cost of dealing with this
by magnitudes
for sure, for sure. I mean, this is,
this is the,
the cl a story which we're going to have a whole episode after this one all about CLAS
and what's the cl A contributor license agreement? Thank you.
But uh you know, with these, some of these companies like has
a
Corp just did this and, and
Bongo and Redis and, and friends, they changed the license
and that created uncertainty because now people are saying, OK,
so they change it to this, but they could change it again.
What do I do? What happens now?
And the thing to remember too is changing the
license or changing the terms of the deal.
It's not just that
it's
what does this really mean or indicate at a deeper level for sure.
The chances are something not good for you,
right?
And that is, it's part of that uncertainty of, oh I was a partner with them,
but now they see me as food.
-- No really.
-- They always saw you as food cart. I just figured it out now.
But anyway, and there's a third story we want to tie into this as well,
which is salesforce and meta.
When I was searching for the salesforce link, I found out the
salesforce and meta
laid off a ton of people and now they're saying, oh and
-- on second thought, we need to bring some of you back.
-- So,
and the best part here is why did all these high tech company layoffs happen?
And from what I've been reading it, it sounds like a
uh tech salaries have been going up, tech people have been, you know,
doing well, doing successful
and a bunch of hedge funds and stuff said we don't like this
and
as kind of an excuse of between work from home, return to office and, oh COVID,
the economy is terrible.
These companies like salesforce laid off 10% of their people.
Microsoft had layoffs
and yet they all had either record or
-- borderline record revenue and profits
-- for sure,
for sure.
And there's definitely weird business shenanigans.
None of us will probably ever understand behind all of this.
There's a spreadsheet somewhere that
-- made the numbers shift in
-- with. Absolutely.
Absolutely.
But the point is if, if a company laid you off and I was like, oh, on second thought,
we need you back like
that's uncertainty to a degree and I don't know how you would respond to that.
II, I would love to say no way would I come back? But I'm not in a position
to say yes or no to something like that.
But as an outsider that feels like a lot
of unknowns and uncertainty that would make me nervous.
-- The
-- thing
-- is, it's been what, three or four months in sales force case. So either
to put it simply either these people found a new job or they didn't.
And if they found a new job, why in the heck, unless that new job is terrible,
why in the heck would they, like, now give notice that, that new job
and go back to sales force or alternatively, they don't
have a new job and, well, maybe they need to pay the rent so they go back to sales force.
But I would assume I would hope that they're, you know,
buffing their resume and like, looking for something with more stability because,
well, you got laid off once it
could happen again.
I mean, maybe, maybe it's definitely,
it's, it's one of those weird things and I, I feel like
there's this huge,
just like weird pot of uncertainty brewing all over the place right now where I,
I don't know what it is and maybe it's just me being a paranoid security freak,
but I feel like there's so much in the air right now
and so many things we can't fathom or understand
that the, the level of uncertainty has my spider sense going off like nonstop.
I, I think that's true because for example, pensions and benefits used to be defined
in the sense of like you work for the government
and for every year you work for the government,
you get 2%.
That's how it works provincially here.
Now it's 1.25% matching funds and stuff.
And a private companies, like, remember when Sears went out of business.
Oh, yeah.
You remember what happened to the pension fund?
-- What
-- pension fund?
Yeah, that's,
oops,
that money was supposed to be protected and put
aside for these people and now it's gone.
You,
you actually reminded me of another angle to
this with the whole government talk is so,
first of all the US government's credit rating
was decreased like it earlier in the year. And part of the reason was uncertainty
because the like the politicians we have in the
United States can't freaking tie their shoes right now.
So the credit agencies were like, this is uncertainty. We don't like uncertainty.
We're going to lower your credit rating,
which
I don't blame them for it all.
But then, but then here's the other thing that really, I find amusing
is
there is a ton of open government jobs in the United States
and they're struggling to fill them.
And one of the reasons is because we have a political party in the
United States saying if we take control of the government in the next election,
we're going to fire half of the government.
-- Would you take that job? Like no freaking way to like, no, absolutely
-- not.
Well, and a great example of this is so there's a list of federal shutdowns here
and
there were 1234, the first four shutdowns.
Guess how long they were
there? The couple days only. I know they were really short 11 day. Ok.
The third one was approximately the, the,
the 3rd and 4th 1 were approximately four hours.
-- That sounds like someone lost the paperwork or something
-- pretty much.
Then in 1990
1995 you have a three and a five day shut down. Ok, that's bad.
And then in 1995 96 a 21 day shutdown.
And then of course, you know, the 2013 1 for 16 days, the 2018,
1 for three days and then the 2018 1 for 35 days
as I speak, as an outsider here, I'm Canadian and I look at it and I'm like,
this is literally insane to me.
Yeah, it's definitely not because
one of the few jobs of government is to have legitimacy.
Right. Yes. And
you're not supposed to show the side of your, like if you're going to have a fight,
you do it behind closed doors like you don't
this in public so to speak.
And so as an outsider, I just find this utterly insane that your government
-- can shut down.
-- I mean, I think most of us here think that also
and all non-essential services like the Park rangers and stuff are kind of like
it
-- just left hanging in the wind
-- like much,
don't go to work, don't get paid
-- that.
-- And so
again, back to this,
but the thing is the beauty is the US government has enough legitimacy.
They're like,
what are you going to do about it? Right. Not pay your taxes. Ignore us
like that.
-- How this
-- works. I don't think that's gonna work.
So
there was this great quote that somebody said it was a Dutch quote that trust
walks in but leaves on horse,
which is to say it takes a long time and effort to build trust and it leaves very fast.
And somebody else pointed out
if you do a great job and make people happy,
they basically won't say anything, whatever, who cares.
But if you piss them off
and break their trust,
-- well, they'll tell their friends
-- it's, it's the perpetual challenge of security.
If we do our jobs, nothing happens.
But when we don't do our jobs, holy cow. Do we hear about it?
And we hear about it
and, and I think the whole uncertainty angle and this is,
this is truly why I wanted to discuss this even is just the fact that
as security people,
if we are, if your organization has like a concept of uncertainty,
especially around security,
you're going to have a problem because part of
our job is removing uncertainty from doing business.
Yes.
Like
that sounds silly when you say it, but that's it.
Well, it's managing risk
and to manage risk, you have to quantify it.
And what really blows my mind about unity is ignoring for the
fact whether or not what they did was bad or wrong.
They made a significant decision
and then a week later, totally reversed it,
which shows
you clearly didn't consider
your decision.
You know, it's like you're playing chess and you blundered your queen.
Yeah.
Like you, you clearly didn't think this moved through and oops.
And now you're like, oh, we're going to take it back like
that doesn't work in chess, but it does work in real life.
But what it says to me is that your senior leadership
is not very competent,
probably not, you know what? It's
probably not provably not because either they would have made the bad
decision and stuck with it or found some way to sell it
or
they would have made the bad decision in the first place.
They would have floated it and been like, oh wow, wow,
that's some negative feedback.
And the lawyers are saying that's not how contract law works.
So maybe we shouldn't do this.
You know, it's like the,
the layoff at sales force where they laid off 10% of their people.
And now four months later are saying
they literally had a Boomerang campaign.
They had stuffed Boomerang plushies and t-shirts.
And my only thought was like, if you throw a boomerang and don't pay attention,
it's gonna whack you in the head.
And
like that's, that was my mental image of this Boomerang campaign.
But they literally were throwing boomerang plushies out into
the crowd trying to like hype people up to
like get them to tell their friends to come
back to sales force after they've been laid off.
And,
like,
it's kind of one thing if you get laid off
from the government because the government is big and impersonal,
it's like nothing personal but just
the, you know, the way the election went or whatever,
but salesforce, it's very much. No. The company laid me off to make numbers
and now you want me back,
it happens.
Well, the next time you need to make the numbers.
That's right. I guess I'm on that list of
probably
here's the fat we can trim
and it just, it blows my mind that
number one,
every place I've ever worked.
Well,
I've actually not been locked out immediately when I
give notice because they generally make me keep working,
which annoys me.
I want to get locked out for two weeks.
-- I wish I had that too.
-- I
know.
Right.
But in general when you lay off somebody or fire them or whatever, you,
you walk them out and it's like work done here
and
because there are a risk at that point,
well, it's not even that they're a risk. It's like
I want to be locked out because if anything goes wrong,
I don't want to get blamed for it
because like, enough stuff goes wrong naturally
that I get blamed for anyways. I don't need to intentionally break things,
you know, like,
like the time I broke, uh,
access to the admin control panel on the website because I forgot,
I'm not in the WF rule
that
everything's fine.
But like,
it's weird to me that we have this idea of this, like,
insider threat of the minute you lay off somebody or fire them
-- and now they're asking them to come back.
-- I mean,
that's a funny conversation.
Like,
are they really going to be working hard and
giving the company all they've got after the company,
like, kicked them to the curb literally.
I mean, look, I don't, I don't think you can make that accusation.
I think it's on a case by case basis.
I think there are people who would come back and like, legitimately be phenomenal
workers and there, there might be people who would come back and not be,
you know, statistically,
you have to think the bell curve would have shifted to a side.
-- Maybe
-- you'd think so.
I, I would think so, but I'm not willing to make that assumption either
because I think anyone listening in that position who would go back,
like,
yeah, I don't want crap on them.
Well, there's different reasons for going back.
You know, a lot of people are very moral and ethical and won't cause any problems.
But at the same time, like,
I have to assume that they're going to be looking for a
new job and going to be leaving at some point because,
you know, they already got kicked out once or
like the unity thing. It was funny.
I was watching, um, you know, day nine, former Starcraft caster and
he's big in the gaming thing. Right on youtube.
Uh very educational, great guy.
And, you know, and he's basically talking about the unity situation. He's like,
Mike, the company he works for, did not choose unity for different reasons.
But he's like, well, you know, it's,
it's just one more thing they're glad about like,
oh, when the CS A moved out of last Pass, we actually moved out of last pass
because we couldn't get access to somebody's passwords when
they left unless they gave us the master password.
And I needed that corporate recovery because that's not their accounts.
-- It's the C SAS accounts.
-- Right. Right.
Plus last Pass had a history of some security incidents.
It was starting to make me nervous.
So it's funny you say that because I remember when
I moved my family from last pass to one password,
it was painful
and it wasn't even because they had a lot of security incidents.
It's because they handled it all incompetently. And I had
the level of uncertainty I had in their product was
off the charts and I was like,
you have to stop using this. Like, this is unsafe.
Yeah.
And the thing is I can do products that
are incompetent and unsafe potentially for certain things,
but something like a password manager or my car
or the food I eat
I, I need it to be good quality certainty. Boring like that.
Nutritional label actually needs to be what's in the package.
My car, if it, you know, starts to fail,
it needs to fail in a way that doesn't involve me
careening into a car accident,
for sure. For sure.
And my password manager, if it has a problem or fails,
I need it to fail in a way that doesn't result in,
oh, they used one round of encryption.
So even if I like,
I'm sorry, but I don't care how good your master password is,
if there's only one round of encryption.
GP us are heck fast nowadays
for sure.
I mean, I just,
I literally bought two and shoved them into my desktop here so I
could have 24 gigs of V RA M affordably for like 600 bucks.
U si got 24 GAV
each. Uh 12 gigs each.
No, I mean 600 bucks for both.
No, 600 bucks total.
They were about 400 bucks. Canadian apiece
like
a pair of RT X 30 sixties with 12 gigs of ra M.
I don't know what any of those numbers mean, but I'll assume they're good.
It has like
somewhere between seven and 9000 K
Decors each and 12 gigs of ra M and like, wow, I upgraded from an NVIDIA super 1616 50
or 1660 super. Also not help.
Well, that's,
that's the actual current most popular card on
steam and has been for four years now because
the video card market went all.
But like
I fire a BNG and instead of it like drawing it like a child with a crayon,
like doing one thing at a time.
-- Like there's your fender b
-- ng the, the driving game you mean?
So like it draws the fender, then it draws the tire, then it draws a boulder
like it's like watching Bob Ross, like over here we're gonna put this,
this one is just like put up.
-- Oh, cool.
-- And it's butter smooth.
I mean,
-- you have $600 worth of graphics card now.
-- Well, yeah, exactly.
But, um, but back to the uncertainty,
if there's uncertainty then,
well, I don't want to plan for the worst case scenario because that's expensive.
But maybe I have to plan for the
worst case scenario because maybe that's what will happen
and conversely, maybe nothing happens.
Maybe I get my best case scenario and I don't have to do anything,
but that's also not very likely because the
company showed that they might do something goofy.
-- I mean,
-- but this is, this is part of our job.
If you get laid off,
you have to plan, you have to do, I need to find a new job.
Yeah. Or do I wait for sales force to call me back?
No, I don't think anyone would say that's a strategy.
That's what sales force thought they were
apparently. Doing.
-- I, I,
-- I have a better example that's less offensive in terror inducing than layoffs.
So
we
at
Encor
have a container registry. We use to distribute our product. Right.
And we're having some
issues with the registry we're using today. I'll say,
and we need a solution and we need it soon.
And this is one of those things where,
like when you have a service that is core to your business.
If it fails, that is an existential threat. Yes.
And it's funny because we were in a meeting and I'm like,
this is an existential threat.
Like we're fixing it now.
You know what I mean?
And that as soon as that is said, it's like, oh, of course,
it is like we need to do it right now.
And I think this is
as security people.
I think one of the really interesting things because anything that is core to
basically the things that keep the lights on and keep pay the paychecks coming,
those are the services you absolutely cannot live without. Right.
Like, I think we could all agree if our email fell off the face of the planet,
we would have enormous problems.
You know what I mean?
We ceased to function as a, as an organization
and,
-- and
-- so how would you even coordinate recovery?
-- No. Really?
-- Well, I mean, so that's another conversation. There are ways
of doing, you know, side channel conversations and things that, that's another,
it's disaster.
-- Recovery at that point.
-- Right. Let me, oh, here's a question.
How would you do a cold start of your company if you had control of your domain name?
And that was it.
I, I have, it's written down.
-- No, it's, it's phone telephones because
-- you're a crazy person that
plans for this eventuality. I guarantee you less than 1% of companies
have thought this through.
But yeah, like this is,
this is one of the things you account for in
a like a tinfoil hat disaster recovery program is like,
let's say literally all of the infrastructure we have is gone,
including employee laptops.
What happens next?
And of course,
the cell phone network needs to survive for my plan to work if that's gone.
I assume society is crumbled. So I'm fine.
Like I have other issues then
like
anyway,
but I, I think this is one of the pieces of uncertainty I think about all the time
is what are like, what are the things we absolutely have to have?
It's kind of like Maslow's hierarchy of needs, right?
Like if I don't have food and water, I don't care if I have internet.
Well, I kind of do, but you know what I mean?
Like maybe internet and food and water are on the same level.
But you know what I'm saying?
And I know like people say, oh,
Maslow's hierarchy has been debunked and whatever
-- they sort of
-- represent the same thing,
their, their foundational infrastructure now and if they cease to work,
then something has gone terribly, terribly wrong.
And now that you say this a lot,
I think this is one of the reasons why A I is
scaring so many companies is because they want to use it.
But
even as like, let's ignore, like, OK,
let's say they use Microsoft's A I which I think we'll agree that
Microsoft as a company is going to be around for a long time and
they only kill products if they like really have to
like, they're not Google
to put it bluntly like,
oh, what was that Google service?
You said you were going to start using and I'm like, in three years,
you're going to be angry about it.
Oh, I forget what it is. They just read the price on Google apps for your domain
and there's, I think they call it Cloud Id.
Oh Cloud ID. That's the one which is where you can keep the login
because like, one of my concerns with,
if I would even try to move away from Google for my domain,
your single sign on
single sign up, but you can supposedly keep that for free.
But at the same time, like you said,
Google doesn't have the best track record in this sport.
They
just
Google Podcast.
I don't even know.
I
have no
idea.
The thing I'm thinking of the,
one of the biggest challenges with A I is not whether or not,
the company stays around and all that.
It's
the A I
models themselves are constantly being modified with new guard rails,
new capabilities capabilities that get worse or go away entirely.
And so if you have a business process that depends on being
able to ask this A I reliably a question of like,
and it all of a sudden
either stops answering in which case, at least, you know,
something happened and went wrong
or worse. What if it subtly answers X
differently in a way that
is like, let's say you're using it for contract reviews
that could have some significant consequences. And,
and, and I think this is
um I've been thinking about this like, why are these companies so scared to use it?
And it's this uncertainty of
and I think this is one of the reasons open source A I will really take off
is because you can basically deploy an A I and freeze it and just be like,
it will behave this way
because even if it's true, I that you deploy in a quote
unquote frozen state,
you know, if you modify the temperature, these things are so complicated,
they can give totally different answers.
00 for sure, for sure.
But you could take away a lot of uncertainty and risk of like
all those, remember those lawyers that were saying like, yeah, man
cha PT four,
like I had to do my job and now they like put
on some guard rails and I have to like rejigger all my
making it, write my briefs.
You know what else this reminds me of is Slack
just changed their U I and I freaking hate it.
And it's like the
worst. This is one of the issues I have with the whole like universe is a service is
if one day Slack decides we're changing the U I
I have zero say in this, I can't be like this is stupid.
I am really struggling with the new UI
I am having not a good time with it.
I don't want, I don't want to feel like old man yells at Cloud here but man, it's
not good.
I'm not seeing how it benefits me. Like I OS has,
I've been using it since the iphone version three.
So whatever version of I OS that was, it was in the single digits and now up to 17
and
they haven't done anything that made it
-- immediately significantly worse.
-- I won't disagree with that statement.
I feel like I just upgraded to the latest I Os. Not long.
What did I know it was my, my Mac, my Macbook,
I upgraded my Macbook to the latest version because part of my job is like
guinea picking all this crap to make sure it doesn't break any of our apps
and
nothing. I I looked at the the changes list. I'm like,
I don't even know what any of this is the one, the one joke I made is Apple.
Now claims like improved gaming experience.
I'm like, oh, I better game for the ne the rest of the week.
Everyone to, to make sure it works.
-- Those seven users care.
-- I wish, I wish I could do that.
Does ma
-- even show up in the steam survey? I have
-- no idea.
Do they? Does steam run on Mac? I don't even know.
I have steam running on that M One Mac over there. It's beautiful.
The M One is a very quick machine.
Ok. That's fair. That's fair.
But
anyway, anyway,
-- this
-- uncertainty thing, I think part of it is there,
there are certain things in life that are uncertain by definition,
like the weather,
the weather is just uncertain and har particularly kind of like this hurricane,
it could go here, it could go over there.
Who knows? The supercomputer said maybe there.
But the European supercomputer said maybe over there.
But there's a lot of uncertainty that people generate
unnecessarily.
Like if salesforce did 10% layoffs and said like
too bad
10% layoffs.
Well, that's usually what that would have been the end of the story,
but now four months later,
they're like literally a boomerang campaign of please come back.
Wow, that's kind of messed up,
right? Like
kind of,
you know,
next
-- year.
-- I
mean, maybe that's a good question.
And so that's the thing is,
I guess if possible introduce as little uncertainty as possible.
So that means things like gaming out the decision before you announce it.
Sure,
maybe like actually maybe like have a quiet side conversation
with a customer and see if they punch you.
No, no, I want, I want to clarify something. We're running ourselves out of time,
but I think we should end on this point.
You mentioned like gaming it out and,
and clarifying decisions and all this.
I have a suspicion that as security people, this feels extra ridiculous to us
because part of what we do
is trying to understand uncertainty before it becomes a problem and address it.
Right? Because we're like, broken humans
that we, we purposely look for the worst in every situation.
And it's funny because you, I mean,
I'm sure we've all been there where you talk to a friend and you're like, oh,
that's not safe and they're like, what's wrong with you?
Why would you even talk about that?
You know, where you see a thing or whatever?
And
I have a suspicion most of the leadership
that is responsible for things like coordinating layoffs or headcount or whatever
has never had to do that
in the kind of way we do so to them,
they had no idea this was a possibility.
They certainly don't do it every day, although
they should.
That's,
that's one thing I really respect is whenever
you watch a competent Western military general,
uh, testifying in front of Congress or the Senate or having, you know,
their internal meetings with their general staff,
they really do
consider a lot of
the potential bad things.
And despite that, we still have, you know, like 20 years of war in Afghanistan
and then two weeks later it's like, whoops. Well, that was a total waste of time.
That's true.
But
they
are at least working towards that because they have real world consequences.
They do and, like, very real. Like, people die in real world.
Like at least when we screw up, like people don't die.
Remember when we were all afraid of Russia and their military power
and now to quote,
I forget who I'm quoting.
But, you know, Russia is still the second most powerful military
in
Ukraine.
Yeah,
like
not the world but
Ukraine.
Right.
Yeah. Oh, for sure. For sure.
If you'd said that to me in the eighties
or nineties or two thousands or even 2000 tens,
I would have been like, what the heck?
No.
Yeah. No, no way. Like you're nuts. No way.
Like they have 5000 tanks.
-- Yep. Yep.
-- For sure. Here
we are,
here, we are. That's like the,
here we are. That feels like the motto.
This is the thing like uncertainty to me
indicates that the leadership has done a terrible
-- job.
-- Well, look, here's what I'm going to end on.
Uncertainty breeds mistrust
and an enormous amount of what we do on a daily basis, either personally. Or in,
as business people
-- trust is the currency that makes it all go.
-- Yep.
That's the reason I can,
because I can phone a random restaurant and order 50 bucks of food and they're like,
ok,
it'll be 30 minutes and then hang up on me
and I don't have to pay for it and I don't have to, you know, they just, it works
because trust
exactly
100%.
All right, I'm calling
to
-- thank
-- you, Kurt. Thank everyone for listening.
Go to the social security podcast.com.
Head up the show, not, it's U Pound us says podcast. Hashtag
hit us up on social media.
Kurt
-- have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.