Hello and welcome to an encrypted copy of
the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
This is definitely not encryption. You could maybe call it stenography
but not encryption.
Well, no, I mean that it's served over http S usually, hopefully,
-- mostly I think it
-- always is.
-- I don't know if you can access the MP3 over HTTP I, I could check that.
-- But
so we're going to talk about,
there's a really interesting article and thread on hacker news about
API S should not redirect http to HTTP S
and
it's, it's actually a really interesting statement because it's actually quite
complicated and complex.
Is it,
don't do it?
Well,
let's start by defining things a bit. So first of all, we have
http back in the olden days, which did not give a font to encryption
because encryption was like for those weird GP G people who had keys signing parties
that were kind of strange and a little bit
saucy
and encryption was on
cod computationally expensive at the time because it's not like your CPU had
des capability.
-- It
-- was slower.
Like if you wanted to encrypt
network traffic. You needed a multi
CPU system notice, I didn't say multicore. We weren't there yet,
you know, I mean,
and encryption accelerators existed,
that was the thing you could buy a PC I card that had an encryption chip
right
-- now. It's just built into your CP
-- U.
Well, and the other, the more important aspect of it is
the original SSL
was patent encumbered in the United States.
And so that, I mean,
this is really where like you had the RS A library and you had
open SSL and like open SSL was technically not legal in the United States,
which we all still used it.
That was not
technically Kosher.
So then along came HTTP S
with a little bit of security on the end.
But the problem is even today 25 whatever, 20 a long time later, a lot of years,
a lot of stuff still kind of defaults to
-- trying HTTP first and then trying http
-- si mean,
I generally type Http into my web browser and then the web browser
magically does the right thing.
And so originally there was,
there was kind of no way to force people to use http.
Yes, short of putting a redirect on the HTTP site saying, you know, I'm not,
I'm not here anymore.
Go to http SF
slash slash C free.org
and the web browser,
people kind of quickly realize that doesn't work because by definition,
if somebody is doing a man in the middle attack
or has the ability to sniff or manipulate the traffic.
They
simply don't
serve that header back to you.
So you stay at HTTP
and you know,
and like literally like logging into my bank was like you went to
HTTP and clicked a login link that went to the secure website.
Well,
if there was a man in the middle,
they would just rewrite that button to not go to HTTP S just
keep going. Http. So we had this thing added called HSTS,
-- right, which stands for what
-- http strict transport security
and all HS
TS is, is a fancy way of saying literally only access this website
over http S for the following amount of time and
then you'd give a list like a number of seconds and
yeah, like a year or whatever.
But there's one sentence in the RFC that has caused so much grief. OK.
5.1 HSTS host declaration, an http host declares itself an HSTS host
by issuing to UAs user agents,
an HSTS policy which is represented by
and conveyed via the strict transport security.
Http response header field over secure transport, egtls
upon air free receipt and processing of this header by a Conformant U A,
the U A regards this host as a known HSTS host.
So it's basically saying that you serve the HSTS header
to the user agent and then it assuming it's correct,
the user agent is supposed to.
Now the question. What can the HSTS
-- header be served
-- over? Can it be served over? Http? I actually don't know
because I didn't, you can't say wrong. I asked you a question.
That's the thing is I just read it out to you. Did you not listen?
Yes, Kurt, I obviously did not listen.
That word salad. You read
it says over secure transport, egtls?
Oh, that part.
-- Ok.
-- Well, you can serve HSTS
http.
-- Ok.
-- That's not supposed to happen
for a variety of reasons.
I mean,
it makes sense because obviously a man in the
middle attacker is just gonna remove the HSTS header.
That's one of them.
And the second reason that's actually think about the time that this came from,
did people have their HTTP S reliably set up all the time?
And the answer is no,
definitely not. So part of this was you could only serve it over the secure channel,
thus having a high degree of confidence that that secure channel actually worked.
And also what you said with the man in the middle.
First of all,
a lot of people serve HSTS headers over HTTP and a lot of web
browsers and stuff accept it because really there's not a huge downside to it,
right?
Like the the attack, there's, there's not a lot of attacks where the attacker,
if they can man in the middle of your traffic,
that they're gonna want to upgrade you to HS HTTP S
-- right? They would they would just stay at http.
-- I want to
interject here because this is what basically has put us in the mess we're
in with web browsers in general today is the fact that the web browsers,
what was this saying?
Be generous on what you receive and strict on what you send
like that.
It was the old mantra of the internet way back in the day, web browsers have really,
that is how they work. They have been
incredibly generous in terms of like how they'll parse html.
What kind of nonsense they accept from web servers,
you know, in HSTS headers and http, even though the standard might say not to.
And I think this, this whole http redirecting the HTTP S is,
is a perfect example where there's this prevailing attitude of instead
of doing the right thing and we put writing quotes,
we're going to do the easy thing because it doesn't make people angry or annoyed.
Well, and it doesn't, it's not as disruptive, right? If I
serve in HTTP S redirect, then it just sort of keeps magically working. Whereas if I
on an extreme example, I,
I used to serve any http at all or I serve http with like a 403 or a 404,
some version of like you can't do that
and things just break
well. Yeah,
people now are forced into upgrading their software as opposed to, well,
it just keeps working with a redirect
Right. Exactly.
And so what's also fascinating is curl added support for hsts like uh four
years ago in 2020 but it doesn't in memory storage of it only.
OK. So it only would be within that session,
but
it does not persist by default across like a web browser by default
will see an HST SS header for like seared.org and be like cool.
-- I'm logging that puts it in a little text file
-- that's expected with web browsers.
They have cookie stores and secret stores and now they, I mean, cripes,
they have magic, just stores for websites, right?
-- Websites can store arbitrary crap. But
-- people forget that most API
clients
don't do that. And they, a lot of people when they think about using the web as an API,
they apply their existing mental model of web browsers
to their API client, which is wrong. All right.
-- Th
-- this topic I think is divergent too divergent from the
actual topic of redirecting http to http S and why it is bad.
Well, and so that gets this is you are now faced with a choice of,
you have a couple of options.
You can not survive
-- http at all, which is kind of the same as serving an error,
-- do that,
just do that.
Well, that's actually not a terrible thing.
It's actually a good solution in some ways. The second one is you can serve http
-- with an error like a 403 or 40
-- four. Don't do that. Don't do that.
-- It's that, that's a bad idea.
-- Why is that a bad idea?
Because
the way the web works
is we have http headers.
So for example, let's say I'm submitting basic authentication.
I'll just use this as my example. But many, many forms of authentication do this.
Cookies are handled in this way.
There's all this information that's sent with the web request, right?
Let's say I'm going to an API and I'm using basic O which you also shouldn't use.
But we're just gonna pretend for this example, spherical
cow,
right? So
when you add basic
a
authentication is that that right? Whatever I pretend it's right.
When you add that authentication method to your HTTP request,
what you end up with
is a header added to the request
that has an encoded user name and password, not encrypted encoded, right?
So now I go to the http site, right?
I send that encoded user name and password.
Then the web server responds with the redirect saying no, no, no,
go to this http S site instead.
I've already sent that information in the header.
-- It's already been exposed, right?
-- And this is going to be true
of any HTTP request.
Like any information you have in cookies in headers
in whatever is going to be sent over http.
So a, a redirect or A 403 is worse than just straight up,
not accepting the TCP connection.
Well, the thing is if the man in the middle can actually inject traffic,
then they can also pretend to be you on http
for sure. Yes, I agree.
This is where the,
this is where a lot of the argument of
basically having it break comes down because then it
gets,
it hopefully encourages people to actually update and correct their clients.
And so, and,
and this is because there's a lot of API S that are very uh verse in their responses,
like it's not just what's the temperature six, you know what I mean?
What's your status, light bulb on or off?
But there's a lot of API S where it's like, you know, here's some data, I need
some sort of response to that data, right?
And A is are a good example because you're basically sending in a bunch of
and expecting a whole bunch of data back. And
all of these A I API S for example, have things like
did, did the,
did the A I actually complete the request or did it like kind of just stall out,
run out of tokens or whatever?
And so for example, open A
I actually serves a 403, but they also serve
a Json Blob as they normally would with the actual
error message that is quite helpful and, and very explicit.
I hate websites that do that well.
So the, the one argument though is that then OK, so now you've tried
accessing with HTTP, it just broke. Now you're forced
-- to do the right thing in air quotes of using HTTP S
-- sure. And, and the 403 is
ok,
but you're still probably sending authentication information with that request,
which leads to the second thing, somebody pointed out
that there are API S that when they receive
access tokens or credentials over http
will revoke them and then serve the air.
-- I did see that. Yeah, that was in the article. That's very
-- cool
that now, now you're really forcing the person to fix it
because it's not gonna work until they reset their tokens and use http.
Si mean in that context though,
why not just turn off http?
Like I fail to understand the benefit to even letting it run?
-- Because
-- if you don't serve http, there's no error. There's is my network broken
is my DNS broken
because I've tried like I've had times where HTTP breaks.
No,
-- no. Ok.
-- Look, let me, let's break down what you just explained.
So let's say there's a man in the middle attack, right?
I connect to the man in the middle.
If the man in the middle knows that the end
point I'm going to is going to revoke my credentials.
If I connect over HETP,
they're going to send the man in the middle data over hetps
again.
This is where
I think just straight up denying this kind of thing is going to be it.
It's a little more brutal and, and you're right, you could say is DNS broken,
-- is a network broken, whatever, whatever, at
-- least with a 403, I get the,
like the common case, I think you would agree is that there is no man in the middle.
Right. Right. They're,
they're not common at all.
And that's why so many people do http to http, read
direct, then serve an HSTS header and say from now on and forever
you
share. And this also and and this is also ignoring HSTS preload.
So there's this thing called HSTS preload,
which is essentially a a text list of domains like
cre.org does that still exist? Yes, it does. And it's still in use for example.
And here's what I find really cool. There's some top level domains in there like DEV,
like dot DEV
is in the preload list.
So everything served off of dot dev by web browser or any rational API you know,
http S client should always be http S.
But the challenge again is that things like curl don't use that.
Ah
that could be I I just, I went, I had to poke through the curl source code
and they support hsts, they can load it from a file, but by default, they don't. And
I think in the case of curl that's actually
valid because for example, I use curl all the time where I'm like,
I want to actually test something on http at an HTTP
SHSTS website like c.org and I need to test that,
like, for example,
the redirect works and obviously I can't test the redirect if curl
-- says no, you can only go to HTTP S
-- right.
I mean, I, I would not expect
any API client
-- to use the HSTS preload
-- list by
default.
I
would
say
it would be nice if it was an option.
I mean. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
But I mean, how many of them still don't do certificate validation correctly?
I mean, it's not zero.
Yeah.
But
so this is, and this is basically we're beginning to see why this is so hard to do
in a way
that is not.
There's always trade offs, there's always a downside,
there's always, well, but what about, what about this? What about this scenario?
What about, you know, so for example, don't serve http at all. Well, yeah.
Now people like go to your website and they're like, it's broken
and how many people are going to see the little dinosaur
-- and think, oh, I need to, I need to add an si mean,
-- the web browser default to http S now.
-- Well,
-- ok, bad example.
Like browsers are a bad example because they're
basically forcing people to do the right thing
if I run a curl command against against http and I just get time out.
My first thought is not that they don't serve http.
It's that something's broken on my end or their end maybe.
Well, because how am I gonna see? Here's the question.
How do I confirm that they don't serve? Http?
I just,
I keep trying it from different locations and it
keeps not working and I go either it's all totally
broken or it's just down whereas if they serve HTTP
and an error or a forbidden or a redirect.
Oh, ok. Now I see what your intent is.
Uh,
I don't,
I don't like your answer and I don't want to say it's correct.
I I'm not saying it is correct. I'm saying basically you got to make a choice.
There's trade offs and they're all bad.
Ok. No, you know what this is. Ok.
No, no, I want, I'm going to reframe this whole discussion.
This is a perfect example of the stupidity of our environment
where
the these libraries we use to access API S because no one is talking http, right?
We're all using some line.
Those libraries should be forcing HTTP connections
into HTTP S and they should just flat
up say don't use http unless you add this this special setting to the call.
That's like
-- I am a bad person equals true. That is what we need to do here.
-- We need to,
we need to flip the thing, which is what web browsers did, right?
We flipped from HTTP to htps but allow a fall back to
HTP because there are API S that are only available over http.
Well, like cramp in my home network. Right. I've got a great example.
So, uh uh a friend, he goes by Signal Nine on Mastodon.
He put a message up the other day.
That's like, oh, no, my, my Fresh RSS reader,
I forgot to back up the database and I've lost everything now because I did.
I've created the container.
I'm like, what's fresh RSS? And I look, I'm like, oh, this looks really cool.
And so I'm like, I'm running it in the basement now.
It's not running over hetps because I don't care and it's
house and it's for reading RSS feeds. So, whatever, right?
Like that's an example.
I really don't want to set it up with HTTP S because it won't be worth the hassle to me.
-- So HTTP is great
-- on an internal network with an internal IP.
-- Like
-- I still don't trust my network, my networks and I have teenagers, man,
this network is probably more dangerous than most corporate networks,
but I'm not going to pretend.
But this leads to, you know, sort of, I would say it really needs,
we decided on a case by case basis.
No,
no,
I don't think so.
I think that's what got us into this mess. I think
what we need to start doing
in the world of software is we need to be more strict about just
like libraries should not be supporting HTTP by default. Like they just shouldn't.
-- There's no reason for it
-- today,
but the challenge is if you have some internal corporate thing.
-- But
-- yeah, and then you have a way to override it, but you make it hard,
you make the wrong way hard and today the wrong way is easy.
That is the problem.
I know the reality of software is there's a
lot of 1020 30 year old software out there that
if, if you break it, people will yell at you and make you switch it back. So it works,
-- which means having to redirect.
-- But we're not talking about
old software. We're talking about
a library. I am using
to connect to a thing.
Breaking changes happen all the time in new versions of software, you forget.
There's a lot of,
there's a lot of people that don't upgrade though
-- and
-- that's then they're unaffected, right? They have other problems.
This won't be one of them
and look, this is the reality of using open source software.
This is why people don't upgrade their open source software.
Because when I go from version three to version four,
it's gonna break a bunch of stuff.
And if one of the things that breaks is I can't load http websites anymore.
Ok. I'm either going to use something else.
I'm going to stay on my old version forever or I'm going to figure out what's going on.
And then I can say, oh, I understand what's happening.
Now,
-- I will fix this
-- and yet you have that
RSS feed reader running with http in your basement.
-- In my
-- basement. Yeah,
I have sort of the exact same moral equipment.
-- I have a bit torrent with a web interface.
-- Here's the thing.
If I put it on the internet and I wanted to access it remotely, it would 100% have HTTP S
right. And, and
I'm pretty sure the web browser would be extremely unhappy connecting
to http
-- in, like open internet.
-- Oh, every time I have to log into my, my local
whatever wi fi router thing over HTP. Oh, my goodness.
I guess like, I'm like, yes, I really, yes, I know what I'm doing. Like, just
bought one and let me change the,
I think I, I haven't verified this in a long time,
but I'm pretty sure at least in Firefox it will not
let you fill out like authentication information on an http website,
it just won't do it.
Which is awesome.
So,
the password field or whatever,
-- because
-- it just wouldn't do it if I may be misremembering.
But I'm pretty sure on the internet not like your internal network because
of the private IP space is treated special by web browsers generally.
But I'm, I'm pretty sure when it was Chrome,
I forget I'm fairly certain I had that experience recently.
Like, this is, to me this is fascinating because there's,
there's all these tradeoffs and there's situations where
I can't upgrade the server but I can upgrade the client or vice versa.
I can upgrade the client but not the server or maybe I can't really upgrade both,
but I can put like a secure proxy in the middle because I've see, I've,
I actually had that at one point where, remember back in the day,
like one thing people did was
you'd have uh like a Squid proxy
that you would connect to over http
because all the computers, if you turned on encryption would like die,
they were so slow
and then you'd have like this beefy server box to then connect out.
-- I mean,
-- this is basically what like a Kuber Neti service mesh does
is you assume the intercommunication between Kubernetes nodes like you can,
you can offload encryption onto the service mesh,
then you don't have to worry about that in your app at all.
But then when you start reaching out to other things,
it gets, it gets hokey
and, and that's OK, like that's how it works sometimes. And, and although I mean,
the Ker
neti service mesh could put a
that could create problems with my totalitarian
solution
because I think in the Kubernetes universe,
you're still generally treating it as HTTP,
even though the service mesh is handling all of the encryption.
So it's not technically HTTP S
but again, this is where you have a special setting
that says yes, I absolutely 100% mean this to be HTTP,
-- which I think is a reasonable solution
-- and there's a problem there.
For example is that there's still, there's like, for example, in the,
in the finance world in the US, there's regulations that say
you must be able to see all your network traffic which has now led to problems because
that was fine until Google started putting
like protections against state level actors.
And the problem is most http S interception software looks
a lot like a state level actor attack because it's,
it is the same thing.
It's like I'm going to get a custom root certificate into your browser and
use that to sign google.com so I can see what you're sending to google.com.
Well, is that
we did a show many years ago. I want to say Kazakhstan did that.
I'm pretty sure it was Kazakhstan
and I think they, they said web browsers, you have to use our root certificate.
I think that,
-- yeah, they were mandating a root certificate
-- and I think the web browser were like,
ha ha no.
And then I think they let it go.
This is why things like Chrome now are like, well, that, yeah, we,
we put protections against that.
But now the problem is, let's say for the sake of environment,
I want to put a custom root certificate on all
my machines so I can sniff my traffic to google.com,
-- right?
-- OK.
Well, I can't, it's like, because, you know,
you're, you're,
these are two different problems we're talking about because what you're talking
about is generally going to be a web browser focused problem.
I would be shocked if any of the
API clients
care at all about certificate pinning or any.
I don't even didn't Google stop doing certificate pinning.
I think they did.
-- Yeah,
-- everybody did uh stop doing certificate pinning because it just
-- too often. So
-- it'll still work fine.
But anyway, you get the point like we're talking about programmatic API S here.
Like the libraries that do this stuff are not particularly intelligent
does it?
We're not, we don't have to worry about. Well, curl is special, right?
Everyone knows that
Curl does everything correctly. Mostly
-- they do a
-- lot, right? I would point out
well and this is part of the problem is like what defines a valid H
TP header. And the answer is like if enough people serve it and use it,
it's now a valid Http header.
I mean, there's, I know there's the RFC headers but you can make anything a header.
I mean,
well, if you look at the RFC headers compared to what's actually in popular use,
the R CS are like 10 or 20% of what's actually in popular use.
-- Yeah, but
-- that was the point, right?
I mean,
this is what makes the HTTP protocol so powerful
is you can turn it into almost anything anyway.
-- Anyway, I think,
-- I think we are simply at the point though where
encryption is now
the default for data in transit and data arrest full stop.
And that's the world we need to live in.
Yeah, I, I agree. I mean, it's, it's amusing that in 2024 someone writes this article
and the answer isn't obvious.
No,
because all the things we've done for the last how many years,
all the things we talk about, all the things, the way everything is treated,
it feels like this should be obvious and it should just be a matter of absolutely not.
And II, I guess though I have a theory maybe. Well, OK, what's your theory?
And I'll tell you mine,
my theory is we've spent 50 plus years trying to build it systems that are reliable
and, and, and that just work which, you know,
the whole mantra of backwards compatibility,
right? And so
not just
we've created, it's not just that like,
updating software is expensive, but we've encouraged people
to not update software by
giving them backwards compatibility.
Like, you know, Windows is an extreme case of this.
I still can't make a director called Pr N one because it
boss might need that for my printer.
But the problem is now, you know, kind of like plastics and microplastics.
We've created an environment where we've catered to backwards compatibility for
so long people have come to expect it.
And I don't mean people in the sense of like individuals, I mean,
it's like a software culture.
There's this expectation that I should be able to write a piece of software that
should just magically work on Red Hat Enterprise Links for 13 years with no changes.
And Red Hat's like, ok, yeah, we'll take your money and make that happen.
So
that is how things used to work.
I
think it is slightly different in some instances. And I think open source is to blame
because like a good example being
when,
when you're running like some binary only crap,
you can't fix it. There's no option.
B when you're using a bunch of open source and you need
to upgrade to like the next universe or better operating system or,
or whatever.
I think there's more capability there.
But it is still hard and there's still lots of people that won't.
-- There's the possibility. Yeah, it
-- exists. Right.
Right.
Whereas with close source, the possibility is you could binary path,
-- which realistically speaking is a, a big fat, no,
-- no one's doing that.
It's, it's not realistic.
-- I mean,
-- it,
it never caught on for security for a reason.
Remember because there was a whole bunch of companies doing
it for security stuff way back in the day.
Like, and, and we're, you know,
we're still seeing it in the Linux kernel world where it's like, oh,
you can upgrade your kernel in place by,
you know, we insert a bunch of trampolines, cut out the code, put it in blah, blah,
blah.
Right.
-- I remember those
-- and you can
kind of do that for the kernel
because like there's generally one kernel,
but you can't do it for common software because there's like 3 million packages.
So let me, let me rewind this back
and I'll, I'll tell you what I think is, is should happen.
If you look at the world of web browsers,
web browsers were kind of in a dumb place probably 1015 years ago, give or take.
And they started taking pretty hard lines about
basically telling users you're going to do it this way because
we said so and there's nothing you can do about it,
right? This is everything from like
-- http s automatically
-- the backspace key,
right? Oh, yeah. Right.
-- Because backspace used to go back,
-- remember backspace.
He used to go back a page and I I used it all the time except
there was,
there was tons of weird quirks
that web browsers have slowly gotten rid of,
right?
This is where like typing authentication
information and unprotected pages warning us when
we go to an http website where it just yells at you.
Now it says this is un insecurity
use HSTS preload where it will not let you like, you can't make your browser go to my
seafood.org on HTP. It just won't let you.
I hope it's not running. But anyway,
so the thing is
the API world,
they've never really dealt with anything like this, right? I mean, most
like most API software used in programming languages kind of sucks.
And it barely works.
And
I mean, it just, that's how it is. But I think this is one of those examples where
it would be beneficial. I think if some of the API
libraries
would become opinionated on these matters and say, like,
you should be doing things this way, we're going to make you do things this way.
You don't get to decide.
Like, even Python, if Python just had like a thing where it's like,
look globally across, you know, pie Curl requests, all these different things.
We're going to start
defaulting to http S like if you say go to
cried.org,
we're going to assume you meant http S
creed.org,
I think they should just not allow http like if,
if the string starts with http colon slash slash, like throw an exception,
but then your r
news read client breaks. So
well, if they break stuff like that, then people will never upgrade their Python.
-- And so the cure is almost worse than the disease.
-- I don't know.
I don't know if that's true.
It is possible. Some won't.
But I,
you, you could make that argument about web browsers.
I mean, why did people upgrade their web browsers?
And one interesting thing though is
-- Google had a cudgel of search engine optimization.
-- They did that helped a lot.
-- I
-- agree. And we don't have that in the API
world. Not right now.
So, I don't know. I mean, I,
-- well,
-- and this is part of the culture that we live in where I'm like I am saying like,
what if the disease is worse or the cure is worse than the disease?
And we break a whole bunch of stuff for people and they never upgrade again.
And maybe the response needs to be ok. Too bad. You, you do that. Like that's a choice.
-- You can make
-- it.
I think it should be because look, I, I think making the argument,
the cure is worse than the disease.
No one's gonna upgrade blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
We've been saying that for 30 years and nothing's getting better. You know why?
Because we're not doing anything
-- well
-- and a stupid question potentially.
But realistically how many men in the middle attacks are there?
There's not many,
I think the bigger problem isn't man in the middle attacks necessarily.
It's the fact that there are a number of organizations
everywhere from your computer to wherever you're going
that are logging a lot of network tr
and so I think
man in the middle is probably less interesting than someone
mining network data for things they shouldn't have or know
as we've seen with the whole argument of quantum crypto where everybody's like,
oh you know, that won't uh you know, we'll switch to quantum crypto.
Well, but yeah, like all the existing traffic you sent could be broken.
Well, but who cares?
Well,
there are people like there's that Utah data
storage facility with its own Wikipedia page,
you know,
and
right, like they're storing something there
and the people forget,
like this data can be useful in 10 or 2030 years
because you can see who talked to who and how they talked
and that's useful in 1020 30 years.
You know, for certain types of activities and organized crime and everything.
If you have nothing to hide, you have nothing to fear Kurt,
-- except what we fear and have to hide changes over time.
-- I
know. I
know. All right, I,
oh, I hate this conversation. Like
I'm still not sure as to what the
for me, I think I will continue
on my, on my websites just leaving the default,
which is like redirect with an HSTS header and I also have preload but on an API level.
Well, I, I cheat in that. I just do http S
because I know
and I'm dealing with stuff that's up to date.
So I'm lucky.
Yeah,
I, if I, uh, I don't know, I don't know. I need to.
If I ran a web service, http would not exist,
it would only be HTTP S but I don't.
-- But what
-- if you were responsible for an internal
API that your company depended on to get work done
-- and it was HT it and it, that I
-- would tell them to upgrade their freaking library.
And what if you had 1000 customers using it?
That's a harder discussion then because that is a sort of
the thing you have to look at and say like,
what would happen if we did this?
And now at the same time,
you could just start reaching out to people and saying, hey,
I see you're using HTTP stop doing that.
It,
it
is not simple. I agree.
I think if you're doing Greenfield, it would be easier to just not run http at all.
I know there's a lot of backwards compatibility,
but at the same time,
if all we do is make excuses for our poor behavior in
the past as to why we can't fix anything in the present.
Like
that doesn't work either.
And I think that's the thing we need to keep in mind.
You know, one thing it occurs to me,
one thing that would really help here is if lets
and Crypt had a very easy solution for internal certificates.
I know, I wish they did that. I've, uh,
I know
because I've done the thing where I literally
actually, I did this for a public facing mail certificate
where I would basically have.
I had the mail server running a little stub web server to
get the let's encrypt certificate and keep it up to date.
And then I just had the mail server use that same certificate.
I know and you can do like some DNS shenanigans and whatnot.
But I, I do, I understand completely. I do. It would be love
if that was a thing but it's not.
Well, it, it's supported with ACNE.
You can do DNS control and, like, with a dynamic DNS provider you could set up.
But I wish there was just like a, like a turn it on and it works and me not having to dip
around with some dynamic DNS provider.
Oh,
I have a suspicion.
There isn't a good way to do it securely so people can't, like, do crazy things on like
internal coffee shop networks or whatever. But
anyway, I'm gonna call this one before we start making up too much crap.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show. Not
two
Z Podos
-- has podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.