Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in thinking about food, Josh Pressers.
I'm thinking about this like unholy coffee. You're drinking.
Kurt put a picture on Mastodon
that OK.
I'm just going to, I'm going to pull up the picture quick because I don't even,
I don't even know what to say to this.
Like
I drink a lot of coffee, literally gallons of this stuff.
But Curtis's picture he puts up, it says brew in the bag power coffee,
the ultimate caffeine kick and then it says be your own
barista and apparently you dump hot water into this bag.
-- Yeah,
-- it's got a built in filter and then you pour it out.
It's uh it was an advent calendar.
It was one different coffee per day
and they're all these little weird bags. You pour hot water in.
They're all like little Emory pouches, basically. Very nice gusset.
-- Very, very nice gusset. They stand very
-- well and you dump hot water in and then,
and then they zip,
they seal across the top like a Ziploc and they have a built in filter
and you just snap off the little pour spout and pour it into your cup
and then kind of give it a squish to get all the coffee out. They're quite delightful.
And is this like,
drinkable coffee you're getting out of this thing?
Some of this stuff has been really good.
There's been a couple because it's 24 different coffees and I,
it was an Advent Calendar gift and like, I,
I'm slow because I like to drink my regular coffee.
But no, some of these coffees have been spectacular.
And one thing that drives me nuts is they didn't like,
there's no way to buy more of it.
Like there's no QR code on it to like go buy a kilogram of it or something.
A kilogram of landfill waste.
You mean
-- the beans inside of the bag? I
-- got you.
This system is specifically meant for things like advent calendars
or like camping or you know what I mean?
Like, it's like a, it's kind of a disposable and the whole thing is from Denmark.
So it is totally compostable and blah, blah, blah.
So let's ignore the carbon footprint of shipping it to North America.
You know, it, it's actually pretty lightweight.
I mean, it's just coffee grounds, dried out coffee.
It's not heavy but no, it's a really cool system.
Do you ever just wanted to have like, buy one cup's worth of beans to try new coffee?
No,
-- I just buy a lot of coffee and then I drink it
-- all well, because, like,
I try new things sometimes and sometimes, like,
it's like Costco. Right. Like I go to Costco and I see something.
I'm like, oh, that could be tasty. And then I buy it and I'm like, oh, it's not tasty.
-- Oh,
-- dear.
And now I have 30 pounds
thing. I don't like.
Yeah, like, right now I have over 50 protein bars, that taste of sadness. And just,
that's when you just throw them away. This is the sunk cost fallacy at work.
I know, but I spent money on this and I don't, I don't like throwing food away.
-- Like I, you
-- know,
I agree. No one likes throwing food away.
But the sunk cost fallacy says sometimes you
have to throw away the terrible protein bars.
Sometimes I buy coffee. That's terrible.
-- And I just don't drink it all because that's the way
-- it
is.
Well, see,
and that's why I would like to be able to buy one cup's worth like a scratch and sniff.
Like the no, like France is doing a scratch and sniff stamp for the baguette,
scratch and lick coffee stickers that you can lick the can
in the grocery store to know if it's any good.
-- No, that would be terrible.
-- Speaking of freshness.
So like there's a lot of vegetables like peas and corn, especially.
So things that are high in sugar
that actually benefit from being frozen
because like if you can get it absolutely fresh and, like,
eat it that day or the next day.
Cool. Great.
Except, like, I live in Edmonton and, you know, it's not California for program.
Yeah. And so,
like, I actually eat a lot of frozen vegetables,
especially corn and peas because the frozen corn
kernels are better than the fresh ones.
-- Oh, man,
-- there's some corn farmers that are gonna, they're gonna,
they punch you right now.
-- Why would they care
-- if you eat it fresh or freeze it?
Because fresh corn is very,
-- very good. Yeah, I,
-- it is better. Yes.
And I've had fresh corn but I can't get fresh corn in January.
-- It is true
-- because I live in Canada where it's minus 40.
-- Uh,
-- right. You can't get anyway. Ok.
What is the, where are you taking this frozen
kernels?
Oh, kernel, I get it. Ha ha ha ha. That's clever. Good Lord. Oh my God, Kurt.
I am the worst person to make jokes to. It is rare. I grasp them.
-- Um,
-- I like teed it up twice for you.
It doesn't matter. I, I'm never going to catch on.
-- I'm not good at this. Ok.
-- Next time I'll make a sign and hold it up like applause now.
Or like this is the joke and like an explanation
that would be fine.
I still wouldn't have gotten it. You could have,
if you would have explained it to me before we hit record. It's possible I would have.
But then it wouldn't be spontaneous.
It never, it,
yeah. Anyway,
ok, we're gonna talk about frozen kernels, ha ha.
Because there was a blog post slash white paper put
out by um Jeremy Allison's name is on it.
Who did what? A lot of work with Samba? And the colonel and
he
invent
Samba.
-- I don't know.
-- He is Mr
Samba is he? I know he was very involved.
I don't know the exact history of it. Anyway,
the guy is legit, right?
And
he for a company called CIQ, which apparently makes Rocky Linux,
-- which is a red hat clone, right? Yeah,
-- back when they like there were real
clones, it's all complicated now.
-- But anyway, so Jeremy's like the real deal.
-- He's got his own Wikipedia page.
-- Like
-- I, I'm not surprised he's like the real deal man.
Like anyway, I love how it's known for Samba. Like, yes, he, yes,
it's kind of like that the guy that did curl or that, that Linux guy that did Linux,
that guy that did curl. Some guy made Linux it's fine.
But so anyway,
the CIQ people put up this paper and they basically did
this like pretty impressive analysis talking about the like frozen distro
model of kernels where you take a version of the Linux
kernel and you just maintain it for some period of time,
usually years
at versus the mainline Linux kernel,
which is obviously constantly fixing bugs and security issues
and all kinds of stuff and adding features,
right?
-- All that. Well,
-- and it's funny to me because,
and let's just set the stage. What does a frozen kernel mean?
Because I think actually there's a lot of
different vendors with a lot of different things.
Like there are some vendors
that have very like we will literally just put in like
critical fixes,
that's it. And then there's ones like Red hat where
all sorts of security fixes and hardware support and
fixes and feature improvements and well new features.
And so I think we can't say like
we can't
say frozen version of software back parts without it
being like a bell curve of 7000 different things.
Yeah,
but we can just generalize it and we're going to focus a lot
on what Red Hat did just because we have all that experience.
And
before I go on a tangent, the one thing I'm going to say though is
no, no, I
for
example,
but
let's say you make a smart light bulb that only
connects to the mothership and doesn't accept any incoming connections.
Would you feel safe with them?
Saying, hey,
we picked a version of Linux and we only fix criticals that can
be remotely exploited and the way the product is set up been used,
the other stuff like there's no local users, there's no software to attack on it.
It's just kind of a client device that's reaching
out and that would probably be pretty safe.
And OK
versus
red hat is a good example of, well,
this is kind of a general purpose server that like people have shell accounts on.
So like, OK,
the kernel needs to be a bit more up to date, even if it's quote unquote frozen.
-- Let,
-- let's explain. OK, so we'll, we'll ignore all of the ramblings just now. But
so the way a lot of Linux distributions used to work,
they don't all do it this way because we had Greg Kh on a while
back and he mentioned that like Android
and Debian are following like Linux upstream,
right?
So they're just taking the Linux kernel and they're putting it in the thing now.
A lot of distributions and like red hat still does this to my knowledge,
Tu does this, I'm pretty sure. So
does this like all the big distributions,
they have kernel teams. So what they do
-- is they
-- take, actually, I think Sousa started doing more of a mainline one.
It's possible.
I, I honestly haven't paid attention in years,
but they take a version of the Linux kernel
and they say we're going to take this version and we're
going to polish it up as best as we can.
We're going to apply the bug fixes, we think it needs,
we're going to test the crap out of it
and we're going to say this is the kernel we're using.
And then what happens is their internal security
team will cherry pick bug fixes cherry pick security
fixes cherry pick features from the mainline kernel
and add it to their frozen kernel version.
With the intention being
there will be additional stability
in that version that you might not have with a fast moving upstream project.
-- I think that in theory makes sense.
-- You know what,
20 years ago,
it
made a lot more sense.
When I think 20 years ago, there were two big factors which is number one,
the delta, the change rate of stuff like the Linux
was a lot slower. It was,
-- and it was a lot more unstable compared to now.
-- I don't know if that's true.
-- I think that's the intent.
-- Let me.
Ok, perfect example. I remember running
Linux 0.99 patch level to infinity and beyond.
Ok.
And the three Com Ether Express pro 10 driver.
Well, what was it called?
It was the 10 megabit uh BNC network card that three com made. That was lovely.
And I remember going from like crashes hourly
to crashes daily
to crashes weekly. No, but seriously, right? Like, as they improved the driver
and they like fixed a few bugs, fixed a few bugs.
It went from like crash, crash to like once in a while to like once in a while to like,
hey, my sister's been up and running for like
it hasn't crashed.
Obviously, this even predates real Linux distributions because this is like 9899.
But that was the
environment that this idea came from was that
the Linux kernel was nowhere near.
Like, sadly,
the LINX curl was actually a lot more stable than a
lot of other software I used like other UNIX is,
that's how bad things were
they like this free thing from? Some dude was
-- more stable and
-- look the in the red hat universe,
there would be two ways that would be addressed.
They would either just say this driver is unstable and we will not support it.
Like if you use it, you're completely on your own.
I don't think that's gonna work for a three Coms main card.
Well, no, no.
What they would do though then is if there was a piece
of hardware that was known to be unstable they would work with.
I mean, this is Red Hat did so much freaking work. They deserve so much credit.
They would have gone to someone like three com
and they would have said let's fix this, right? We will work with you to fix this card.
-- So it works correctly.
-- In this case of memory serves.
It was, what was the guy that did the
Beowulf cluster software from NASA?
Anyway,
-- he's the three calm driver guy and he got it all working is that
-- Donald Becker?
-- He did all the cards,
-- right? I think that's the one. Yeah,
he did a ton of network cards.
I mean, he's the reason I could use the, the network card. I had way back in the day.
I remember going to his like FTP site,
literally FTP and you had to download the drivers and build them.
It was wild.
But that's the thing. So
the thing to remember is the system we have today
-- didn't just spontaneously emerge and pop out
-- for sure.
It came from a context,
but that context was different and it has well since changed.
Like the Linux kernel unpacked won't fit on my first five computers.
No. Really? Right. Like the current Linux kernel unpacked is so big.
It's over a gigabyte of source code.
I believe that. I wonder how big the binary is anymore.
Actually, I'm on a Linux machine.
-- Let me
-- look if you, well, and that's a loaded question because like,
are you compiling a static monolith with every driver or
like a totally stripped down thing with driver or,
you know, whatever?
Right. Well, no, just the,
just the kernel on my system.
-- And this is obviously there's loads of modules in a directory
-- where do I even find it?
Now? It's in slash boot. The VMR is, I'm on Fedora. This is 6.8 0.8 dash 300.
Oh, my slash boot is empty.
-- Oh, it's a container, right? That's why
-- because you're not on a real computer.
But uh this is 15 megabytes.
And remember when the kernel had to fit on a floppy?
I remember when my system had like that much storage.
Yeah.
So anyway, it's, it's, it's pretty big and plus there's loads of modules, I imagine
-- kernel is using gigabytes of memory at this point. Anyway.
-- Anyway, hang on a minute.
This thing says it's seven. Why is there a 75 megabyte file in here? What's in it?
-- RD
-- again?
-- In it? RD is the initial,
-- didn't in it red. Used to be tiny.
-- It, it used to be, it doesn't have to be.
-- It's 75 megabytes. Now.
Uh What is my,
my in it, RA mfs is 60 megs on the system
-- again. That's bigger than the hard drives through.
-- But that's the world we live in.
It's
like, I'm literally holding up to the camera.
I bought another two Terabyte SSD because I
got to reinstall windows on this machine.
So I'm gonna swap in a fresh drive and get it all cleaned up and installed. And
this was Tuna box like magic.
Yeah. Right. Anyway. Ok. Ok. Early days, early days. Right.
-- Well,
-- but people forget all this stuff is early days and we're,
but it's been 20 years now.
-- Well,
-- it's
-- not early days anymore. Well, that's
-- what I'm saying.
We have like the Linux.
Linux has gone from being a horse and buggy to a spaceship in 20 years, for sure.
Right.
But we still behave and all the red hat business processes wrapped
around having a horse and buggy where the horse poops a lot.
I mean, a lot of them are. I,
I think though, we, we, I want to back us up though first and, and I want to,
can I just point out something real simple and kind of sad redhead
enterprise Linux version 9.0 is distributed with
the Linux kernel version 5.14 0.0.
Now, without looking,
without looking, tell me about 5.14 0.0.
I mean, I can't tell you anything about. I know this computer is running 68.
-- It's not
-- a long term kernel.
-- Are there, there are no more long term kernels
-- are there 515, 61666860, sorry.
The long term
kernels are 606 61 515 510 54 and 419.
-- But
-- it doesn't matter because Red Hat has their own developers.
-- They don't need to rely on the upstream long term kernel.
-- Exactly.
-- And that's so they're taking on a lot of extra work.
-- Well, of course, they are.
I mean, that was why you paid them right? Is they were going to do this effort.
This is part of the problem is Red Hat is taking on all this extra work.
And here's the question that we're ultimately trying to get to is, is it any help?
-- Is it worth it? It
-- might not be anymore. It was though.
And I can't stress this enough. Like
we're talking about like 2001, 2002. Right way. Way back in the day
when people were afraid of open source. Right. Linux
was scary. It was a cancer.
It was, I mean, it was literally called the Cancer by Steve Ballmer.
And people were afraid of it and they heard about how
fast it is and how unstable it is and it's gonna,
you know,
eat your business and you'll have to declare bankruptcy if you run this
stuff and along comes Red Hat and they made all of these promises.
I mean, heck, there was the, the, the skull lawsuit right there was, if I run Linux,
I'm gonna get sued by skull
and,
-- and it was wild and
-- that thing dragged on for like a decade.
Oh. Right. Right.
And Red Hat shows up and basically says we're going, you know, come sit by our fire,
we're gonna keep you warm and feed you.
We'll do, we'll do what needs to be done.
And it also can't be understated.
The chaos of drivers back in the day where
I remember it was like we were at Red Hat. And so obviously
we thought what Red Hat was doing was correct is
it's easy to do when you drink the Kool Aid.
But there were kind of two universes where there was,
there were people taking binary blobs and they were, you know, NVIDIA and,
and all those awful network cards and like wind modems and
there was all this hardware that the only way to get it to work
would be to go to a vendor website and download a blob of garbage
and the blob of garbage was doing, who knows what on your system? Right.
And Red Hat and Fedora had a very strict, like, we will not do this attitude.
This is why I bought three com network cards. They were expensive
but
they had an open source driver.
Yeah.
Right. Right. Exactly. There was tons of hardware I bought
just because it worked on Linux.
And I mean,
now the idea of buying hardware that doesn't work on Linux is laughable because,
like, everyone wants their stuff to work for the moment,
but this was not how it worked.
Right.
And so Red Hat was giving these companies this peace of mind of knowing, like,
if I buy Red Hat stuff and I buy my server from Dell,
everything is going to work and I'm not going to have to worry about, you know, like,
someone breaking into my house and stealing all my
dog food in the middle of the night.
Like, it's going to be fine
hands up who here has spent time looking at a hardware qualification list.
So, like Dell, for example, listing this set of servers with these set of add-ons,
work with RNT
four,
whatever that for sure.
I used to spend a lot of time and everybody did because you could not,
like I once bought a T A 55 CD, a CD ROM.
Drive from the IBM store at the mall here locally.
Yes, folks, there was an actual IBM branded store like IBM logo.
They sold IBM Gear and I got verbal assurances that it would work with OS 22.1 warp.
-- And I assume it didn't because you're telling us this story.
-- No, absolutely not.
And you gotta remember like we didn't, we,
we technically had the internet and the web but there
wasn't the rich content or search engines to know.
Oh, yeah, it was super hard. Like I couldn't search TX 55 CD. Like
I literally bought laptops and hardware
that
either were on the hardware compatibility list
or hardware qualification list for like rel or for something or
literally like,
oh the Open BS D developers are buying this
brand and specific model of vio super slims.
So I know it 100% works with Open BS D
Erico. There's a very good chance it'll work with Linux.
I remember going to best buy multiple times in a day
because I'd buy a thing and it wouldn't work with Linux.
I'd bring it back and get a different one
and bring it home and that didn't work either.
So I'd bring that back.
-- Well,
-- we didn't have best buy up here until a while later
anyway. Ok. Ok.
So let's, let's assume we've set the stage for the past.
So now let's fast forward to today.
We talked to Greg Kh like a month or two ago and he was
very clear about the stability and reliability of
-- upstream Linux
-- kernel don't break user space.
That is a big freaking deal.
And one of the reasons I love Linux is same thing with Windows, love it or hate it.
You still can't make a director called PR N one on
Windows because that's ad os device name for your printer.
-- Right.
-- Right. So anyway, now you have these,
we'll,
we'll call them historic like Linux distributions that are
still doing things the way they did them.
And
you have the upstream Linux people saying, don't do it like this anymore.
And now they've also been saying that for a long time,
-- you're
-- saying that the Linux distributions do this, but you're,
you almost said it if it as if it happens in a vacuum
and this, the one thing we forget, there's a lot of customers that have been trained
to expect
and use
a air quote stable distribution,
which means
frozen in time and back parted
and Red hat, for example, spent 20 years educating people that this was the way to go.
And now we're just saying like, yeah, just like like password rotation, right.
We spent 20 years saying
password rotation, you should do password rotation followed by like whoops, no,
it's completely wrong.
Nist has recanted and even posted guidance saying it's wrong
and people still repeat it
-- and believe it,
-- I think on the
distribution topic, it's not as simple as just saying, oh,
we don't have to do it anymore.
Exactly.
That's what I'm saying. I think the kernel is potentially special.
Like, I'll give you an example. I have a machine in my basement that I do.
Like a lot of weird stuff on
and like a lot of, like doing data analysis type work. Right.
That runs Debbie and 11. Debbie and 12 is out now. I have not upgraded it.
Do you know why? Because when I upgraded from Debbie and 11 to De
and 12, all of my stuff is going to break, I know this 100%. And so I just
basically need, at some point,
I'm gonna need a free weekend where I'm going to do the upgrade
and then I'm gonna spend hours and hours and hours fixing scripts,
fixing binaries, rebuilding things
-- because it's just how it is, right. It is what
-- it is.
-- This is actually one of the reasons I chose Python. It's all in
-- Python. Kurt.
Almost all my scripts are in Python. They will all break when I upgrade.
I 100% guarantee it. It's just how it is. It is what it is, whatever.
All of, all of this change, all of this churn,
the things we're scared of the things we don't like.
There's, I think two pieces to this and, and I think first of all,
there's the fact that Rocky Linux
wrote this article,
I have a suspicion,
the secret reason they did this.
And I don't know, I haven't looked at Rocky Linux in a long time,
but they're either they either are or are
going to start running upstream kernel versions.
And this is their justification for doing that.
And that would solve two major problems. One
way less engineering, like just grab stable and or
not grab the limit
and use it.
But number two red hat has historically for the last few years,
made it harder and harder to get the source code for their Linux kernel.
For sure
to the point where it's valuable.
Well, it, yeah, like that patch set,
like which patches went in how like even the order they go in matters to some degree.
Sadly, like it's
matters a ton.
Like I think this is one of those things
where people think of patching the lin external as like
applying a three line patch to some piece of software. It's like,
well, no, but you laugh and I laugh but we've lived the pain.
I've, I have actually had to edit a Linux kernel file to like,
fix a thing because the patch wasn't out for it yet.
And I would have had to wait weeks for it to come out.
But somebody posted to the mail and West, hey, I tried this and it worked a little bit
better.
Good luck.
But like most people don't, you know, they haven't experienced that pain,
which speaks to the whole Linux ecosystem.
And, and business part of it
succeeding,
you know, that they haven't had to hand whittle their own spears.
-- Yeah, for sure, for sure.
-- But the,
I just keep coming back to all the current business kind of culture and what we
teach people and how we do these things came from 20 years ago and that,
-- that world barely exists.
-- It's way different now for sure.
And, and here's the other thing
there, there's, there's two pieces of this. First of all, they
put a lot of focus in this paper on security specifically on vulnerabilities.
And
the the vulnerability situation in the Linux kernel I think is very unique
because not everyone
ability really matters.
Like this is a good example of Red Hat doesn't
build every single piece of hardware supported into their kernel,
right?
So some of the patches don't work. A lot of them will,
can you even do it?
-- Probably
-- not because didn't, somebody doesn't like once every couple of years,
somebody tried to compile all the Linux kernel code and be like
these old drivers are just totally broken and don't work anymore.
Maybe.
Oh, I remember seeing this at least a few years ago where somebody was like all this,
I think it was like X 25 stuff or something.
It was all just broken or
so the point is right,
you can focus on vulnerabilities and now
this is where Red hat kind of has
a, a two paths.
They can take, they can take the, oh, we're just going to take upstream and use it and,
and we're gonna make sure the upstream stuff works the way we want
it to work and they're gonna test the crap out of it.
So it's not like they're just going to take it in YOLO. It, right.
They're still gonna test it to death.
And, ok, I'm gonna, when we worked at Red Hat,
it took a week to
test
-- a kernel because
-- yeah, it probably takes at least that. Now
people forget
there's hardware testing that literally
involves somebody like physically pulling a
plug and plugging something back in to see what happens,
right? Like like a scuzzy device drive rate array or whatever.
So the thing people forget too is like real, I hate to say
air quotes. Real.
Linux kernel testing involves physically moving stuff around and unplugging
stuff and just you can't automate this stuff really?
-- OK.
-- Now that I think that's part of the story is
the the page
talks about security specifically, right? But what about not security? Like there
is a red hat kernel more stable than a non
red hat kernel. Like I can't answer that question. I don't know.
I think you, they're going to say yes and open, you know,
the upstream kernel people will probably say no,
I have an answer for that.
And the thing is you're forgetting something very important.
The red hat Linux kernel, for example, does not exist in a vacuum of testing.
So
you say Red Hat tests the crap out of it. But that's wrong. What about Dell?
What about IBM? What about all the system vendors that
ship and certify and don't just ship Red Hat Linux,
but literally say
this will 100% guaranteed work,
which is why you're paying us like twice as much for the hardware.
I was just buying it. All right.
I mean, that's fair.
-- There's, there's definitely that whole ecosystem
-- and I mean, I remember, but like,
you think
Hitachi doesn't do an insane level of testing for
their high end systems running Red Hat enterprise,
Linux.
Yeah, I mean, that's why you pay for it though. Right,
let's say for the sake of argument, Red Hat starts,
uh, at a located so they get a new upstream kernel once a month. So 12 times a year,
they actually currently do a lot more than that.
But because it's air quote stable and back ported, it's a little less scary.
But the thing to remember now is what is Del gonna do,
they're gonna take what Red Hat gives them. That's what they're gonna do.
-- And
-- historically, however, with the, with the, with the kernel being just backed
stuff, Dell can look
it and go, we can like,
basically ignore 90% of this because it's like
they're not touching any drivers we care about,
they're not touching stuff we care about.
-- But with a upstream curl. Now, a lot of stuff is getting touched.
-- Yeah.
There's a lot more churn in that regard and, and that's fair.
-- And see, and that's,
and then, and then Dell has to take the,
the, you know, how much do we trust upstream not to break stuff?
I mean, this is gonna be kind of the question, right? Is we don't know for sure.
I have a suspicion.
It's fine just because android is using the upstream kernel in Android.
What did Greg say 4 billion devices? Like, come on.
-- Well,
-- and a diversity of devices, right. That's
my favorite thing is you look at the screen chart size for the iphone ecosystem
like 10 maybe.
Yeah,
there's like 10 screen sizes and then you look at
the one for Android and it's just a mess.
-- It's a squiggly line of shoelaces. There's like a couple
-- 100.
I bet it's at least, I bet it's more than 100. But anyway,
it's one of those things where it's fine until it's not like,
remember when we fixed heartbleed, did we?
And,
and a bunch of people rebooted their Dell servers
and then Red Hat had to send out an emergency notice saying
please don't apply this update and reboot because you know,
-- yeah, you might have to get Dell to like fix the hardware,
-- did it?
-- I don't remember that.
-- Yeah, I remember that was bricking systems.
I don't remember that, but it, nothing would surprise me.
-- Was
-- it
-- heart bleed or was it something else?
Uh, no, not heartbleed. Sorry. What was it was one of those, uh CPU ones?
-- What was the CPU?
-- Like?
There was like shell shock and ghost and stuff.
-- It was like shell shock
-- wasn't CPU. What
was the one that affected the CP US?
And that the fix had like a 30% performance hit? It was the predictive cashing.
-- Wasn't
-- that specter meltdown? Right.
Yes, that was the one.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Anyways, the point is it bricked
-- systems?
-- OK. I wanna, I wanna move us in the
of,
of coming to a reasonable conclusion on this.
And I guess here is my thought on all of this stuff.
We just talked about this paper that, that was, that came out.
I have a suspicion
we are approaching a point where the days of like trying to cast this
software in Amber and maintain it for long periods of time is probably over.
And the single biggest reason is just the, the
volume of software we interact with now is probably somewhere between 10
and 100 times as much as it was 20 years ago.
Well, and to add to that, it's not just the volume you're interacting with.
It's your dependency chains
that
used
to be. Well, no, no, it used to be.
You interacted with a lot of different software,
but they were sort of like little islands independent of each other.
But now you stand up a web app
and
PM packages get pulled in
and if one of them doesn't work,
right.
And that has changed, like,
the system used to be like, you could just rip out random libraries and like,
one or two things that depended on them would break.
But I've been paying attention when I installed
certain Python libraries now and I'm like this,
like, it's installing over 100 and 16, like
yt downloader installs FFM
peg and
who that pulls in
everything
or there's uh the Python.
Uh I was doing some OCR and Python and it just is like,
I'm going to install 200 megabytes of stuff.
And I'm like, yeah,
that's
pretty
normal. Like you do, you, that's how it works.
Now, again,
that's bigger than my system used to have
-- a hard drive because
-- it's a different world,
but it's a dependent.
But the thing is, it's not a volume of software anymore. It's dependency chains.
-- It's, it's, they're reliant on each other.
-- Those are the same definitions.
So,
but basically going to this, we need, ultimately,
my theory is we need better testing
to catch bugs and fix them faster.
And if you have to do that anyways,
you might as well run current to put it bluntly.
And I think a lot of projects are gonna
slowly, hopefully level up.
I don't think all projects are going to get to the Linux kernel
level because most projects are like one or two people or 10 people.
But conversely, hopefully, maybe they're simple enough that,
you know, they're not so unstable, like,
like something that converts dates or whatever.
Right. Like, hopefully it's somewhat more stable than the Linux kernel.
I, I don't think there's an answer and I don't think testing is gonna save us.
No, it's not gonna save us but going to make things better. So perfect example.
Right? I was fetching about this before the show.
I have a I consistently output Jason which makes life a lot easier to deal with
and it randomly sticks smirk one in.
So I I wrote a giant hunk of Python that sanitizes it and cleans it.
Cool like and and as time goes on and I do more of this,
I will find more corner cases and fix them in the
in my sanitization code
which is available for free online and other
people will run stuff and hopefully do it.
And
then even though the A is are doing dumb stuff of like spitting up buggy J so
cool we fixed it and that is what will let us, for example, use A I.
That's what will let us use more up to date libraries is the assumption that yeah,
something can and will go wrong
because it will at some point, right?
There'll be a buggy library or a flaw
and
well, you better catch it and deal with it.
-- I
-- don't think it's that simple and I don't know what the answer is gonna be.
-- But
-- the solution of,
let's freeze our software and just run software that is like a solution.
-- Static and good.
-- We can't. Well, ok. No, no.
Look,
a lot of people freeze their software and they
never touch it because they don't have to.
And that's the way it's going to be because I read a web app and I,
if I never update my dependencies, my web app never breaks.
Now, will I get P
someday? Because I'm running some old horrible javascript library.
Maybe, maybe not. That's the thing. Right.
Well, and the problem is
if it's an internal app that you're running,
you have the incentive to maybe care about security.
But if it's a light bulb that you sold too bad soccer,
this is the problem in software today.
Right?
Is, it's,
it's easier to do nothing than it is to do something
because when I do something I might break it and,
and I don't think we, we don't have good answers to any of this today.
You can say we're gonna run current and in things like Linux kernel. Yeah. Sure.
-- That probably works.
-- I don't know that that's gonna work on light bulbs though
because I don't want my light bulbs.
Like the other thing to remember is if one
in a million devices break during an update,
which absolutely will happen because a cosmic ray is gonna
hit them or like one cell of memory is bad or
whatever, somebody turns it off while it's updating and, you know,
like every time I update my bias now,
I love that the little screen progress bar marches and it's like,
do not turn the computer off in very large letters.
And
so the thing is if you brick a device one in a million,
if you sell 10 million light bulbs and update the monthly,
that's going to be a lot of dead light bulbs, it would be. Yes.
And again, people forget this.
Like these things happen at scale and at scale one in
a million is eight times a day in New York City.
Yeah, I don't, I don't, that's the thing. I don't know what the answer is.
We, no one does.
-- I think. No,
-- you don't either.
No, no,
I think what would help is making a bit of a framework to define the problem better.
So for example, having a system running a Linux kernel that has shell accounts.
It is vastly different than having a Linux kernel running on a pump in an oil field.
In that it probably won't have medical users,
but the failure mode actually might be far worse.
Ok? I don't want to keep, we're, we're just making crap up at this point.
Here's how I want to end this show
is just by saying this sort of paper
I think is beneficial because it's,
we need this.
It's shining a light on some of the way we
did things because there's a lot of things we,
especially in software, especially,
especially in security that it's like we do it this way because we do it this way.
This said to rotate passwords 20 years ago. Why are you not rotating passwords?
Right.
There are many, there are many good reasons to ask questions and say,
is this the right way to go anymore?
And
I think that's great.
-- It
-- might be still the right way for some people
and not the right way for new people using it
for
sure. I think people forget,
not everybody,
well,
not everybody uses software the same way you do.
And I think a lot of people honest to God, forget that.
Yeah, I mean, that's one of the things that makes software so crazy and awesome
is just the fact that it's different. Everyone uses it different. But
yeah, I don't, I don't know. I mean, this was, it was fun to read.
It's fun to think about.
I am very curious to see what Red Hat is going to do with all of this
in the future because I think they are
probably the single most impacted organization in this space
and
I have a suspicion, whatever they do
is going to be where the entire industry follows.
I will bet a dollar that Red Hat keeps doing what
they're doing because that's what they've trained their customers to expect.
-- I mean, it is true.
-- Retraining.
The customers will be more expensive than just continuing
to burn money on the pile of stability.
It could be, it would my, my suspicion
if I was going to bet you a dollar
is that Red hat will continue with their
long term kernel or whatever they want to call it. And then also, so
in conjunction, have a,
we'll say less tested upstream kernel that exists for people who want to,
we say not have 700 security vulnerabilities reported in their kernel.
I thought about that. I actually, it's funny. I was thinking about that before.
The show is like having that,
that dual strategy.
It's too late. You already bet a dollar you can.
I will still keep my dollar on saying what I said.
Red Hat would do because again, I think that would just be way,
way too confusing for customers and way too confusing to message and to teach.
I don't know,
I don't know. We'll see
it. It's good. It's a fun paper.
All right. I'm ending this episode. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening.
Go to
social security podcast.com. Head up the show notes. Easy
Podos has podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too.
And if you can afford it, eat some fresh vegetables, they're delicious,
-- especially
-- corn.
Oh
my God.
Like when I,
when I can get fresh
corn
from the roadside guys. And so
-- that is amazing corn. All right.
-- I'm leaving. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.