Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Seyfried and my partner in identifying things. Josh Bresser,
I guess I identify things.
We had to assign Cwes to all the bugs and Red Hat Bugzilla security bugs.
-- Anyways, did we
-- assign CWE? Si? Don't remember if we
did,
we did
-- YCWE equals.
-- It's been
so long.
Yeah.
And, and this brings up so, ok,
because I've been thinking about this a lot. The last two weeks is what is
CWE good for and
first of all, what is CWE? Right?
I
-- was going to say probably start there.
-- Ok. So CWE is similar to CV E,
I have a fun fact.
We used to work with a bunch of people in the Czech Republic
and then obviously the Eastern European languages like V and W sound the same.
Well, also German, it was always confused
-- whether it's like, are we talking about CV E or CWE?
-- Yeah, and like in German, V
and F
-- Yeah. Right. Exactly.
-- So,
ok.
So CW, well, let's just say so CV E is common vulnerabilities
and exposures
and CWE is common weakness in numeration,
right?
And so the idea of cwe is that,
what's the difference between a buffer overflow and a buffer underflow or an
overflow
or an integer overread or blah, blah, blah, blah blah.
And so the idea was to identify and categorize all of these
because to put it bluntly,
if you're going to talk about a security vulnerability and
you don't have an agreed upon term for it,
you know, if you go to the doctor and say my Flis blang hurts, he's gonna be like a huh,
I'm gonna need a real name for that.
And you know, they're going to want like your arm, your leg or specific muscles. And
the
the other thing is CWE has, for example, well,
examples of that flaw in different languages,
how to fix it, how to address it and so on and so forth
and
it was quite useful. I think in the past for two reasons.
One,
it allowed the infosec industry to start talking about things
using the same terminology kind of before we had these
larger consensus mechanisms that we have now like
God, forgive me for saying this.
But things like Twitter and X where if enough people say hashtag log for J,
that's what it's called.
I think it
so we, we need to, I think discuss a little more about how it works first, but I,
I will give you my hot take.
I think CWE is as useless now as it always has been,
which is unfortunate because I think it has the
potential to make enormous difference in the industry.
There's one thing it used to do
that was magic, which is
closed source vendors
would announce a security vulnerability and
they wouldn't really give much information.
But if they gave ac we,
you had a pretty good chance at guessing how bad it was.
Because for example, if internet information server running on NT four
has CWE 79 cross site scripting. you're like, OK, that's bad. But
I, I can live with that.
But if it had CWE for like a buffer overflow, you knew you had to patch now.
And that's the one thing it was for a time good for.
And
however, since then,
most of these close source vendors have actually not all of them obviously,
but a lot of them have actually gotten better at giving like CV SS data and other
useful information so that, you know, if you need to patch or not, right?
Whereas in the past, we had to guess, like, especially I'm gonna say oracle,
you know, they'd be like my favorite was always like this score is a 9.9 but like,
don't worry about patching it.
And we're all like, what are you talking about?
Or my favorite would be like, they'd be like, this is an update you need to patch now.
And we're like, is it a security update?
-- They're like, we're not saying just patch now, like you have to patch now.
-- Oh,
-- those were the worst. Yeah, I remember those sort of things
-- and we're like, but
is it secure? Like, do I need to panic? Like, just patch now? Like right now
now
-- don't ask questions, do what you're told and
-- then you're on the,
that would come out that it was like a remote pre
ath
buffer overflow
or some goofiness.
And so cwe was for a brief period of a few years useful in assigning.
How bad is this vulnerable?
I,
I think you have a skewed view because you
worked for a company that would try to unwind
the vulnerability landscape and then sell it to other people.
I can tell you as when I was a Cis Edmund doing that sort of work.
And in the early days of Red Hat,
I found Cwes to be virtually useless.
Well, it was just one,
it was one of the few clues we had quite often with these vendors but by and large.
So
how it in theory could be useful is
ironically
on
NA na,
na,
I want to talk about how they categorize and arrange
all this because there's actually some clever things they've done
-- that I think is a very good idea. For example, they
-- have and some terrible things.
-- Well,
-- there are terrible things as well
-- like CWE 1003,
-- I don't even, I don't know what 1003 is. What's 1000.
That's the simplified view of CWE that people use without telling us.
-- Oh, that
-- thing.
Yeah, we'll get to that.
That's NVD. I thought everyone, well, I don't know how I knew this.
I did not know this until two weeks ago.
-- I
-- literally, anyway, we'll talk about that in a little while.
But
the one thing cwe did that I think is very
clever is they've created like this hierarchy of vulnerability types.
And so for example, you can have things like input validation, right?
Input validation can mean a lot of things.
Well, it's everything,
well,
not
real.
I mean, it kind of is,
-- that's
-- my hated thing is CWE 20 input validation because technically,
well, everything is input at some point
like, I
mean, not, not necessarily like for example,
I'm actually looking at 121 which is stacked buffer overflow
and it's a child of
access memory location after end of buffer in a child of out of bounds, right?
And so there's like these, it kind of builds on itself where you can
go simpler or you can get more complicated, which is nice.
-- I think you
-- can go simpler or more complicated
depending on what CWE has.
And the dirty secret is, cwe has stalled out
like 10 years ago for a long time
and
has not had a lot of updates like they're fast
tracking some A IC WES for maybe the summer.
I mean, well, it's like look, it,
it suffers from the same problem CD E does where you have a giant
defense contractor running a program at the speed of the old US government.
The new US government is actually quite agile and impressive.
The old US government was a laughing stock of it.
Well,
you know, given what they were working with and what they were supposed to do.
Right. Right. Yes. Here you have a potato in two forks. Like you have to have a web page
and you're not allowed to
use them after 5 p.m.
That's right. Exactly. Right. Right.
And oh, and there's a government shutdown. So now you can't look at the potato.
-- Yeah.
-- Anyway,
the thing that's interesting to me about CW is in theory
it could be a comprehensive list of kind of all,
not just
well, the weaknesses
but
examples of them in different languages or how to fix them, how to detect them.
There's,
there's one other thing we forgot to talk about
that I think is very important and very cool.
So we mentioned they have like the hierarchy.
They also have this concept called chaining, right? Where you can,
you have like
input in
like invalid input then leads to a stack buffer overflow.
And this goes to the classic kill chain, which I know is a terrible phrase to use.
Nowadays, I forget what politically correct phrase you're supposed to use.
But this idea of a kill chain and military terminology of like, OK,
see the person call in an artillery strike, kill them like this chain of events,
this chain of things that happens to affect something
and yeah, so like
a P
to own, you know, at Cans
West.
Yeah.
Now it's famous for like, oh, I, you know,
I have this like $100,000 bounty bug in Chrome
and it's like actually 16 things in a chain.
Right. Right. Exactly.
You know, because like chrome is no longer,
like chrome is secure enough and Firefox
and most browsers are secure enough now that
yeah,
-- you need to find a bunch of vulnerabilities in a row to like get somewhere
-- useful.
That's right.
First, we have to get around these six mitigations,
then deliver our payload and then do these
-- other things to execute the payload
-- and well,
and that's for example, where the CWE is also weaknesses,
like it's things like exposing the address and memory, which on its own,
an attacker can't do anything with.
But if you've got a buffer overflow and you don't know your address and memory,
it's tricky
to exploit.
But if you know the address in memory all of a sudden, it's a lot easier.
And so that's the other thing to keep in mind is the common weakness.
Enumeration is not just like buffer overflow,
it's also things like just exposures of information or
it could be also patterns like generating random numbers,
not cryptographically randomly secure enough,
like they're technically random but not like cryptographically secure random,
right.
-- We can put a link to that show from back in the day.
-- I
-- know.
-- Right.
Actually fun fact for anyone who doesn't maybe follow this kind of geeky thing,
the go random number generator,
the default one was cryptographically weak and the documentation of course said,
like, never use this.
And it's like, then why did you idiots put it in here like this?
Because no one reads the docs
but they fixed it. It's fixed like they have a proper random number generator.
-- Now,
-- 20 years ago, I could totally excuse having a
air quotes random number generator and
the computationally expensive cryptographically secure random
generator 20 years ago. Sure. But in the modern world
there's no excuse for that.
Every random number generator should be cryptographically
secure by default and we should just not
have insecure ones because like
just get it from the kernel.
Every kernel on the planet has secure rng.
-- Now,
-- simple example,
all hot dogs are precooked now because we realized if you don't precook them,
people don't cook them.
-- Right? And then they get food poisoning.
-- I believe that.
Right.
-- Like it's that simple.
-- I don't think I've ever had an uncooked hot dog.
-- They
-- used to exist.
-- I bet they were good
-- except they cause food
once in a while, minor detail and
people would die.
So, and that's the thing, right?
Like I and oh, encrypting stuff used to be again,
computationally expensive except now every chip has a S 256 built in and like
you can just do it.
And this is part of where CWE also has not just fallen
behind in terms of coverage like it has no Blockchain coverage.
It, well, no, it has like three things from the Blockchain.
It has like three things for A I. That's it. Right now. I have a list of
over 100 A I things.
-- I don't, I don't want to dwell on all the shortcomings, but
-- it's,
it's important because the thing is it went from being
useful to now being out of date so much like
checking on CWE 1003 or whatever it is.
I did not know this until two weeks ago where I found an NVD entry with an in
correct CWE.
And so I contacted them and said, you know, this CWE is wrong. Can you please use CWE?
What is it like 204 or something like that?
And they're like, no, we can't,
we're gonna use 203 and I'm like, what? What?
But, and they're like, we used the simplified CWE view. So it's,
-- and that's from 2015.
-- Is
-- it
-- that old? I didn't know how old it was.
-- Yes,
-- it is that old.
Well, it also has 100 and 30.
It's
versus
-- 1300. So it's missing about 1000 CW
-- es. Well, and that's the other thing.
All, not all Cwesrcwes MC WS are what are called views like the Os top 10
or
the simplified views,
which I wish they hadn't done that but whatever.
-- Oh,
-- oh, it says here there's 938 weaknesses, there's 374 categories and 50 views.
So there the numbers are.
So here's Kurt.
So this is actually funny because Kurt started
complaining to me on signal about this.
-- I'm like, I thought everyone knew NVD. Use CWE 1003.
-- I bet almost nobody does.
And I, I literally have no idea how I knew this.
I, I don't know,
it probably came up because I probably emailed them at
some point and they sent me the exact same answer.
You got it like we only use this particular view. Now, here is my comment on this.
NBD has an impossibly hard job.
There are, let's say 1000 Cwes,
I'm just going to use a number of 1000 because
I'm a monkey with 10 fingers and I like it.
So 1000 Cwes,
these NBD analysts are already under intense
pressure to understand and categorize these vulnerabilities,
I think unless you tightly constrained the number of I DS
they can use and figure out because here's the thing,
100 and 30 I DS.
If you do this kind of work all day, every day,
you're going to keep all 130 of those in your head,
right? So you're going to be able to like, you know, crank these things out like that.
But if you expect someone to deal with 1000.
It is
unrealistic and they're probably gonna make a ton of stupid mistakes.
A lot of those 1000 are obsolete or like, they're like.net specific or something.
But they're like, so hyper specific.
Well,
what's interesting is they wouldn't actually meet the current standard to be ac we,
because they're specific.
No, II, I brought this up on a board meeting. It's not a, maybe it's
a, I discussed this on a board meeting with them. I'm on the CWE board so
I can actually speak from authority here. I know it's not the best thing to do, but
in this case, it's true.
I will say this,
I just ran across there is nvd.n.gov/phone/categories and they say NV DC,
we slice the common weakness.
Enumeration specification provides a common blah, blah, blah, blah blah,
all individual cwenvd integrates CWE into the scoring of CV vulnerabilities
by providing a cross section of the overall CWE structure.
So they say technically that they're using a
subset of it, but they never used the word subset or reduced or CWE 1003.
Like they never explicitly say, were you,
they say here's the 133 that we're using
and they give a list, but they don't like explicitly say
like you would have to scroll through this page and realize it's kind of short
at this point.
It's clear that NV D's ability to communicate is like they rolled a
zero when it was time to fill in that particular entry on the,
on the,
so
they did
the die, fell off the table and they're like, it must be
-- with
-- it.
Right.
Yeah.
So, like, I'm looking at this and like,
I've been dealing with the NVD for 20 years and I didn't know this,
-- you know,
-- anyway, we're like, halfway ish through this episode.
I want to talk about what CWE should be because I
think that is vastly more interesting than complaining about that.
-- It sucks.
-- Let's use the Linux kernel as a perfect example where
there's a um I forget his name at the Linux kernel, but basically,
he's trying to get the Linux kernel to be more secure.
And one of the things that really helps him is when he can look
at a piece of code and say this code is generally vulnerable to CWEX.
And here's a pile of CV es like actual vulnerabilities of
that type because he's dealing with developers who are busy.
If you go to a developer and say, please
rewrite a bunch of your code
to use this more secure memory structure thing that we now provide.
It's gonna take you a few days or weeks, but it'll be air quotes more secure.
They're like cool. I have a lot of work to do. No, thank you.
But if you come to them with data
and you say, hey,
look when this memory structure that you're using like it we keep assigning
security vulnerabilities to it because it keeps being exploited by the bad guys.
Right.
So,
like here's some actual data showing how bad it is most developers are going to go.
-- Oh, yeah. Ok. Right. Yeah, I should probably,
-- I
think you're on the right path,
but I'm going to steer us in a slightly different direction.
I'm going to point at the
-- WASP top
-- 10, which top 10,
-- they have multiple top tens, the top
-- 10, like the top 10, not any of the other ones,
-- like the top
-- 10,
the O A
top 10,
I was listening to a podcast maybe a month ago and I
don't remember which one this was for the life of me,
but they were discussing O Wasp
and
like its structure and how it works and everything. And I have
explained
at length in public
that the O
A
top 10 list is the most disappointing thing
I've ever experienced.
And the reason being O
Wasp had an opportunity to take the top 10 list and try to like,
let's eliminate the top thing on the list.
Like let's just literally make it not exist anymore as a vulnerability.
And all they ever do is shuffle the list around every couple of years.
The reason this is I found out is because
WASP
is run by consultants.
Consultants don't want to eliminate
classes of vulnerabilities because they're making
all of their money advising and dealing with this stuff.
And I heard this and I'm like,
I cannot argue with what was just said because my observation of O
A
100% backs that up.
-- I
-- mean,
you did that presentation where you basically boiled down the
list to three things which was use a framework,
use encryption.
I can't remember the other one now
-- use authentication, something
-- like that. I think single Cyon
was probably one of them.
-- But
-- like looking at this sensitive data exposure,
broken authentication injection, XML, external entities broken, you know,
like, and then, yeah, they literally get shuffled around.
-- Here's
-- my, my,
like my big to do CWE is 100% in the
same list if we were serious about solving security problems.
And I know we all say we are, but it's kind of one of those things of like, oh, do you,
you know, do you want to cure homelessness?
And we're all like, of course we do and they're like,
we're gonna raise your taxes 1% and they're like,
uh maybe people like sleeping outside,
you know, and that's, this is a very similar problem.
I think what CWE should do is every vulnerability
should get ac we and then you as an
organization should look at every CWE you have dealt with
in the last 12 months and then you should say we're going to pick this one in our,
say top 10 list, our personal top 10 list
and we're going to make sure we never see this vulnerability again
or defang it,
-- you know.
-- Sure.
And the reality is we cannot do that today with our tools and our process,
it just can't be done.
And I think part of it is I'm getting to the point where
things
here's how I view software you need to do and write as
little software as possible unless you can write truly good software.
And so by that, I mean,
you need to use as much open source software that is good as possible.
And then you do kind of as little as possible
because then you actually have a chance to do it right to get it right.
Because like, for example, no people used to write web servers
and some people still do. And I'm like, that's insane. That's fair, right?
And so I think basically what it boils down to is like industrialization.
I don't make my own screws anymore. I go to Home Depot and buy them.
What I would really love to see is where frameworks like Django,
like what there's even entire languages like Python where it's like,
yeah, that kind of cwe just can't really happen.
And if it does it's in the core language and we will fix it very quickly.
And I think it's that kind of thinking of industrialization
that needs to start happening because I think this idea of,
oh we're gonna like fix all the buffer overflows in the software we wrote.
No, no, you're not like open BS D can't even do that.
And Open BS D hyper aggressively finds a flaw and goes, oh,
let's eliminate all the ones like that.
Yeah. They're literally the best security developers on the planet.
Like the people who write open SSH and they still
make mistakes for sure if they can't get it right.
There's zero hope for people like Curt and myself.
-- But
-- then they do stuff like the virtual temp stuff and it's like, oh,
so like all the temp bugs
done
gone.
Poof.
-- No more
-- temp file vulnerabilities are a great example because what, 1015,
20 years ago, temporary file vulnerabilities were a, an actual legitimate,
real problem.
-- They're gone
-- and
the biggest part of the solution,
no more multiuser systems
in the sense of like you're in a container, you're not all
glommed into the same room.
Exactly.
And so that's a perfect example of like, oh,
you want to get rid of temp vulnerability is actually 100% for real.
Yeah. Just
like use containers and that'll
solve most of it.
Yes.
Yeah.
And so I think that's part of the other part is it's
not just using CW to start squashing vulnerabilities and getting better results.
But using it to think at a sort of more industrial academic
scientific scale because if your plan is to go through your
code and fix all of the vulnerability of type X.
No, no,
I have, I have a great example of this that we talked about the, was it not the NSA?
I think it was the NSA and CIA release the, oh,
you should use memory safe languages documents.
I'm certain we did an episode on it a long time ago.
I'm sure we did. I'll be completely shocked if we did not.
-- I will look and put it in the show notes. I vaguely
-- remember this news item.
But
yeah,
but anyway, the point, yes,
how many Cwes
can you completely eliminate by using Rust or,
or any memory safe language as opposed to C or C++?
-- I literally have no idea
-- even better than that. It's not just that you can
eliminate a couple dozen,
but it's often a couple dozen of the really
impactful ones
because to put it bluntly again,
cross site scripting.
Yeah, that's not great but whatever we'll deal with it versus buffer overflow.
I mean, it's catastrophic if you're a web service. Uh cross
a scripting is a buffer overflow of web services.
It's sort of, it depends if is it reflected or stored blah, blah, blah,
just like buffer overflows. There's 100 kinds of them.
And this is a perfect example of where
knowing CWE really helps because I'm looking at A I stuff and A is are now spitting out
json to feed into API S and others.
In
this situation.
A cross site scripting goes from, oh,
you can display something annoying in a web page
to
oh, now it can cause code execution in another system.
And so knowing what a cross site scripting vulnerability is,
it's funny because I was like looking at this in the context of A I early on, I'm like,
whatever, it'll be bad.
But,
and, but now A I has this new capability of talking to API S and it's like, whoa,
this is a problem and this is the kind of thing where CW is very important because
the answer to that is not
to, for me to try and fix it. It's for like the framework and the A I vendor to fix it,
right? You know,
like we don't ask everybody to figure out how to make safe water.
-- We, we deliver that as a service.
-- That's a good point actually. And, and I think
the whole SASS universe now
has made it more obvious where I think in the past if you got a development
environment for someone like Microsoft or Redhead or
whoever you'd use it and you'd be like,
oh I added another buffer overflow to my code.
It must be dumb.
In reality, it was like,
why is this development environment even allowing us to do this crap?
Like this is stupid.
Yeah.
And so, but, but in the SAS world, it's,
I think more obvious of like if your service has a cross site scripting flaw,
it is not my problem to fix.
You need to go fix it.
Which speaking of that we should talk about Sass bomb at
some point because that's like the S bombs for SAS.
But anyway, back to
CWC.
-- We, but
-- this is a good example of where CW can be valuable because there's this,
there's, there's a whole bunch of new A I vulnerabilities.
I've, I have like a list of over 100 of them, but there's also a list of really old,
like 20 to, like, they're old enough to vote
vulnerabilities that are actually
like
really terrifying in an A I context now that A I has
gained certain capabilities of like talking to API S and stuff.
And if people are not aware of this, like it's going to end badly, I mean,
most people aren't and I don't think CWE is going to make it obvious to them either.
I don't think CWE as a vehicle for
conveying information to other people is necessarily valuable.
-- No,
-- it's terrible. But for example, it is the
head end
of a lot of code scanning tools that go
well, what do we code scan for?
Well, the answer is you,
you kind of go through CWE like uh brakeman for Ruby essentially goes through
and looks for a bunch of stuff in CWE that applies to Ruby.
So like obviously not really buffer overflows but things
like cross eye scripting and blah blah blah.
And that is actually really useful because asking somebody to
write a code scanner and oh as a side project.
Just re invent the universe of security vulnerabilities. Very easy.
Yeah, super easy.
But if we actually have this nice thick catalog of, like,
here's all the bugs and how they look and what they look like.
E even if it's not in your language,
like you look at the Python example to the go example or the C example.
And you're like, oh, ok. I get it now
and that's where it could be very useful, but it's
so slow to update that. It's,
yeah, sorry, I've, I've pushed for various things to speed it up.
And cwe was averaging point, what was it?
0.9 of ac we per month for the last 2, 2.5 years.
Well, look, I, I have the same complaints about this as I do about CV E and it's,
the reality is like we exist in a world now where the, the,
the way open source works needs to be applied to things like this
and these sort of projects need to exist in like independent foundations.
-- No,
-- it's not gonna happen.
Miter gets 30 million to pay to fund this and they're not going to give that up.
-- It's
-- cash money. Right.
Imagine what a foundation could do with $30 million you know.
Yeah, I think, was it 34 point something, whatever. Anyway, a big number,
it doesn't matter. It's not going to get fixed,
but
we can even ignore CWE we can say, oh, yeah. If it's in a foundation it would get fixed.
But like the Os top 10 is a foundation
and they're clearly not doing anything with it either.
So, like, I don't know,
-- it's
-- kind of a disappointing because the Os top 10 could be like, it is well known, but
-- it's completely well known,
-- but it kind of does, it actually result in really,
truly actionable good outcomes.
Well, it does
the
consultants that are using it to sell product and services.
-- I
-- mean, I always kind of wonder like PC I DS S, if it didn't exist,
would things actually be that much worse than the answer is probably.
Yes.
Yes, for sure. Yes.
And the reason I know this is because I worked at an ISP in 1998
and I wrote Pearl Code for them,
which that's like a blast from the past.
And there was a, we, we wrote a website and now this
was mind you when like
having any sort of web forms, like this was CG I bins, right?
-- Like way back
-- in the
-- day,
-- common
gateway interface for those of you that don't know what that means?
No one knows what that is and don't, don't look
it up.
But
no, it's
-- technology. It's like knowing how to crank start a car.
-- Right.
Anyway, the point is we had to collect credit card numbers for some like
it was a marathon.
People were registering for,
this was back when like registering for anything online was basically
magic.
We were just collecting everyone's credit
card information over an unencrypted website.
Http
and we were writing them to a sequel database completely unencrypted.
And then we were emailing
the contents of the SQL database to someone at the end of every day.
So they could manually charge the credit cards.
Like,
yeah, in into the PC I world. That would be like a hilarious number of
now, rightly.
-- So
-- look at physical bank security compare now compared to what it was 100 years ago.
Right. Like, they have the cash machine vaults.
They don't have tellers with drawers full of cash. Right? They've, they've,
they've done a lot of things now that, you know, would, like, basically,
if you try to run a bank from 50 years ago in today's world,
it would basically be illegal.
I would hope so. Like, it would be so insecure.
Yeah, the cops would probably show up and shut you down.
No. Really? Right. Like having,
you know, drawers full of tens of thousands of dollars of cash.
I imagine the cops will not be happy about that because they know
you're gonna get robbed and they're gonna have to deal with it.
This is a great example.
Actually, Kurt using banks and the way they've from PC I DS s to
the way bank robberies and everything used to work. This was an example where
the risk was
understood
and then they took efforts to reduce and eliminate those risks.
Now, in the context of banks, they have literal, actual money on the line
and literal, actual money is like,
the one thing you can guarantee capitalism cares about everything else is a detail.
Well, it's also, you can measure it.
That's true. It's a number, number goes up.
Everyone's happy.
Like, remember when everybody thought, oh, company getting hacked,
it's gonna take their stock price.
So they're not gonna want to get hacked. Yeah, it turns out it doesn't matter,
doesn't, doesn't matter.
Like it, every study of every major breach is like their stock did tank for like a day,
like 3%
or something.
But nobody cares.
The other thing too is a lot of this is dependent on newer technology existing and,
and in it,
we really don't have an excuse there
because we're constantly inventing new cool technology
and then
not using it
like frameworks. Like
there are so many good frameworks that when I see somebody, like,
I see a lot of people writing stuff and I'm like, why there's like a,
there's a really good framework for that or like,
there's a really good thing that like curl like, but be blunt,
if you want to talk and get something off of
like any remote site and you're not using curl.
I, you better have a good excuse.
-- So
-- actually I have a fun fact for you, Daniel put, uh, I'll,
I'll try to dig up the blog post.
24% of games on Steam and Bed Curl.
You know what I thought when I read that I'm like, only 24 percent
don't like
because like, literally if you, if you said to me, Kurt,
we need to talk to something on the internet, I'd be like, yeah, use curl.
What else would you use?
-- And like, they would have to have some really corner case weirdness to justify
-- it.
Yeah, I, I don't even know what else there is. But anyway, OK.
OK, we got to bring this one home.
I feel like, so, so let's,
let's close it on your point about using frameworks because there's a lot of web
frameworks and a whole bunch of them do a lot of things to make it,
for example,
very hard to create cross a scripting vulnerabilities well,
or they just magic all the authentication so that that's done and
there's, there's a lot of that,
but I think that might be a good
example of we probably don't understand like which frameworks
eliminate which vulnerabilities, which frameworks have made it.
So like you literally can't do it at all or it's really hard to screw it up for or?
Yeah, like you're gonna, you're gonna blow your foot
off if you're not careful type, you know what I mean?
And there's like these varying levels of what
are the things that we're eliminating or not eliminating
and like something like cwe should be ripe to help us categorize these things.
And II, I don't, I don't know of a single source of that if someone knows, like,
let me know because I would love to read this sort of analysis.
I've seen people do academic analysis like this,
but I've never seen like a kind of an ongoing thing,
right? Like it's always an academic point in time snapshot.
They get their thesis and then they go to industry and move on.
-- And
-- again, this is something I think like ow
would be perfect for of saying like here's the top 10 list,
here's how the framework compares to the top 10 list.
And you could be like, oh this framework fixes seven of the 10,
this framework fixes negative four of them.
So let's not use that one,
which I mean, some of the older frameworks are definitely terrible like that.
Well, and also bolt on things like mod security for Apache, right?
Like I I wanted to use that to help prevent cross site scripting
by sanitizing input and output, right?
How can mod security sanitize cross
a scripting and like the output is cross
-- a scripting on most web apps
-- because it can take actions based on previous things.
Just trust me, it's
it's,
it's
I'm not talking about just like reading the output and being like her
walking.
I know
very
little about it. It's
mod security has got some very interesting hooks and a
perfect example is like the CS A for example,
has
this ancient PHP app that I keep trying to kill.
And it's like a read only app of just some data with like a kind of a visual interface
that was written by somebody in a Yahoo framework that
like is no longer supported like 10 years ago.
And every time I've turned this thing off, research yells at me and tell us,
turn it back on because people love it.
And I'm like, oh, I hate this thing.
And I finally realized, you know what I did, I just blocked ankle brackets,
right? Because there's no need for angle brackets to go into this app, right?
Because it's just literally like you're
clicking on this little interface and looking
-- at stuff with this little visual interface
-- that is not 100% effective.
There's other ways to get around that.
-- But
-- this thing doesn't do authentication, it just displays data.
And so one thing we kept coming was people like, oh, this crossing
flaw in it because you can do this.
And I'm like, yeah, but it like it doesn't take authentication,
it doesn't talk to any systems.
It's just a little visualizer of some data.
And so I just blocked angle brackets and like done,
not
done
anyway.
But that's the thing like I solved the problem.
Like is the application technically still vulnerable. Yes.
But even if you get cross site scripting in it, you
can't really do anything other than use it,
I guess with social engineering to be like, hey, this is a CS, a login, like,
please give us your password and credit card number or something.
Right? And then like,
the person would have to enter that.
Do you, do you run it on the CS A domain or if you created like some,
it's
on a subdomain.
But anyway, so, but I, but I fixed it by blocking angle brackets because I'm like,
if you block angle brackets or present whatever the two F or F, whatever it is,
I'm excited for all the people who are gonna message you on Mastodon
about ways around to just blocking angle brackets as uh a mitigation mechanism.
If you can inject, see like, yes, I know you can do CS S without angle brackets,
but
it's
nobody's going to bother.
I think there's other ways to inject the characters
depending upon how your decoding is being done.
And I don't remember all the details,
-- but I do it at the cloud flare level where it normalizes it.
-- That could be,
I don't know. Anyway. All right, we should end this episode.
All right.
Message everyone. Message Kurt, I can't wait to see what he learns from you,
-- but it's a good enough solution for
-- now until someone pones you.
So
thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to put
our security podcast.com. Head up the show, not Susie Pounds
says podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon.
Kurt have a marvelous. Rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.