Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurtz Fried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser
-- December 11th.
-- So 67 reasons you shouldn't get on a 737 max.
Why? 67? I don't understand that.
Well, honestly, there's, there's a couple of big ones,
but I just made it up an arbitrary number.
Ok. And I'm guessing that, I mean, that's,
you know,
and, and I hate to say, but what it really boils down to at
the sort of meta level is that this whole industry effort to create a plane that was,
you know, cheap in the sense of it was a better plane than the 737.
But it was also similar enough that pilots wouldn't have to recertify, you know,
resulted in a lot of changes to the 737 that actually made it fly very differently.
So they added this automated system, mcas to essentially
prevent the plane from crashing
because that'll, that's a thing, right?
The, the plane is unstable in certain configurations because of, well,
they put the engines high and forwards which change the balance and anyways.
The idea being that, you know, you, you take a couple hour refresher course and boom,
you're good to fly this plane.
And as we know that didn't
turn out too well for, well, there was at least two fatal plane crashes.
So,
you know, it's wild is you put this in the, the notes
and I had completely forgotten
that the 737 was even a thing
just from everything else.
-- And the fact that
-- it's the school bus of the airman,
-- I
-- haven't gotten on an airplane in,
I don't even remember how long it's been.
It's been, I don't know what, I don't know what an airport looks like anymore.
You know, it's terrifying.
Somebody posted pictures of that,
those Thanksgiving busy airports in the US and they were packed
well,
by this point in time because it's
totally not November right now before Thanksgiving.
Yeah, by, by the time this airs we will know if there was,
or wasn't some sort of obnoxious aftermath.
So,
I guess future dwellers, I wish you. Well,
good luck.
-- Anyway, 737 would you get on a 737 today?
-- Well, 737 max, and the answer is no,
I
wouldn't get on a 737 max for
more than just the 737 max.
The pandemic. Ignoring the,
would I get on this plane
and the answer is no, but also they're not certified to fly in Canada yet.
Like the FAA is certifying them to fly and
it looks like Europe's going to follow suit.
I would somewhat trust it in Canada
in the sense of Canada, Europe, the US are kind of rich enough to actually, you know,
have the pilots go through training and stuff, but in other parts of the world,
do you think they're not going to take shortcuts?
So why, so wait a minute, you're saying
that
the pilots have to take new training to make the plane not crash?
Well, they have to understand what the MCAS system is and does because it's,
it's the pilots, the two fatal crashes appear to have been the pilot,
the MCAS system kicked in and tried to put the nose of the plane down so that it,
you know, would gain speed and not crash.
And of course, the pilots, like, no, we're trying to take off. That's not,
that's not how this works
and they pull up and they, they essentially weren't expecting the MC A S system.
And the thing is if you are expecting it and you've
been trained in it and you know exactly what to do,
it's, it's a non problem
and if you don't know what's going on or you're not trained to deal with it.
Well, we had two fatal accidents.
So, like there's your answer. And so
my,
my concern too is apparently this mcast stuff and some of the behavior of the plane,
it's all software driven So it's like an option,
but not all the planes had.
Oh. Right. That's right. Because you had to buy an add on. I,
-- I, I'm remembering this now. It's been a long time.
-- Right.
This whole thing is just such a giant cluster of, I mean,
and this really speaks to iot safety in that typically IOT devices, you know,
aren't full of jet fuel and taking off with
-- hundreds of people on board and
-- airplanes are heavily regulated
as we're well aware, IOT has
no regulation at all.
So like I said, I know
a
big part of the problem is I no longer trust the FAA, right?
Because the way the FAA, well, what the FAA did to lead up to this was failure.
And I would say the way the FAA handled this is a failure.
And I think that speaks to a larger
discussion for the world of security is that if there's certain groups,
we have to put our trust in to, I guess, keep us on the right path.
And I mean, I've seen this happen with like security
groups and companies is if your security
group becomes untrusted by the organization,
it is a very bad outcome.
And honestly, there's generally speaking,
you just have to clean a house and you've got to get rid of all of them and bring them,
bring all new people in because there's no way to fix it.
We've already seen this happen like with
doing self certification programs, you know,
underwriter laboratories used to be the gold standard for this thing.
Won't burn your house down.
And then they brought in a self certification thing, like almost
decades ago.
And there's, now I forget the mark,
but it's a self certification done by the company, blah, blah, blah.
And it's like I buy IOT devices and I noticed that,
that it's not ul it's that wonky self certified thing.
And I'm like, well, great,
I guess how do we recreate these institutions with
trust when all the market forces want to come
out with the cheapest products that may or may
not burn your house down like those ring doorbells.
And lucky for us, we're out of time. So we don't have to try to answer that.
I'm all right with that.
We will see you all on December 12th.