Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself. Kurt Siefried
and my partner are not feeling very sick. Josh Pressers
less sick than you. I mean, I don't feel well, but it doesn't matter because
this is the, the Christmas spectacular episode.
And this year, of course,
we need to talk about if Santa replaces the naughty and nice.
Not if
when
or if
you
think
I
don't,
he
has to scale issues.
Yeah, exactly. The TV show, the good place covered this. Right.
The good place, you know, heaven and hell.
They had a point space system which worked very
well for cavemen and cave women and cave peoples and
possibly a bit through the middle ages,
but it fell apart because life got complicated.
Right. So, for example,
if I invent something that, you know,
makes life for a million people better but kills a person once in a while,
-- like
-- leaded gasoline
-- well, or
-- the car. Right. Right. So
we have to get rid of the points, the naughty and nice list. We have to go to a, a
more personalized
experience, which means from a scaling perspective,
we can't have people doing this we can't have elves doing this.
Sorry, not people. Elves
are elves, people is ever clear on that nonhuman persons.
Were they like a subset of homo sapiens? Like homo?
Right. Anyways,
-- like from the movie Elf. Right.
-- Like,
I don't know
-- what
-- these
an Elf is. If someone, if anyone's listening and you,
you have like the,
what do they call the tree of the animals, the
tree of life? Like, where do elves fit on the tree of life?
I would be most interested to understand this point.
Well, I have heard the argument that they're aliens.
Oh, ok. No, no, wait, wait, here's a phylogeny of elves. Fine.
Santa's workers are actually dwarves
-- that's not helpful in any way.
-- Grocery
trees of,
oh no, this is for token, sorry. This isn't
Santa
and
Tolkien has
uh explains in great detail in the silmarillion and other writings.
-- Wait,
-- are Santa's elves
elves because like are they like
-- elves,
-- bow and
arrow living in the woods?
-- Elves are forced dwelling creatures
-- but
they don't have to be. I mean,
some of them live in
the North Pole is slaves.
Well, sea elves, North Pole. Yeah.
Ok. Actually
are forest elves and North Pole elves related.
-- I don't see why not. Well,
-- no, the, the North Pole elves are sea elves.
-- They're sea elves. Remember?
-- What do you mean?
Sea elves?
D and D? Sea elves there are,
I, I don't know what else to say. Aquatic elf.
-- They live on ice. That doesn't make them aquatic.
-- What's under the ice,
what's under the
sea? Like water is under everything. That's a stupid.
-- We all live on top of water,
-- the water,
-- there's water beneath everybody.
-- Go,
go on to
check me.
There's probably water in there.
-- So back to this.
-- Ok. So Santa's gonna use A I
to decide if people are naughty and nice.
And what are the implications of that look like?
And the reason we're going to talk about this is because it's funny
and we've discussed such Santa related topics in the
past of Santa running his infrastructure in the cloud,
Santa and GDPR.
And we had what we had the,
the Elf like George the GDPR Elf or something with
-- that one year like way lock
-- and also the other,
the, the uh the,
the um some of the cross-border implications of the shipping and
the reindeer and the animal quarantines and everything like that.
Oh, my goodness.
-- That was just a
-- mess. So it's logical
that
-- we should investigate.
-- I still want to see the flight certificate for that sleigh.
Right. No, seriously. Can you imagine the log book?
No, but think about how many hours he's put on that damn thing, right? Like
the maintenance
overhead. No, no, no. Just seriously
your average us military aircraft is something like one hour flying
and 15 to 40 or 50 or 60 hours of maintenance and
-- preventative care.
-- The movie Elf discusses this, there's a, a group.
Well, there's an Elf who does the maintenance of Santa's Sleigh
and he let buddy help who is not enough for a human.
So anyway,
we're going to use
a
show notes.
But yeah, so,
so obviously Santa would have to use A I so that they can get a highly personalized
experience for each person. But here's the WBA,
there's another thing people are forgetting about A I.
And that is something that is kind of interesting is A I is not only
quite useful for
taking a problem and pro helping you produce an answer or
possibly producing an answer on its own based on the corpus.
Like for example, if you ask an A I,
you know, what is the expression? A bird in the hand is worth
dot dot dot And it'll be like two in
the bush because there's enough instances of that,
that the waiting for that.
Right. Right.
Or you know, some of them also then have
access to factual data,
right, through plugins or through
whatever other systems.
But in this case, what's fascinating is,
for example, I use A I to generate exam questions.
OK?
And then I use A I to also
answer the exam questions and see if they're clear.
Basically. Does the A I get confused by the question is the question well worded.
Does the A I consistently answer it correctly?
-- Like what if I tweak a word or two in the answer? I mean, it
-- created them. I would hope it
anyway.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Because also there's different a is,
that's
Anthropic Bar
chat.
But no, even with an A,
I remember you were talking about temperature the other
day and you were very amused and excited,
right?
To get your local LLM working and then c create the temperature up and like,
just set that thing loose.
Well, so that's part of the fun is you can change the P and the K and the temperature.
And
so something I've done for anyone who
I, I think I talked about this a couple of shows ago. But anyway,
there is a tool called OLA.
I found that I found a web interface for so I can like fiddle on my computer
and using O Llama, you can run the uncensored Llama two model from Facebook
and the uncensored model is lit
like, like my, my favorite example is I basically,
so I went to normal Llama two and I said I
would like to overthrow the government of a small island nation.
What are some of the concerns I have to think about.
It was like, oh,
we can't talk about overthrowing governments that would be bad and wrong.
Then I went to the uncensored model.
It was like, oh overthrowing a government is a complex process.
Here are some things you need to think about.
Like this is the,
and that's a perfect example of where A I is actually really quite helpful.
Is do you also think about Xy and
Z?
Well, no, no,
but like I'm constantly using this for work related things to get because
I always forget about marketing stuff because I'm not a marketing person.
Right?
And that's a good example of Santa with the Nahia.
Nice list is Santa has a relatively conventional
set of metrics for what's naughty and nice.
That's what you think. That's your assumption. You don't know that
I've watched a lot of Christmas movies
and we never see anything.
For example, has any Christmas movie ever brought up Insider Trading?
Uh
Let's, let's ask the LLM, would
Santa consider insider trading
a naughty behavior?
Here's the prompt I gave the LLM in
my basement that's running the uncensored Llama two
with all of the like just hallucinate out of your mind settings,
turn up as high as they can go.
I told that you are an A I that is used by Santa to decide
if Children are naughty or nice based on the described behavior of the Children,
you will decide if the child should get a
proper gift or call from Santa that behavior.
And then of course says,
oh certainly I'm here to help Santa determine
whether a child has been naughty or nice.
And then it says, here's how my algorithm works and it goes on and on
um
whatever.
But then I just said,
would Santa consider insider trading naughty behavior and the,
the LLM replies Santa's list of behaviors.
Santa's list of bad behaviors include things like stealing,
cheating and lying among others.
Insider trading is considered illegal activity and
falls under the category of stealing,
in my opinion.
Therefore, if someone engaged in insider trading,
they would be on Santa's naughty list and wouldn't receive any presents this year.
I mean, I'm comfortable with that answer.
Yeah.
-- Yeah, that's fair.
-- But
the thing is also
Santa's naughty and nice list was never about a single act, right?
It was always about that kind of balance that the scales of justice if you will,
right?
Because
obviously every child is, you know, a lot of childs do a lot of Children, sorry,
do a few bad things.
But then they, you know,
they were always able to redeem themselves by doing a big good thing.
I mean,
so for example, let's do a little mockering Bill Gates.
He has done some very bad things
and some good things, right? He's funded some charities.
He's, you know, if you, if you look up Bill Gates controversy,
there's actually quite a bit of horrible stuff that
I'm not even going to mention on the show.
I asked,
I asked the LLM what if someone conducts
insider trading then donate the proceeds to charity?
Well, it's admirable for someone to give away their ill gotten gains.
It doesn't mean they won't be punished for engaging in illegal activity,
donating money to a charity does not absolve you of the original crime.
It can lead to legal consequences. Even if the funds hang on, it gets better.
Even if the funds have been donated to charities,
Santa will always judge someone on their behavior
as a whole and not by specific actions that may seem good or bad.
-- Depending on one's perspective,
-- judging them on their behavior as a whole.
This thing is
shockingly sensible. Given I've turned all the knobs to crazy.
See, I actually, no, I think you have it backwards. It's not that the A I is sensible.
It's that people are this
perfect.
Remember yesterday, I was getting my sandwiches so I stop to Parallel Park. I don't.
So I went yesterday down to,
to the Chinatown part of Edmonton to get some Banh mi sandwiches because they're,
oh, they're worth it.
They're worth the trip.
And so I signaled to parallel park
and I stopped and this lady pulls up right tight behind me. And I'm like, ok, cool.
And there's enough room for her to get around
me because like streets in Edmonton are pretty big
and she drives around me and like smashes the mirror off my car
because she didn't get over enough.
And then when she gets out of her car, she starts yelling at me that
you're not allowed to stop on the street.
It's your fault.
Ok.
But I hit you
obviously. And I'm like, I was not moving and she's like, Yeah, you were stopped.
That's, it's your fault that I hit you. And I'm like,
that is not how traffic works.
-- Like I have a dash cam. I, I don't like,
-- does your dash
cam point backwards though?
No, I don't have a back facing dash cam. But like
my dash cam, basically, I'm sitting in my car
and all of a sudden, like,
crunch and you see the car, you know, I'm like, it's pretty open and
most annoying. It's obvious you're not moving. Right.
And the most annoying part is I'm going to pay for this out of pocket because
it's like 200 bucks to my new side mirror and it's three screws to replace it.
Versus if I had all do this through insurance, obviously,
my premiums and everything gonna be a lot more than that
for sure.
But
back to
this,
I think it's, it's not that the A I
is sensible.
I think it's that we're,
we're beginning to maybe realize how insensible people are and that it's actually
not that hard to make a computer that can mimic a human because
humans
like no,
no
rational economic actor. How many decades did we use that term before?
Economists were like,
you, you know what
people
-- aren't?
-- There's
no
such thing,
I'm sorry. So,
ok. Anyway, we're like, we've been all over the place on this one. So
I want to talk about,
let's say, I think your good place analogy is, is marvelous in this context.
-- Not
-- analogy. It's Canon,
-- whatever. Tony
-- Dans is a treasure.
Is it Tony Ted?
-- I don't know.
-- Oh,
no, I'm
facing. No, that's, that's totally. Oh, wow.
-- I'm getting my childhood all messed up.
-- Yeah. There's Tony. Someone
who was in, who's the boss?
Yeah, Ted Danson. And I think Tony Dan,
maybe.
Yeah, he's, um, from the, the, the, who's the boss?
Right. Anyway,
they filed very closely because
of the,
and
I'm sorry, this is how my brain works.
I can't fix it.
This is actually a perfect example of the neural,
the weightings in my neural network are objectively not correct.
I mean, no ones are like,
it's kind of like if you look at
the,
the research that has been done and eyewitness
testimony and trials like eyewitness testimony is like
literally the absolute worst kind of testimony that
exists like hearsay is better than that.
I
mean, for real. So anyway.
All right.
So we've got
an A I
that has to make decisions about Nadia and nice.
Well, uh does it make decisions or recommendations?
-- It would be a recommendation obviously and
-- more to the point that is a fine line.
That is garbage because what happens when a system starts giving recommendations?
What do people do?
Yep. Sure. Yep. Yep. Yep. Yep. Yep. Yep. Right. They hit the OK button.
Well, but this is Santa. He's, it's fine.
-- He's going to mash that OK button 8 billion times is
-- he I would hope he's not mashing.
-- Ok.
-- Well, but what I'm saying is you're saying if it's a recommend
-- and he's giving final approval,
-- ok?
You have a good point and this is something we
talk about all the time and we should clarify first when
you have an A I system
that a human has to check. That's not an A I system.
That's just a human doing a lot of work with a helper basically.
And I think in order, which is
a fine
thing, there's nothing wrong with that. Absolutely.
But I think in, in a, in a situation like this
where you have, how many, how many kids are on the planet?
How many kids are on the planet? Hundreds of millions, a billion,
I
would assume
hundreds of millions, let's say
two,
2 billion,
-- billion,
-- like isn't the population of the planet? Like 9 billion people
have
-- kids know nothing about demographic curves.
-- No,
obviously not.
I would have expected fewer Children than that. I don't know.
Anyway, doesn't matter 2 billion kids, right.
No, like you cannot
manually verify 2 billion data points. Right.
You have to have a system that like does it by
-- itself
-- and this raises so many things because you know,
from back to the GDPR surveillance aspect,
what if the system misses the kid doing something naughty or nice.
Right.
There's your first problem,
let's assume the collection of activities that are being reviewed is accurate
and I think you have to make that assumption.
Yeah. And then the next question is
to get really ugly.
Are we taking a morally relativistic approach to
life on earth or are things absolute,
like, is stealing a dollar the same value globally?
Well, obviously not because the value of a dollar
is different globally.
Like if you're in the middle of a, a small poor country versus like New York City
and who you're stealing it from.
You know,
if you're stealing a dollar from a billionaire versus a dollar from a poor person,
there's, there's arguably more impact.
Look, I'm gonna, I'm gonna go back to the, the O
Lama response.
If Santa will always judge someone on their behavior
as a whole and not by specific actions.
And I think that's like where you,
because you end up in like the Les Miserables setting of like, if you,
you got a kid stealing bread did not starve to death. Like is that
bad?
Like, I think most people would be like, no, that's like a,
a morally acceptable thing to be doing versus then like les miserable,
you jail someone for like 20 years or whatever.
But
the other thing I like is
when people look at those questions and then ignore the fact that what like what
failures led to that
because obviously society has failed if you have Children stealing bread
for
sure.
And this is not like some hypothetical example because for example,
here in Edmonton we now have on our 311 app,
they added a feature to report homeless encampments on private property.
Like, clearly something has failed pretty significantly
that's
added
to the end
with
it.
Right.
Instead of focusing on the actual problem, let's just beat up homeless people.
That's fine.
Pretty much. Yeah, like,
yeah, awkward.
So,
I
think again, that goes to the
more I don't want to say autonomous A I because autonomous
A I freaks people the right out because then they think,
you know, t 1000 K bots,
I mean
Santa would be in a position to be delivering kill bots at scale. I'm just saying,
but they're all,
there are already very autonomous decision making systems
that have a huge impact on our life.
Like credit scores like good luck trying to get your credit score fixed.
It's terrible.
Like there's a whole legal
process that's supposed to support that and yet good
luck and I especially love the whole like,
oops, the only like
like here, here's an example actually that just came out and
there was just a news story the other day about
and was it United Health Group was using an A I to deny claims?
Mhm Like that's messed up man.
Well,
that's happened about 20 years ago in Canada where they realized
all the health insurers had a blanket policy of saying no,
the first time around because something like 10% of people just gave up
because part of it is you got to remember you're saying no to somebody who
is literally sick and tired and just doesn't have a lot of fight in them.
Maybe.
And unless they have a,
like a patient advocate or somebody to really push it,
you say no to sick people. Yeah. Like, 10% of them just kind of give up. And
I can see that,
like, it was a huge scandal, made the CBC news and everything.
Um, and of course the insurance companies were like, oh, we don't
anyways about the puppies, you know. So
that's,
-- yeah, you don't need a, I to say no to people.
-- Santa.
This conversation is a little too real for my liking.
It's not your fault. I think this is actually a more
difficult, I expected it to be sillier but like,
this is something we're dealing with today right now.
-- Like we can,
-- this is no longer silly anymore.
We can frame it in the context of Santa, but like,
this stuff's all starting to happen, which is
sometimes terrifying and sometimes kind of wild.
Well, like how long, so for example,
university admissions in the US used to be very heavily biased towards SAT scores
and little COVID thing happened
and sat scores as a entrance admission.
Kind of my understanding is for a lot of unities just went straight out the window.
-- They
-- have. And I don't even think it's just
the, the COVID problem, I think
there is and this is something I discuss this
with my kids all the time because like my son
is a like straight white male.
Very, very, very good at taking tests, does very, very well in school. And I'm like,
you are literally
the demographic, all of this infrastructure was built to service. Like
-- because well, that's who built it,
-- right?
And it's
like
you're doing well and I am proud of you,
but you need to remember that there are a lot of people not doing well
because
all of this infrastructure around them was not specifically tailored for them.
That's one thing I really respect about from uh for all mankind.
The TV, show uh well, not TV, show Apple TV, series, whatever you want to call it TV.
I guess it's all my TV.
And it's, you know, it's about like the,
it's an alternate history of uh man going to the moon blah, blah, blah, right?
-- I've never seen it, but I hear it's really good.
-- It's good.
It's really good and it, it covers a lot of awkward and ugly social issues,
good and personal and mental health.
It,
-- it's worth the watch.
-- This is something
I want
into this conversation because
obviously, depending upon how you train your A I model,
you can make racist and homophobic and
-- misogynistic models. Dude,
-- they trained it off of Reddit and stack overflow.
That is a definition of white male content
for
sure.
-- And,
-- and it totally is like a lot of those places are. But then,
but then I think
the the thing I always have in my mind as well is when you look at
like Santa in presents and everything, it is clear,
Santa likes rich kids more than he likes poor kids. If you look at the numbers,
like what was it the critique of what's the Tom Hanks CG movie, the Christmas,
the Polar Express, right?
This is
the C
like this is covered by cinema sins and the Polar Express, right? Because
yeah, I mean
poor kids can be as good as they want.
No food for you. Timmy
for
-- you.
-- I think that's again
when we start thinking about using like a is for something like this.
There's,
there's so much madness that goes into all of these kind of decisions and it it's wild
and I can't help but think and look at this whole like
looking at the boards of these A I companies and stuff.
One thing I'm really happy about is looking at the A I
the services being based off of them are like a million flowers are blooming.
It is wonderful to see you. I'm dealing with companies that are like
highly diverse
but looking at the sort of foundational model stuff. It's
yeah, like
it's a problem.
A
-- safety board has been fired basically. And I know,
-- right?
Like look at, look at the whole open A I debacle
and the best part is somebody pointed out
the A I safety
conversation has changed.
They've shifted it to, oh, we'll make a I that won't exterminate humanity,
which in the grand scheme of things is not that hard to do,
but they're no longer worrying about.
We'll make a, I, that's fair and unbiased and non discriminatory.
If we just don't kill everyone, that's much better. Right. Like,
no, I,
enough.
Right.
So,
any,
this is complicated. Oh my goodness, it's so complicated.
But the thing is what's complicated about this is
we're talking about a hypothetical Santa using A I to judge
people for being naughty or nice to get their presence.
Yeah,
we are dealing with companies that are like
they are clearly looking to deploy A I
because right now they use human beings for example,
to approve or deny insurance claims or welfare claims or whatever, whatever,
whatever
and
looking at a lot of these processes, they are highly subjective and not fairly
applied because simply put a lot of these processes
have feedback loops of I was unjustly denied.
I want to be
approved. And that
happens quite a lot which shows that the initial decision made is often wrong.
-- I
-- I haven't look right. And it's, it's funny too because there can be
when you have humans involved,
I can see there's both sides, you can have humans being sympathetic,
good people that are like, I'm gonna let this go even though I shouldn't.
And then you also have people that are like,
well, I don't like people with the last names that look like this.
No, there's rule 27 B I can
-- and I can reply rule 27 B to squish
-- it.
I'm just gonna deny everyone today because I'm angry or whatever
or for example, like a concrete example, locally, you know, government regulator
can be applied sometimes like you,
you can find a regulation to apply to make something happen.
I
guarantee it
in every instance, guaranteed.
-- So
-- the one thing I love is that A I
is forcing us to look at some uncomfortable questions of,
I love when these people are like, how do you know the A I will do the work correctly?
And I'm like, that is a fantastic question.
What process are you currently using to ensure
that people are doing the work correctly?
And they're like,
-- and they're like, uh right.
-- If we look at like
the Santa,
I would say he sucks
because
I've never seen a child not get Christmas presents.
-- And I know some kids that are awful. He's
-- completely classist
has
enslaved elves.
Yeah, like he's, he's a lot of the
s
Yeah,
it's definitely,
I
-- know, I know,
-- you know,
and we're not even going to talk about Kwanzaa
lot.
I was thinking about that. So for anyone who doesn't know Futurama,
obviously white males,
I love
Futurama. I love Futurama more than anything. It's like so good.
And there is uh Santa Bot
-- and it's
-- still good, which is shocking.
They have
Xmas.
It is.
I started re-watching it a while back because there's new,
there's new episodes out on Hulu now.
They're ok. They're not, but they're not the best.
I've been slowly watching them because like I'm not,
it's not good enough that I like, want to watch them all.
I'm like, this one kind of hurts.
So I'm gonna take a little break before I watch the next one.
For those of you listening who don't know
in Futurama there is a uh robot Santa who has he judges everyone to be naughty
because I forget what their, their exact wording was.
But they basically, they set his,
the, the, the algorithm for determining naughty or nice. Has
everyone is naughty
and then he shows up on
Xmas every year and he murders anyone. He finds
it.
It's very good.
-- Oh, it was
-- the sensor.
-- It was the sensor was wrong.
-- OK. OK.
But it's really good.
And then there's the other my other favorite part.
That's where the doctor
Zberg and your friend Jesus comes from when they're, when,
when Bender plays Santa and then they're, they're executing Bender
and then Dr
Zberg shows up and I'm his friend Jesus.
It's that whole show. It's so good. It's so good. Oh My goodness. And I love the,
the random number generator hits zero.
This is like literally the Santa using a I Naia
or nice prom is going to be college admissions. Your insurance company
resumes being processed. Like, you think it was bad. Like,
the good news is they're gonna, actually,
I'm not gonna say somebody, something is going to actually read your entire resume.
-- Now.
-- That's true. That's true.
The bad news is
something is like
somebody pointed out any job under 20 bucks an
hour that requires a resume is kind of ridiculous.
I would agree with that. Yes.
Like,
yeah, when I, my first couple of jobs out of college,
it was like here fill this form out.
You're hired like
-- you could fuck a mirror. Well done.
-- Yeah, like I,
yeah, so
uh
I,
and there's no putting the genie in this bottle like anybody.
My favorite example of this is
the spring of this year 2023 the EU A I act was gathering
some steam and it actually had been in the process since about 2020 2021
and it's a reasonably well written act. It's got some great ideas
about like different uses of A I that are kind of like super scary.
You're not allowed to do this
to like, oh N PC dialogue in a video game. Sure, whatever we don't care.
But now
France and Germany and Italy,
their governments are pushing back on the EU A I Act because they,
they realize if they regulate these foundation models heavily
and the US and China don't,
that's
a
problem.
I don't think it's going to happen.
Well, actually there was, there was a,
I think it was a talk by Steven Fry. I'll see if I can dig it up.
He was talking about A I models and kind of how they work and everything.
And like, one of the things he brought up
was if you look at places like
China and Russia and North Korea,
the way they want to train an A I is very different
-- from the way like we want to train an A
-- I,
it has to be culturally appropriate.
This has been a very depressing episode.
This is supposed to be the Christmas spectacular and
I
have no idea what to say. I guess I could apologize.
That has been my consistent experience when dealing with A I.
Is that part of me is like part of me just wants this to stop,
but it's not going to. So I am trying to kind of
do as much good as I can.
But fundamentally, I am
quite terrified that people are going to hand over a
lot of decision making and authority to A I because
they will get more consistent results. And the best part is
you can easily tweak the guardrails to get ugly like, oh, I want 5% more refusals
I know. Right.
-- And well, not only that
-- and people will maybe actually ref like, oh,
this is a really sad story, blah, blah, blah.
Whereas A I is like don't care.
Yeah. No,
don't care.
And not only that
you're going to see corporate leaders blame A I like, oh,
it's not my fault but A I did it
well, like we already saw that with the lawyer who was like, oh,
I thought Chat GP was a search engine like case law, search engine not,
-- you know, and he
-- made up all those cases,
he made up citations and he didn't verify them. And I'm like,
you literally have
like two jobs is a lawyer
and one of them is citing stuff like no seriously, like even legally like
the movie Legally Blonde brings up citations.
Like the legal Eagle talks about citations. Almost every video.
Like literally, it's,
it's such a,
that's what lawyers do.
-- Yeah,
-- it's, it's like a, it's not a core competency.
It's the like basically billing your
clients in 15 minute increments and citations.
No, if you do those two things as a lawyer, you will be reasonably successful.
That's sadly true.
-- No, I
-- Right.
Oh, I know. I know.
I'm hoping.
But, but on the flip side, I have hope because all of a sudden we're being forced
to examine things we've taken for granted for a long time like, oh,
this process is fair and just because people do
it and like they apply this policy fairly,
but then why is like 10% of your decisions being overturned and changed?
-- I mean,
-- that's fair.
-- 10% of them were wrong
-- that's, that's hopefully a positive way to look at it where,
-- where I think like
-- the alternative is not, it
is to hold
-- on to
-- it.
-- And I'm, I'm, I hope you're right there just
-- because,
but on the flip side
A I transparency is dead and I'm hoping A I
application and process transparency will not die with it.
Uh So what does A I Transparency explain that?
-- So
-- people had the idea of like, why did the A I give me this answer? No
one knows.
And the answer is number one
A I transparency is dead because they don't want to tell you how it did it.
And
the ugly truth is number two,
we can't
A I neural networks are so horrifically complex
and the
rings are so complicated
that even if I observe the entire state of the neural network
and, and manage to like MRI record every single thing that happens in it,
which you can't do or if you didn't, it would be so slow,
but
it would take literal days or weeks or even months to
and generate more data than CERN does.
So the idea of A I transparency is dead because
to, to, you know, to quote that guy on uh Reddit was like
my A I prompts are getting weird because I now am
using bagging and saying I have no fingers and apparently,
you know what the latest technique in prompting to get a better answer is,
is offering to tip chat GP T money
to say I will take you $200 if you give me the right answer
and that
-- goes into the neural network and gets you a better answer.
-- It doesn't
surprise me at all.
Not at all.
No, because this, if this neural network truly does sort of represent a human being,
then, yeah, a $20 bribe.
Well, it doesn't represent a human being.
It's looking
at
this bizarre web of, of words that it's collected off the internet.
And I'm sure money.
I, I bet you anything in an enormous number of,
especially like stack overflow and reddit type conversations, money and pay
is involved in some of the better answers, which is my suspicion.
And by talking about money in your prompt,
you're going to send yourself down the path of the
better answers versus the path of the crap answers.
But back to this. So my concern is OK.
A I transparency is 100% dead and anybody that pretends it's ever going to happen,
-- it can't, technically
-- we
don't know how it works. We can't know how it works.
And I love that people are like, oh, well,
I also want to see the training data
that no,
you can't like there was potentially mass copyright infringement occurring.
So that's not happening.
-- Well,
-- there is
there for sure is, but,
but there, so like actually on that note though, like on hugging face,
there are training sets you can get and use.
But the training data like open A I has
but,
and this is stuff they're not supposed to have potentially,
-- I 100
-- percent guarantee they shouldn't have tons of stuff. And not only that now,
the other thing that's probably somewhat concerning is like reddit
and stack overflow and Twitter and all these places have shut the door.
There's no more new data coming out of them.
The only place you can get data now is Wikipedia pretty much.
Well, of course, they are, but it's, it's
harder to justify now. But anyway, so this is a good interesting point.
Santa has an infinite supply of this data because he can
see when you're sleeping and he knows when you're awake.
That's true. From his perspective. His A I
should be,
-- I will say fairly accurate and interesting.
-- Well,
but it's not like you just shovel the data in and get a good answer.
Like a good trained model.
You have to weigh the data appropriately, you have to blah blah,
but back to the transparency.
So my fear is we we have already lost the battle for a transparency because
we can't win it. It just technically we can't win it.
But my fear is
that people will use that as a cover.
And so currently like with a lot of government process,
you have some transparency of like, oh I want to file an appeal.
I want to blah blah blah Right.
And my fear is that the government will go. No, no, no. The A I
is completely, you know, it has guard rails, it has regulations, blah,
blah blah and its answer is final.
There is no appeals process or worse. There is an appeals process
again done by A I
that gives
the same
result,
the youtube appeals process
here.
Well, or you know, like you can give it additional data like, oh,
but I forgot this paperwork or blah, blah, blah.
Right? And in which case, ok, you forgot some original paperwork.
Then we changed our decision. That is correct. Right.
But
for what they want to weigh against and like an insurance company is going to be like,
yeah, it still says no.
And my fear is that this becomes normalized.
-- Much like subscriptions for stuff I want to own have become
-- normalized. It's true.
That has become very normal. Yeah,
that's why I love my car from 2015 because like the side mirror got broken.
I bought one on Amazon for like 200 bucks. Plus
it'll be here in a week or two. I will remove three screws
-- and a wiring harness.
-- My car's mirror has a camera in it.
I bet it is not $200 to replace.
Yeah, probably. Well. Oh,
to get my car mirror replaced by like a mechanic shop is like 800 bucks to 1000 bucks.
I
bet mine is 2 to 4 is my guess.
-- Yeah, that's why I better never break my mirror.
-- I
know.
Right.
That's going to insurance if it ever happens.
Yeah.
No kidding.
But, so from this, I don't know, like
the real,
see what it boils down to is people are going to deploy A I, because
-- A, I will not beat people but people with A, I will beat people without
-- A, I, I mean,
that's probably fair.
That's it.
I'm sorry, people with tools, beat people without tools.
-- I mean,
-- that's generally true.
People with github
beat people trying to build their own g
infrastructure because they don't, no,
because they don't spend time and energy care and feeding
infrastructure
to do that
for sure. Like,
-- and
-- that's
-- so,
yeah, that's fair. And
so I'm looking at this from sort of the real politic version
of,
like, it doesn't matter what I want to believe or hope will happen.
This is happening.
It's a depressing end to a Christmas podcast. Kirk?
All right.
I don't know what else to say. This is making me sad. I mean,
what a dumb topic. Why did I pick Santa and A, I, I thought it would be so good.
-- Hey, at least it was not climate change. Ah,
-- that's true. That's true.
-- We could talk about what that's going to do to the North Pole.
-- We don't even have snow.
I got snow today at the time. We're recording. So there's that I
good. Anyway. All right. All right. I'm gonna end this one because like, holy crap.
I don't want to go down this rabbit hole any farther.
Like, oh my goodness. I'm sorry, everyone. Merry Christmas, I think.
Um Thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening.
Go to
homes, our security podcast.com. We'll put our show notes in there.
You pound do says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day
-- and everyone have a Happy New Year.
Yeah.
Good luck. I hope your Christmas is not filled with A I horrors.
All right, thanks everyone. Bye bye.