Hello and welcome to episode 28 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
Kurt. How are you?
-- I'm excellent. It's like six above here. Celsius. Like
-- a crazy heat wave.
Yeah. Basically I went skiing without any mittens or gloves yesterday.
I've done that before,
but it's
pretty rare to say the least.
Yeah. So, no, it's nice.
So
today Rs A is coming up.
Oh, yes, it is. I can hardly wait.
Hopefully my head cold to be gone by then and we can freeze to death in San Francisco.
-- It'll be cold, man. Bring a coat. True.
-- Yeah. Well, it's, you know what it is?
Honestly, it's a damp cold. Right.
And I'm, I, I can handle, uh, dry cold, like, minus 30 dry. Sure, whatever.
But like, even like five
°C and damp and I'm like miserable.
You're insane.
I will take my, the damp five degrees over your minus 30
any day.
Uh,
it's, it's, you breathe it in and it just feels cold.
Uh Yeah. Yeah, it kind of does, but it's ok.
The, the Mosconi Center will be filled with people and it will be
-- so hot. We can't stand it.
-- It does get pretty funky
-- in
-- there.
It is, man. It's crazy.
And you end up with the,
the, the floor with all the,
the booths and all the craziness there and there's always
just strange smells and horrible noises and I mean,
it is what it is.
Right. It's,
it always reminds me of, I don't know
if you've ever lived in an apartment complex but in my younger days I did and
there's,
there's always somebody cooking something that it's like, how can they eat that?
It smells terrible.
And that's, that's the conference center, right?
-- I've decided I'm not shaking hands anymore at conferences. Oh, who
-- cares, man.
Whatever. Don't be a sissy.
I just, I keep picking up horrible,
horrible bugs and I get sick like a day or two after I get home.
If you don't shake hands, I will ensure you,
you gain some terrible incurable disease from the floor of the muscular.
Its
more likely than not,
you know, the way I kind of look at it is,
yeah, shaking hands probably transmit some level of disease.
But in all seriousness, just like just being there is probably as bad over
Mythbusters episode
when they did the shaking hands and myth like touching and stuff.
I recall this and shaking hands did transmit a significant amount of
because people touch their faces constantly. And I mean,
that's like the least scary thing people touch
Yeah,
like my one kid keeps scratching his butt.
-- I like
-- go
-- to the bathroom
-- and wash your hands.
I think we didn't need to say that
while he's young.
But, uh,
yeah. No.
Anyway, so Rs A so for those of you that don't know, both myself and Josh will be there.
And, uh,
so I'll be doing a talk with Kent Landfield of Intel on saving
CV E the common vulnerability and exposure database with the open source way.
Basically.
Now tell me,
are you focusing just on CV E or are you going to
work DWF into this or what's kind of your angle here?
Well,
that's so the DWF is basically was sort of one of
the catalysts of how we're going to save CV E.
Uh But in general, the whole model of CV E is
changing to a much more open collaborative model, right?
Because like when it started back in actually 1999
it was essentially run and all the work was done by Miter,
-- right?
-- And
Steve Christie,
all
of the work
who worked for me.
And yeah, he was, he was a workhorse, literally a workhorse. Um
You know, and
that was appropriate back then because quite frankly, you know,
we didn't have the buy in on CV E, you know,
um I remember there were competing standards like, you know,
bug track ID numbers and stuff like that.
Um
I think
nus nus I DS
and um so you know, basically miter kind of bootstrapped it
the good old fashioned way by, you know, doing all the work.
Um, which, and, and, you know, it's almost comical looking back like they, they,
for example, had a process where
a vulnerability would
-- start out as a candidate. A
-- CV N
and, and if it was, like, sufficiently bad
it would be voted on and become a real CV E
-- which, you
-- know, Pinocchio.
Well, exactly. And, and, you know,
now with the,
the volume of CV ES we have, that's,
it's just impossible, right?
Like CV E assignments have to take less than five minutes
because we have right now. Well, last year we broke 10,000 CV S,
right? Like, and there's a few more trickling out. So I think it's about 10,500 CV ES
last year,
you know, and, and if they take more than five minutes to assign each, that's,
that's a huge amount of time.
Um, and going forward. Well, and that's basically where, where we're going is.
So some of the big things we're gonna be doing
in the CV world is we're moving to a Federated model
of CV numbering authorities.
So kind of like DNS U of Miter as the root, you know, the catch all they control it.
And then you have these
essentially hierarchies.
So for example, the D, the DWF will be the open source hierarchy.
So like you're dealing with open source and you want to be a CV numbering authority,
you come to us and we make you AC N A
uh JP Cert, the Japanese cert is also going to be
a hierarchy, you know, for the Japanese software market which
you know, that deals with the language barrier, the time zone issue,
the cultural issues, all that, you know, boom problem solved.
They're dealing with the,
like the beauty is they're dealing with JP Cert who
is who they've been dealing with,
you know,
and
so we're going to see more of that, you know, for example,
we're looking at uh the medical device market, you know,
they're gonna need their own hierarchy with their own sort of
uh
flavor of CV E, you know,
they have slightly different requirements because they have
a lot of regulations covering what they do.
Now,
is there gonna be some special way to denote the difference between a miter
CV E and say ad WF CV E and a JP Cert CV E.
So that's a good question.
That's um so the provenance of the data is important because
different CNAs will have slightly different, you know, qualities and,
and reporting requirements and stuff.
So the open source world is a good example because quite frankly,
most of my CV S are really easy because,
you know,
here's the line of the code,
right?
So, you know, it's like,
I don't need a whole bunch of research and
proof because it's like here's the source code,
it's on github,
it's this line.
Oh yeah, that's totally a buffer overflow,
you know. So
other, you know, close source vendors, for example,
you have to maybe trust them a bit more.
And so there will be um
essentially blocks of CV S,
right? So
Miter
will essentially, well, ultimately,
Miter owns all the CV S and they've given the DWF, for example,
-- the block of 1 million to 1,999,990
-- nine.
Ok. Let's, uh, just in case someone doesn't know,
let's tell them what a CV E ID looks like.
So CV ID
historically looks like CV E hyphen year hyphen a four digit number starting at 0001
going all the way to 9999.
Obviously,
that was a problem because we needed more than 10,000 vulnerabilities here.
And so the format changed
and what we did simply to make it very backwards compatible is
0001 through 9999 are still a four digit number.
And then we go straight to a six digit number and larger. So for example,
-- um,
-- or, or just do infinity, right? I think people
understand how,
like there's, there's no end now.
And so the idea is we assign blocks and then, you know, sub CNAs will
have.
So for example, the DWF has a block of a million CV S and
for the sake of argument.
Yeah. Well, we might need more, but we got a lot of engineers
and then we can use the imaginary numbers.
And, you know, part of my goal is to make this a bit easier for people. So
my plan within the DWF is to assign essentially a static block.
So for the sake of argument, you know, open stack becomes a CV numbering authority
and I'll give them a block of, say
100 or 1000 or how many ever CV S they're typically gonna need in a year.
And part of that will be is it'll make a lot easier to search for stuff because you'll,
you know, kind of know what prefix to look for, kind of like a phone number, right?
Yeah.
And you know,
obviously blocks can be recovered if projects merge or go out of business as it were.
Um And you know, and that data will be kept
um but it will make life a bit simpler because also,
you know, the reality is when you give a block of numbers to somebody,
if you give it like currently the, the,
the way they do it is every year you get
like your blocks. And actually in past, you had to basically do it quarterly.
So you had to keep going back for more numbers.
Yeah. Or in red hat's case, I was going back to them like every month I was
gonna
say, I remember at one point
Steve was only willing to give us something like 10
or 20 at a time and literally twice a week,
I was begging for more.
I remember when I took over that job for you, I still,
I managed to get them up to 50 then 100. And I think the biggest we got to was 500.
I want to say,
um something like that.
And one thing so people may have noticed this year is
that the CV numbers miters assigning are starting in like,
I think it's the four or five thousands
because they essentially gave everybody a big block for the entire year,
which is totally the right thing to do.
I agree.
Well, and part of it too is, you know,
because we're not going to run out of numbers now because we fixed the CV
10-K problem. Right. And that was legitimate, you know, back in 99 right.
You know, I remember.
So I, I just looked here and in 1999 it looks like there were 894 CV E I DS,
which is,
I, I mean,
I guess for the year that that's a pretty
impressive number given in 1999 nobody cared about security.
-- For the most part,
-- we literally had like bug track and maybe
I
was gonna
say
full disclosure,
full disclosure was,
yeah. Yeah, full disclosure probably came out. It's been around a long time.
I feel like
I bet I subscribe to most of that stuff.
It would have been about 9495 and I started to care and I'm
pretty sure full disclosure has been around for most of that time.
I do know Bug Trek was
and there was even, oh
man, I can't even remember some of the other mailing lists. Now it was
uh
there was
a,
there, there were, there were a handful and, and none were great for the most part
closure archives go back to 2002.
Well, no, no,
that's the new full disclosure because remember there was
the old full disclosure that was shut down and then
somebody started up the new one.
Yeah,
Larry Rosen was the original one if memory serves
and he got sick of just being
like, treated very poorly, which I mean, I kind of get it right.
It's,
you're very much the messenger in that instance and there's not a
good answer to running a mailing list filled with zero day vulnerabilities.
Well, and this was back in the day too where, you know,
there was talk of suing and lots of, you know,
this is back when vulnerabilities were really, really scary.
And then we learned that, no,
this is just how life is.
You know, it's like car accidents there.
It's just a thing like the police don't even come to accidents now, unless it's,
you know, there's enough damage or people are hurt,
they're just like whatever you can report it online if it's under two grand now.
That's right. So, so tell me about your talk.
-- We're kind of getting, getting ourselves
-- into the weed here.
So we're gonna be talking about how we are
basically saving CV with the open source way.
And, um,
the biggest takeaway is we're gonna really teach
people what they can do to get involved,
you know, with respect to becoming a CV mentor
and, or becoming a CV numbering authority and how that whole process works.
And we've, I've greatly simplified it now like a
three
step process.
The CV E mentors exist yet.
-- I know you've been talking about it, but they don't
-- exist yet,
but they will hopefully in the next uh they'll start existing in the next week or two.
Nice. Very cool. And um so we have a list essentially of people who are
basically, it boils down to train to do two things. Number one,
is this a vulnerability? Yes or no.
And number two, how to assign the CV E counting rules to it?
Like how we,
because we actually sort of pragmatically smush some vulnerabilities together.
Like if you find a big pile of cross site scripting vulnerabilities
in one piece of software in the same version, then
there's no real value in having a lot of CV S just one will cover it, you know,
assuming they all get fixed in the same patch.
I remember,
you know,
and that's basically it. And then
the beauty is this will allow organizations to uh use a CV numbering authority
to either get a CV E number like when they need one or
to get the CV, mentor to sign off on the request
and then they can hold on to it.
And then when they actually want the CV number,
like say they wanted an hour before disclosure,
they can just submit that signed request. And essentially,
you know, we'll look at it and be like, yeah,
that's a properly signed request by Josh Pressers, for example, we trust them.
So boom, here's your CV,
right?
And that handles the uh the embargo issue because the one of the problems
with the signing CV S is when it's a public issue super easy,
right?
You ask for a CV, I give you the CV, I put the information in the database
done.
But what if you need an embargoed CV for an issue that's not
yet public and maybe won't be public for hours or days or weeks?
You know, I don't want to have to hold on to
secret information and like
-- make sure I don't disclose it until the right time.
-- So you're pushing this,
I guess responsibility
onto the mentor to sign off on.
Well, they don't have to keep the information around.
See, that's the beauty of it, right? They just sign the record
and then they can forget about it. It's not their problem anymore.
Interesting
because there's really no need for the CV mentor to keep that information,
right?
So they don't have to worry about holding and handling private information now.
Well, I mean, you say that, but when people send
information,
be it email or instant messaging or whatever,
it's often difficult to keep them secure.
Well, true.
So for example, if they use um well, one requirement will obviously be that,
you know, signed requests are well signed using GP G.
Uh which means of course, every CV mentor has to have a, you know, a working GP G key,
which means people can send them encrypted email and you can just
have the encrypted email sitting in your mailbox and reply to it
-- with a signed message. And you're done so very
-- simple,
very simple. Yes. As we
talked about how terrible P GP is what, three episodes ago?
It's, you know,
these are people who are somewhat hopefully security knowledgeable.
That's
-- probably
-- fair, you know, and this is
I, I can't really find a better way to do it, to be honest.
-- And I've thought about this quite a bit uh
-- signal. Yo
uh
the problem with signal is um what if I need to send you some sort of file artifact,
you can send files over signal, right?
But then the person now has that file artifact on their system.
So they'd have to encrypt it anyways to keep it secure.
-- Yes.
-- See, that's the problem.
No, but that's
nonsense. Because
if you send me an artifact with GP G, I'm going to have to decrypt it
somehow on disk
to do something with it. I mean, I know. Yeah. Yeah. There's things I can do without,
-- I
-- think into the details here.
It, but fundamentally, you know,
there has to be a simple secure communications channel
and here's the reality, everybody has email,
not everybody has a cell phone or more importantly,
like me is I'm definitely not giving my cell phone out to random people.
I used to be like that.
I've given up like my cell phone number at this point is like my email address.
It's not even hard to find
my cell phone number.
You know what that's asking for trouble. But
if you want to,
you can email me or message me on Twitter and I will give
it to you and then you can send me messages on signal,
for example.
And in fact, there was, I remember there was one time I saw a
support person
at a conference was talking about, you know,
how important it is to contact customers and stuff.
And
he, he put his cell phone number up on the, on the slide
and said this is my number and this guy is like a VP of, of customer support at this,
this place.
And he did that.
And then after like five minutes, he's like,
I have to turn my cellphone off now because
people kept calling him while he's on stage.
And that's,
it's that quality of life issue. Right.
I don't, I, I prefer to use my cell phone as little as possible for incoming calls
unless it's people I know.
-- And I like, but,
-- but here's the thing too is if I give it out too easily,
it would be
potentially someone could use it just to cause trouble.
But basically I,
if you want to get a hold of me and you go look for it and it's not hard to find,
then you have a purpose. So I'm less concerned in that instance.
So, well, it, it seems weaselly of me to say this and then not, not give it out on,
on the podcast.
There, there is a method to demand. So anyway, OK, so you're at CBE talk if I show up
and I say I wanna be a mentor at the end.
Mhm
Is it gonna happen?
Hopefully by then I'll have the website up and running.
Um But essentially to become a CV mentor, the absolute minimum
process is essentially you have to have a working email address,
you have to have a GP G key.
Uh that doesn't expire anytime soon. Like I don't want to deal with
all of them
ideally. Yeah, that'll work. Um
And then essentially you're gonna have to take
a little bit of training on essentially,
you know, by miters and CV E standards.
Is this a vulnerability? Yes or no?
Because quite often, some of these things are more security hardening.
So they don't, you know, they're security related
but they don't actually qualify for a CV E.
Um, there's some rules around sort of what is, and is not covered and how we do that,
you know, just sort of some housekeeping stuff and,
and the, uh, the CV,
counting rules around how we split and merge vulnerabilities to make sure that,
you know, the CV S are kind of applied correctly.
Um
And then, you know, a little bit of basic process where essentially,
well, basically the two ways you do CV assignments are you either
um assign them sort of in real time
and give the data, you know, back to the parent uh numbering authority
or you sign off on this request and give it to a person who can then, you know,
use that signed request to get a CV later on like when they need it.
And um
-- that's basically
-- it, that seems remarkably simple to do.
Yeah.
And the only other thing is so there,
there will be a public registry of these uh CV mentors and all it is is the, the name
and when I say name, the name they want to be known by,
like I don't care if it's Fluffy bunny 69.
Um I really don't
uh they have to have a uh like a primary
and a backup email address because like one thing I
run into is people use like their work email address
and then they move somewhere else like companies or whatever.
And then they're like, oh, it's me, trust me, it's me.
And I'm like, well, I can't really verify that.
So I, you know, they'll have to submit two email addresses which let's face it.
Everybody at this point has at least two emails, a work one and a private one.
Or you just set up a Gmail account again, I don't care.
I just, I want a way to reach you when your primary address goes bonkers.
Um optionally, they can also, you know,
I'll let them submit like their linkedin or
Facebook profile or whatever if they want.
Um
Because ironically that's something that like people never change.
Like once they set that up, they keep it for life
and then you have to submit a copy of your GP G key
and then there's a little bit of information on sort of whether or not,
yeah,
your public key obviously.
Uh And then there's a little bit of information to confirm that you've taken
uh the training on, you know, yes or no.
Is that a vulnerability uh how to do split and merge?
Uh whether or not you've agreed to like the terms of
use the contributors agreement and the uh the CN A guidelines.
So basically, you have to like, just agree to the rules,
you know, the community rules and whatnot.
Uh And that's the minimum and then also, for example,
some people will choose to uh also provide training.
So, you know, you might
um because there will be CV, mentors, for example, that don't do CV S,
they might just do the training primarily and train other CV mentors.
You know, that's, that's one of my personal goals.
I don't actually want to do CV, si just wanna create people who are CV mentors.
Um So optionally, there'll be people who are, you know,
trained on how to give the training and
they in turn will be able to help create CV mentors, right?
Because we got to scale this out.
Um So essentially, my goal is to make it look kind of like the Linux kernel, right?
You have subsystem maintainers who have their own little groups of people
that they know and trust and validate and
you know, stuff feeds up hill and well, you know, I trust Bob.
Bob, trust, Alice, Alice trusts Eve, therefore, Eve's OK.
This is sounding remarkably like the GP G web of trust, Kurt.
It
is except it's actually a small community. It's not some random group of
-- people.
-- That's true. It's not random.
You need
some level
and fundamentally like for CV, mentors to work, well,
we have to be able to find each other.
Like people have to be able to find you. It's true,
right?
Otherwise it's just not going to work.
Um And then optionally in the,
you can also declare sort of what your specialties or interests are.
So, for example,
you know, I know one guy who, like, he writes firewall or a VPN software,
so he's probably gonna specialize in like VPN and crypto because
especially when he asked for CV S, I'm kind of like, uh, those,
I recognize some of those words.
Sure. Here's your CV E
I,
you know, III, I don't want to spend six hours like rereading, applied crypto
to, you know.
Right. Right.
Understand what his email said in depth. You know, it's, it's a trust thing, right?
And fundamentally,
if a CV E assignment goes wrong, we just reject
it. And that's the most important part of this I think.
And this is something actually that, that Miter struggled with for a long time is
people are gonna make mistakes. It's never gonna be perfect.
And so you just make sure your system can deal
with mistakes which the old CBE system really couldn't do.
And you know, so, yeah, I mean, that's basically what it boils down to.
Um I'm also gonna talk a bit about where I'm currently working on the new,
uh I'm now on to the fourth version of the uh data format we're gonna be using.
Um, so we've iterated quite a few times and it's,
it's a good time for us to iterate because basically
nobody's using it except for Miter and uh Nist. So
you should take a bet
and say when Rs A 2018 rolls around. What version of the data set will you be on?
Well, we're going to do again back to what uh
Glynis did we,
well, back in the day we're going to do even a number.
So the event
4.0 will be like the stable stream
and then we'll have a 5.0 for experimental.
I bet you're going to be on version 10 in a year.
I my hope is to rapidly iterate and
the only time we'll actually have to bump from like version
4 to 6 is if we make an incompatible change.
So we either require something new that must be there or
we remove something that used to be required.
10,
here's the dirty secret
for Miter to accept a CV E
uh assignment from somebody.
They actually only require five pieces of information.
And that is the CV V number. Obviously, you have to have that
you have to have the vendor and the product like that's affected, right?
Sure.
What the problem type is like buffer overflow XSS, whatever.
Um
And I'm blanking on the fifth one. Wow, my brain just walked up completely.
It must not be important that
anyway.
So the point is, you know, this isn't rocket science.
No, it really isn't. So that, that's really cool. That's really fun.
The description of the vulnerable
description of course.
Yeah,
literally.
So
very exciting. And your, your file format is
JSON, which means it is
very
easy to
um the only catch being is uh you will want to or not want to,
you will have to also support Unicode because you know, like JP, sir,
those Japanese guys, they would like to use their language.
There's no reason not to do unicode these days.
I'm just gonna,
I
would
fully
-- agree. Now,
-- if you ever want to experience nailing your hand to the wall,
you should try doing unicode in Python two.
It is
the most ridiculous horrible process
ever.
Yeah.
And yeah, I mean, that's gonna be unfortunate for me because I mostly live in Python.
But, um,
realistically it's, it's, you know, it's text,
it's like strings of descriptions of the vulnerability and stuff.
It's, you know, again, it's really not rocket science.
-- I'm
-- going to turn myself into a new security researcher whose name is Snowman.
Snowman Airplane just to watch all of the various CV E
tracking applications fail when they try to parse my name.
Yeah. No, it's, it's gonna happen. Right. I mean,
I've often wondered, you know, how long,
well, there was actually the case of, there was a CV E
where in the description they put, um, an example of the regular expression
that caused the problem and it actually made, uh, one of the vendors CV systems,
like,
really choked hard on it and did not like
it.
I love it.
And that's the other thing to remember too. Right?
Is because we're going to have you know,
descriptions might have like an example of regular
expression or some mangled unicode or whatever.
Um And that's the other good news we're gonna have test data.
What
is that? I
know
we're literally, we're, uh it looks like right now,
what we're gonna do is set aside a block of CV S
and essentially we'll have a block of test CV ES that are like intentionally
slightly mangled like, but within the spec, right?
So they're like, man, like very, maybe a lot of nested data or a
-- whole bunch of like, yeah, poop emojis in the title or whatever.
-- I like what I hear.
Um And so essentially,
that'll be kind of like your for like unit testing and
stuff like essentially if you can parse all of those valid,
but you know, ugly CV S, then your system is probably gonna be OK.
And you know, ideally as we
find more, you know, cases where somebody submits a CV that makes the system break,
we'll add that to the test data.
And then there will additionally be sort of a set of reserve numbers
for like internal testing because part of it too is with CV,
we're, we're moving towards automation,
which means I'm going to want to test my system and generate a bunch of
CV S and then hand it over to your system and see what happens.
We
don't want to run the risk of maybe those weird CV S escaping into the wild as it were.
But if they do escape into the wild,
they'll be using numbers that are registered as being like, these are test CV S.
If you see them in the wild, ignore them. They're not real,
you know, because
people will need to, for example,
create CV s with like really high impact ratings to test that their CV E, you know,
munching system
sends out a phone alert saying, hey,
I just saw the CV with a really high rating that affects something we use.
Right.
-- Yeah,
-- and that makes sense.
Yeah.
And so essentially we'll have that testing ability which will help lead,
uh towards the automation stuff that we're working on.
You should, uh, use 19216811 as the first test CV E ID.
-- Uh,
-- we probably wanna use the 900,000 range.
-- Yeah,
-- that's, that's cool and make sure, don't forget to have a test CV ID.
That's like 30 digits long.
Uh, well, we already have those, uh, for the, the CV E
10-K stuff they issued like,
uh CV E, what was it like 11,000,
uh, like 123456.
I think some, you know, a couple, there's about 13 or 14 CV S like that,
that they issue,
you need to make sure one
exceeds the 32 bit integer maximum value
because, you know, something will break
and
maybe, maybe if you really want it to be exciting,
you could exceed the 64 bit integer value, but we'll, we'll let that one go probably.
Um, well, I actually have a plan for that.
That will scale better.
But, um, anyways,
so, yeah, we'll have, you know, long term,
uh, CV, is getting a lot more healthy.
We're making a lot of changes that needed to be changed.
I mean, one of the beautiful things is last year. I mean, they minted,
I think it was like a dozen new CN CV numbering authorities.
You know,
there's like a lot of new CV numbering authorities
like the Apache Foundation and heck even Larry Cash
dollar like Larry Cash,
-- Daler himself is a CV numbering authority. You know,
-- that's
human.
He's the only individually that is officially their own CNA I guess.
I mean, technically I quasi
am but not officially,
but no, he is like, he's the, he's a one man CN A literally.
And I mean,
he also holds the record for like one year
skewing the entire stats for the CV numbering system.
Uh
-- You know, he went through um what was it? Um
-- He did the, it was Jumla,
right.
Yeah. And well, and just other plugins and whatnot and just found
gazillions of
you gotta think.
Now I actually, I read a statistic the other day that, that N PM,
the node Js package manager has 40,000 packages in it.
Now,
you gotta think that is a bare minimum of 40,000 security issues.
Probably magnitudes more.
Well, yeah, same last time I
Ruby Gems, it was 54,000
and
was about 50,000 as well. Like, there's
a lot of software now. Like, that's just the reality of it.
A
lot of terrible software. Now, let's admit it. Most of it is awful.
And these people don't even know what security issues are now.
Mind you, I'm not blaming the people. It's not their fault.
They don't know, they just don't.
It's crazy.
And that's a good point.
Actually, this totally leads into what I'm talking about at RS A.
So I'm gonna steal your spotlight now because I can.
And so I'm doing a peer to peer session
on managing your open source.
And
the challenge here is the way I like to say it is open source one.
So literally, you are using open source in your organization,
you either know it
or you don't know.
And you are,
there's no like secret option three where you're not using
open source and that's basically accepted today in the universe.
At least everywhere I've gone, everyone I've talked to,
they understand that this is real.
But the problem now is if you have all this open source everywhere, you know,
in the instance of like N PM is a great example.
What are your developers using? Where are they getting this stuff from?
Is it any good? Can you trust it? Should you trust it?
And how are you gonna take care of it?
And this is true of there, there's kind of two sides to this discussion.
There's the developer side
which is obviously, you know, things like pulling stuff out of N PM, for example,
but there's also the operation side where you think there's
guys running Linux distributions where they get them from.
There are people using containers they found under the rug.
You've got people who might say, you know,
we need these 12 libraries to make this application work and they just
literally like type it into Google and download the first thing they find.
And
so part of the, the, the challenge for the security folks is like, what do we do now?
We've got all this crap everywhere. How do we start taking care of it?
And so the, the idea is it's meant to be a very discussion oriented session
where,
you know, come with ideas and we can discuss what works, what doesn't work,
kind of kind of how it's going.
And my job is to basically just keep the train on the tracks essentially.
So one thing I'm curious, have you found that cloud has impacted this?
Because I, I find with cloud, one of the biggest things is
people have realized, yeah, I'll go to my IT department and ask but if they say no,
I'm just gonna go do it anyways.
I
don't even think it's that man. I think like Dev
ops is
really changing the face of all of this. And
I know the discussion we've had in the past is it's pets versus cattle,
right? Where
it's difficult to shoot your dog.
If it's a cow, you're happy to, to turn that into a hamburger. And so
I, I think Dev
Ops is kind of seeing that where people are becoming less,
uh,
reliant on systems that are kind of carefully constructed and make
sense and it's moving to something that's a little more quick.
And I think the impact Cloud has from what I see is
if you do it right.
And I'm putting a huge asterisk next to that because most people aren't.
But if you do it right,
you can move quickly enough that you don't have
to worry about a lot of these security issues
as long as your developers are are doing the right thing,
stuff like when you rebuild a container you use,
make sure you're refreshing all of the software there.
It's not like, you know, you get cloned and forget about it. You can't do that.
You have to keep updating this stuff and
keep testing for changes that you care about.
So yeah, it's, it's crazy days, man. I mean,
uh where it ends up. I don't know.
And
there's scanning software that can help with some of this.
There's, there's various vendors that do some things,
-- there's people who manage software, speaking
-- of that,
uh you're familiar with Black
Doc,
I am
-- Uh So maybe you could explain to our listeners kind of what Black Duck is,
-- right?
So Black Duck is a software company
that actually they made their kind of claim to fame
was looking for open source software in your product.
Because again, this comes back to the manage open source.
There was once a day when including open source in
your application was seen as a dangerous thing to do
where you wanted to make sure there was
no open source in the product you were releasing
or if there was, it had to have a nice license.
Now, people like e don't care whatever full of open source I can live with it.
So now the challenge though, and this is what blackjack
is doing today is basically scanning the open source and saying
which bits of this open source are outdated and which bits of this are OK.
And they even have the granularity where they could tell you like individual CV E
I DS affecting a specific package that you might have included in your product.
So it can do some really cool stuff actually.
And so a nice piece of news there is Black Duck
has been nominated for membership on the CV E board.
Uh We're currently in the voting period
but so far everybody's been positive because
like quite clearly Black Duck are a sane people and B doing useful work.
Well, no, no, no, not everybody's saying that's something you, I mean,
for anybody who's in the security community you're
like shaking your head and you're going,
and everybody outside the security community is like, yeah, I hate them.
They're all insane.
Um,
yeah, I mean, they do good work and, um, yeah, so they're going to be on the CV board,
which I love because
one of the challenges is, you know, CV E usage has grown.
It's, it's, you know, become the de facto standard
and there's a lot of stuff going on that, you know,
wasn't planned in 99 or even in 2010 or even last year.
You know, and it's
a
funny story for you.
There is you talk about CV E usage is the standard now and I remember in probably 0506,
give or take,
there were open source projects I would work with
that didn't understand why they should worry about CV E I DS
and well, no, no, I mean, large ones, we'll say, ok, like
I'm not going to throw them under the bus,
but everybody knows the name of some of these organizations, right?
And I remember it reached a point where I'm like, look, you guys don't have to care,
but I'm assigning I DS.
All right.
And we came to the mutual agreement of they didn't want them,
but they were getting them anyway.
And of course, for the most part, people all all understand this now.
But yeah, I mean, I, I remember that man, it was
still,
is the case with some vendors, they really don't want CV S because they,
they think CV S are, you know, a negative reflection on them.
And part of the model we're gonna be moving to is, you know, the simple question is,
do you
want as a consumer software,
do you want people to have CV S assigned to
all their vulnerabilities whether they like it or not?
And resoundingly the answer I've heard is yes.
And that's gonna be one of the things we're looking at how to do,
you know,
well and properly for the CV, whole ecosystem.
You know, how do we make sure we have coverage especially, you know,
true today though, you can get a CV ID assigned to a piece of software,
-- whether the vendor wants it
-- or not, but we want to make it easier
and like,
yeah, that's fair,
you know.
Um
Yeah, because right now what'll happen, you know,
is we'll go to the vendor and if they dispute it, then it becomes a huge problem,
right? It's a very heavy process,
right? And we, you know,
the reality is we're gonna be dealing with internet of things, vendors who really,
really don't want CV S assigned to their products.
That's probably fair.
I could see that.
Um And, you know, again, one of my long term goals is to turn CV,
the perception of a CV in a product from something negative
to something positive and that will, you know, one thing we'll need is more data,
right?
So when was this, you know, when did this CV come out? When did the vendor fix it?
Oh, wait, you know, the vendor found it and fixed it.
That's good. That means the vendor has a security process and is auditing code,
you know, so this is like a positive CV, you know, they're proactively fixing stuff,
you know, versus the vendors that have CV S that are still unfixed 10 years later,
you know, or maybe it's just a CV, that doesn't really matter and that's OK.
-- You
-- know,
it's a theoretical attack or whatever,
you know, like a lot of stuff say the lens kernel, like we just,
we give out CV S like candy,
we don't require people to prove that these things are
exploitable because some of them are really difficult to prove.
Like you need special hardware, you need,
I've seen cases where you have to like build a kernel module
to make the kernel more exploitable to hit the race condition.
Yeah, I've, I've seen that as well.
But on the other side of things, you also have instances where in the kernel,
we would say this isn't a security issue because at the time it wasn't.
But now with technologies like user name spaces,
you've opened up certain code paths to non route users who are
pretending to be root.
And historically, it was said, well, if you can't trust root, you're screwed.
So, who cares?
So, it's, these are some crazy issues
-- to think about
-- and that's part of what's also changing is, you know,
what is a security issue?
Right? It used to be encryption is a great example. Right? Des used to be secure.
Des is no longer Secure Des 56 bit can be cracked
-- in real time
-- on a phone if you're using it,
-- like that's clearly a security issue,
-- you know, same thing with like MD five, right?
And I remember when 20 years ago MD five was totally fine.
And then some guy I forget who it was. I want to say
an Italian research group with a bunch of,
what was it? Um PS twos or something
with the cell chips. And anyways, they, they made this like crazy board
thing of like 100 or 200 PS twos
and generated a valid
MD five collision for a
SSL certificate. So it wasn't just like here's an MD five collision. Ok.
That's cool. It was, here's an MD five collision for a valid SSL certificate,
ok. We have to stop using MD five for these things.
Um The same thing with Sha one now,
-- one years
-- later we
did.
-- Yeah,
-- and sha one is now being slowly but surely phased out, you know, it's now
January, the browsers like Chrome and stuff and Firefox are,
are no longer trusting Sha One certificates
um
like the root certificates, the end certificate on the server can still be sha one.
Um, but, you know, as time goes on that's going to be phased down, I believe,
I think Google said, like 2019 or something is when they're just like, you,
you better be off of sha one.
And that's fantastic because we actually have time to do this. Right.
-- Instead of it being lit on fire. Holy crap. Do it now.
-- Yeah, exactly.
Um, and so for example, like right now if you're using DES in like any way,
shape or form in software,
that's the seat like you, you're wrong. I'm sorry, but that's wrong.
You cannot use DES anymore.
Same thing with like three does, three does is just not strong enough.
Same thing with MD five for say password storage. It's just not strong enough
with
Rainbow,
you can crack it in like minutes.
Now, the thing though that,
that can get interesting and I'm going to pick on MD five
here because I've been dealing with some MD five things lately is
when you back up data into Amazon S3,
they use MD five as a check
zone,
but it's not security related, right?
However, however, you know,
there's some ridiculous standard out there somewhere that says,
like you must never use MD five under any circumstances.
-- And, and S3 probably is a problem for them because
-- a
good example. So like AC RC checks some say on data sent over a modem
is not making a security claim.
It's, it's essentially making an effort to like,
-- make sure if your data gets mangled, it gets noticed easily and
-- it's fast.
Right.
That's, that's the reason they're using like MD five is not because it's secure,
but because they can calculate it really freaking quickly.
And so, for example, that's,
that's a good example where if MD five is
either being used in some sort of security claim,
like, oh, we, you know,
use MD five to secure your data from,
you know, like
Excel certificates, right?
To prevent them from being monkeyed with after they've been signed.
Uh That's a problem or if you're using MD five implicitly
in some sort of security operation like say storing a password,
you know, you're essentially making the claim that this is secure from cracking,
right?
That's a problem.
But if you're using MD five as yeah, as a check sum for data, like on your say,
yeah, S3 buckets or whatever,
as long as you're not making a security claim that says like this will, you know,
make sure that the data is completely valid.
That's OK.
Now,
if you were using that MD five signature and then signing it cryptographically,
now you're implicitly making a security claim saying
that this MD five sum is really,
really like correct
can't be faked. So we're signing it.
Now you have a problem
and then like long term, essentially,
you know,
MD five will
generally, you use MD five,
you get a CV E unless it's like some
specific case where it's definitely not a security issue.
-- Do we, do you do that today for MD five?
-- Not yet.
Well, we, for example, for password storage, you win a CV, automatically
because just with Rainbow tables, you can crack that stuff in like minutes.
The rainbow MD five tables are only several, I think, tens of terabytes, which
there's,
I mean, there's a bunch of stuff
-- even
-- with the salt, you can still, like, you can rent time on Amazon.
There's a guy doing real time. Um,
uh, it's the windows password cracking, you know, the network credentials
and he's, you know, it's, I think it's like 50 bucks and he guarantees you,
he'll spit out an answer in like less than half an
hour and he's just got a giant pile of rainbow tables
and then, you know, like
they rent time on Amazon GP U systems and voila,
you know,
like, yeah, you need 10,000 servers to crack this thing in half an hour.
Well, you can do that now with Amazon,
you know, like we discussed in the Santa episode.
Right. Totally doable
and
more to the point, not only doable, it's cost effective. That's,
that's a big bugaboo,
you know.
That's true.
I suppose if you have a password cracking service like that,
you just power down all the gear when you're not using it and then
when you need it just room away.
-- We go
-- and you just, and you can also use the spot instance market.
So you're not even paying the full rate.
That's true. You can get for
one server dies, just
start it with the data.
So
the, yeah, so the bar of what is and is not A CV is constantly moving and,
and one thing I do want to do long term is have us more carefully document it
because, you know,
obviously that'll make life easier and less subjective for everybody.
Um But, you know, that's one of those things on the to do list for long term.
Um
But as these things change, you know, I'm, I'm guessing at some point, you know,
we might
quantum cryptography becomes a thing and like
we have to like literally declare every existing
encryption algorithm like, yep, nope, don't do that,
man. That would be
the greatest day ever. Can you imagine the work that's gonna be involved
and,
well, but in all seriousness, I mean, this,
it, it's all super related, which I think is really funny about that because we,
we come back to thinking about managing your software then and
like, do you know if you have a product,
do you know what the encryption algorithms being used in your product are?
-- Well, and which ones are actually enabled?
-- Right. Exactly. It's
rights
-- are they're using open SSL which supports
-- everything.
It supports a million things. Exactly.
You know, and it has to right,
because somebody has to interact with an old system somewhere doing MD five.
So open SSL, the library must support all these old algorithms and,
and that's going to have to continue.
But I mean, is your software actually using it or?
Right.
It's, these are crazy problems and this is what people have to start thinking about.
It's not going to go away and if anything, it's going to get worse
because
you see that
email recently about, um, it's essentially a, an effort around
long term Linux kernel support. And when I say long term
they're talking time frames of 50 to 100 years.
Who is? No, I haven't seen that. I mean,
it was for industrial devices, drilling, like,
think about it.
There are people with sensor packages on the end
of drill bits that are like probably running Linux now
everyone's running Linux
open
source one,
it is everywhere
you have, like for example, a pump
running, you know, an oil pipeline, you're not going to be replaced.
Like there are, I know, um, some of the water systems in the US,
they have pumps and valves that are from the late 18 hundreds, unfortunately,
you know,
and you know, like I remember what was it that really big?
Uh, I think it was for Boston, they built that really huge new water pipe.
It was like tens of miles of New York. Yeah, that's the one
because the old ones from like 1875.
Yeah, the original valves and they're, like,
afraid to turn them more than a few degrees.
So, because they're all rusty.
And anyways, yeah, the point being is you think that,
that tunnels that they're building and the pumps that they're installing?
I'm assuming they're planning to have those run and be there for 50 to 100 years.
You know what I am sensitive to this topic.
And in fact, I just had a call with a partner yesterday. It was
where we were discussing exactly this problem
and it
is, there isn't a good answer today.
But I can tell you now that when you start thinking about technology and,
and this was one of the things that came up is
you can like, like we'll use a car as an example. So, in an automobile
it is, I mean, there's 100 year old cars that still run. Right.
But technology specifically, electronics
don't last for 100 years.
Right.
And so they, they don't, they just don't, like, that's the reality of it.
If you have a pump with a computer attached to it,
you're going to have to have the board on the computer
be easily replaceable.
And so what you don't need a kernel that can last 100 years,
what you need is to build your stuff so
you can easily field to replace those electronics and
potentially upgrade them in the process. Like that's the only real solution
stuff is not really field replaceable, easily,
like undersea cables or undersea pipeline.
It isn't today and it also doesn't have a computer on it in some instances.
But if they want it to last for 50 years or 25 years or 100 years,
you're going to have to make it field repairable because electronic components,
especially the kind of stuff we're talking, that's like,
literally like lowest bidder wins.
Let's build it now, sort of stuff.
It's just not gonna last 50 years. Right. That's the reality of it.
I mean, certainly at the price point that they're probably willing to pay.
I mean, these are not spacecraft where you really, you know, you,
you send it up and it's, well,
I think the Hubble spacecraft is really the
only thing we've ever fixed in outer space
-- and the ISS, of course.
-- But do you, if you've ever, I shouldn't say ever
look at the kind of gear they put into the space equipment,
it's not like off the shelf stuff they put in very specialized equipment. And
that's the thing, right? Is, it's even a specialized equipment.
It's, it has very understood life spans. And, yeah, a lot of it outlasted.
I mean, you gotta think like those Mars rovers were really
like, what a couple of months was their goal.
And now, I mean, it's like 10 years and they're, they're like,
they're limping along.
Thank goodness.
But, but even then, like, they're upgrading this gear in space, right?
They send updates to the software as it's.
But additionally, this stuff is operating in nonhostile environments
because you, you don't have to worry about bad guys attacking your rover on Mars
now.
And this is something I think about actually is I've
heard before that like the communications between the rover and,
and NASA are like unauthenticated and unencrypted in every way.
Now in their instance,
you need probably a several million dollar satellite dish to communicate with,
with the rover, which
the barrier of entry is fairly high. But like you gotta think, man,
if it was possible for random people to connect to
and mess with that rover, they totally would
you
like
exactly. You'd have a giant picture of, of genitalia
on the service of Mars
for all
time.
This leads to a because right now spacecraft are one of the few
places where they people have traditionally always had to deal with really,
really tight energy budgets, right?
We just don't have a lot of electricity
to run the stuff, right?
Because something like the Voyager probe, you know,
it's so far away from the sun now, even with big solar panels,
it's just not getting much light and power
uses plutonium.
-- It doesn't have solar panels.
-- Oh,
-- that's right. Yeah. They use a plutonium nuclear
-- pile
and it's supposed to die here in a couple of years. They figure it won't have enough
juice left to power anything.
But, and that's going to become more of an issue for as we deploy
electronics more and more remotely.
I mean, solar panel is uh solar power is definitely one option, you know, but
for example, stuff that's in the ground or under water,
you know,
how are we going to power that, you know, like batteries
ignoring the power considerations. How do you take care of it?
How do you, I mean, let's face it, it's gonna run Linux,
it's going to be full of open source.
How are you gonna, what, what does it mean? How are you going to secure this stuff?
How are you going to keep track of what you're running?
Like these are crazy problems.
Well,
and what I was trying to get at was though is you
have to make these tradeoffs between energy budget and say doing encryption,
-- right? Encryption will cost more electricity. Is it worth it?
-- Exactly.
That that's a really good point actually.
Is this kind of stuff needs to be taken into account? You're absolutely correct.
So,
yeah, I mean,
the good news is we're doing a lot more encryption on chip instead of in software.
So it's super,
super like uh what is it those intel chips with the Aes on board can do like
10 or more gigabits per second of
now? AES is an easy protocol.
What happens when we have something doing, say RS A or a more complicated algorithm?
And we find out that the silicone has a bug.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, you can, you can patch some of it.
I mean, in fact there's micro code and even,
like the Linux kernel can work around certain CPU issues.
Do you remember the competition around A
-- s though? Back in the day? About 1015 years ago?
-- Yeah.
And they, they do, they're doing sha
three. Well, I think
three, just one, didn't it?
I remember because there were five serious contenders finalists, uh, for a, as, uh,
there was rain.
All the Dutch one which is what was chosen as a s there was Mars from IBM,
which was essentially like a really upgraded uh des,
which was my actual personal favorite because it was
understandable and well known, you know. So,
um, but,
you know, one of the reasons why they didn't go with Mars if memory serves,
I have no idea.
Took too many gates to implement in silicon.
That is a valid concern.
Yeah, because they're like,
this needs to go into ATM S and 10 years ago ATM S were not running like, you know,
full P CS.
They were actually running, you know, specialist,
uh, chips and stuff 1015 years ago
now. Of course. Yeah, they're just a windows PC on a board,
right?
Or whatever. But, you know,
and so that was a vow thing like, uh smart cards, right?
Smart cards need to do crypto and gate count is a real issue there and that still is.
Yeah. And so Rain doll one because it was actually implement
and not,
it was actually surprisingly few gates.
Um I think it was in the tens of thousands. Uh We'll have to check that.
It's probably on Wikipedia somewhere. But so the, the reality is like NIST,
the, that's the National Institute of Standards and Technology is, uh you know,
the,
the people handling these competitions and essentially picking the finalist,
the winner.
You know,
they're smart enough to understand these prompts because
they've been dealing with it for 2030 years.
So the good news is we have some really competent people doing it
and they
got the group that's working on
TLS 13 as well, aren't they?
Which, uh, you know,
it's gonna have perfect forward secrecy by default. So,
yeah, it'll be pretty good.
It's got a lot going for it.
The, the challenge with that actually is going to be when TLS 13 comes out. It is.
I bet everyone's going to want to turn off one too
-- and it takes time to get this stuff deployed.
-- Well, yes and no, it used to.
But now you can outsource that to say somebody like cloud flare or Amazon, you know,
like their elastic load balancers.
And chances are you want to outsource some of this
stuff because do you want to do certificate management?
Not necessarily, do you want to
be responsible for properly configuring a TLS end point
that's public facing or more to the point.
-- Remember we were talking about denial of service attacks. Right.
-- Yeah.
Yeah, that, that's a good point actually. That's, that's very fair.
And this is one of the things I've been thinking about and
I'm hesitant to make any claims one way or the other,
but the world is a different place today
and when TLS 13 comes out,
I am
expecting its uptake to be very different from
the TLS versions that have come before it
and, and I, I think it'll be faster, but don't, don't quote me on that one.
Well, for example, Clown Flare uh already does TLS 1.3.
Well, good for them,
you know, so like,
um I think they're already doing it. I think you have to be on a business account.
I forget.
Uh but anyways point being, you know,
if somebody like cloud flare turns it on for
everybody that's like 30% of the internet traffic apparently,
or Netflix or Amazon web services deploy or imagine
if like Google Amazon and Microsoft and say the next
10 big cloud providers all deploy TLS version
-- 1.3 on all their stuff that's public
-- facing.
And that would be
like 90% of the internet
immediately. Exactly.
Which, which is cool and that's the way it should be. I think it is,
this is the world we live in
and this is the world open source built is things are fast now, they're so fast.
Also, there's an advantage to TLS, 1.3 is it is faster for connections than TLS 1.2.
That's true. There's,
yep. Yep,
which is awesome.
Of course,
until researchers find some terrible problem with that and the
solution will be to add the extra round trip,
but especially on like mobile, you know, removing a round trip from a connection.
I mean, that's a significant thing in mobile, you know,
for battery consumption for latency, for everything, you know,
that actually makes a real difference.
And so I suspect because of that, that as well will, you know,
to put it bluntly TLS 1.3 is better, it's faster, it's stronger, it's smarter,
you know,
it's like that's how we're, you know,
that's why HTTP S adoption finally got really driven forward is Google was like,
-- well, if you do http S you get better search rankings, that's it,
-- which is awesome.
Yeah,
you know, so
people have a huge economic incentive to adopt http
S now like to improve their search engine rankings,
which is awesome.
Actually, there was somebody had a tweet the other day that was like security.
People use TLS because it's better business. Uh and
then Google says use TLS because it'll get
you better search rankings and business goes,
we must have TLS now
which, but at the same time, like so I get this and this is,
this is one of the other things that, that comes up a lot in fact,
I'm gonna do a Birds of a feather of this at RS
A is a fact that how do we justify spending money on security
because
we kind of suck at it. And that's a topic for another day. I'm not gonna get into it now.
But obviously,
as security people, we struggle to show why this matters.
But obviously, when Google says,
right, when Google says, if you turn this on something good happen to you, now,
all of a sudden there's like actual reasons to do it
and
we'll have to talk about the economics of security at some point,
which I guess we kind of Sprinkle in here and there.
But
it's been,
yeah, we've, we've drugged this on long enough. I think it.
So if folks, if you're gonna be at RS A by all means,
let us know we'd love to have a drink or say hi or, or hang out or whatnot.
And obviously, you know how to reach us on Twitter.
You can go to open source security podcast.com and we've got links to,
we'll put links to our RS A sessions there.
I know there's really not a lot of show notes for this week,
but we've got uh links to Twitter as well.
The, the Pound Os S podcast hashtag can be used to get a hold of us.
Uh
Yeah, I don't, I don't have a lot else to say, I guess. Just,
yeah, let's look forward to Rs A. It should be exciting and fun as it always is.
And Kurt,
if nothing else, you have a fantastic day.
You too.
All right, folks. Until next time. Thank you and take care.