Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in writing bad code.
Josh
Reser.
Yes. And I don't mean I don't know about that intro for today. We have a guest today.
Actually, we have
Jill
Monet Correo, Director of product Security Engineering Response at
github, which I guess is kind of a fancy way of saying you run the github bug bounty.
So, Jill, welcome to the show. We're really excited for you to be here.
-- Thank you so much for having me. I'm excited to be here.
-- Fantastic.
So, so tell us, tell us what you do
and, and kind of what's going on.
So I guess the short version is I organize chaos.
Um But
what I really do is I manage the teams,
the product security incident response team as well as our bug bounty in that,
just like I said, organizing chaos. It's a,
it was a fun time
doing what I do
setting the stage for everyone.
Kurt and I spent a very long time at Red Hat doing product security work.
I mean, this was back before it even had a name.
I remember we what do we call it originally? It wasn't product security, it was
security response,
whatever doesn't matter, doesn't matter a long time ago.
So we're very excited for you to be here
and, and I guess I want to start out with the bug bunny because
Github has a pretty big bug bunny.
And I would just love you to explain
what is a bug bunny because we're gonna have people
listening that think they know what a bug bunny is.
But I think as anyone who's ever managed a bug bunny,
what we think it is and what it really is are two very different things generally.
Very true.
Um So a bug bounty is an open forum for
folks of all abilities to report vulnerabilities to a company.
So for us, we are looking for
any and all walks of life to send us a report in on
something that they think doesn't quite fit their expectation of our product.
Whether that ends up being a valid report or not, we'll
interact with that person, coach them maybe in the right way to get a valid report.
And then at the end, we'll reward you with some money,
maybe some new fun non monetary rewards that we're launching soon
in the case where it's not a valid report.
We'll go ahead and coach you for the next time.
-- That
-- is definitely not something we really did when we were at Red Hat.
When you say coaching. No, I'm actually really intrigued now. So
in,
because again,
my traditional view of bug bounties and eating security reports is like,
that's not about go away.
I have work to do. So, you're talking about coaching them.
So, what does that involve?
Yeah.
So especially in the last few years with the state of the world, we've seen a lot of
folks coming to
bug bounty to kind of test their skills, test the waters.
So we see a lot of folks who are reporting their
first vulnerability in that
we might get a report that doesn't quite meet our scope,
even though we have a pretty broad scope, pretty much no holds barred there.
But if they don't meet the scope or if they're
kind of going down the path and maybe we can give them some documentation to
push them further so that they're able to be successful
and then we can celebrate their first win with them.
We want to see people be successful. We want to keep the doors open.
We want you to report your first vulnerability to us.
We think it's so special to have that community
come to us and report things.
All right, Jill,
I'm going to ask you to clarify what you mean by scope because there's a link,
I'll put a link in the show notes, you have a scope on the website,
but I would like you to explain that.
Yes. So for anyone who has not participated in a bug bounty. It
is not free and open fields on every product.
Every bug bounty has some bounds, there is a little bit of a fence to keep the cows in.
You want to,
you check that out for each individual product. So for us,
uh, we want you to focus in
on our heavy hitters. So
github.com,
come on and take a look if you're
seeing repo permissions or something that just doesn't
smell right spidey sense. However you want to equate it to you.
Um, go ahead and look at our scope,
see if it falls within the bounds and then send it over.
Now,
like I said, we want you to report your first vulnerability to us. So
even if you're not sure send it over, there's no
harm in sending it over to us.
I noticed you explicitly have a like a safe harbor.
I don't want to say agreement necessarily like, because I guess,
well, it's not really a click through, but it's just you've stated that, you know,
basically boils down to
you're not going to sue them if they report security flaws to you. Which
as we, I we did this years ago with the auto industry announcing that we're like,
that is actually a massive step forward for large companies to officially say that.
Yeah, and we, we do have to reiterate it at times,
but we do want to make sure that everyone is aware of that case.
And,
you know, just
be a good human report, things be actively involved in the community.
So, one thing I'm curious about is I'm actually just looking at your bug
man results.
Number one,
I love that your top leader board person has tried
to put a javascript um escape into his user.
But one thing I'm curious about is so
a lot of the bug reports are undisclosed. And
like, I guess one thing I've noticed is like we have, there tends to be, I find,
especially in the web space weirdly not so much the software space,
but in the web space,
like there'll be
like trends, I guess would be the word I'm looking for. Like somebody reports a bug
and then like six more people report the exact same bug. And it's kind of like,
like, is it the same person, like what is going on? Right. And
I'm wondering, do you, does github
also see that
-- we
-- do, um usually the trends that we see tend to be the same
hacker or researcher pulling on the same thread. Now,
sometimes if they're a little more involved in the community,
they're actively participating or engaging with other researchers,
we'll see a group of them kind of hit the same spot because,
you know, they're chatting in whatever forum saying, hey,
yeah, I found something here.
They may team up together,
uh they may individually attack and at times, you know,
that causes collisions where they may report the same thing, duplicate reports.
But for the most part,
usually it's one individual researcher pulling on the,
-- the same thread. All right.
-- So
you just said something,
I think that not everyone recognizes or I guess understands about
bug bunnies is when two researchers report the same thing,
what happens in that situation.
-- It really
-- depends, it depends on the program.
It depends on the team that's managing it.
Usually,
if there's a duplicate report with a mitigation or a fix in play at that point,
we will inform you that, hey, this is a
duplicate report.
We're already engaged in a fix, engaged in the response activity.
Um So it may not
qualify at that point for a reward. We may give you a thank you reward.
We're quite known to be generous in that regard of, hey, thanks, we appreciate it.
And then on the other end, if it's before we've even gotten a chance to
maybe triage validate the vulnerability to
start a mitigation at that point, we may duplicate the report
and then go ahead and reward both parties for what it is.
And, and I guess we should also clarify,
you use hacker one to manage your bug bounty program, right?
Yes,
we originally did not. We started doing it homegrown and then a few
years back, we went ahead and joined the hacker one platform.
I just,
I can't even imagine like the tax implications of trying to pay people and like,
do you even know where they are half the time, right?
-- And I just, yeah,
-- I actually have some experience with that. Um So before I joined
github, I was part of starting up the Apple Bug Bounty.
I was on the team that maintained that
and we did that homegrown and
that was definitely a struggle of tax and
all that craziness.
OK? I want, I want to clarify what this means because
I also went through this, I started the bug bunny program at Elastic and
every that I feel like there's this bug bunny journey,
you could document of this like just sinusoidal wave of ups and downs.
And one of the stages is always we could do this ourselves.
But when you are a United States company,
there are places you necessarily can't engage
with people
and send them money.
For example, like there's,
there's a list of countries that are banned and so explain kind of that piece of
it because you've obviously participated in two huge
bug monies and started one up and,
and
I don't think everyone recognizes
just kind of the legal implications of paying people.
Yeah, I mean, I'm no lawyer, so I'm not going to go too far into that topic.
If you're getting legal advice from this podcast, we have
bigger problems
in that case. It really kind of depends on
world events, a company's feelings, it's very individual, you know,
it may be restricted to the country and what's going on at the time.
But,
you know, we,
at least in my experience we do our best to reward people for what they're finding.
Well, I think one thing people forget is
there's a big difference between running like a bug bounty for a website
that whatever, you know, gets 10 or 100 reports a year
versus something like what, you know, github
or Red Hat or Apple are doing because, and so just for context, uh again,
because I was like Google stalking your bug band program
and you know, your total payouts are over $3 million.
Like, you know, there's,
and I'm looking at the page of like listing all the payouts for like the last,
you know, 23 months. It's a, it's a lot of reports and
I,
I guess one of my questions is how do we get across to people that like,
it's different at scale,
right? There's a big difference between 10, 100 and 1000 a year.
And like, because I, I'm assuming that github
is, you're in the roughly 100 to 1000 category for bug,
you know, which
like, how do you do that? Like, like team wise and process wise?
What, what do you do to make that work?
Yeah. So we take a very human approach to it.
We know that there are bounds to what we're able to do within a work day, work week,
et cetera.
And we just
take empathy into factor which is,
there's a human on the other side of the screen and
we're also a human on this side of the screen.
So the best that we can do is communicate and say,
hey, we're running behind or hey, we are looking at this or,
you know, in the times of the holidays,
we're taking some time to regenerate and let us
get back to you when we can. Here's a realistic time frame for us to get back to you.
You know, obviously
there's someone in every communication that doesn't feel
great about that situation and we just try and
manage expectations as best as possible.
Oh, I remember these conversations.
It's always a treat but, but no, I do agree with you.
I think the human angle is hugely important and I feel like
the hacker, one community
has done a nice job of fostering that attitude amongst the hackers, which is great.
I, I give them a lot of credit for that. So, so let me, let me ask you, you manage a bug
but you also handle product security.
So what is your kind of weighted average of, of percentage coming of, of,
I guess work coming in by, by a bug bounty versus
internal discovery and, and fixing? And I'm, I'm, I'd love to know,
-- I don't have a good percentage on that. You can
-- guess wildly we're fine with that.
It's a, it's a good,
I would say for the product security incident response team,
we are seeing a lot of bounty reports as
well as internal reports and probably around 5050.
Wow, that's awesome. I mean, that means you have a pretty solid team.
That means which is cool.
So, ok, this, I want to now lead this into the inevitable discussion
that comes up when bug bounties and product security
are kind of tied together
is
I often hear
people in public that
are claiming a bug bounty can be your product security.
You don't need an internal team necessarily doing this sort of work.
Whereas we can we have a bug bounty we're covered.
I would love to hear your hot take on that
-- as
-- someone who has homegrown the bug bounty team here at
github actual physical team, we started that about two years ago at this point.
And so we were managing it through our product security team and it was working.
But for any program to mature, I think having dedicated resources is people who
understand the workflow and don't have to split their time or feel guilty that
something takes more priority.
It allows us to lean into that human aspect as well is getting people who truly care
about our program.
I've got one report who I always say is the golden retriever of our team.
He loves everything bounty
and he is wonderful and it shows in the work that he does
and having someone have to split their time.
You see things where there are difficulties in communication,
people get frustrated with the program, slow response times.
So I think it's really important to have those dedicated resources.
And also one thing you just mentioned that
I've never considered about hacker one was that
like,
not only are you getting them to deal with
the hassles of like taxes and payments and like,
like, because I, I've done cross border payments and with some countries,
it's just, it's ridiculous.
I don't understand.
You'd mentioned that essentially
between
like github,
actively coaching the people that come to github,
but in general, hacker one also fostering that community and sort of, well,
it sounds like kind of teaching them how to behave and how to be,
I
don't want to say responsible, not the word responsible, but maybe effective.
And like that, that seems to be,
I think maybe one thing that I've been missing in the value of hacker one and,
and the maturity piece of bug bounties in general
because again, at scale, right, you're not dealing with one or two reports,
you're dealing with hundreds.
And so I'm curious, like,
have you seen the industry mature or the researchers mature?
I should say,
definitely over my time, I've seen the researchers mature.
I think one thing that was really impactful for our team in this last year is
we did our first solo focused live hacking event with hacker one back in June.
And so we got to
hang out with our researchers see how they interact with other researchers.
And you saw these friendships form this elevation of reports, people showing, hey,
you know,
I always submit a video proof of concept versus
someone who may be extremely detailed in their writing.
And then you see those researchers band together and
create this wonderful report which is magical for us.
You know,
anything that can shave some time off the
top by communicating more effectively is great.
So
I think events like that events like hacker 1702,
the Vegas event where there's multiple customers as the target.
-- It just brings that community together and fosters better
-- work.
I'm going to ask you to explain what a live hacking event
is like because I have attended live hacking events from hacker one
and they are
incredibly interesting and just intense and amazing.
And my favorite
is every time they're like, oh, well, you should go meet the, the
the employees in the,
in the war room and you open the door and they just look at you with like get out now.
They're so busy and it's, it's so cool.
So please like, I would love it if you could explain more for the people who have no,
no idea what that even means.
Yeah.
So a live hacking event is a group of folks that are dedicated towards invited,
right?
Yes, this was an invite only event.
So invitation for our researchers to come join us in person
or remotely because that's our world now.
And so we met up in Austin, but the two weeks before we opened the floodgates, we said,
hey, start hacking on our product.
And so we started getting a flood of reports in.
And thankfully,
we had a little bit of a blocker of a day where we
could travel into Austin and not feel like we were running behind.
But the team hit the ground running.
We went into a ballroom and we're all furiously, you know, hoods up, heads down,
hacking away at
what everyone was sending us in. And then as you mentioned, it just got chaos.
I mean, it, you got a lot of reports in our case,
a small team and we were just trying to get through
everything and make sure that the day of the event,
we were able to
adjudicate everything,
get everything a number to it so that the leader boards were accurate.
Now at these events,
there's a leader board that shows how much money you're
getting reputation points in the case of hacker one.
And at the end, we're able to
give a rating.
So most valuable hacker, some other rewards, uh, best report, things like that,
I think covered most of the event without going too rambling on it.
Well, and,
and I want to clarify because this is the thing that I think was most bizarre to me
is there are two groups,
there are the hackers and there are your people doing the triage work
and they're not necessarily talking to each other,
but they're both physically present at the event, which I, I find amazing.
Yeah.
So
we really wanted to focus on
the valuable community aspect of getting everyone in the same space,
especially after, you know, two years of not being able to see people in person and,
and break bread and just get to know someone.
So while we were hacking away in the other room,
we were making sure to send somebody out
one at a time to go interact or if we had questions
pop over to the other room and try and
discuss with the researcher because
it was valuable. We didn't have to send them a message.
We didn't have to wait 24 hours of time zone or whatever the case may be
to get their answer.
And so, um
in some cases, we had this renewed energy from researchers because they were like,
wow, you actually took the time to come chat with me and that's
so important to
us.
There's so much fun.
If anyone listening ever has a chance to attend one of the live hacking events,
-- they're so much fun. You would not
-- regret it.
I Well, part of me honestly, like if there was,
if one of those happened close enough to me and like allowed an audience,
like, you know, it's like going to Bliss con and watching Starcraft.
Two professionals play Right. Like, no, seriously, I would
like, I know I'm a minor subset of weirdos but, like, I would go watch.
But
that leads to my big question. So,
as I've understood it, the,
the premise of a bug bounty always is you
get security researchers coming into you reporting bugs,
you fix them, your product is more secure.
Are you actually finding that to be the case?
Like, are you finding that there are less sort of in, I guess with github,
it's a little different because it's not like apple phones where, you know,
they're finding zero days in the wild because bad people are trying to break into,
you know, journalist phones.
But with github,
are you finding that,
you know, well, for example,
Attackers are trying to exploit flaws and you're like,
ha ha we fixed that three months ago, you know,
because this nice person reported it to us properly, like, is it actually
impacting your security in a measurable way?
Oh, definitely.
I mean, we have, I believe over 94 million developers on our platform.
So being able to fix something ahead of time and fix something
that hasn't been exploited yet is so incredibly valuable to us.
You know, it protects us, it protects our users. You know, we run github
off of github,
so we definitely are the affected party there too.
That's awesome.
Your bug bounty is against the live sites.
You don't have like a secondary infrastructure
that you're asking people to mess with,
like, you've got people actually attacking github.com and all of that stuff.
Yep, especially at 2 a.m. or Friday at five. You know, those are my favorite.
Oh, yes, I bet.
-- What
-- is it with the Friday 5 p.m. security reports?
Like, like why are they always the worst?
I don't know, there have been some weeks where I felt like tweeting out.
Please stop sending Friday at five vulnerabilities. But, you know, I can't do that.
So
don't stop sending them in my team's around. We'll take care of it.
Oh, yes, yes.
I mean, but at the same time, you've also got what the, the infosec folks that are,
you know, seeing all these attacks, I guess.
Ok, so this is a good question and this is something that I've,
it's a very difficult answer.
So you have the bug bounty people obviously doing their thing
and you,
I imagine have some sort of like information security team that's doing like
event monitoring and you have a SIM and all of that jazz.
So how does your internal security team, I guess.
How do they delineate?
What is an actual attack action needs to be taken on versus
what is probably the bug bunny people doing the bug bunny thing?
Yeah, we have a pretty good grasp.
I wouldn't say, you know, lock proof on that, but we do know
the handles of most of our, our researchers, you know, coming to the platform.
So, you know,
we're always keeping an eye and we're always vigilant on those things.
So whether it is a bounty reporter or
potential malicious act activity, we're going to act the same way.
Now,
the communication may be different if we are very sure
that it's a researcher in our bug bounty program,
we may just confirm things, but
we're going to take the same action. We, we see there is something going on.
We're going to take care of it.
So that's interesting because it actually had not occurred to me that well,
to be blunt, if I was going to test get.com, I would not use my account,
right? Because I don't want my account getting booted off or locked out or,
I mean, fun fact.
I actually ran an ill behaved w get script once that I got my IP block from Cloudflare,
which meant I had to like reset my Mac address and
get a new IP and stop testing stuff from home.
You actually have researchers that are like
doing their bug bounty activities like from their main account,
like live
a little bit of both, but usually that's communicated very well.
They're very forthright with that information typically. So
-- yeah,
-- because I just for me,
like I said, it would have never occurred to me to use my actual real persona account,
whatever you want to call it
to,
to do this kind of testing because I just
assume at some point I'm gonna get blocked out or
-- whatever.
-- We should probably also clarify that when you use hacker one,
they have a special domain called we are,
is, is it we are, we are hacker one.com, right?
One.
Yeah.
Where it's expected that the researchers will create like an email address.
You know what like Kurt at, we are hacker one.com
and then
register that
almost certainly as a separate account and then use that.
And that also is a way to signal
to whoever is on the receiving end of this, that I am a researcher, you know,
with good intent.
I'm not a bad guy from somewhere,
although I'm sure there's bad guys that do this too because they know it's,
it's camouflage, but that's a whole another conversation, I imagine.
Yeah,
definitely.
Oh, my goodness. Yes. Yes. That's so cool.
Ok. All right. So I, I guess I have one kind of last question
that, that's rattling around in my mind
is
you have a page on hacker one
that lists your bounty amounts
and
the low on the low end it's 2000, medium is 10,000,
high is 20,000 and critical is 30,000.
And like
those are pretty solid amounts to be handing out.
And, and do you know off the top of your head?
Like what is, what kind of distribution do you see on those values? Is it,
are you mostly on the lower end?
Do you see a lot of reports do you get a lot of good criticals? I'm I'm curious,
-- I'd say
-- we have a pretty good smattering across the board. Um
This past year we actually awarded our highest bounty ever, which was 50,000.
There is a lovely blog post on our blog about that report.
Can you sum it up for us by chance,
October of last year,
we discovered that there was a vulnerability that an attacker
could publish new versions of any M PM package.
Um
And so it allowed an attacker
to publish anything without proper authorization.
So we quickly validated that in good old bounty fashion,
our researchers went ahead and pulled on the strings there and were able to,
you know, get some other
vulnerabilities in the space
and we should clarify.
Github
is kind of responsible for N PM, right?
Yes,
github
is responsible for N PM.
You have like all the stuff. I love it.
Yeah, I mean, we're very busy but it makes the days go by fast and it's a lot of fun.
We've run ourselves out of time and Jill,
this has been an absolutely amazing conversation,
but I kind of want to give you the floor to
take us home. You know, what is
whatever you want to let the audience know or
what you think the takeaway should be or whatever.
It's all yours.
Yeah. So my biggest thing is if you're even considering bug bounty,
send us ad M on Twitter, send us your first report, poke around at our product.
We are more than happy to take the time to
go ahead and coach you into this wonderful mystical world of bug bounty.
We want to expand our community. We want to get more folks invited to
live hacking events in the future.
We really want to be able to encourage you to take your place in the space of security.
So
I'm available on Twitter, the team, you know, github
security on Twitter, whatever you'd like to do, um, bounty at
-- github.com or hacker one. Feel free to reach out to us.
-- Amazing.
Thank you so much, Jill. It has been
an absolute treat talking to you today.
-- Thank you so much for having me. It was wonderful getting to meet you both.
-- Thank you.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the