Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner are avoiding advertising, Josh Pressers.
Oh, I know.
I know we were just complaining about
chrome we'll say is starting shenanigans with,
with ad blockers.
-- Yeah,
-- we're making it better. So you can't block ads. It'll be better.
That's right. Well, it's better not for us.
There was like some very convoluted Google statement
about why this is better for us.
And I'm like, I don't think that's the case.
-- Yeah,
-- we all, we all know, we all know and, and look, they're a company,
they need to make money.
-- I'm not going to knock them, but I'm going to continue running
-- Firefox.
I feel so bad for them because they've desperately tried to diversify to
the point of like forming the alphabet thing to hold all the companies.
But it's like,
no, it's still like 90 what is it? Five or 98% of their
profits come from advertising revenue through Google.
I mean, you know, this is maybe a topic for another day,
but if you look at the history of the vast majority of companies,
there are
an exceedingly small number of large corporations that have managed to
radically change direction
in a meaningful way.
It is. It is very, very rare.
Like nokia started out making toilet paper and
somehow ended up making cell phones and,
and how's that going now?
-- Like,
-- well, I, I,
but they managed the transition and for a while they were amazing.
Yeah.
Yeah. Oh, absolutely. 100%.
I mean,
Nintendo is probably a good study for that too
because they started making playing cards and that's games
and,
yeah, I, I guess, I guess,
but there's even some funny stories in that of how they
kind of went from cards to where they are today.
And that's a whole another story.
Anyway, I have a hilarious thing to tell you about my internal network problems.
Right.
-- With the, the disastrous laptop.
-- Yes. Right. That's right. My laptop.
So, so the laptop, the, the network would go down with Linux
and Windows. So, obviously I know it's not Linux.
I know it's Windows,
which I didn't know when we told the story a couple of episodes ago.
And I've done an enormous amount of testing trying to
figure this out and I literally cannot figure it out.
Ok.
Now I had a friend visit me literally just yesterday and, uh, he, his,
his name is Joe and he's an old, old friend of mine from, from like, pre college days
and he listens to the show
and I said, did you listen to the episode because he's a networking guy.
I'm like, did you listen to the episode about my, my networking problem?
He's like, no, not yet. I said sorry. Ok.
So I explained it to him and everything and he goes, did you check the cable?
I'm like, no, it's in the wall. He's like, not the cable in the wall. You idiot.
The patch cable between the wall and your computer. I'm like,
no, he's like, I bet you it's a bad patch cable.
Yeah, you wouldn't think to because it's a patch cable.
Like, how does it get damaged to go bad? So,
it, I'm pretty sure it's a patch cable.
See, and that's what frustrates me is unless you buy like a $10,000 fluke meter.
Like, yeah, pin one is pin, one, pin two is pin two. Sure. It's a good cable.
Yeah. Yeah. And, and
he said it's, it's probably something wrong with the patch cable,
something wrong with one of the ends
and when it was going to sleep it was
like ARP nonsense into the network for whatever reason.
And you had some weird
crossover something. I don't, I don't, I'm not a network person. I don't get it.
But anyway, I did a bunch of testing. In fact, I can't even reproduce it.
Now, with the original cable
cut that cable in half with scissors and put in the garbage.
-- No, I've not cut it in half yet. But the point
-- is that's a rule.
I have the minute I suspect a cable of being evil,
especially because lighting cables especially,
I don't know what it is about lightning cables.
But after like 3 to 6 months they just,
they only work, put one way into the phone or like half my phone.
And so the minute that starts happening,
I take a scissor, cut them in, half, throw them in the garbage because I'm, I'm,
I'm done fighting bad cables
honestly though, like in hindsight,
-- why I didn't replace the patch cable immediately
-- because it's a patch cable.
It worked, I guess. I, you know. Right. Like I have a bunch of patch cables.
I would never think that
they're, how do they go bad? Like, do they rot? Do they go stale?
Do, do you need to put them in a Ziploc?
I can't even reproduce it now with the same patch cable. But I, I have unplugged it
since
in all my testing,
but I haven't plugged it back in and then reproduced it and now I can't reproduce it.
So I wonder if it was even just plugged
in cockeyed because it's been plugged in for months.
Like, anyway, whatever it is.
I mean, well, this is the number one rule of network cabling management is like,
the first thing you do is unplug and plug it back in
-- to make sure it goes in smooth. And like I didn't do that.
-- I bought a new switch
mostly
unplug and plug
everything.
Yeah,
it was a patch cable
or whatever. I have no regrets. My switches were old.
They probably needed to be replaced anyway.
But just like
whatever, whatever.
That's the thing I like about my new old switches.
So it turns out I bought switches that were like, last supported in 2018.
Well, no one knows this. So I, I, Kurt and I have been
discussing my saga
and when I told Kurt, I bought all new switches.
He was like, oh, I should probably buy new switches too.
So, but you bought newer switches that are end of life, right.
-- Well,
-- they were end of life like in 2018.
Right?
But basically I just wanted like a low end smart switch for, well, if I do need V
lands or quality service, I can turn it on.
But more to the point I've got error reporting, like broke.
No, no, no, like broken frames and stuff. Right. Like, um
-- it probably would have been handy if I had that just saying.
-- Yeah, exactly. Right.
And that's, and that's what I realized is I want to switch.
That is just smart enough to basically say like, yeah,
I'm seeing a ton of garbage frames from this port.
Yeah. Yeah. Anyway, anyway. All right, that's enough.
And I want a spanning tree because my, my existing,
apparently most modern cheapo unmanaged switches don't even do STP anymore,
which, ok, fair enough.
They're like
30 bucks,
like, you know, that silicon costs five bucks, I guess. I don't know.
But, yeah, I wanted, I wanted air management primarily.
Like, that's the reason I loved smart on the old hard drives is like,
oh,
I've got a few errors on this hard drive and then
I remember checking one drive in my pool and it had,
like, 27,000 errors.
So I'm like, oh, time to buy a new one
-- drives still do
-- smart. Yeah, but on S sds, it doesn't really matter.
Like mechanical hard drives can sort of start to slowly fail
and you get a bit of a warning. Whereas with an SSD, it's like,
-- you know, I've never had an SSD go bad on me.
-- I think I had one early one die.
But like we're talking like this is from like in the,
like this
literally like two years after they were available for laptops.
Uh See, I actually, I don't know if you remember this,
but you and I used to argue incessantly over S sds where I was
just trolling you and saying they're unnecessary and dumb way back in those days.
That was a, that amuses me to no end anyway.
All right, we have a real topic today that isn't just us
cet
about hardware
time t open source.
I'm excited for this one. So
for anyone who doesn't know, I'll put a link in the show notes,
but there is a blog post that
Andre Stoltz.
I apologize. Andre for
pronouncing your name,
wrote a blog post called Time to Open Source Alternative. And this is from
-- August 27th. I thought, I feel like this is older than that.
-- It's pretty recent,
14 days ago.
What? No,
-- what?
-- It's September the 11th
Kurt.
If you would have asked me how long ago this story came out,
I would have told you a minimum of six months
that sums up my September
in the modern timeline. That sounds about right.
Uh
Anyway,
so what happens here is
Andrew
kind of laid down a bunch of technologies like the UNIX Autocad, MATLAB, Winzip,
youtube, Twitter and then has
the publish on like kind of the date this
this product will say our technology was released.
And then he has another column that says open source alternative and obviously,
like UNIX has an alternative of Linux,
right?
And then he's got the number that is time to open source alternative,
like in the case of UNIX to Linux at 6560 days.
But anyway, and I think the
I feel like the intent of this maybe was to try
to justify that the time to open source alternative is maybe
becoming faster because if you look way back in the nineties versus
more recent things, the time is, you know,
thousands and thousands of days and it's much less now,
the velocity of software in general has
it's
you and I literally bought Linux in a box on a CD.
-- I bought a book that had a CD in the back and I threw the book away.
-- Yeah, exactly.
Like I remember getting, you know, Wordperfect and,
and then two or three years later I would buy the new version of wordperfect.
Like there was no concept of downloading an update.
Like we hadn't, we barely had the wet back then,
-- you
-- know.
-- Yeah. And you paid for upgrades
-- like Windows 3.11
was an upgrade from Windows 3.1. And it's like,
it's not like I was downloading patches every other Tuesday.
Was that a free upgrade or did you have to buy the new? I don't, I don't remember.
Well, in hindsight now,
I understand that Windows cost money but like the computer we bought,
came with Windows 3.11 for work preloaded.
And like, again, in hindsight, we didn't pay for it. So,
-- I mean,
-- I guess I, I remember
what was it was?
Well,
I remember I bought a computer at Windows 95 and then I feel
like I might have hired an NT for it way back in the day
when I was uh like a high school kid.
I used to have a Windows 95 license key
memorized the uh the local University of Alberta one.
-- Anyway.
-- Anyway. Ok.
So here's the actual direction I want to take is we could
go through this list and talk about time to open social alternatives.
And I think in some instances
the examples found are good in some instances I don't necessarily agree with them.
I want to say there's one big problem with his list,
which is he conflates services and software.
Ok. Yes, that's part of it.
But I'm more interested in fact in,
in talking about security things
-- because there aren't, are there any real security items on
-- this list?
One password?
Yeah, there's,
there's, but
ok, yes, one password was one of the ones I wanted to actually discuss, I think,
well, bit keeper sort of security. That the Bit Keeper story a whole another.
That's something
when I said bite,
I was thinking of bit warden. Never
mind. Yeah.
Yeah. Right. Bit keeper and git. Whoops. Sorry.
-- No, no, that's fine.
-- I'm literally having my coffee right now.
It's, it's like
what, two, it's three
this morning,
which explains like why my brain has just not been firing on all cylinders
I could if II I,
I'm super addicted to caffeine at this point.
If I don't drink coffee probably by eight or nine in the morning,
I will have a raging headache.
So that's just out of the question.
And it's funny because I go to the doctor and they're like,
you should cut back. I'm like, don't even bother. There's,
you're wasting your time. I'm not gonna quit drinking coffee.
I don't care like, whatever it's my life now
I give up.
Uh, ok. Ok. So anyway,
so here's what I think we should frame this as is
the, there,
there's not a lot of security stuff in here but I feel like
there's a reason there's not a lot of security stuff in here because
how many security products
can you name
that have a truly open
source alternative?
I think if anything, many of them started open source and unopen
-- source.
-- Yeah, I was gonna say like the only ones that kind of
uh commercial and then, well,
but the thing is like uh key pass X or whatever has been around for so long.
I suspect it kind of came out about the same time as closed source password managers,
right?
Um I mean, and yeah, famously like um well,
the good examples would be N map was open source still is open source
but their sort of data set of
identifying network devices based on their TCP fingerprints
is
no longer as open source as it was or same thing with tenable, sorry with
-- NSA, which turned into tenable.
-- Oh, dude.
Keep
pa
is dead.
What?
Yeah. Ok. Ok. So I just looked uh key
pass X came out in 2005 but on the Wikipedia page,
it says as of December 2021 key pass X is no longer actively maintained.
There's a fork called key
pass
-- XC. Now the first one came out in 2005, sorry
-- key
pass
XC
-- XC is the new fork the community fork.
-- Oh, ok.
Because yeah, the last release of Key pass X was in 2016.
-- So that's definitely,
-- but I mean, so this is,
I think this is one of the interesting stories
though is if you look at the security products and
it it like one password versus Bit Warden is the example we'll pick on right now.
So bit
worden is
we'll say bit Warden's code is open source, right?
But I would hesitate to necessarily say bit Warden is
truly open source from the context of it's a service,
right?
You can run your own bit
Warden.
But I think this is where in my mind and this is,
this is what I want us to talk about and this is what I was hoping
we could untangle because I actually don't know
what your opinion is on this necessarily.
But something like like bit
Warden or or we can pick on git lab
is another good example of there are the they are they are open source.
So there's the operational aspect,
it's really hard to run this stuff, right?
Well, let's just go with simply something very simple with operational aspects.
So from an operational aspect, there's a lot of applications now
that I want to have
either collaborative editing or
the synchronization of data to some degree.
So like as a very simplistic example, you know, I use omni
focus
and my to do list better be the same on my phone is on my ipad is on my desktop
because otherwise I'm gonna have a bad time. So that means synchronization.
Well,
that means having something to synchronize to and you can run
your own web DEV server and I have in the past.
But then they added encryption of the data using your own encryption key.
And I'm like, oh, I'm just going to pay them to do it because
-- again, operationally, this means now I have to care and feed a server
-- bit bit
warden has a service you can pay them for.
And bit warden also has all of their stuff like open source.
In fact, you can literally just run your own bit warden infrastructure,
they have instructions to deploy it.
But at the same time,
like if
in the company goes away,
bit ward in the open source, I think is functionally dead
unless somebody decides to take on it and wrap a company around it.
Yeah, because the the amount of work and effort and there's a lot of
like there's a lot of boring work and boring effort
needed for these things that are not super awesome.
Yeah, I mean, Git lab, I think is the same story.
If git lab, the corporation disappeared.
I don't think Git lab, the the product would continue to exist.
And I think this is true of an enormous amount of open source, especially security,
open source stuff because I think a lot of this work sucks
and no one wants to do it unless they're literally paid to do it.
Well, I think it's actually worse than that in that if, for example,
a company like git lab or whatever goes away, their stuff doesn't die.
It's sort of just
zombies along
if it died,
that would actually almost be better because it would force people to deal with it or
to come up with a new solution or to actually properly fund it or whatever.
But instead you get this situation where they kind of keep you.
It's like all the people still using Windows 95 because
they have to for some piece of hardware or something
and they're just sort of zombie along with this like stale out of date software.
That's
-- one day is just gonna fail.
-- OK? Hold on, hold on
you. You may have brought up a really good point accidentally.
So if I'm running Windows 95 today,
I am sol like I am. There's absolutely nothing I can do
if I'm running
some product
and I have the source code to that
-- I could theoretically do stuff
-- theoretically. Right. And that's the thing, like
how many people on this planet have the expertise to go into the,
let's say anything with crypto
-- code base and fix it properly.
-- Oh, barely anyone. I agree.
And I think that's where the theoretical part comes into play because
the Linux,
oh, here's the source code. Sure, you can just fix your device driver.
No,
-- no, you really can't.
-- No, no. Hang on, hang on, hang on you.
I think you're missing the point.
So if, if you and I are running the Linux kernel and we encounter a bug,
we can file the bug
and pray someone takes pity on us and does something about it.
And, and at the same time,
I would bet you 80 or 90% of Linux kernel development is
by people who are paid to work on the Linux kernel,
right?
Like these are not volunteers.
It my guess is it's probably like 95 to 99% but we'll be generous.
You and I are at the mercy of everyone. Now,
there is a size though, if I am a corporation.
Uh and if, and if there is a financial benefit to me, say building Linux patches
and, and including them in Linux,
there's a line somewhere.
And I think when you look at security products though,
I have a strong suspicion that the line of when is it
worth it for me to say fork something and keep it alive
is well past
any amount of money any company is willing to spend.
That is my suspicion for security products.
I think one of the dimensions here is it speaks to package and software complexity.
So a great example is the Linux,
the Linux kernel is, it's complicated
like it, it just is, I mean,
you can, but there's, for example,
there are PHP libraries that are not as complicated.
And so a great example of this is I needed. What was it, the PHP open ID plug in
to work so that I could have media wiki authenticate via open ID.
And the
software itself
was still being supported. But the Fedora package
wasn't the the developer just ned
out of her and never tried an update in ages and it was broken
in. And so I actually took ownership of it, did like the two line fix, got it working
and then I abandoned it
right
because I fixed it for myself,
you know,
I
I don't want to own a puppy.
Um
But so there's that aspect of sort of the complexity piece.
So for example,
taking a simple piece of software and fixing the packaged version of it,
like bringing it up to date
that is pretty doable, you know,
fixing a PHP library or something that's probably doable ish.
But like fixing the Linux kernel, like no,
like you're going to need so much knowledge and expertise that's domain specific.
Like I don't care how good of a programmer you are.
If you don't have at least 6 to 12 months of experience with the LINX kernel,
you're going to need that.
Sure.
Now, now, OK,
so here's the second part of this conversation now
and you actually like you introduce us perfectly.
If there is something I need to do,
I can go to a company like red hat or canonical or so
and say,
I want to be your customer
and I need this thing fixed in the kernel
and they're going to ask for extra money obviously,
but like they are in a position to do that.
And so now
if you think about like this time to open source,
a lot of these open source services and, and in fact,
a lot of the things on the list of time to open source have,
have companies behind them.
And I think that's,
that's kind of part of that incentive is if we look at
something like bit warden or we look at something like git lab,
like you have a company behind that you can become their customer,
you can fund the development,
you don't have to go and find like some open source nerd who can create
patches and work with upstream because now you have a company to work with.
So here's the interesting thing when you look at this list, OK,
if you look at the top of the list, at the old stuff,
the open source alternatives are products,
which kind of makes sense because like services
just didn't exist back in those days.
And as we move down,
the services being replaced,
the
open source alternatives are not like community open
source projects.
They are corporate funded open
-- I think the term generally is open core.
-- Uh No, no, no, no, not necessarily.
I mean, like git lab and matter,
not matter
most well matter most as well, but like git lab matter
most and,
and, uh, bit warden are like completely open source.
It's just, they're so complicated. No
human can run them
without.
I could give you all the schematics to a modern vehicle and you can't build it.
Aws is a better example.
If Amazon said here is all the source code to Aws Cart,
then there's nothing you could do with it.
Nothing
I'm gonna grip for, I'm gonna grip for rude words.
That's it
just to amuse myself.
And, and that's the thing though.
If you look at any modern service,
one human cannot
work with modern services because they're just so complicated and difficult.
The thing I'm realizing and this is I'm doing what I'm doing
with a lot of my work now with threat modeling and stuff is
writing it down because holding these mental models in my head,
even if I can hold a mental model in my head of what this thing is.
The model I'm holding in my head is different than the model you are holding in
your head and we're trying to discuss it
and we're both holding different models and,
and both are wrong.
Yeah. Oh Absolutely. Yeah, 100%.
And
yeah, the the other thing is operationally
like what people expect is the bare minimum nowadays.
Like I expect collaborative editing.
Like
this is why I I'm finding
git and github
very frustrating because I want to have like a text document with three people
editing and commenting
and you can't,
that sucks for that, man.
So we
use Google Docs which drives me nuts because then I can't index the text and blah,
blah, blah.
You know what I mean?
So you know what, what,
what I'm seeing is relatively successful use Google
Docs for like the first cut and then
get
and that's actually probably what I'm gonna end up doing.
Like here's a great example, right?
I was at elastic elastic is one of the examples of
something that was Apache to in change of license because in,
in the elastic instance, Amazon
took the elastic search,
just suite of stuff because it's, it's a huge amount of stuff
and they were
deploying it and,
and violating the trademark and all that stuff and like there were
a bunch of court cases that all kind of sorted itself out.
Well,
I'm going to interrupt because I think that's one aspect where
people got a lot of this wrong too is they,
they hear something like elastic and they just think elastic search,
they don't realize there's 20 things behind it or add it
on to it to actually really like dashboard stuff like can,
what is it? The one that starts with a KKK?
-- Sorry.
-- Yeah. But, and here's part of that story though, is
Amazon is one of the few organizations that could actually
run that stack in a manageable way for customers.
But fun fact, if you look at what Amazon actually did with it,
they sort of did the bare minimum and, and they forked it since.
And that's something I've noticed with a lot of these large companies,
it's not like they're devoting a team of 50 people to it.
They're like getting it stood up just enough so customers can run it and use it.
Because, for example, Amazon used to have their,
an actual Blockchain as a service thing
and they've abandoned it like, it's, it's a dead end.
They've got like, version 1.4 and that's it.
It never went past that. It's a quota
if memory serves.
And like, I guess they just didn't get enough customers or whatever.
And so it's just, it's a dead end and that's something like,
unless this thing is a success, the company is not gonna put
any resources into it more than they have to because, like,
that's how companies work,
you know?
Exactly.
But then the problem is that steals so much time and kind of market and effort from
sort of the, the, I hate to say the real one, but from the real one basically,
and then you get the, the,
the true open source one kind of atrophies and dies and then, well, it
-- just sort of goes away. Right, blows up and dries up.
-- Now,
here's, here's the last bit of this conversation for today and that is Sig Star,
right?
I think Sigs Star is, I think one of the most interesting projects today
because if you look at the history of
like encryption and key management and all that,
there's like tons of super overpriced terrible products
and, and
no one will disagree with me when I just literally call them all terrible. Right.
That is, that is not a point of contention.
It's the same sort of market as the certificate market was
it? It's they're literally, they're a circle
with be
die.
But here's the thing.
So Sig Store has
a ton of work coming into it.
Like obviously, like Google and Redhead, I believe, were the founders
and you've got
an open source community doing a certain amount of work.
And I'm curious to see if Sig Store maintains
its success as an open project because like Cooper
Neti is maybe an example of something that's managed to do this.
But I don't think Kubernetes is as niche as Sig Store is.
And that's what I find the most interesting.
Most security things are actually remarkably niche
when it really comes down to it.
So what I've kind of noticed and this is one of the reasons I actually
chose to work at the cloud security lines is
the cloud security Alliance has
hundreds of corporate members.
And so they kind of cancel each other out,
like there's no one big member that kind of can throw their weight around
and So
if you look at something like Kubernetes kind of
or the Linux kernel is even a better example,
like, yes, Red Hat is like, what was it?
8% or 13% of the Linux kernel.
But there's also other huge companies in there and it's,
and it's not like Red Hat can ever, even with IBM acquiring them,
can ever be big enough and rich enough to like, hijack the lens kernel.
It's just,
it's like trying to hijack the silver market, like it's just too big.
And Cooper Netti has escaped that and gotten to that
size where they have lots and lots of players.
But if you look at sig store,
they only list four
entities on their community page.
It's Google the links Foundation, Red Hat and Purdue University
and I hope they
escape that kind of having because like of those four organizations, clearly,
one of them is bigger than the rest.
Like really like, like on a, on a, on a, on a,
like if we did a graph of revenue,
you wouldn't be able to see three of them
without a logarithmic chart.
It's like, no, we didn't forget to print those three bars.
They're just very close to the,
it's down there. OK.
So this is an interesting point actually and this is
not something I had in my mental model of all.
This is you are correct when you have
a plurality of contributions coming from one organization.
If that organization has any problems,
they, weird things start to happen and it could be, the project dies.
It could be the project. It's taking close source. It, it, who knows? Right.
But when you have a truly community project like Kubernetes or the Linux Kernel,
there's nothing that can stop it at this point. Right. It's just, it
is a, it is a truck speeding down the highway.
Well, and that's the thing, it's like a truck's being down the highway.
You've got Google in there, you know, uh,
semi truck with like towing a pile of dump trucks
and it's not that they like, wanted to run over you. It's just that
like,
it's like a
200,000 pounds of moving mass
doesn't turn on a dime.
And so, for example, if I look at the sig store thing,
my perception is right now is like, oh man, like if I want to get my way, I have to like,
kind of
like, if my way doesn't agree with what Google and Red Hat want, I am
like, good luck,
you know what I mean?
And so even if they're totally willing to be nice and reasonable,
but I'm looking at this saying basically I have to like, deal with Google and Red Hat,
not a community.
I have to deal with those two specifically.
I mean, that's the problem is,
I don't know if they're going to be good and reasonable or nice or mean or,
and they're not
going to probably be very mean.
It's just, again, part of it is like there's the Google view of the world
and it probably is not my view of the world. Like a great example.
I was talking with an airline and they're
talking about how they're moving into the cloud
and that they have a rule that says they have
to have visibility of all the incoming and outgoing traffic.
And I'm like, oh, that's really not going to work so well with a lot of these, you know,
blank as a service,
you know, like, I don't think Google's gonna let you do that.
And he's like, oh, we'll get exceptions. And I'm like,
you're gonna have to get exceptions for everything.
Like it's, it's gonna become meaningless and he's like,
we might have to rethink that.
-- And I'm like, your
-- exception diagram is a circle of the planet Earth.
Exactly.
Well, except those three things still in a data center,
you know,
and
like they have to rethink their corporate it security culture because it's just
incompatible with the modern world if they want to use the modern world.
And,
and that's kind of where this is going with these big things. It's like,
again, it's not that they're bad or evil or opposite to me. It's just
like Google has their view of the world.
Yeah.
And
it's different than I
am.
And, and look, I think that is part of the story is if you want to
have any sort of sway over an open source project,
you either have to pay a company working on it a bunch of money or
you have to get involved yourself. Right.
And I think that then creates the conversation of, OK, so if, if an open
source, the project is owned by one company, is it open source?
It has an open source license.
It, it, well, it's open source, it's not community, I guess,
would be maybe a more accurate.
The frustrating thing to me is we've all
agreed that open source means o si approved open source licenses. OK.
Let's just stick with that to simplify things greatly.
But the promise that doesn't say that they're going to take good patches.
No. Right. Absolutely.
And I mean,
how many,
how many times have it?
I mean, we've been in the open source world forever,
like you can suggest something to a project and the project can be like,
-- we don't care, go away or they'll
-- just ignore it.
Yeah,
I would almost rather than tell me to go away than just ignore it.
No, I, I agree. And that's
so that is one of the things like, so obviously at
Acor, we have sifting gripe which are open source projects and that's something we,
we really started putting an effort into.
Like
if someone sends us something,
we cannot let it sit like we need to at least say we like this.
But we're gonna get to it later or we don't like this.
-- Like this is why we don't like it or whatever.
-- A perfect github
desktop is open source.
Issue number 78.
Yes. You said that to me yesterday
is GP G signing doesn't work. That's issue 78. That's, it's like from 2016,
it's very
old. It's six years old.
It's clearly not going to happen and then sign off doesn't work.
That's issue 5000 and something. And it's like four years old
and
-- because of the stupid DC O stuff
-- and it's like, it's four years old at this point
and github
hasn't even really replied to it other than to say, it's not on the road map. Well,
yeah, we figured that out
and
like so github
desktop is open source but
it is, it's not a OK. It has an O SI license.
I mean,
so this is probably a conversation for another day
that we're because we're basically out of time.
Here's the thing is
I think historically,
if something had open source code, it was open source.
And I think in, in many instances,
communities would just organically form around it.
Like Gimp is a great example of open office, whatever.
There were all these technologies that I think
just naturally were magnetic to the community because we needed these solutions,
right?
Like we had no option.
Whereas now I think when we look at some of these products and services that are,
they're technically open source because let's face it at this point.
If you're basically not open source, I think you're,
you're just not going to exist in a lot of instances, for many reasons,
-- you
-- have to spend a lot of money reinventing the wheel.
And I think it's, it's a good marketing ploy to be like, look, here's all of our code.
And honestly, when you're doing like a lot,
a lot of sales motions,
having your source code in github
solves a lot of problems
people will be like, have you, have you scanned your source code? No, but it's here.
Oh,
that's good enough. Like I know you're never gonna scan it.
You're never gonna read the report. I'd send you either.
But like at least we can pretend that this matters.
Would you buy a house with a locked door that they won't
let you look behind until you pay for it and it closes?
Of
-- course,
-- I
would, I, I don't, I, I part of me would want to buy it just to look behind the door. Like
what's in there? I must know it's like, remember the Reddit safe where the guy was?
Like, what's in the safe? There's nothing in the safe. But
like
anyway, anyway,
so I, I don't know.
II I was hoping discussing this with you would bring
me to some sort of like internal mental resolution.
And I feel
just as confused before I started as I am now and I think the thing
I am now going to think about
is
I think what we called open source in the past
was really
a community.
And now
we, they are very separate.
I think they were, they were naturally the same historically.
But now I think like you can be open source and not have a community.
Well, can I, maybe here's something that's adding confusion to it is
the distinction between open source as a software, as
a,
as a piece of code and open source as something
that's also a service and primarily useful as a service
because there's like back in the day, we didn't have internet connectivity.
So all of our software sort of ran locally and
was useful without a software or without an internet connection.
But nowadays,
I have almost no software that is actually useful without an internet connection.
Like apart from Notepad where I shove notes occasionally,
I'm just looking at my menu bar.
Yeah, there's not a
single thing in there. Yeah. Notepad.
Notepad is literally the only app I use on
my desktop that would be useful without internet.
Uh You should get there, there's a note taking app called Obsidian
and you can check it in github.
Very
nice
-- anyway,
-- but like
it's the world has changed.
So I think that's part of the challenge is what does open source mean now. Well,
the pure definition of it's this open source with this license
no longer works because for example, will they take reasonable patches?
Will they do reasonable extensions? Like to me, it is unreasonable that github
-- desktop will not add support for GP G signing and signature or sign offs
-- well.
OK.
No, no, no, no, no, no. Has someone offered a patch to do this?
Yes.
OK. If the patch has been offered and they won't take it, that's inexcusable.
Not a patch patch per like it wasn't, I didn't check too much,
but for example github desktop just needs to support the G pre commit hooks
because I set up pre commit hooks in my personal directory and it ignored them.
-- But
-- no, no, no. OK. OK. So here's how I want it. We're, we're,
we're way over time,
but here's how I want you to think about this and we can talk about
this some more later because I think there's more to this than what we've got.
So asking github to add a feature, they don't have to.
Now, granted, they should just say we don't care, go away.
But
I think the way open source works is you don't show
up and ask you show up with a patch right now.
If you show up with a patch and they don't take your patch,
that's kind of weaselly.
But I think we've also conflated now in our minds,
this idea of I can go to the community
and I can ask them to do things and they'll do it for me
and no, they won't like that.
No, they won't. In the past,
there might have been some of that where people could say something like, oh,
this is a novel feature for this open source project
and sometimes they'd come with patches, sometimes they wouldn't.
But if it was clever enough people would be like, oh, yes, that's a great idea
because they were doing it for fun and it might have been fun.
Something like GP G signing and github desktop.
That's not really fun.
You know,
I think the problem is open source.
Like I said, it's no longer just about the software. It's also a lot about services.
It's a lot about will they take updates, improvements, code patches. It's,
it's all about the community and a company is not a community by and large.
No, I, I agree. I agree 100%.
And I think historically community and code were the same thing
and now they're not
and a company with open source code doesn't make a community. And I think that is,
that is going to be the next mental gymnastic.
The open source universe has to figure out is open source as we define it today.
Is licenses from the O SI
but open source.
The idea is the community.
And I think unfortunately
the term open source has been hijacked by a lot of people. And so
there will be many years of untangling that.
-- Well, they are technically open source. Just
-- that's true.
They are
tech
technically correct is the best kind of correct. Right.
The problem is the definition of open source. Well, the world changed
and I agree, I agree 100%.
-- 100 percent.
-- Look, I'm just looking at these, uh github
desktop contributors.
12,000. It's like a long tail of,
yeah, they always are.
I, I would expect in github desktop that 99% of commits are from github
employees
and maybe a couple of random contributors.
Oh,
man, it's a sharp tail. Like the top 10 contributors are
the,
I believe it.
I mean, that's how,
that's how most open source works where if you
have a company paying someone to work on it,
that's what you get anyway.
All right, man, I think,
I think we got a lot to chew out on this one
and I want to call it because we've been dragging it on.
So, thank you.
Thank you, everyone for listening.
Got up with our security podcast.com. Head up the show, not
use a Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.
The.