Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in building a good podcast with secure methods. Josh Pressers.
Do we build a good podcast with secure methods?
Well, I mean, we have, we secured our supply chain.
-- I thought we had like, I make sure you, you and you make sure I'm
-- me,
we've never claimed that even in Jest
and I don't think I ever will. I'm,
I don't want to say this out loud,
but I'm starting to wonder if securing the plight supply chain is an intractable,
-- but I'm, I'm hopeful it's not.
-- Here's the thing. Can we secure the supply chain?
Absolutely. Well, absolutely not.
-- I mean, that's true,
-- but that's true of all security.
Like we can't even secure nuclear weapons. Like
there's a list of nuclear weapons that the US has lost and to be fair,
none of them are recent,
but there is like a bomb sitting in some mud somewhere outside Savannah, Georgia.
It should be clarified
if there was a recent one. It's just not declassified yet.
That's
probably why we might not know.
Anyway, we are going to discuss SSDF the Secure software development framework,
which is a NIST standard, nist 800-2 18.
For those of you playing along at home.
Actually, we're not discussing the SSDF,
we're technically discussing an attestation form which
sly, so I'm going to
let me try to explain this in a way that doesn't sound completely ridiculous.
So nest the National Institute of Standards and Technologies,
they
have a smorgasbord of standards. We'll call it
and there is a,
the National Institute of Standards and Technologies has a list of standards,
a smorgasbord of standards. Kurt.
So Nist has a class of they, they like have, I I forget what they call them,
but like there's the the digits in the front in 800
denotes
information security policies, right?
So you've heard of like 800-53 which is basically the granddaddy of all
the cybersecurity policies on the planet.
-- They almost all refer back to that
-- and like all the pips and the crypto and the right?
It's all in there
and
800-28
is they call it the secure software development framework and it lays out,
I think it's 42 controls
that discuss how to securely develop software.
And you can imagine 42 controls is quite a bit, it's hard to unwind sometimes
and additionally,
so they have this standard, but just having a standard is meaningless,
right?
You need a way to kind of collect information and enforce it and,
and do some attestation.
Now,
one of the things that will happen in the world of compliance
is you can get a third party audit done. The auditor gives you a phone book of a report
and then that report, then you have to work with them.
It's, it takes like months and months,
years and then that report is like proof
that you are following the given compliance standard.
-- Right? You'll hear about
-- this or you have compensating controls or other
exceptions or to be clear just because you meet the audit standard for the,
the whatever standard it is,
doesn't mean you actually have to meet the standard that
the actual specific controls because that's something
I see a lot of confusion about because
like, well, like with star,
like we all the cloud security lines also has the Secure Trust Automation registry
and for example,
we have stuff where the classic thing is and this happened very early on where
the the the the cons
the consensus assessment initiative questionnaire,
the cake ask things like physical security
and a lot of SASS vendors are like, um
no, like
we run an Amazon
and we're like,
yeah,
just kind of pass through like say you run on Amazon and
then they go Amazon's entry and make sure that it's legit.
And
so
with almost all of these standards, you can pass the standard
and not just like passing it to pass it, but actually pass it like
in the spirit of being secure
and not pass all of it. And that's fine.
And that's again where things get complicated and,
and generally speaking,
I would say in most compliance standards, if you have an answer of, yes,
I do this to all the questions.
That's probably a good sign. You're, you're making it up.
So, anyway. Ok. So you got n
800 to 18
and
Cisa,
which is what does CISA stand for? Do you remember
-- every
-- time?
I never remember
cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.
It's interesting to me that cybersecurity becomes, well, I guess is,
is, is, is,
is,
yeah, it has to be Cisa. There's no way to rearrange it
ways anyway.
Well, no,
I'm just saying it's interesting that they put
-- cybersecurity first and not say infrastructure
-- anyway,
whatever
Cisa,
-- which is part of the Department of Homeland Security in the United States.
-- I think
everything is part of the Department of Homeland Security
-- now in the USA lot
-- of stuff is,
but Cissa released this thing that's called the SSDF at a station form.
And the intent behind this is you are a company looking to sell
products and services to the US government.
Well, software and services largely.
-- That's true. I don't think it's for, it
-- doesn't apply to widgets.
There
would be
specific, there's widget standards for that.
Exactly. Right. Right. This is like the famous Nist brownie recipe, right?
-- Or
-- like the screws like and in fairness if you build screws wrong. That's,
that's bad.
I mean. Right. Right. Oh, for sure. For sure.
We, it, it's fun to, it's easy to laugh at n
for like brownie recipes and $1000 pound peanut butter and stuff like that.
But like,
they basically are the glue that holds society together.
-- So,
-- like, and something that might. Ok.
So from the, the SISA thing to further complicate this,
there's the executive order 14028,
improving the nation's cybersecurity.
But
it's like uh the hip bones connected to the knee bone situation.
So essentially the executive order told
Sisa to do a thing and Sisa
used the new standard to tell the rest of us to do a thing.
And now they have the attestation form to say that you did the thing
right
now, the attestation form we are going to discuss,
we're like what we're like almost 10 minutes into this thing.
-- But
-- honestly, this stuff is complicated because like,
like the, the the relationship of the White House to Sisa to nist like
-- that's some complicated moving parts.
-- It's true.
It's true. It's true.
So,
so Cisa releases a self
attestation form.
And what that means is
an organization looking to sell software to the US. Government
is expected to fill this form out
and not nece you, you're not involving a third party auditor.
You don't have to like incur a bunch of costs that may come someday.
But for now, it's a matter of I'm a company,
I'm going to fill out this form
and then I'm going to submit the form I have filled out
and someone important in my company who basically attest to like I,
I have the authority to do this, signs it and then
I assume sis is going to collect them and put them in a folder on,
on a shared Microsoft drive or something.
So, yeah. So essentially this is self attestation where
I
validated that we
to pick on Boeing, I validated that we put door bolts to hold the door in.
Yeah, turns out maybe you need a third party to make sure that happens.
Sometimes you need it. Yes, but not always.
And the other thing that's interesting is this does like it,
this is one of those classic if you lie on this government form.
Uh Yeah, there's the potential for criminal penalties.
Uh It's,
I don't know if they're going to criminally prosecute people for this, but
they're, they're for sure going to
pull the business, right?
So,
yeah, with respect to this form, it's a self attestation form. So like we,
well, basically, yeah, we filled out this form and we're, we say we're not lying.
It's kind of like my tax returns where my accountant says we didn't audit Kurt.
Like he basically promises that he gave us all the paperwork,
didn't hide anything, doesn't have a Swiss account we don't know about.
And what's interesting is you were saying before
So third party assessment vendors can demonstrate performance
through a third party assessment performed by a
fed ramp certified or agency approved third party
assessment organization. A three pal,
which I love that acronym. That's one of my favorites.
Yes.
And then, ah this is the thing,
the form must be signed by the CEO or
a designated employee with the authority to bind the
company uh testing that the software is developed in
conformity with secure practices outlined in this form.
That's a very,
like we're not messing around statement.
-- Like,
-- I mean, it, it kind of is, I agree,
you know, it feels,
I mean, it feels like there's some, some maybe teeth behind it, but I,
I have a strong suspicion
-- like no one's going to jail over this form,
-- uh,
willfully providing false or misleading information may constitute
a violation of 18 US C 1001,
a criminal statute.
It is technically a criminal statute. But again, like
it is far more likely the government is just going to pull
their business from you than they're going to put you in jail,
right?
But in classic terms, the overton window is moving.
-- I
-- mean,
maybe,
well, no, like if you'd said 20 years ago, hey,
you could go to jail for selling insecure software.
Sure, I'll agree with that,
-- you know,
-- and now it's like, no,
it's,
-- it's in the paperwork,
-- it's not
going to jail for selling insecure software. You're going to jail for lying.
That's
right. Yeah, you're going to jail for lying.
If you just say my software is utter trash,
you won't go to jail because you're telling the truth.
But if you say this software has no security bugs,
now,
it's not that it's, if you say,
like we have a secure development process and you don't.
And so there, there is one nugget in here that I absolutely adore.
It's, uh, where are we? But halfway P page four, I think it is,
it says
in the event, an agency cannot obtain a completed self
attestation from the software producer,
an agency may still decide to use a producer software.
-- It says if the producer identifies the practices and
-- blah, blah, blah, I mean,
there, there,
but there has to be an exceptions rule right now because
there's just not enough vendor doing it securely to pick from
and there's already vendors that are pre deployed and it's like
they're not going to do this or they can't do this in a timely manner.
OK? We're, we're, we're, we're dwelling too much
on this.
But there
-- is actually one
-- thing that's fascinating to me, also, ongoing compliance, right?
Vendors must notify agencies if they cease to make consistent
use of the secure development practices outlined in the form.
And that is also something that is again the Overton Windows moving.
That is a,
that's a new thing because all of these certifications
like used to pretty much be a point in time
and like
it was kind of hoped that you would stay good, but it wasn't
kind of written that way necessarily always and it is increasingly happening now
for sure, for sure.
Um So, OK,
and there's, there's literally a check box
that says, I further attest that the software producer will not
notify any agency to which it has submitted this form if and when the producer
ceases to make consistent use of the
practices identified above in developing the software,
which again, like it, it might not have any teeth out of the gate.
But the fact that they're writing this down
is something and, and look,
here's the other thing I want to say just before we get going into the actual content,
the reality of what's going to happen here
is
you're going to send these to Cisa.
Cisa is going to collect them all, they're going to collect a lot of them
and then they're going to look at them and they're
going to figure out what is going on here,
what's making sense, what isn't making sense and then they're going to change it.
This is just like how
all of the cybersecurity insurance companies
just like handed policies out like candy because they were collecting data.
That's all they were, they weren't actually underwriting insurance policies.
They were collecting data about cybersecurity.
A perfect concrete example of this is I just bought travel
insurance because I'm going to the US for three days.
Right.
And if you are fully vaccinated for COVID, you get $5 million coverage
and if you're not fully vaccinated for COVID, you get 2.5.
Oh, interesting.
Right. That's it. And you,
you,
you can't buy more coverage if you're not vaccinated,
like, they just won't.
I mean, that's because insurance companies, they run out of spreadsheets,
like they understand the math
and to keep in mind, like,
I'm a Canadian going from a single payer state to the US where
like, everything's fine here. It's great.
It's
great.
I once paid and this is like 30 year, well, 20 or 30 years ago,
like I paid 100 and 70 bucks out of pocket because I got strep while I was
in the US and I needed antibiotics and like
she literally looked at my throat and went,
yeah, that's strep.
Here you go.
-- I'm impressed. It was only 100 and 70 dollars.
-- Well, this was like 25 years ago.
Ok.
That's fair.
But, uh, yeah, now, I, I don't even want to know.
All right, let's dig in,
let's dig into this form because I think we've spent what,
like 15 minutes going around in circles.
All right. All right.
So I want to start out by saying the form is broken up into four sections.
OK? Section one
talks about your environment.
This is like your company, your, your cybersecurity, your information security.
I don't think cybersecurity is right. Whatever it doesn't matter.
So, so basically what I'm just gonna read it,
it's
a
number one, the software is developed and built in secure environments.
Those environments are secured by the following actions at a minimum.
A separating and protecting each environment
involved in developing and building software.
B regularly logging,
monitoring and auditing trust relationships used for authorization and access.
And then it says I
to any software
and build environment and I I among components within each environment,
c enforcing multi factor authentication and
conditional access across the environments relevant to
developing and building software in a manner
that minimizes security risk and d taking
consistent and reasonable steps to document as well as minimize use or inclusion
of software products that create undue risk
within the environments used to develop and
next page build software e encrypting sensitive
data such as credentials to the extent
practicable. Is that a word and based on risk, you must be a word
f implementing defensive cybersecurity
practices including continuous monitoring
of operations and alerts and as necessary,
responding to suspected and confirmed cyber incidents.
Cool
winds.
They
eventually responded. It was fine
to
remember
like the whole,
oh, it just affects one customer. Oh, maybe just 20,
all of them.
So, so here's what I find,
I guess kind of the most interesting about this whole form here.
So if you look at the SSDF, it's broken down into similar sections
and it has like a multitude of control examples. But I will say
the,
their, their references they use are like all over the place.
And that is just,
I think a common trait of a standard that isn't as fleshed out as it would be someday.
But I think,
I think by distilling this form like this
makes it accessible,
I'm just looking at the first thing and there's 1234567899 different vendors
and agencies or organizations represented in
something like a dozen different standards.
-- Like there's,
-- uh,
-- you're looking at the SSDF,
-- the
-- spreadsheet.
-- There's like nist a loss. There's n,
well, sorry, I counted this twice.
There's um,
oh,
wow. There's B SIM, there's PC, I, there's,
it's alphabet soup.
Oh, it's, it's bananas for sure.
And there's even some of that stuff.
I couldn't even find some of those when I was looking them up one day.
I literally don't know what they are.
I will note that most of them are not hyperlinked and that's one thing that drives
me nuts every time somebody says let's use iso 8601 for date and time standards.
I'm like, cool. Have you read it?
Because I sure as heck haven't because I went to and it was like 200 bucks.
Yeah, you have to pay
for
it.
-- So I
-- use RFC. What is it? Triple 39 or 933.
-- I
-- don't remember the number but I know it, they're, they're almost exactly the same.
There's like minor differences.
But that's one thing I realize now that I really hate is
when people make standards where you have to go by that standard.
Because back to the Lutz and Crypt thing, even a one penny
is
too much hassle and too much difficulty for most people. And,
well, these things should be easy to find if you to make them a standard. Right.
And it's funny because courts have ruled but
like governments can't
make
requirement like legislation secret,
like you have to give it away for free or make it available because that's,
that's a thing now that's happening where like a lot of governments,
regional municipal plumbing codes.
I don't want to dwell on this section
either because this section is information security.
And I think from the perspective of supply chain, it is vastly less interesting
than the other sections. I will say this though. I think
the days of just being able to ignore a lot of information security and be like, yeah,
whatever, it's good enough.
Those are done for any company selling anything to the US government.
Like just
you, you, you're gonna, you have to have information security.
You have to have things like logging, you have to be doing like single sign on.
It's the way it is now. Like
-- that's it.
-- It's, well, it's a maturity thing, right?
We've gone from it being a nice to have, it helps the business to
mcdonald's had a global ITO
and couldn't sell hamburgers.
I heard that.
Right. Like this is no longer, uh,
it's a core part of life and
secure development is
becoming a core part of shipping software
securely because the Attackers have figured out
like, why hack a government agency
when you can hack solar winds
or you can hack
Octa or you can hack
somebody who, you know, well, like, uh, not Petya. Right.
Russia smartly was like,
why should we hack Ukrainian businesses when we hack the
one piece of tax accounting software that they all use?
All right, let's keep going. I wanna, I wanna read number two.
So number two says the software producer makes a
good faith effort to maintain trusted source code,
supply chains by employing automated tools or
process to address the security of internal code
and third party components and manage related vulnerabilities.
So,
I mean, the idea behind this is basically
like, don't use crap software when you build your software
and also probably have version control because not everybody does.
That comes next that
it's number three.
But I mean, this is an example of the, everyone keeps talking about how
you, you shouldn't just be like
running year years out of date dependencies and
like what is going on inside of all this third party code you're running.
And, and historically,
we've ignored a lot of that
and I think this kind of harkens to a degree to like S
bombs right where you're going to need to know what you're running
and
you're going to need to know where it came from.
But that, that's not in this particular section
but, and not only that,
but the thing I like is they talk about automated tools and if you look at the, the,
the 800 to 18, it, it, it points at 13 of the controls for this particular paragraph,
which is quite a lot.
So like this, this reads simple, but it's not gonna be
super
-- duper simple.
-- Well, this is like saying, you know, you need to build a safe car
-- when that involves the car rolling over down a hill,
-- right?
-- You're gonna need some engineering
-- and,
and here's the thing I like the most is when you read this,
it says you make a good faith effort,
right? It doesn't,
that's, that's part of it as well,
I think is when you're dealing with a lot of this compliance stuff,
like
sometimes making a good faith effort to do the right thing
-- is valuable.
-- Well, I would actually say in this case, it's what's practical
because we don't have an actual like,
-- yeah, standard to hold people to like
-- that's true.
But this is a great example like like the car industry where it was like, ok,
you know, we, we make safe cars but now that has meaning of three point seatbelts,
airbags headrest, so your head don't get whiplash crumple zones.
-- Um All sorts of clever engineering.
-- This is a good example because today, if you read
N I
800 to 18, it's not very prescriptive, right?
It talks about a bunch of these activities.
It references a bunch of standards and if
you read a bunch of the reference standards,
they don't even necessarily
have any teeth or make sense sometimes.
And this is one of those instances where
if you look at the, the evolution of automobile safety,
it took 100 years to get better.
And this is like step one and a lot of these controls aren't well written
and they're really squishy and you can meet them
with very poor solutions. But
that's ok. Again, this is why SISA
is going to collect these
and then they're going to learn to put it
bluntly infosec is still at the arguing about handwashing stage
of safety and risk management.
Yep, for sure. OK.
I'm gonna move on to number three because we're running ourselves out
of time and we still have a lot more to go.
All right. Number three, the software producer maintains provenance
for internal code and third party components incorporated
into the software to the greatest extent feasible.
Which is a polite way of saying if you ship a Java app,
there's gonna be stuff in there that you can't figure out where it came
from because some maven think built another
maven thing that included a maven thing.
But now you're stuck with a package with an MP3 in it.
-- So
-- we have no idea what software provenance really means.
Here's what's going to happen.
You say software provenance to a lot of people and they're going to say, oh,
you just need digital signatures and you can use SIG store and you
can use this tool and you can use P GP and all this.
Here's the honest truth
and, and you can add me on Mastodon all you want,
like all of this digital signature stuff.
It all sucks and most of it doesn't actually work. Well.
-- It also presupposes a trusted supply to sign it
-- to a degree.
Yes, it, it, you, you guarantee nothing for sure.
Well, this is like saying, you know, uh
the bank kind of keeps track of all the money coming in
but you don't know if that's money laundering money or like Kurt's paycheck, right?
-- You don't know where this money and
-- look, this is a problem we need to solve.
I'm not saying we shouldn't solve it. But I'm saying
-- anyone telling you they can do this is probably selling you a bridge
-- there.
And there's a simple reason why it's because
we haven't even properly defined the problem yet.
And so if somebody says they have the solution to this,
yeah, we, like I said, we have not properly defined. We don't.
And for the people that have defined the problem,
ask three vendors and you get three totally different answers,
right? There's no agreement yet.
And that's part of the maturity process where like
Cisa and Nist and the US government comes in
and drags us forwards into
the like, essentially like English.
If, if, well, if the US government says you're putting barcodes on everything, then
people say, OK, we're putting barcodes on stuff
and barcodes become a thing.
Yeah, for sure. Now, now here's the thing I want to point out for, for provenance
is
if you read the SSDF standard, it defines this in a, we'll say,
not particularly just prescriptive manner.
-- I don't know where to
-- go.
They do.
And that's ok.
And look, here's the thing
in many instances,
you can meet these if you have an S bomb with check
sums and you store the S bomb in a secure location,
which I can't define what that means either.
But,
well, I think what they, the intent would be is it can't easily be altered,
it can't easily, you know, so like github
-- would work
-- exactly
right. The, the point of this is to be able to say that
I have some software that Kurt gave me and Kurt got some software from somewhere else
and it looks like what I have
isn't what Kurt gave to me?
What happened along the way?
And where was the problem in,
in? Is it, was it malicious? Was it stupidity? We don't know.
And this is the problem with the whole digital signature thing
is like I download a binary for the sake of argument,
I'm gonna pick on curl.
I download a binary from curl. Right.
And
I,
and let's,
let's pretend that curl doesn't publish checks,
sums in a secure manner that I can verify or validate against.
So I take this
package curl
blah, blah, blah dot TGZ.
And I get the Shaw 512
and I put that into my little secure repo we thing.
And then, yeah,
when I hand it to you and you hand it downstream and downstream and ship it,
we know that what I downloaded that. Shaw 512 is what ultimately ended up
in the software, we ship that, you know, runs a car or an F-35 fighter jet or whatever.
But
yeah,
like we don't know what the heck Kurt downloaded could have been an accidental,
it could have been a copy of Tetris for all we know.
No, like and that's the thing, right? So all and even even if
so let's assume Curl provides secure digital hashes,
you know that they publish on the website that are signed and blah, blah, blah.
But like what process did they do to make sure that this thing is
-- kind of what we all think it is. Well, let
-- me, let me, let me use a better example. Ok.
So I'm installing packages with N PM,
right?
Or, or no, I'm gonna use Go go is a better example because it is
so I install a a go package
which I don't know if they call them packages doesn't matter.
So I install the Go, I'm calling them packages. I install the GO package.
What, what happens then
is you end up with this Go dot Sum file in your Go project
that just tracks the hashes of all the stuff you've installed.
And so now I can say, ok,
this your Go dot Sum has this hash,
I see that go dot Sum traversing the, the C I and development process.
And the thing, the go dot Sum at the end is the same as a Go dot Sum at the beginning.
So I know that
everything inside your walls was operating on this particular artifact.
Now, let's figure out where this artifact came from and make sure that's the thing,
you know what I mean?
And that's the beauty of this is now
the ST prior to this,
we didn't even know what to check and
like validate an audit.
But now we actually have a thing that I can hand to
the auditors and say this is actually the thing that we used,
right?
It's like screws
if I get a box of screws.
And I like there's manufacturing processes that do this where they literally set
aside a few items of the screws or the components or the whatever
in case there's a problem so they can go back and test it
because some testing you can't affordably do
in like metallurgical testing for example. Right.
Um Well, I guess you could do a strain test.
But whatever point is, this is part of the road to
part of the frustration I think is that we won't actually have
a secure system and ecosystem until we've done all these other steps.
And they kind of,
and it's like to put it bluntly, even 95% of doing this is
you still don't have a finished solution.
And that's part of the challenge here is like, OK, so even if you do s
bomb and even if you do digital signatures perfectly and securely and everything
today, you still effectively have
not a lot
like you can't actually attest that this software is safe and secure.
I mean, that's a different problem though, right?
This is a matter of showing the provenance chain of command,
but the people are conflating these issues.
That's why I'm saying it's
true.
That's
-- true
-- in the real world people are saying,
so this software is secure and what they mean
by that
is like, oh,
you audit it for bugs and it's secure
and it's built development and what we're saying,
no, no, no.
What we mean is
we have like there could be ferrets and peanuts in here.
We're not entirely sure it's, there's a big power source,
but it was curl
version 1.2 0.6 us released by curl and we made reasonably certain
that's what the like the rest of the world agrees on that,
which in past worked quite well.
But now it doesn't because Attackers have learned, like, with solar winds again,
like
you
compromise
the C I CD at the source
and yeah, everybody's like,
yeah, we all agree. We all downloaded Curl. It's this version. It's all the same.
Hash, we're good. Right. Well, maybe an attacker got it. Maybe they didn't,
you know, Curl does have, as he said, you know,
they've had their build process and development
process audited and they're open source.
So that actually makes it a lot easier.
But for a lot of close source stuff like,
-- yeah, come on you and I both like,
-- yeah,
yeah, for sure, for sure. I I'm gonna read number four now and, and that's it.
This is like the last one. So it says
the software producer employed automated tools or
comparable processes that check for security vulnerabilities.
In addition,
a the software producer operates these processes on an ongoing
basis in prior to product version or update releases.
B the software producer has a policy or process
to address discovered security vulnerabilities prior to product release.
And c
the software producer operates a vulnerability
disclosure program and accept reviews and
addresses disclosed software vulnerabilities in a
timely fashion according to any timeline specified
in the vulnerability disclosure program or applicable policies.
-- And
-- to be blunt,
what this boils down to is you consume CV E and maybe your language ecosystem thing
and you
-- pay somebody for a bug bounty,
-- not necessarily pay someone for a bug bunny, I
mean,
or not a bug bounty, but like you have, like, security, whatever
you need a security ad in, in a vulnerability disclosure policy, which is,
there's an iso standard that you have to pay for and kind of sucks. But
there's, it's, it's very doable. Right.
I find the part almost more interesting
is just talking about automated tools to
look for vulnerabilities because I think historically,
-- that's never really been a requirement for anyone. Right.
-- You know what?
You're probably right. And again, that's the overton window shifting.
Like we accept that these have to be automated tools. They can't,
it, well, it can't be anything else.
-- Yeah. That's right. That's right.
-- Like, it can't be people.
Right. Right.
You know, especially if you're doing a new build every month or every week. Right.
Right. For sure. For sure.
Kurt and I have talked about this at length
countless times but, like
we worked at Red Hat and we were, like, we were very, it was silent. Green of security.
Right.
Like, it was all people at that time because there weren't tools, like, always.
-- Yeah, it was people
-- and
I bought S sds so I could unpack all of the
source code and then run Grep and wait half an hour.
Yeah, I remember doing stuff like that
-- also
-- finding ways to run Grep on all that without it running out of argument space.
Right. Because you can grab 6 billion files. It just grap
goes too many arguments. But
so you have to like do a find with X rgs.
That's
right.
Uh Which you can also thank goodness you can run in parallel
-- one
-- to
-- four good rule, thumb, one grip per core
-- giver. Anyway, the point is right.
I I
found this particular section the most interesting.
Now, mind you,
it has 19 of the controls from 800 to 18 are referenced
here and then those controls reference all kinds of other stuff.
And so unwinding this one is going to be really, really, really hard to do.
But fundamentally this one makes sense, right.
We're going to scan our product before release
-- for security
-- vulnerabilities for known security vulnerabilities.
Right. Right.
And then it doesn't tell you what you have to do with them.
It doesn't say you have to fix all the criticals before release.
It doesn't say you have to fix all the importance before release.
It basically just says
you have to do this thing
and then it does say that you have
a policy or process to address discovered vulnerabilities,
which I mean, that totally makes sense.
If you're a a company, you're going to do that.
Well, the reality too is again,
it varies by vendor and sector and vertical and whatever,
you know, because one thing I was always wondering like for example, submarines,
they can't get like over the air software updates,
right. You know,
and also
they're like running windows 95 on a system that is, well, it's water
gaped, not air gapped,
but it's like water gapped. And so,
you know, there's, there's,
I think this boils down to this is part
of finding out like what are the risk profiles and
getting the vendors to behave in a rational way
because if you try one size fits all here,
it's gonna fail horrifically.
Right. That's right. That's right. And again,
sis is going to collect this. Now, now here's the other thing I wanna, I wanna say.
So when you submit this form, you don't just sign the form and be like I'm all done.
Good job, everyone, you need to submit evidence,
right? You can't say we have a
a policy for addressing
discovered vulnerabilities.
You have to attach your policy
attachments.
And so that's what's actually going to happen with this is this is going to collect
a gigantic amount
of information from that evidence that gets submitted.
I just found a major flaw in this thing.
Did you read page eight yet?
Uh I've read all of the pages.
The public reporting burden to complete this information collection is
estimated at three hours and 20 minutes per response,
including time for reviewing instructions, searching data sources,
gathering and maintaining the data needed
and completing and reviewing the collection of information.
I'm sorry,
I'm I don't think there's many vendors that are mature
enough to do this in three hours and 20 minutes,
like collecting the data and getting it all together is probably gonna take days.
-- So,
-- ok, I want to address that specifically because
when I fill this out at anchor,
it's gonna take me about four hours to collect all the data. But, but
I have been spending months
putting this stuff together because like when 802 18 was published,
obviously as a company that works with this stuff, I'm like, we're gonna make,
we're gonna make sure we can meet all of this.
And of course,
being a company that literally builds the
solution that meets most of these requirements.
I'm like
just by existing, we meet a bunch of these requirements,
but you get the idea right is like
I spent months
making sure we had all of our ducks lined up if you start from nothing
and you have to implement this. And I think that's the key.
What that, that burden statement,
that burden statement assumes you're already doing this stuff.
If you're doing all of these things,
collecting the evidence is probably gonna take three hours and 20 minutes.
It assumes the maturity level of the Linux kernel.
If you're not doing any of this stuff, it's going to take you six months.
Like
I suspect well,
and the classic thing is a lot of places probably are doing some of the
stuff but ad hoc not automated or not consistently or not monitored or not.
We all and, and that's part of the whole point of this is to
drag the maturity forwards.
-- Sure, for sure. And that's a good thing. Yep.
-- Yep. That's right.
It kind of amuses me that you pointed that out because I do remember reading that
and at first I was looking through this and I'm like, I don't see anything, like
there's not really anything about evidence in here. Right.
It doesn't really say anywhere specifically.
And then I got to the burden statement, I'm like, ah,
there it is,
there is where they talk about it.
Well, I think honestly my parting thought on all of this is
there's a reason that all of these standards have a dash version number.
That's, that's my take on this is that this is
a good start
and we will learn from it
and there will be a new one in about 2 to 3 years
or maybe
sooner even.
-- No,
-- it won't be sooner. Ok. So here's the other thing to remember though.
So uh the latest 218,
um I think it's version two we're on now. No 1.11 0.1 I just looked it up.
Well, I don't mean just that, but the, the
attestation form itself,
-- the
-- form, but here's the thing. So here's the thing you need to understand
that
attestation form is about a year in process right now
where
SISA released a draft of it.
And, and also I read the draft and the final version aren't like hugely different.
They, they added some of the I pinky square, I'm doing this boxes
check and stuff. But
as a rule, a final draft of a government document should not
like if the final draft and the actual final are different,
that means that you messed up big league
-- thing. But, but so
-- basically, like it took
almost a year to go from creation of this to final draft when they update it.
-- There's a lot of subtlety
-- here,
but what's going to happen is they're probably going
to collect data for at least a year,
then they're going to change it.
And then, so you're talking a minimum of two years,
probably three or four from right now
until we see the next version of this form, which is wild.
The other benefit of this form too. Is it basically states
what like vendors and products like security,
vendors and products need to do and provide?
So I assume at anchor,
you were like already kind of doing this stuff because like, well,
if you're doing supply chain security
-- and you want to make it secure,
-- we're basically doing all this stuff.
You're going to be like at least 80 90% overlap.
But now it's like, no, no,
here's like some of the specific things we really need to
support or do or handle and make easier for customers.
And that is a definite boon to customers
because it makes their life easier and they can actually,
you know, get better security. And that I think is the most interesting thing is this
also now this becomes part of the ecosystem
and it defines other parts of the ecosystem
that now vendors can step up and do better and make more compatible and easier.
And to put it bluntly,
this is one of those things where
it's not perfect, it will never be perfect.
But yeah, if every vendor actually did this attestation form,
like with at least 90 95% actual sort of compliance.
Holy cow, would the industry move forward?
-- Like that would drag so many people out of the stone age
-- and, and that look, that's,
that's the key, right?
And that's how we're going to end this show is just the fact that this isn't perfect.
Everyone knows it's not perfect,
but it's the first step in what it's going to be a very long journey.
Well, and the thing is, there's also been a lot of other little steps along the way,
like the standard, like
the executive order, like
your stuff didn't exist 20 years ago.
No, no, I mean, Anchor
is like five years old.
Not even well, but I mean,
it didn't even exist as an idea of something we should maybe do
really.
And fly chain security was kind of like
it's on a server and we back it up to.
Well, well, no, no, I think like Red Hat
started the journey.
But Red Hat's solution was just to hire a
lot of really smart people to work really hard.
And that doesn't fly anymore.
-- Like that's not how it works
-- well. And that's a perfect example. The fact that
this has to be automated,
that's it.
It just like we can have people building
tools and operating tools and managing the tools,
but we can't have people doing the work anymore.
-- That ship sailed,
-- I mean N PM is millions of packages
like
it.
It's still my favorite example was still the time
I told some people at the open ssf if we
conducted a security audit of 1000 packages a day,
which is an insane number, there's absolutely no way that's reasonably practical.
It would take 10 years to audit N PM assuming
no new versions are added over that 10 year span
and that they're like their heads exploded because it's like, holy crap.
This is a ridiculous problem.
I was trying to find some code I wrote and something
specific I'd written and it took me about half an hour
just to find my own code.
Yeah. Yeah, it's,
that's for sure. So anyway, ok, let's, let's, let's finish this one out.
Here's what I'm gonna say.
I'm really excited for this at a station
form partially because I'm a huge security nerd,
partially because I already did a bunch of work.
So I actually get to fill it out and be like, hey, look, at me everyone.
I did it, but more importantly is just the fact that we,
you and I have been complaining
about
all of this security crap for so long and how, like, we don't do it right.
And no one takes it seriously.
And like, when are we, like, think of the Children, everyone.
And this is it, this is how it starts. It's going to take decades
to get to a point where I think we'll see like good real change.
-- But this is how it starts
-- survivable car crashes.
Like
most car, like most car crashes. Now you just
like you walk away from them and you leave bits
of your car behind.
Exactly.
Exactly. That like
this, this is it, this is what it looks like. And
now I'm, I'm hopeful
it continues because there's also the possibility
that the industry will complain and gnash their teeth
and whale and the government's gonna be like,
all right, I guess we'll let you go.
I don't think this can be undone. The genie is out of the ball.
We have too many high profile hacks.
You have the entire US healthcare system stumbling along for a few weeks.
Like
this is not an option anymore,
right? Like people realize
software runs the world that we depend on to live.
It does. We're gonna find out, man.
I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to social security podcast.com. Head up the show. Not CZ Pound
Doses podcast. Hashtag
Ione Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.