I'm always right.
Put that. Keep that in the show.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Episode 158 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Bresser.
Oh, my goodness. I finally have faster internet than Kurt. I am ecstatic today.
Allegedly. A good day. That's true. Allegedly, we,
we will. So
for, for listeners,
we use a service called Zencastr to record these shows where basically we
both connect to a website and we do our business and at the end
we upload the wave files from our respective computers.
And
when I hit stop,
Kurt's upload is done.
But by the time my finger comes off the stop button, I think,
and then my upload takes more than one minute and it makes me sad.
And I just got gigabit internet installed
10 minutes before we started recording this.
The tech left my home. So in theory,
-- I have extremely fast internet right now.
-- Yeah. No,
we'll see. I'm excited.
I'm excited. Yeah.
And, and I mean, it sounds like it was really easy to get that internet too.
I mean,
they just dropped the fiber in your backyard and bam it was installed right away.
Right.
-- Isn't that what happened?
-- I could write
an epic tale of everything that happened as part of this process and
it's everything from my existing or my, I guess my old internet company now they,
the people who work for them tried really hard to help me,
but it's clear
they did not know what to do when I would say
because it's so,
I'll just tell you the beginning of it is I called them up and I said, look,
a new company just dropped Gigabit fiber in my backyard.
What can you do for me?
And they just said, we can knock $20 off your bill.
And I said, I don't want $20 knocked off my bill. I want Gigabit internet
and they said, well, we can't do that. And I'm like,
that's it. Like,
that's the thing though, like hard. Like
this is what gets me is a quote unquote, simple problem. Like
getting you potable drinking water
is actually really hard and expensive.
You know,
I know a guy that lives out in the boonies and the city he's near wants to force all the,
all the sort of acreage donors onto the city water system
so that they can essentially,
it looks like they want to force the existing owners
onto the city water system and have them pay for it
so that the new land developers can get water a lot cheaper
because guess what the city is going to be charging him the,
the sort of the cheapest plan to hook him up to the water city supply.
-- I bet it's outrageous.
-- It's about 45 grand Canadian.
Yeah,
that's about what I would expect for that
because running all that is very expensive.
Well, 45 grand Canadian to put in perspective, like that's
the back of the envelope that buys him about 200 years of water trucks,
which is what he currently uses.
Like he literally just has a guy in a truck show up once a week and fill up his cistern.
He doesn't have a, well, they have a well,
but they don't drink that water or cope with that water.
Right. So, yeah, they have a well for like
whatever, washing the cars and stuff, you know, that kind of thing,
watering the garden.
But yeah, no, they have a system because, you know, it's really hard water.
It kind of, you know, it's not nice.
Yeah. Anyway, so, I mean, that's the thing, infrastructure.
I mean,
this is why I think cell phones took off so rapidly is
because you only got to run infrastructure to cell phone towers,
not to every darn house.
-- But
-- even in that respect, I mean, especially in the United States,
we don't have a lot of options for cellular service
and internet is generally even worse in most places.
And
I mean, I guess this is part of the story that,
that I think comes out of this is the fact that
my old internet company
was the only game in town if you
wanted anything faster than just potato speed Internet.
And the new company runs fiber optic all over the place. And the old company is like,
we don't know what to do. We, ok.
-- And they, they tried to offer me,
-- you know, I have a hard time feeling sorry for them.
I, I don't, I really don't, it's, I don't really care for either, but whatever,
it doesn't matter.
-- I have gigabit Internet.
-- Well, here's the thing.
What gets me these companies, uh, no offense.
Clearly the future of the internet is faster. Internet.
Yeah.
But a
lot of these companies don't seem to get it or care, you know,
like for the longest time when I talked to so, locally I have Sean, tell us.
Right.
They, Sean owns the cable, tell us, owns the phone stuff, you know,
I would have said copper but now it's a lot of fiber
and so, like Shaw for the longest time.
I was like, ok, you have, you know, you have pretty good coax
cable.
Most of it's relatively, like, less than 30 years old you put in two way op amps.
So it's, you know, you can get pretty decent speeds. But like,
yeah, what, what are we going to do for, you know, how,
how's that a whole I PV six thing?
And how's that whole, like, faster than 50 megabits thing coming along
and for the longest time they didn't really have a good answer.
So I was like, well, ok, you know. Yeah, the, uh, the other
evil company dropped fiber in my neighborhood, you know, and they'll sell me
faster internet for cheaper than your plans. So, exactly. What can you do for me?
And they're like, again.
Yeah, they're like, we can, I think it was take $5 off your bill.
Yeah, it's like, I don't care. I want faster internet.
-- Well,
-- no, but it's like I'm still paying more
-- for slower internet. So, like, right,
-- and even at one point
they offered me
double the cost of the new company for almost similar speeds.
And I was like,
I would probably take that deal just because I don't have to
go through the hassle of an install and all the other nonsense.
And then they like, ok, well, it's turned on
and I said, uh, don't, I need new gear and they're like, oh, no, your gear is fine.
And I'm like, this is pretty old gear. I don't think you can do those speeds.
And of course, they,
they transferred me to the tech support
department and tech support people are like,
we need, we need to send a tech out to your house.
It's going to cost you $200. And I said, no, I'm not paying you to like,
right, new company has reinstalled like, just no way. And,
and it was funny they were completely unable
and, and I don't blame the people. Right.
I think the people who were trying to help me were legitimately trying, but, like,
they were completely unable to do anything about this
and at the end of the day it's like,
well, screw it.
I wonder what it's like to work for a company like that to, I mean,
do these people realize that they're basically on,
they're on a clock now?
I'm certain they know it and I'm sure they have ridiculous requirements
where they have to get off the phone after so many minutes.
And that's the thing, like at the end it's
says, oh, can you, will you take a survey about the person you spoke with? Right.
And even though they didn't help me, I gave them all like tens because it's,
I knew that if I rate them low, they're going to get freaking fired.
And that's ridiculous too because it's not,
it's not their fault that your company is a flaming pile of garbage.
They're doing their best. So anyway,
but then the story gets even better
because new company wants a credit check. Right. My credit is frozen
and I haven't unfrozen my credit in over five years. And actually
the, since then
the US government passed a law that says
credit freezing and unfreezing has to be free.
It used to cost me $10 per agency per action I took,
and I saw that as an advantage because no
fraudsters gonna pay $10 to unlock my credit.
Right. If they have it. So, anyway,
I go to unlock it. One of them, I couldn't even get it unlocked.
I have to actually mail them a bunch of paperwork now to try to sort all this out.
So I couldn't even get it unlocked with one of them. A second one.
they gave me like a pin. I'm supposed to have to use to unlock it.
Yeah, I totally didn't need that. I ended up.
Uh, so they're like, oh, you have to sign up for a website.
I sign up, I click. Ok. And it says
we can't, you know, we can't create your account.
Please call this phone number, something's wrong.
And I'm like, oh, this is exciting.
So I called them up and I'm on the phone for a long time, we'll say.
And finally I get a human,
which is nice because for company one, I can't, I can't even find a human to talk to,
to be like, what is going on?
What's up? Right.
So, I, I don't know, I don't know if there's like fraud in my account.
I have absolutely no idea what's happening there and I cannot get a human to talk to,
which sucks.
So, anyway, other company
I,
I call them up, I get a human
and I said I tried to create an account on your site and it
didn't work and told me to call this number and the guy just says,
oh, yeah, the account creation is down,
try again in a couple of days and I'm thinking what a couple of days?
This is
just what I mean.
Could you imagine if, if Google's login system went down and they were like, oh,
yeah, in a couple of days we'll have it working again.
Like, no, they would have fired three quarters of that company in a couple of of days.
-- Why can't they also have the website? Tell you this.
-- I don't know.
And that's part of it is, it's clear this website is a, a heap of trash,
unquestionably.
The fact that they, this guy didn't even skip a beat was like, oh, yes,
it's down try again in a couple of days.
It's clear
I was not the first person he talked to about this that day.
So anyway, then I said, fine, whatever
I need to unlock my credit with you. He's like, oh yes, that'll be fine.
And he's basically asked me like two or
three questions which are big in all seriousness.
They were pretty much public knowledge questions.
Then he's like, ok, your credit's unlocked. And I thought,
but no, what? No, I've got this number, I'm supposed to be
you. He's like, oh no, it's fine. I took care of it.
My favorite is, um, I got a piece of mail from Revenue Canada
it was a statement on my account, you know, showing what I paid.
So it's got my name and address on it
obviously because that's how mail gets to people.
And they had
at the top
my uh
social insurance number, it's uh in Canada,
it's a nine digit number and they'd Xed out the first, what is it?
Six digits or something? So you can only see the last three digits.
And I'm like, fantastic.
Except
these forms come in a standard, even if it's like a, even if you have like a zero
balance,
it's a standard Remittance form and in the standard Remittance form,
what do they print at the bottom?
-- Let me
-- guess your full ID.
Yeah,
I was like, well, they're trying, it's,
it's better because back in the olden days it just, it had like curtsy free,
you know, 123456789, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
-- So now you'd actually have to unfold the letter and look at the bottom.
-- Yeah.
In fact, I remember there was at one point it was, I think a gas company,
my account number was my social security number
and I'm thinking this is probably not. Ok. How's that legal?
It will, I think it was at the time. I don't think it is anymore.
Or even if it is still legal, they don't do it.
-- Well, no,
-- they just changed it on the back end to show a different number. But the
back end is
still
very
much.
Yeah, whatever.
Anyway, anyway, so it gets even better. Ok, whatever. They unlock my credit.
I don't give them the magic number. I'm supposed to have to give them
and I'm like, I don't even care. Whatever. Ok,
so then third company,
the letter they sent me
long ago. This was like, I think 2007 was when I did all this.
So in 2000 it looks like it was typed on a typewriter by a human.
Like the thing they gave me because II,
I was looking at it and I was like, this really doesn't look like a computer did this,
which whatever I don't care.
Like I locked my credit
very early in this whole universe. So it is conceivable.
A human actually did a bunch of this one.
I go to their website and it, it looks like something out of the nineties
and it was ridiculous.
And right, I click around, I do my, uh,
it probably is out of the nineties but it worked.
It was the only freaking one that actually worked.
And I'm thinking, I don't even know what to say.
Yeah,
probably because it's the same mainframe running
from the nineties and it actually,
you know, some human updated of files.
It was just like I,
I get done
and,
and then luckily I sign up for internet and I'm thinking,
please don't use that one credit agency that I
can't figure out right now and they didn't.
And, and,
and then the here's the best part though,
the one shining light in this ridiculous story
is I click, you know, I click the button. It's like, great.
You're all set, pick a day for the install and freaking tomorrow,
which is today was on.
And I'm like,
this is insane.
I see it. Literally, I signed up last night,
the guy showed up 12 hours later
installed my internet and, and I told him I'm like,
I signed up for this last night and he looked at me and said,
there's at least a 10 day waiting period for almost everyone signing up right now.
So I'm like,
I'll take it, you know, finally for once the universe smiled upon me after the,
the pain and suffering I went through to get here.
No, it's, it's good. It's good.
It was,
it was really fast and I'm impressed by how all this gear
works because actually I was bugging the heck out of the guy
when he was doing the install.
And I mean, I remember back in the day when you ran fiber optic cable,
you had to be like, nice and straight
and you had to worry about, you know, if you, you clipped an end,
you had to do all this polishing.
-- Yeah. The new stuff is super squishy. Freaks me out. Yeah,
-- it's what he showed me.
He bent some of it like he broke it
and you have to bend it substantially before it works
like it was wild.
Well, the bend radius on the cable they installed internally in my house here,
the bend radius on it is literally a few millimeters like you can, you could,
you could pretty much tie it in a knot.
Pretty, pretty much. Yeah. Yeah, it's wild. It's nothing like it used to be.
I have a funny story for you after Equifax breach. Here's your next story. Weak pins.
So,
apparently the pin numbers they've been setting
on these credit freeze things are guessable.
Can't be reset. Always quite often don't work and so on and so forth.
That doesn't surprise me. And this is from September 2017.
Which, yeah, again, I mean, I wonder how many of them are? 1234.
No, no, they send you the pin. Yeah, that's what I mean.
-- They set a pin and,
-- but they're, no, it's not 1234.
Like mine are actually like 6 to 8 digit numbers. They're fairly long,
but I don't know how they generated them. I mean, it's conceivable.
It's just like a freaking hash of my last name or something too. I don't know.
But I would,
I would not trust their random number generators for these pins in any way.
It's just at the same time
it's enough work.
I don't think, uh, uh, unless like I'm being actively targeted,
I don't think anyone's going to care enough and let's face it,
I'm being actively targeted.
They could just come and hit me with the stick until I give them the documents,
which I, I totally would,
-- please don't hit me with
-- a quote from somebody in the industry is we
are engaged in a process that will provide consumers a randomly generated pin.
What were they doing before that?
I, I could, I could read that a couple of ways. It could be like a Atotp style token
or it could be a matter of quit picking freaking 1234. And here's some numbers.
See what gets me is it seems like that classic thing of like we gave you security.
Why are you complaining?
Yeah,
the security doesn't really work and it's horrible to
use and it's like you might as well,
you know,
it's like having somebody standing behind you with a plate and a fork going screech.
You know, the whole time
from my perspective, actually,
the intent of my credit freezes is just so basically nobody can steal my credit.
-- And I would say,
-- well,
they can still steal your credit, they can just
-- as easily.
-- Ok, that's fair, but it's very difficult.
So I think the bar of difficulty is even higher than I would expect it to be.
So, on that note, we're doing great,
but the reality is as a consumer trying to actually use these services,
uh they all get a giant for, well, the last company
they don't.
That was, I think, Transunion,
but everyone else fails. I fail the rest of them. Well, there's only two others.
-- Well,
-- it's not like you can take your business elsewhere. Right.
-- No.
-- Exactly. I have no choice. So,
whatever.
I mean, I think this is a fundamental problem is you can freeze your credit.
I can still very easily steal your data.
It's now just a little bit harder to use
your data And see that's what fundamentally this all,
uh, it's a lot harder.
Well, yeah,
compared to the average. Right.
But what frustrates me and this is what
gets me about this whole identity theft thing is
the problem isn't the stealing
of identities.
The problem is that it's so easy given a little bit of information about somebody
to then go do things like purchase a mortgage in
their name or get a car in their name or whatever
where these companies are like, well, basically we're going to
hand over this asset to you that may be
worth tens or hundreds of thousands of dollars.
And, uh, oh, you, you seem to know your own address, phone number and date of birth,
mother's maiden name.
Yeah. Good enough close.
Right. Right. You know,
and it terrifies me,
you know, that we have these really major assets that you can then be on the hook for
and
there's no real and quite often there's not really
a good process to deal with problems in it.
Like the great example is that guy,
there's a story about a hacker who got the license plate of null. Null.
Yeah, that was a good one.
And he's getting like thousands and thousands of
dollars in parking tickets and speeding tickets and stuff
because when they don't know, like what the license plate is or whatever,
they just put null.
So they mail this guy, like this guy is getting all these tickets
and
the system isn't inherently
able to deal with this.
First of all,
don't do dumb stuff. And that guy was too so clever. He's dumb.
Well, I mean, this is like the time when my, my old ISP again, shaw,
not to pick on them too much.
But they used to let you pick your host name.
Right. That was kind of cool because they gave you a static IP.
-- And you could pick a host name and
-- you pick something stupid. I remember this.
-- I
-- picked a local host.
-- You were stupid. It's your own fault.
-- That's not stupid.
-- It
-- was
-- fun. Kurt. It was stupid.
-- I have no sympathy for you
-- until my cable modem tipped over.
I have no sympathy for you. You
did,
it was fine for me. The problem is it broke everybody else's computers.
And so, you know, about an hour after I did this in the evening I told, um, you know,
I actually knew the guy that ran their network and I was like, hey, you know, Kevin.
Um, remember how you, like, restrict host names, like o admin and stuff.
He's like, yeah. And I'm like, you guys didn't reserve local hosts. He's like what
he's like, that explains the network problems we've been having.
Imagine you have an amorphous graph of bad ideas.
And there's a small band in there called Clever Things. OK.
-- Where, so
-- what you're saying is it's like shower temperature,
right? It's exactly like that. Yes.
Where it's a small sliver, it's not big but you cross the line from Clever to Dumb
and it's not a big line.
And the guy who set his license plate to know he crossed the line from Clever to dumb.
I don't feel bad for him. You know, these systems are not written terribly well.
They're not using, you know, the best developers in the world because let's face it.
If you're the best developer in the world, are you going to say?
I really want to write a ticket tracking system for the local police. No, you are not.
And this is the reality of it like,
yes, it's clever but it's so clever. It's dumb. I have no sympathy for that person.
You are you, you are getting the punishment you deserve for your cleverness.
Well done.
Well, I think what, what I find interesting about it is,
is it shows the real fragility and the lack of handling of corner cases,
you know, because a great example is when I told the guy, I was like, I grab local.
He's like, oh,
you know, I'm going to put that on the reserve list, like right now, like, yeah,
that's the correct response, like,
you know, and then, then they added a bunch and I'm like,
you probably want to grab a bunch of these other quasi
reserved names or, you know, common names or what was it?
There used to be something like it was like a default host name, something picked,
you know, a bunch of stuff like that.
And so it's like, OK, you know, they
basically updated their, their blacklist,
but that's what I'm seeing with null is a very weird and special case.
And yeah,
do you put in a specific corner case for null or do you maybe have a generic blacklist?
And like a great example is, you know, we just, I uh I took three of our older websites
that were, they just serve static content, you know, like font files,
stuff like that and I shoved them into an S3 bucket, put cloudfront in front of it,
cloud
in front of cloudfront
and then it broke and I'm like,
oh, why did it break? And it was because I forgot to put a Coors policy on it, you know,
is it cross origin requests?
Something what
I forget,
you know, doesn't matter.
And so then I was like, oh, you know, just for now to make it work,
I'll put a star in there instead of the actual host names of,
of the
things we do, which, you know, and that's on my list
to be clear. That's on my, to do list for today to fix.
So it'll be
fine.
I'm gonna ask you in a year if you fixed it.
-- I bet the answer is no,
-- no, because it's, uh, we're
anyways, but
the thing is what I'm really noticing is
lack of forethought.
And then when people do spot a problem, they almost
always just
spackle over the problem as little as possible to get it to go away
and then move on and I get that because, you know, we're all busy.
They don't do like an actual bit of investigation and go like, oh, whoops, you know,
we should also handle this, this and this and this and we can also fix this problem.
I don't know, like with this whole thing with security,
like this whole credit freeze pin number thing seems to be like,
well, what's the minimum we need to give these people to get them to, like,
shut up and to get the legislators to off our back?
Well, offer a credit freeze and like a secure, a long enough pin is a password. Folks.
Right. To me, a pin is like 12 is a four or maybe even up to a six digit number.
Anything longer than that.
We're starting to talk about passwords. I agree.
And it's so they did the bare minimum they could do to get these people off their back.
They showed them something that sort of worked back in the day.
And of course, you know, 10 years later it doesn't work like you phone, you can't,
your pin number is broken or doesn't exist or the,
you,
the file or who knows?
Exactly.
I don't know what to do or say because this is,
I feel like this is a boiling the ocean problem.
It kind of is, I mean, it's a really hard problem to solve. How do you, let's face it.
We need, I mean, this was, this came up in our conversation with,
with the clerk about the physical name book is
we don't have like a way to identify people beyond a reasonable doubt.
And so we make up all these hodgepodge one off crap systems
and, and this is just the result. It's,
and I don't even think it's that these,
these credit agencies are purposely trying to make my life miserable, even though
-- they do a wonderful job. It's all they have.
-- Well, they have.
Yeah, they have,
it's not even that their technology is bad is that they have like
a business model and a business process from basically the seventies or eighties.
Right. Exactly.
It hasn't changed and the world has, you know,
the world changes a few percent every year.
What I really noticed today, you know, I was in line at the Starbucks
and it was a long line because we hit it right during prime time.
So my son, you know, gave him my phone, he's playing Minecraft.
So he, he, he does not care how long we're going to wait playing Minecraft.
I noticed everybody else in line was like, had their nose buried in their phone,
their smartphone.
Right. And nobody really cared about having to wait in line because
I got the whole internet in my hand.
-- These things have only existed for 13 years.
-- I know it's crazy.
I, I actually, I had a conversation the other day about that with
it was, it was someone in Vegas
and I said, I mean, you think about it,
the smartphones have existed for a little over a decade now.
And could you imagine taking a trip without one? I mean, I remember
I would print out plane tickets. I would print out maps. I would have directions.
-- I would print out all my hotel confirmation numbers
-- because, oh,
I'm ignoring all that.
I'm just worried about being bored on the plane.
Oh, screw that. Like I don't, I'm not, I still read a book for that. I don't care.
But I'm just saying like I used to travel with a folder full of
paperwork and I remember I would show up at hotels and they'd be like,
I don't know who you are.
And I'd say here's my paperwork and they'd say, oh,
they misspelled your name in the system, you know. Now it's better
and it's just,
now I've got a phone and I look on the phone
and the app for the hotel says you have a reservation and
heck there was,
I think it was Hilton. I don't even have to talk to a human anymore.
I just show up, I click a button. It tells me my room number. I go to it.
I hold my phone up to the door and it lets me in and is it insecure? Probably do I care?
No, it's awesome. Like that's, that's the beauty of it.
Hotel security gets me the weirdest because, you know,
fundamentally if you want your room cleaned and you're not gonna haul all your
nice stuff out of there. You know, I, I honestly I got over that years ago.
I just leave all my junk in the hotel room, you know,
and if there's an evil maid attack then yeah, I'm up the creek.
I do not. I'm still very particular about my things.
In fact, when I was in Vegas, a lot of people I work with were like,
why don't you set your bag down?
And I said I, no, not here. I will stay on my back and yet
it sucks. But that's all right. It's, it's how it is.
-- I see
-- this is one of the things I love about how more and
more devices have biometrics because I hate
typing in passwords at these conferences.
I'm always worried somebody go shoulder surf a camera,
you know.
But I, I don't know what's the lesson to be learned here?
I mean, the, in this case they gave us, they gave us security with air quotes.
It doesn't seem to work.
The lesson is if you complain about a problem
on a podcast, you feel a little better at the end.
That's the lesson
I'll buy. I mean, let's face it, man. There's nothing I can do.
I can complain and wine, I can write my con.
In fact, I remember
some time ago I wrote a lot of letters
about all this stuff that the congressman I have.
And they were like, we don't understand what you're talking about and we don't
care to
go.
And it's like, what do you do?
Right. The people in charge don't know what's going on.
The companies that are lobbying for this don't
want change because change is hard and expensive
and as normal people, it's like, well, there's really not a lot we can do either.
So it's like,
I guess we just live our lives and accept
the fact that everything sucks except gigabit internet.
So like, yeah.
And I guess at the same time I have this ridiculous story. It took me
probably three days to get through all this.
But at the end of it, did I get what I wanted? Yes.
Am I gonna remember this pain in a month? No.
So there you go. Yeah,
-- I don't know what else to tell you, man. It is what it is.
-- Well, I think that's sort of,
maybe that's part of the life lesson here is, you know,
people in security need a bit more perspective.
-- Uh,
-- what's, what's their perspective though?
Well, things are not as bad as things are.
We still have, you know, the whole world isn't actually physically on fire.
-- At least not yet. Give it a few more decades.
-- No, I agree with that.
I,
and, and I mean, this is one of our problems, right? Is
I, I have this discussion at work often where
a security person will say,
well, look at this terrible thing
and then someone will say it works right? Like it really isn't, it's been working.
It's not that big of a deal. We're not seeing anyone doing it.
And then, yeah, again, the security person's like, did you hear me yell doom?
I'll yell louder for you.
And it's like they don't care and they know probably as much
about the system as you do and they're not going to listen.
And
now at the same time though,
the, the right way to deal with this is it is an opportunity
to
evaluate
what is happening
and come up with an appropriate response where I think historically,
the security answer has always been,
oh, no, we can't do anything.
You know, let's all go live in caves and,
and use smoke signals and throw rocks at people
when the reality is like, we might get hacked if we do this.
But the payoff
in the meantime is this and if we get hacked here's what we're going to have to do
and it's still significantly less risky and costly than not doing this thing.
And I know that was a bunch of weird descriptions. But, I mean,
it's, it's like, fundamentally, I would say it, it's like
I'm gonna,
I could put a ridiculous steel door on my house that costs say $20,000 and has
the greatest lock in the world.
But is there a payoff there if I do that?
No, not really. I have a normal, you know, couple of $100 door.
You'd have something to talk about at parties. Why?
Because I'm the freak with the big door. Like I'm already a freak for enough reasons.
Kurt, I don't need another one.
I
mean,
I've got, there's, yeah, I, I've got enough against me here.
I don't, I don't need to add to that pile, but like for real. Right.
Is there a payoff there? Definitely not. Is it more secure? Definitely.
But is it stupid?
Yes. Yes, it is.
And anyway, we should, we should stop.
I could complain about this for months and not run out of content. But I think,
I guess fundamentally, yes, that will, we'll make that our lesson.
We look at my ridiculous story. I have a, a silly story to tell and I will tell it.
I promise you.
I will tell it.
So, I've got my stupid story to tell. But at the end of the day, did I get what I want?
Yes. Yes, I did.
And
ok. Yeah, I lost a couple days of my life properly. But
whatever I got gigabit. Internet.
-- Any, I, I'll give you the last word here.
-- Honestly, people
get internet. That's at least 100 megabits a second. It is vastly superior.
No, I'm not kidding. Like it's the difference is,
you know,
you don't necessarily need gigabit. But I mean, I remember when I went above 100. It,
yeah, if you can get above 100 get above 100.
-- It makes life so much, so much less
-- waiting right now.
-- I can watch my Netflix even faster
-- and then,
but the best part is web pages will still load slowly until you get an ad blocker.
Yes, that is very true. The ad blockers make an enormous difference 100%. Uh Cool.
All right. Good deal. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open social security podcast.com. Hit up our show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to get our attention on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.