Hello and welcome to the Open source Security podcast episode 54 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
So, I must say Happy Birthday to Canada. Kurt. I heard it's 100 and 50 years old.
What, a couple days ago.
Yeah. That's awesome. Yeah.
So, well, and Happy Fourth of July to you.
Ah, yes, I know.
Yes. Celebrating all that freedom. Right.
Well, that's, you know, kind of your, one of your inaugural dates.
Uh, yeah. Anyway.
Right. Well,
we'll just ignore that for now. Ok.
Uh, I'd prefer not to get into a bizarre discussion about the state of
the world politics
anyway.
Right. Right. It's,
uh,
no, II, I had no idea.
Actually they were talking about it on the radio about, um,
all the big celebrations in Canada and all the crazy stuff going on.
And I thought, wow, that's,
that's awesome. 150. That's old man.
It's old.
Yeah. Well, yeah.
Yeah, I mean, I've,
I've lived in Europe where they were renovating a 500
year old house in the town I lived in.
Yeah.
But, I mean,
Europe's weird like that because while many of the countries have existed for,
you know, many hundreds of years, sometimes thousands,
they've gone through an amazing amount of turmoil and
borders have been fought over in crazy ways.
And so I think when you think about kind of continuous governments,
there, there probably aren't very many that are more than 100 and 50 years old.
Right.
Well, and the thing to remember too is technically Canada, I mean,
we are constitutional monarchy.
So ultimately, the queen is our head of state.
So we would fall under that government.
You're part of the commonwealth, I guess. Which,
-- no,
-- no, you can be part of the commonwealth and not be
under direct
rule.
So Australia, for example,
changed their constitution back in the, I want to say the nineties or two thousands.
I mean, we, we did a partial change and I think it was 1982. But for example, I mean,
well, the lieutenant governor is still the
head of government in Canada. Like when we have an election.
Um you know, we, we, we vote for various parties and there are those MP S
from the various parties, you know,
uh essentially whichever one gets a majority then goes to
the lieutenant governor and ask permission to form a government
and they can be, they can be told no, right.
Like they, there have been cases where they're like,
uh I think it was uh they wanted to form some sort of coalition government.
I forget exactly what it was and, and they just were flat out told, no,
you can't do that.
You're gonna have to like, figure it out and come back.
-- It sounds
-- like security spending. No, go figure it out, come back later.
So, in some ways, I think it's nice because it gives a bit of sort of stability.
But at the same time it's,
you know, as much as I hate the four year election cycle in the US, for example,
we have a totally
arbitrary election cycle.
So, so does your election cycle work in the same way?
The UK does where the Prime Minister could just be like, oh,
we're going to have an election now.
That's one option. Yes. That's crazy to me. I can't even,
I can't even fathom that.
Well, we went through, what was it? Three national
or three federal elections in the space of like a year or two.
That's insane. People are going to just not care by the end of that
half the people already don't care
anyway.
-- Sorry. But that's the sad reality.
-- You know,
let's talk about sad reality because we can not
Petya.
Uh
Yeah. Well, that's interesting.
I mean,
it appears to have been what a state sponsored cyber attack against the Ukraine.
That
-- ransomware,
-- which is, which is wild because this, this attack actually came out.
I was about to publish the last episode
and then Twitter lit up and I thought I can't publish
anything right now because nobody's going to see it and,
and, you know, I'm not going to waste,
you know, kind of strike when the iron's hot sort of situation. So,
so, anyway, it was funny because we'd recorded shortly before it came out as well.
So we obviously didn't talk about it. But that's probably a good thing
because
what,
there were probably three or four days where nobody had any idea
what was going on and this is just an insane story.
Well, it's, you know, that's one of the things
that that's really actually almost worrying to me
is it's so easy to obfuscate your motives
nowadays.
I mean, for all we know like something like wanna cry, you know,
there were those initial
thoughts that wanna cry was like a targeted cyberattack that went wrong.
Uh Yeah. Yeah.
And, and there's many people who still think it leaked out early because of just the,
the sloppy mistakes that, that it had.
Well, and see what gets me about the sloppy mistakes is that they were,
it wasn't like a,
an error that was like a fundamental like
you guys really aren't good at this or you're
really good at this and you're just pretending to
be really bad at this because quite frankly,
you don't actually have to be that good at
this to like create a worm that rampages through.
Well, WINDOWS XP. I mean, come on.
Uh No, I don't think XP was vulnerable was it,
I think it
did wanna cry affect XP.
Was it only seven?
I
forget
you wanna cry, affected XP.
But in theory you could get the key out of memory because it wouldn't reboot.
But once you rebooted you were up the creek.
No, it's, it's crazy though. I mean, it,
the, the thing that gets me with this is, and, and I forget who even said this.
But I mean, this is,
this is really like
a, I hesitate to say it but it's like a cyber world war at this point. Right.
I mean,
there's clearly countries attacking countries and they're just raising about it.
I mean, there's,
they don't hide it, they're not secret, they're just,
they're,
they're going out and they're just doing like these wide sweeping operations,
which is just kind of it, it's crazy to think about it.
Everyone knows who's doing it.
Everyone knows what's going on and we're like, oh, ok.
Well, part of what gets me is that, you know,
how essentially it really strikes me as the, the, the classic proxy wars, right?
Like where, you know,
Russia and America can't actually have a war
because that will escalate and become a real problem
and
the human race.
Right. Well,
it'll be bad for us.
Um,
and also here's the thing, like,
how do you retaliate to a cyber attack against, say,
a private company or a single bank in your company, uh, country, right?
Like,
do you respond in kind and attack one of their banks or
something or do you take down their power grid for a day?
Like, you know, because there's also that Russian power grid hack, right? Where?
Sorry, the Ukrainian power grid got a bit hacked up probably by the Russians.
And I say this because I'll,
it looks like at this point in my life I will never travel to Russia.
No. Seriously. Right. Like,
uh but yeah, I mean, it's how do you respond
and more to the point kind of,
does that sort of teach them not to do it? Do we?
I,
I part of it is do we end up with like a mutually assured destruction scenario where,
you know, I don't hack you because I know if I hack you, you'll hack back and like,
-- trash my economy for, I
-- don't, I don't know if that's ever gonna happen.
I mean, this is so different and it's so weird.
It's,
it also depends like the,
the mutually sure destruction scenario kind of depends on these
being nation state hackers who actually care about their nation,
right?
Like if you have sort of an, an like, remember anonymous, like anonymous is a brand,
not a group.
And so like,
you know, I don't
think 90% of anonymous would give to figs worth of, you know,
caring about the power grid in some arbitrary country where a bunch of them live.
So how do you sort of threaten retaliation against a group that
isn't even, maybe a group necessarily.
I, I mean, yeah, that's certainly, well, ok.
So, in that case, I think that's the, where law enforcement is kind of a big deal.
And one of the challenges though is
many of these people live outside of the jurisdiction
of the law enforcement where the crime occurred.
Right. Where if you have someone sitting in, you know, middle of nowhere Russia
and they're, they're attacking a credit union in Georgia.
What are the Georgia authorities? Well, Georgia,
I shouldn't say that because Georgia is what
a state in the United States,
Georgia
with the,
let's say Washington DC,
right?
Like, like you attack a small bank or something and, and what do the authorities do?
They can't extradite that person.
There's, they're operating in almost complete impunity,
but then there's also the other side of it where let's
say you have a nation state attacking another nation state.
What,
what really happens there? I mean, nobody's dead.
Your infrastructure might go down for a couple of
days or maybe they stole some hacking materials or,
or whatever.
But, I mean, at the end of the day, I think what,
what really makes a difference in wars is
the kind of attitude of your population really dictates
the war where if the people support the war,
you look at something like World War One, World War Two and,
and America's involvement in it will pick on
the American people were very positive about that and they
were very much behind the government and the soldiers.
Right.
And then you look at another war like Vietnam,
the Vietnam conflict in the United States.
Which, which for those of you who don't live here,
you
know, it wasn't
a war.
I
know.
know
it's madness. But, but anyway, like,
at first people thought, oh, yay,
we're going to bring freedom to Vietnam and then
after a while it turns into a quagmire and,
and they were like, this sucks.
Let's go.
And part of it, I think with, and it's similar to cyber war.
So I, I've read about the Vietnam war bit and
apparently one of the challenges or problems was,
is America viewed it as, you know, sort of communism versus the rest of the world.
And apparently the,
the majority of Vietnamese people viewed it as an internal civil struggle.
It's wild. Actually, I watched a travel show
one day on the local public television station
and they went to Vietnam and they were,
they were showing off like all their memorials and everything and it's like,
holy crap.
They,
they clearly don't think of this conflict like we do,
you know it, yeah, it was very much about bringing freedom to Vietnam and
we thought we were the ones bringing freedom to Vietnam and it's like, this is crazy.
But, but whatever the point being though,
that when we're talking about a cyber conflict,
if if the people don't care,
I don't think you're going to find the, the will to do anything.
I, well, the thing is you don't really need the support of the people, for example,
for, you know,
some government agency to spend $10 million attacking another company, uh,
country's power grid.
But more to the point again, sort of what does that accomplish?
Because part of the challenge too is so somebody hacks a bank.
Well, why, what is their motivation? Did they want to damage the bank?
Did they want to steal money? Did they want to harvest information
so they could chase terrorists down?
Like
we really don't know.
I, I mean, that's true.
There's, there's many different cases and, and I guess at the same time,
let's say somebody hacks a bank, let's say somebody steals all the money,
you get all your money back if you're, you're the, uh, a customer, right?
Because it's insured,
let's say someone hacks the power grid, what are they gonna do?
They're gonna turn it off and they're gonna flip the manual override switch and,
and so, yeah,
power might be down for a day and then it
comes back and two hours later after watching reality TV,
everyone forgot that they didn't have power.
Right. It's,
it's tricky
that they don't do a really bad hack.
But there are, you know, with industrial control systems,
there are a way to permanently damage those things that
take weeks or months to replace
and, and that could certainly be the case. It's,
I don't know, this one's tricky man because I don't
without proper public support, I still feel like this is,
this is not a fight that anyone can really win.
And not only that, I mean, let's face it.
A significant number of these events we've been seeing
have been done to embarrass the country where it happened. Right.
Whereas they could also be in the sense,
warning shots like when you test fire missiles into
the middle of the ocean or, you know, like the American,
you know, we, we can land a man on the moon so clearly we can drop, you know,
a one ton payload anywhere we want in the world.
Well, and part of it too though is
so, so let's say
Russia hacks, United States and it's all over the news and,
and it's super embarrassing for the NSA right
now, let's say the NSA hacks Russia back,
but it's not all over the news because obviously they
don't have the same kind of media we have here.
Now. What? Right.
Did, did your, so in that case, you can't embarrass them,
you have to actually go after infrastructure and in, in many instances,
a lot of this infrastructure probably you can damage some of it,
but I bet a lot of it you can't
just because it's let's face it, it's, it's old and crappy.
Well, and
-- in
-- every country where they've
unintentionally damaged their own infrastructure.
You know, they,
I remember this is back in the eighties.
They, they tried to run part of, you know, the old,
like the electrified train system,
they tried to run it at a lower, either a lower voltage or, you know, they,
they basically tried to save on electricity
and they ended up damaging like thousands of motors.
Interesting.
I wonder what that was because actually running it on unless power won't save power.
Motors are weird like that.
They might have turned it up,
turning it up would make sense because you actually
become more efficient and that would burn out motors.
This
is also a country where, you know,
they have that gas pipeline leaking so they just increase the pressure in it and then
-- exploded,
-- right?
Um
Yeah,
minor
details
or,
or you look at the way Chernobyl was run and it's like let's do a
low power test in combination with some
other shenanigans in combination with the night shift
and not really plan it out. And, well, we all know how that ended very poorly.
Indeed.
No, I, I don't know, man, I still don't know what to think of this. I feel like
we're at the beginning of something but I don't know what it is yet
and
that
-- part of it is these people are just taking exploratory shots and it's
-- not even just,
there's the exploratory nature of it, but there's also the aspect of like
infosec or, or cybersecurity, whatever you want to call it
is.
We're in such an infancy. We don't even understand what a lot of this means.
We don't really have processes to deal with.
We just,
we don't know. Right. Like something happens. Twitter goes crazy.
Everyone's running around like crazy people
and then,
and now it's like, it's a week later it's mostly over and we're like me, whatever,
nobody cares.
Well, a great example. So last week uh Interac
Ransfer it's a,
it's an interbank and payment system in Canada, you know, debit cards and whatnot,
kind of like Visa or mastercard, right?
They basically have the brand and they also run the,
the kind of back end.
Uh it, it failed, it just stopped working
and it took them like the better part of a day to sort of actually admit it, right?
Like people were like, I can't do transfers and,
and the banks and everything are kind of like, oh,
have you tried turning your phone off and on or
have you tried, you know, like just all this dumb stuff where it's like,
you know, it's, it's everybody is affected.
Like literally everybody I can't transfer money or receive money. I, you know,
um luckily it wasn't like the,
the point of sale systems were not affected because that happened once.
Like TD was like, oh,
we had a motherboard failure and like interact payments for all
of our like Western Canada failed for like two days.
Yeah. So uh I hope they never have a fire at that data center.
But anyways, like back to this interacting, like,
you know, this is a legitimately huge problem.
Like you can't transfer money between the banks.
Uh like from, say I have an account at TD to an account at, you know,
Bank of Scotia or whatever.
And like I said,
it took them the better part of a day to admit that it was a
problem and then it took like one or another day or two to fix it.
Yeah. And like this is a great example actually because
how many people are going to even remember this in a month.
No,
no, you might. And, and now we will and we've, we've etched it into
the, the history of Canada since it's on our podcast.
But I mean, let's face it, it's,
it's just not something people are going to really think about or care
and, and even the business probably, I'm sure they lost a couple of million dollars.
But my suspicion is
didn't because people just did the transfers later.
It was towards the end of the month too. So people had to do it was on June 30th, right.
So, like people had to pay their rents and stuff.
Um But it kind of reminds me of when people talk about
Ecommerce site outages.
Well, yeah, your,
your Ecommerce site for the sake of argument takes in a million dollars an hour in, in
orders.
Well, and you have a one hour outage.
Did you really lose a million dollars or did they, like,
all come back a day later and buy stuff?
It depends.
I've actually experienced this where I've gone to a
site and it didn't work and then I went elsewhere
with interact.
You don't really have an option of going elsewhere because it's like
how you transfer money between banks in Canada.
Your other option is to go get cash and walk it over somewhere.
Right.
Which, yeah,
because you guys don't have those fabulous paper
checks we do in the United States do.
We
do. But they really discourage use of them.
Like the last time I looked at ordering checks it was, they wanted about $2 per check.
They give them to old people for free.
That's solid man. I was at the store the other day and somebody wrote a check.
Oh, my goodness.
And it was an old person, in fact,
but this person that was writing a check to the cashier and I just wanted to, like,
grab them by the shoulders and shake them and scream what is wrong with you?
There's,
there's nothing, I mean, I would rather watch someone pay with a sock full of change
than, and a check just because it's like, what, what is the matter with you?
Why would anybody use these terrible things anymore? Especially at a store.
It's just it's
because it's what they know, it's all they know.
Like, I've, I've been at places where, like, again, I hate to say it,
but older people using intact
and the person behind the counter is like,
now you have to enter your pin,
man. You know,
and we've had chip and pin here for 20 years.
Like, the only reason I carry cash now is in case the interact system dies or
I end up there's this like dodgy uh
ice cream place nearby that doesn't take anything but cash and they don't have a,
an ATM.
Yeah, I, I had that the other day.
I, I went to uh a nursery to, I needed dirt for, for my yard.
I, I get there and they said, oh, cash or check only I thought, well,
I'm not giving you a check.
So let me go get some cash.
But, you know, I was like, who doesn't accept credit cards today?
Like, what's the matter with
you?
Like,
I mean, there's, there's, what is it? There's a square, there's stripe.
Oh man. So, you know, it's really cool. I was out
there the other night
and, and uh the, I'm sure this is not news to the rest of the civilized world but uh
the, the guy walks up with his ipad with square with the stupid thing on top.
I'm like, whatever, you know, stupid stripe
and he whips out this little like it must be a Bluetooth. Uh car chip reader
that, that he plugged my, my card into and then, like things happened
and then, yeah, and, and then I paid for my meal
time.
Sorry, when you,
because now that I'm thinking about travel to the US,
-- I don't think I've ever seen a mobile chip
-- terminal.
This is the first one I've ever seen it was from.
And
I'm like, thank goodness,
yeah,
because here that's the pretty much the default unless
it's like a small restaurant that just hasn't upgraded.
And
this was a super
small restaurant. It was very new, right? But it was like it was brand new. I was
um yeah, it's, I think it's the owner and his wife and, and that's it.
So it was awesome. I I could not believe it.
Yeah, it's funny cause I, I've like, I mean the,
the only places here that are pay at the counter are
like small places or old places like everybody else has,
you know, the mobile.
So for those of you that live in the US, it's, it's think of a game boy.
Well, smaller than a game boy basically.
But yeah, it's like a little, it's got the number pad, a little L led screen, a little,
you know, roll of paper and a printer and then make swipe on the side and you,
you shove your card in the back.
Uh and most of the newer ones are also tapped, pay.
So they basically just bring the thing out to your table, you,
you put in how much tip and then you just tap your card to it and then they,
they ask you if you want a receipt and then they walk away.
Yeah, it's, it's fantastic. I do love those things in Europe.
Although it was, it was very funny. I was, uh, I was in Amsterdam a couple of months ago
and I went somewhere and they,
they pull it out and it was the first time I'd use my credit card there.
And I said this is, this is the crappy American chip and sign. Can you handle that?
And the guy just started laughing hysterically
because he's like, yes, yes, we can
the whole point of these standards.
Oh man, I hate chip. I, I have tried to get a pin from my bank and they will not get,
-- well, you have a chip but no P,
-- no P I it's chip and sign you, you put the card in
the chip
because people still haven't upgraded their payment infrastructure to handle P
because P I can be on chip verification.
Right?
Yes, I know. And in fact, I actually had a credit card once
that I got the bank to give me a pin.
And this was, this was a different card than I use now
and it was great and everywhere in the U si just entered my pin and it was fine.
But, but the current card I have, uh, the bank will not give me a pin.
And so yes, I give them,
they scan the card or they scan the chip and then I
sign a thing and then I'm go along my merry way.
It's completely ridiculous.
Well, I, I guess it's better in that.
-- It's harder to clone the card,
-- whatever, it's ridiculous. Uh, fundamentally
according to the,
whatever credit card companies or whatever here or
the banks or whoever is issuing them,
they were concerned, the
people are familiar with swipe and sign.
And so they were concerned a pin would confuse them too much,
-- which
-- I honestly, it probably would.
But you, you get over it. It's like when Canada got rid of pennies,
uh, it took about a month for us all to get used to.
If you pay with cash, they round up, round down and if you pay electronically,
you pay the exact amount that that's done.
It seems easy enough.
Let's face it. It's the old people right now.
It's old people. They are the problem.
Oh, my goodness. I apologize to any old people listening to the podcast.
Well, you know,
I realize I'm turning into an old person because I'm
getting to the point where I don't actually want to learn
for the sake of learning about technology. I just want to learn what I need to know.
Uh, you know, I've become very sensitive to that fact and I, I make a point to,
to do silly things just for the sake of it
to, to keep it fresh, so to speak, you know, using my cool young person lingo.
Uh, because, yeah, II, I recognize that where I was like, oh, that's stupid.
Why would anyone want that?
And it was, in fact, my kids really got me into this where they,
they play games on their tablets and they do things and I'm like,
that doesn't even make sense. I don't get this.
And then one day I thought I'm turning into an old person. I can't be like that.
So now I,
now I play the weird games with them on their tablets and I
download the apps and I try it all out and it's actually,
it's a lot of fun.
Honestly, it's way easier than being old and crabby. So
I prove,
yeah, speaking of which my one son is turned into a murder hobo in Minecraft,
a murder hobo.
What
does he ride the rails
where there's a village?
And the, he'll go to the village and if he gives it the full treatment,
he will fill it with zombies,
then he will burn it down
and then he will flood it with, uh, sorry.
Yeah, it's zombies.
Fire explosives,
lava is the sequence of essentially biblical plagues
that he will visit upon these poor villagers.
I'd keep an eye on that one if I was you.
Well, it's,
it's, he takes such delight in it.
So he's playing on creative mode, I assume now you use it.
He's playing on a tablet though, right?
That's too bad
because if you play on the computer,
you can type in like cheat code commands.
And uh one time I created a block of TNT that was, I think, 500 by 500 by 500.
And then I, I set it off and
it was amazing because first it starts exploding
and obviously there were a lot of TNT S and my computer, like,
basically froze and I just walked away and thought I'm gonna see what happens
and I came back in like an hour and it was still exploding.
And then, uh, I waited a bit longer and eventually it settled down
and the carnage was amazing
because it would have blown the blocks outward.
That's
it.
Exactly. Because some of the looking
and, and in fact, I then, like,
wandered around quite a lot to see what was happening and,
and you could see explosion damage
like farther than you could see
where this stuff. It just, it was amazing. It was so much fun to do
anyway. This is, this is a security podcast. Kurt.
-- Why are we, why are we talking about? Mine? Minecraft
-- is fun.
Speaking of fun.
Right.
Let's, uh, so I read a thing that they want to
make you take your books out of your bag
when you go through security at the airport. Now,
-- what do you think of that
-- this is airport security in the US. Correct.
-- Of
-- course.
Sorry. I know.
I,
-- although
-- I don't have a lot of high ground to take as a Canadian but
every once in a while you guys do this and it's just like what,
I, I don't even know what to think of this.
It's,
-- well, you have your business card situation.
-- I do.
And, and for those of you listening, I, I, whenever I go places to,
to various conferences, I have a box of cards.
I made up for the podcast that I hand out.
That is like the website address and Twitter handles and stuff on it.
And they're, they're very thick cards.
And
every time I have a box of those in my bag,
my bag is pulled aside and they tear it apart
and then they spend a significant amount of time messing
with that little box of business cards because I,
I suspect the density must set off their uh scanner,
which is just like, yeah, it's business cards
and then they look at me funny, like,
sure,
open it up, man. Yeah, I'm pretty sure, you know, it's,
although I had that too, I was going through security a while back and they,
they flagged my, my microphone, my, my little podcast microphone I carry with me.
It's not that
it's
the
Mike, the Samsung go oh
man, dude, this thing you can like, beat someone to death with this.
I'd be amazed if they let this on an airplane.
But
for those of you who don't know,
I have a road podcaster as my mic and it is really heavy and it is huge.
I would not bring this anywhere.
Uh But anyway, yeah, the go mic and they were like, the, the lady kept looking at it.
She's like, what is this? Like I said, it's the microphone.
She's like looking at me looking at it and it's just funny because, you know,
they're obviously,
I imagine they act like this because they're waiting for
you to like get nervous or sweaty or something.
And it's just,
it was bizarre.
And then of course, when they're done, you know, they're like,
give me my pile of garbage and I have to put it all back together.
But,
uh,
although I had that too in, uh I was in, it was when I was leaving Amsterdam,
I, I get to the airport and I have to go through security
and, and they,
they send my bag to the X ray and the lady says we're gonna have to double check this
and then she opens it up and she just looks at me and goes OMG and they literally
took every single thing out of my backpack and it had a ton of crap in it.
It was just insane. I bet it took me half an hour to get through security
just because this poor lady kept taking stuff out and then running it through
the X ray and taking more stuff out and running through the X ray.
What
traveling with, I mean, I travel with uh like a tablet, my laptop,
my kindle my battery, a pile of wires,
the wires I think are what really set it off.
But then I also have like USB hub and my charging stuff and I've got
my, my portable battery and I, my Nintendo three Ds and a tablet and
just a bunch of weird. The thing is none of it's
big. It's just a bunch of weird little crap.
And they had to take it all out
every and, and, oh man, it was so annoying.
I'm actually, you know, here's an idea for a start up.
Somebody make a thing where I can get a custom made
sort of like a roll of plastic with pouches on it
all custom sizes. So I basically put into the website, what electronics I own.
And then you send me this thing and it's kind of like
I put the electronics in this clear plastic roll up pouch,
put it in my backpack and then when I get to the airport I can just pull it out,
unroll it and be like
here.
That would be kind of clever.
Yeah.
Like, you know, those old leather things that people would roll their tools up in
pockets for their tools.
Let's face it. Right. Like we're like,
well, and they were talking about that laptop,
not banning laptops from the cabins of airplanes, but making them, like,
more difficult to bring on board.
And I'm like, well,
the reality is, like, I mean, if I'm going, like,
I can't spend 23 hours at the airport,
then a couple of hours on the airplane without my laptop.
Like, I, what am I going to do? Right. It's a waste of a day basically at that.
And that's actually been one of the topics that keeps coming up.
It's the story evolves in the bizarre and strange ways.
It does is they think a lot of business travelers just aren't going to travel.
-- And I get that
-- right.
I would certainly avoid it if I could, like, if II, I don't travel a lot. But, um,
I, I,
I'm not gonna travel without my laptop because otherwise I've lost an entire day.
-- Yeah.
-- Right. Right.
No, I, I wouldn't,
I would very much be in a similar situation where
I would think long and hard about that trip.
Yeah. I mean, what am I going to do? Bring, like, Warren Peace to read,
uh, if you ever read Warren Peace?
No. And I never will because I've read about it.
It's very long, it's not the most exciting book either.
I'll, I'll say I did read it because I thought
this feels like one of those things I just have to do as a human
and, uh, I will never read it again.
I'll just say that.
However, however, the one thing I will say is you can tell it was written by a Russian
because it makes Napoleon seem like an incompetent moron all over the book.
It's very funny like that. Yes. Yes.
Oh, man. Just thinking about it.
It took me so long to read too because, well, the other, the other hard thing and,
uh, I,
I found this when I was a youngster and I read Crime and
Punishment for the first time is I am bad at Russian names.
I can't pronounce them, but not only that many of them look the same to me.
And so I remember reading Crime and Punishment, I reached a point.
I was actually writing names down on a piece of paper
and what they did.
So when they would talk about somebody be like, oh, that's the policeman or?
Oh, that's the landlady. You know, because I, like, I could not figure it out
just because, like many of them look the same to me and, and I had no clue.
Yeah. Right. Right. Um, although I had the same problem with Lord of the Rings as well
where, like, all the made up name,
I don't even know who this person is in
his future point. I just read it actually, I just finished it maybe 23 weeks ago
and
now that I've read it like 100 times and I've seen the movies many, many times.
I, I know who everyone is,
which does make the book far more enjoyable rather than the first time I read it.
I'm like, wait, wait, who's this guy? What's he doing? What? Who?
Yeah.
Although I guess at the same time I can tie that back to security.
That's probably what normal people feel like
when we start talking about something,
-- I don't know
-- the
acronyms.
I keep running into these acronyms where I'm like,
I absolutely don't remember what that means or, you know,
it's an acronym that has multiple meanings.
Those are the best kind, aren't they?
Yeah,
but his GP Dr
R oh man, we should do a show about that at some point.
It's, it's gonna be messed up and, and it's one of those things that at first I thought
that,
that corporations would find a loophole or something
around this and it sounds like they're not,
they don't,
it, it sounds like it, man. It's gonna be, it's gonna be crazy.
Yeah.
So, well, speaking of crazy.
-- So you recently got to deal with sort of a standards related?
-- Oh,
yes.
So,
so I'm excited to talk about. This is
so, so I live in, in a very old house.
It's, it's was built in 1990.
It is, it's on the
National Historic Registry or something in Washington DC.
And it's uh
right. So, so the house has not been
remodeled a lot.
It's all a lot of original,
everything on the inside which is actually a good thing because in, in, like, the,
the fifties and sixties, they,
they would do these horrendous things to
these historic properties and it was awful.
And so I'm very happy that I don't have that problem.
And anyway, uh,
I wanted to add a door,
like there was a wall and I needed a door there. Sort of add a door. Right.
-- This isn't like, oh, just go by a door and put it in. No, no,
-- no, no.
-- And this is an exterior door too. Not
-- exterior
door. It's an interior
interior. Oh, well, that shouldn't be a big deal. I mean, it's not a load
bearing wall. I,
it was,
uh, but no,
that's ok. That's, that's easy. That's no big deal.
It was from a bedroom to a closet.
And,
right. Right. Because,
yeah, yeah, it's, the house is weird and
basically every bedroom
and, and
the, the way it's set up like every wall of a bedroom butts up to a closet.
And we wanted one of the bedrooms to have access to two closets instead of one.
And so you can actually now get from, uh,
every room but one just by walking through closets.
Which is kind of weird. It's, it's just, it's an old house. Right.
Old houses are weird. Anyway. Anyway,
so the point is I basically had to cut a big hole in the wall and put a door in and I,
I didn't just, like, go by a door.
Right. I had like an old historic door in the basement.
So I use that and, and, and right, it, it's crazy. And so
my grandfather was a carpenter so I knew how to do all this stuff
and I, I don't like it when other people mess with my stuff.
So I,
I don't like letting contractors work on the
inside of the house because they mess it up
or, or they don't listen to me, which is even worse.
But,
but anyway, anyway, the thing that really got me thinking about all this is
like there were no standards in 1919, right?
People just built stuff, everything was done by an artisan
and it was crazy because nothing makes sense and,
and you don't even know what you're going to find
until you start taking it apart and then it's like,
why would anyone do that?
And, and I only hit that three or four times. Thank goodness. But,
but the point is it really got me thinking about security while I was doing this and,
you know, cursing at things and smashing my hands with,
with hammers and stuff like that. But
the point is
if you look at security today, we do artisanal security for the most part, right?
Where it is,
everything is kind of a one off special thing
and then
it
is, it's madness but not only that,
the other thing that I was really thinking about a lot is
when you have this old stuff,
it just sits there for a long time and, and you kind of get that, you know, a,
a body at rest wants to stay at rest. Right.
And I feel like there's a lot of security and it like that where it's just,
it's this old stuff that if you touch it or you look at it wrong,
it just collapses and you end up with a mess.
-- Right. It's
-- worse. You know, people have built additional things onto it
based on the lessons they've learned. You know.
Well, it always reminds me of the Mozilla code base, right.
When they, they basically made an effort to rewrite Firefox and they basically
almost died because,
you know, the amount of sort of work, um,
like, what always gets me is, you know,
especially whenever a business tries to do an SAP or some sort of, er,
p deployment
and the problem is to do that,
you have to move all your processes into a computer and computers are dumb
and they're not like Agnes from accounting
who has 50 years of institutional knowledge and
can like paper over glitches in the form or people forgot to fill out stuff.
You know, you have to put your exact data
models and processes and everything into the system for it to work and it
always fails or ends up going like 3 to 10 times over budget.
Well,
yes, I
don't know what they're doing.
But this
is,
this is the same problem though, as, as working on 100 year old house is
in the absence of standards, people just do whatever
and doing whatever is fine
if it's only a one off weird thing.
But as soon as you have more than one person or
you're talking about long term maintainability or anything like that,
the lack of standards becomes a nightmare and
something will take two or three times as long
as it would if their standards, I mean,
and I got to thinking about this,
like you go to the store now and every piece of lumber is basically a standard size,
right? It it makes sense there are you buy doors, doors are a standard size.
You know, you've got doorknobs, standard size. All this makes sense.
You don't have to worry about it.
Instead, I'm out in my garage trying to like build a door frame
because I have this door. That's a bizarre size and weighs 10 million pounds.
And not only that, like
I had to dig through,
I've got this like bucket of parts because whenever I find old timey parts,
I buy them because
you can't, you know, you can't buy them for real.
So anyway, you know, I'm like digging through, trying to find hinges that fit right?
And trying to find like the door closer and the knobs and
I'm thinking this is crazy, like just
it's complete madness, right?
Because everything was completely different and, and yeah,
I ended up doing like an insane amount of
surgery to make this stuff work and just thinking,
you know, this took me four days and really it would have taken if
it
was
-- you make
-- any documentation to leave behind for the next time.
No. Screw that guy.
Right.
He's on his own.
And that's,
that's one thing that got me was as part of a modern building process too is,
um,
you have your blueprints and especially, well, more so for like, you know,
industrial stuff where it's big and complicated
versus like a relatively simple house,
but you have your blueprints and then you have your US built plan
where you literally take like the blueprint and modify it because,
um,
so I spent six months working for a large
electrical contractor locally that did primarily industrial work.
So things like, you know, oil refineries,
like all the wiring for a new oil refinery or whatever.
And, you know,
and it turns out that like this thing and this thing are both bigger than we thought.
So they don't fit in the same room or, you know, whatever, right?
This machine has to be moved over here.
So you got to move cable over and, you know,
you, you can't just have like random, you know,
15,000 volt lines running around your plant and not know what they are.
You know, that's ok.
Like, honestly in a house you can have random 120 volt lines and you probably do,
uh, not my house because I had it rewired.
Yeah, from scratch. But, you know, most people don't have to do that.
Thank goodness.
And, you know, that's the thing that gets me too is like when I look at all these,
it deployments
and security deployments, not only are they handcrafted, most of them are not
documented or if they are documented, they get documented when they get built
-- and then they get changed.
-- Oh, man, they, they're never documented and in fact,
any time I talk to someone about starting like a security program
or any sort of like they want to start doing security.
What's the first thing you say, you say, get an inventory of your stuff? Right.
And even that is an insurmountable problem for the vast majority of people I talk to
where they, they just, their heads explode when they think about it.
Well, yeah, I mean, even if you know your entire IP space,
there's still stuff potentially behind that
or running a private IP space
with the computer under his desk. Right. I
mean,
actually that's, it's one of the really funny things I remember many,
many years ago I was working at a small company and uh, yeah,
like the web server was a computer under a dude's desk.
Literally.
It's just what, what
like, how did
today you think it works?
And it's madness. But back then like that was, that was no big deal.
That's still what a lot of small businesses do. Right.
They'll have their one copy of what is it? Windows,
small business server sbs
and it's in the broom closet. Right. Like under the leaky water heater.
And
-- exactly,
-- there's a tape drive with tapes being rotated out.
Actually, I remember that too. II, I remember working for a company that
they, they had a tape drive
and they just kept, like, someone knew it was their job on, on Friday to, like,
switch the tape.
And I remember thinking, like, do you even know if these tapes work?
And, and they were, the tapes are like,
five years old and they'd all been written into a million times and I'm thinking,
I bet these things are shot and they probably don't work at all anymore.
But that was someone's job on Friday. Go switch the tapes.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, I mean, it's, these are tough problems and, uh,
yeah, I, at this point I'm even, you know, I have a small home network and, uh,
I actually had a surprise system on it at one point I'd forgotten about.
I always love the stories too of the university that, like,
sealed up the old sun server behind a wall or something and
nobody knew it was there and it was running for 12 years.
Or,
I believe that that kind of stuff happens all the time,
I guess though. This is a, an ad for cloud.
Well, it's gonna happen in cloud two people already do that.
You know, they, they set up a cloud service and they forget it exists or,
uh, the classic thing with like Amazon and whatnot,
you set up virtual servers and forget about them.
And so there's actually like, software and services now that will go through your,
like,
infrastructure and actually match it to what you're paying for and then be like,
there's all this other stuff you're paying for that.
-- We can't figure out why you're paying for it. Right.
-- Exactly.
And, and that's what makes it nice though is because, I mean,
let's say you're a moderately sized organization,
there's no way you can scan your IP space and,
and accurately know what's going on just because people do crazy stuff.
You know, you might have had the guy from accounting,
brought his old home router in and now he's got
10 things sitting behind that and you can't see him.
You know,
there's just all kinds of crazy stuff like that. That happens and,
and I get it because let's face it. People want to get their job done. Right.
They don't care about security. Security isn't a feature.
It's the thing that gets in their way.
And so if bringing the old router in, fixes their problem,
they're going to do it and they don't care what the security guy says.
Yeah, I think, and it kind of goes back to, like,
inventory control for physical stuff.
Right. Companies used to be terrible at that.
You know, when you think about, when you look at the, like, the losses
of product during shipping prior to containerization.
Oh, man, I can't,
it
was
a
show,
you know,
uh, in some things it was as high as 10 or 20% between the factory and the end store.
I believe that, whoops, it went missing,
you know, and the time involved as well as shipping this stuff and,
and to say nothing of actual breakage.
Right. No, I totally get that,
you know, and I, I think that's,
that's one of the benefits I think too of
Cloud is that you have this external organization.
That's like, well, if you're going to use this,
we're going to send you a bill for it and we're actually like,
we have to know what you're using because we want to bill you for it.
Right. That's,
you know,
how many companies have stuff that's well past its
like three year or four year amortization date,
but still in use.
But officially it's like, maybe off the books.
Oh, man, I bet there's tons and tons of that.
Tons of it.
Yeah. Well, if it still works then, yeah, I mean, use it.
I, man, I remember that too. I remember when I, when I was a cis
edin
we had machines that were, I mean, they were old, like, scary old stuff but it it ran.
So nobody touched it. But again, we kind of come back to that,
you know, a system at rest wants to stay at rest. And everyone knew,
like, don't touch that machine.
In fact,
I remember we had one machine even that we were afraid to power off and we would,
we would shut down the whole data center
just so the UPS could keep running that one machine because we were definitely
afraid it would never come back to life and it did something really important.
I don't even remember what it was. It was some accounting software or something.
Yeah. No, I imagine I had that happen.
I had a fan freeze when I rebooted a server, uh, due to a power outage and it,
it came back up and then, uh, yeah, the, the main case fan
was frozen.
Did
you?
But
if you spun it with your finger, it would
spin but it didn't, like, it was sticky enough that it on its own,
it couldn't get going
interesting.
Now, could you turn it on and then, like, poke it with your finger and everything?
Yeah, that's what I did the first time.
I was like, oh, dead fan and then I spun it with my finger, of course.
And it started moving and I'm like, oh, ok,
part
Dead fan. The best kind.
That's like,
that's how so much stuff in it works. All right. We pushed it down the hill.
Everything's cool. Let's go back to work.
Yeah, exactly.
It's not on fire
yet
so.
Well, it's, it's the human condition. I think
it is. People are the problem. Right.
Well, it's, it's funny because, like,
they even have this problem in the space station
on the, is SS where on the one hand,
they kind of want the astronauts not to be living in,
like a rat's nest of exposed cabling.
But at the same time the astronauts are like, we don't want to spend time like
putting cables back in place.
We just want to fix whatever it was and get on with all our other stuff because,
you know, there's only so many hours in a day.
Yeah, I, I totally get that. I mean, well, that's like any server room, right? It's,
I, I, I've been in the position before where the server room got so bad.
We, we decided, you know, and the next time maintenance was happening, we,
we literally took all the cables out because
it was just, you, you could not figure it out
and we ran new cables and then, yeah,
like a year later it was a mess again because nobody, nobody does it right.
You know,
we had everything beautifully organized and we had zip
ties around groups that needed to be together.
We had every, you know, they had the overhead rack thing, whatever the,
the cable trays.
Yeah, whatever,
you know, everything was nicely lined up. It all made perfect sense.
And, yeah, in, in a year it was terrible again. And we're like, well, so much for that.
It's, I, I don't know, it's crazy, man.
You know, the one part of me always wants to have tidy cabling,
but the reality is quite often, you know, it,
it's just not actually that much of a problem, like,
and that's the problem with a lot of security, right,
until you get attacked or something that, that security hole is not, you know,
those old windows XP machines that were running the,
the National Health Service in Britain
were generally not a problem until, you know, they all got wiped out one day.
That's a good point. Actually, I think Cabling makes a lot of sense in this analogy
because it, it doesn't matter in most cases, well, until it does
because we've all been in that situation where, where you need to figure out what,
you know, what, where the other end of this cable goes and you just, you can't do it.
It's,
-- it's a nightmare.
-- Yeah.
And there is, and, you know,
there is a small chance that it just won't be a problem and you, you get away with it.
So, and if you do then great, you know, you just save the business,
how many hours or dollars.
Right. Right. You know, I have a great Cabling story. Actually.
I don't, I don't think I've ever told this one on the podcast, but I was, I was,
but a wee lad
out of college, it was my first job
and
there's
the,
the server room was wired up and they had run two cables to go from the router to the,
the firewall.
Right.
This was, this was back in the day when,
like you had just a special router to connect to the T one line,
two cables. That way they had redundancy.
And I look at it and I, what's that?
So what was the purpose of
the, it was dark, right? It was just dark.
They did this because they thought they might need an extra cable some day
or if it went out or something.
And I remember I looked at it and I was, I was,
this was when I was planning out how to rewire everything
and I said, hey, uh these cables are mislabeled
and, and this guy, this was back, remember when the M CS ES were all like, oh,
I'm so special.
I have an M CS E and they all thought they were amazing.
I had an M CS C back in those days.
So, you know exactly what I'm talking about
in fairness. I test well during multiple choice exams and getting the M CS E,
I actually managed to get it down to four hours
reading the prep books and then just go write the exam
well done,
you
know.
But anyway, uh this is one of those guys, right? Like I have an M CS E I know everything.
And I was of course, the young starry
eyed open source fanatic.
And I remember I, I mentioned
that, hey, these cables are mislabeled. He's like, no, they're not.
I said no, but they, they really are.
Look, the, the light isn't lighting up on this cable, but it is on that one.
Which means that's the one in use. He said no, the,
the it was a hub, literally a hub that had the cables connected to it.
And he said, the, the lights in the hub are broken.
And I thought
what, like, why, why would, why
would the lights on the hub be like,
exactly flipped on these two cables exactly in this way.
And this guy was like, I labeled these myself, I guarantee the the hub is broken.
I said,
so if I unplug this cable here, the everything should still work, right?
He's like, yeah, go ahead
and I plugged the cable
uh effectively turning off the internet for the building.
And of course, as you can imagine, like two minutes later,
everyone was like banging on the server room door saying the internet's broken,
what's going on?
I just remember looking at this guy and I'm like,
but now, you know, and you got to get really mad, of course. But,
you know, it's just, it's always stuff like that.
I, I think about especially in security where
we love to think we're right.
You know,
-- reality sometimes it,
-- well, it, it came up kind of with the whole stack
thing, right? So, for those of you that don't remember the whole stack guard debacle
have stack guard pages.
That's like three emergencies ago.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly. So we're gonna have a little recap.
So you, the idea being is that you don't want the heap and
uh the stack and what not to grow too big and get to areas they shouldn't.
-- So that, you know,
-- they,
they grow,
they grow towards each other.
And if they, if they
clash,
then you have problems.
So we have like this guard page in the middle and
you know, there's ways to kind of jump over it.
And so anyways, one of the things was there's this,
uh what is it F stack check or protect?
I always,
I can't remember
F
stack check. So the idea is F stack check, you compile it in
uh
it's a
Gipsy thing
and I think it's available maybe conceptually in some other libraries.
But anyways, you compile it in and you get a bunch of well checks and protections,
right?
Except the,
except the code apparently doesn't really work as we'd hoped because it was
written 20 years ago. And based on a, a
whoops,
which is a programming language
that has
a very different design culture behind it than say c
you know,
uh it's, it's a very different
environment. Uh And so these assumptions taken from a
A and applied to like
glib
Z
just don't work,
like, it's so f stack it, it just, the, the protective mechanism
doesn't work at all as well as we'd hoped.
And, but again, because nobody really uses this mechanism much, it,
it just sort of had never come up,
you know,
your cabling issues or your whatever issues, you know, like,
and that's the problem is, you know, now, well,
now we've discovered it's a problem and, you know, people are working on it.
But again, it's one of those problems where, you know,
we can't just make a simple change to it because it's,
it's not
like a code flaw. It's a,
and it's not even a design flaw, it's like a, a cultural historical
precedence,
you know, where it comes from conceptually flawed.
That's crazy, man.
It's like comparing X 86 to arm.
They're, they're two very different things.
You know, they share a lot of concepts because they're computers.
But fundamentally, there's just some things that are, you know,
if you're an X 86 guy and you go to arm,
you know, you, you need to relearn some things.
I
feel sad that they have a proper stack on arm.
It's slightly better, but they, they, they had a chance to get that right.
And they didn't.
That's right.
Actually the Titanium and, and I know this is probably a terrible thing to say,
but the Titanium actually did this right is, they had a special
area for, for the stack registers.
-- That way you weren't like pushing it. Well, it's
-- kind of, I seem
to remember it caused some performance issues.
-- Probably
-- the whole freaking chip was a performance issue
because it was like a nightmare to program for.
But regardless of that, they got the stack part. Right?
I think, because they had something like, what was it?
Eight or 12 registers just for stack variables.
And if you surpass that, then they'd put some things on the stack.
But generally speaking, the important stuff lived elsewhere.
And so it was very nice actually.
But then, you know,
there's an example of your program needs to
do the right thing because there's programs that
can and in some cases legitimately do need
huge stacks like megabytes or even a gigabyte.
-- No,
-- the stack can be large.
The problem was the registers because what happens is when you,
when you jump into a new function, it basically takes all the registers,
pushes them on the stack, then starts execution of the new function.
And then when you, when you pop
right, you come back from that function and the it replaces all the registers.
And that's obviously the issue with a stack buffer
overflow is you override a bunch of these registers,
they get restored.
And all of a sudden whoa crazy things are going on.
And,
and obviously in something like the attan,
the the stack
registers were nowhere near the buffers So even if there was an overflow,
you were just overflowing other data, not that, that can't be abused,
but you get the idea.
It's
how big were those stack registers in the Itanium? Right?
There were like eight or 12 of them. I, I forget there weren't a ton.
So basically, that meant you could essentially,
if you were passing more than like 10 variables
into the function call,
then it would have to do some stack shenanigans.
But if it was obviously the compiler decides all this
and if it was less, then it would just use the,
the special stack registers to take care of it, which obviously made it much,
much more safe.
But,
but anyway, anyway,
uh
-- and, and then see that's
-- the problem I have is a lot of this.
The problem now is we have such a catalog of software that runs on
say X 86 and arm with a whole pile of assumptions behind it.
If you break one of those assumptions, you just broke everything,
right?
And that's one thing I really respect about
the Linux kernel guide is their mantra of,
you cannot break user land.
Uh Yes, I like end of story and I agree because,
well, we, we, you know,
there's some issues with some of the snack
card patches around some of the Java stuff.
And so yeah, no, it's, it's, it's not good. It's
potentially for some people really bad so much
so that they can't use the security update.
Wild.
Wow. I
didn't realize
that's
lucky now.
Yeah. You know, and it's
so, you know, we,
we can't burn it all down and start fresh. We just can't afford it.
You know, it would be like changing the width of railway lines,
didn't they do that in the Czech Republic or something once?
Uh,
-- they, well, I know Russia used a different gauge than western Europe,
-- I think.
I think it was the
Czech Republic,
-- a
-- former colony might have like a well not colony but former satellite state.
Sorry,
might have been in that situation where it's like, you know, it's worth it,
spending the money to switch from, like, you know,
being compatible with Russia to being compatible with Western Europe.
It's like the US and the metric system. Right.
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, a great, well, talking about building supplies, right.
Like, if I want to buy a sheet of plywood it's a four by eight,
-- you know, feet. If I buy lumber it's, it's imperial.
-- I was wondering that actually.
-- So, so all the lumber in Canada is the terrible imperial
-- units.
Yeah, because we export so much of it.
Let's
not talk
about
lumber disputes. Ok. That's, that's a bit of a,
one of those touchy subjects for us, Canadians.
We're a little bit,
it's one of those things that we're a little bit
annoyed about because it's been going on for 30 years.
But
fundamentally, yeah, I like
um, plumbing supplies. Right.
It's all the, you know, it's basically the same stuff as you guys use. Right.
So it's half inch OD copper
p,
here's the thing and here's what we'll close on. Ok.
Is, so the imperial system is the worst way to measure anything ever.
And we can all agree on that.
Ok.
The metric system is vastly superior.
But even if you're using the worst system in the world,
as long as there are standards, it's OK and consistency, consistency. Right.
Exactly. And, and that's really the lesson is
it doesn't matter how bad your measurement system is.
As long as it's consistent and standardized across your organization
or industry,
that is what matters,
right? We just had this exact conversation in CV E world
where somebody was like, why do you do it this way?
And we're like, well, it's not ideal,
but it's what we've done and we consistently keep doing it.
So we at least have the same rule and every you, you essentially have
-- of standard expected behavior and no surprises.
-- That is exactly correct.
And I can think of no better way to end the podcast than on that point,
which if you take nothing away from this, this lesson or if you made it this far,
let it be that right.
So anyway, thank you, Kurt, thank you everybody for listening.
If you want the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com.
We have links there to Twitter. You can use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag Get a hold of us. We've got a Facebook group.
You're welcome to join and hassle us about
and, yeah, if nothing else. Thanks for listening everybody.
Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. And I guess, be safe with your fireworks. Folks.
-- I hate fireworks so much.
They're so noisy and annoying.