Hello and welcome to episode 104 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So I heard Gen two got popped.
Yeah.
Yeah. Well, part of their github, uh,
their
github infrastructure, I guess
github
organization. Sorry. That's the correct.
-- Yes.
-- Their github
organization got popped. Yes.
So that's neat.
Well, what's funny to me is this reads like a classic airline disaster of, like
this guy forgot to put the screw back in the engine and was like, eh, whatever.
And then the next guy, like, forgot to check the engine and was like, man, whatever,
put some tape over that hole.
And then the pilot was like, oh, we're losing fuel, let's, you know,
pump fuel from the good tank to the other tank because why not?
And so the whole thing is just like this series
of sort of incremental mistakes that results in an attacker
taking over the organization. And luckily the attacker was apparently an idiot.
I'm comfortable with that statement.
Well, considering what they accomplished and then what they did with it, it's like,
what?
Right.
You know what this really makes me think of when I look
at the timeline of events and everything that happened on both sides is
in order for a disaster to happen, a
bunch of things,
I'll get to that.
So in order for the mistake to happen, it will say disaster.
In this case, a number of mistakes need to be incident, right? Like
the incident,
a number of mistakes need to be made.
But on the other side of the coin, when you're the attacker,
you can't make mistakes, right? You have to basically play the game. Perfect.
Well, he did make a mistake and that's what made it real obvious that they got.
Right. Well, that's my point, right.
So if, if you think about a situation like this where you're talking about like
uh essentially the events leading up to a compromise,
you need like the perfect storm of mistakes.
And then after compromise,
you need to play the perfect game of no mistakes because when you make mistakes,
you get discovered and on the other side,
if you only make mistakes, then you end up, but they compromise.
And so it, it's kind of interesting to think about the, the two aspects of this, of,
of making a bunch of mistakes.
But then also when you're the attacker not making a
bunch of mistakes because you get found out right away.
Yeah.
Well, and, and the other thing too is looking at this
monetizing this attacker or essentially how do you gain benefit?
Like let's assume the attacker got in and was quiet,
how do you actually benefit from this attack?
And so one obvious answer is crypto mining, right? That is actually like
uh like those things with the hostile Docker images or not,
let me rephrase because Docker images with crypto
miners are actually a legit thing.
Um And so basically what, what it turns out is, you know,
people deploy stuff like kubernetes with no
authentication enabled.
Uh and, and publicly on the internet and of course, Attackers find it
connect to it and they're like, who, you know,
free resources to run virtual machines.
Well, again, how can I monetize that in a way that
doesn't attract a lot of attention like while spamming and denial service
attracts a lot of attention. Well, you know, crypto mining, right?
-- People are
-- like ransomware. I
mean, ransomware is in your face,
crypto
mining
so
much.
Um So, yeah, how do you monetize an attack like this?
And it's reasonably difficult, like if it was part of a targeted attack? Sure,
you know, then it would have just been a stepping stone like, oh,
we have an organization that we know uses Gen two's github.
OK. Let's attack them via that. Now, that would be super clever, but
clearly, that's not what happened here.
-- Now, this was clearly malicious.
-- Yeah.
Well, and that's what I mean then, then sort of the next thing is, well,
if you can't monetize it.
That typically means it's like vandalism.
Right?
Like a great example was there was a porta potty or a playground
that we go to and somebody went full van Gogh mode inside,
you know.
And like, yeah, exactly. It's exactly what you think
-- the medium was.
-- Yeah, exactly.
It was, I was like, my son wanted to go and I, I, like, popped it up because I check,
you know, because these things happen.
And I was like, no, he's like, I want to look, I want to look, I'm like, you don't.
And so I, I open it and he's like,
uh and he runs away
and then of course his brothers, like I want to see what it is. I'm like,
don't. But whatever
lesson learned, everyone line up
-- pretty
-- much,
let's all go wash our hands. Now,
the thing that gets me is like most vandalism isn't that
clever.
And by definition, the attack on this was actually,
I don't want to say super clever but reasonably clever,
-- you
-- know. Yeah, but you could still argue it wasn't clever enough.
No, no.
But I mean, the, the attack itself wasn't like, you know, they,
they had some known vulnerability that they didn't patch, right?
That that's always the classic one, right where an organization literally
gets popped because
they like literally
were, you know, running Java struts or,
you know, running a uh like a database just open to the public.
Alright. Well, let's do this, then let's gen to, to their credit.
I'm,
I'm going to praise these guys immensely as
they've been remarkably open about the incident.
And if you go to the show notes,
there's a link to a wiki page where they have documented
kind of everything. Why don't, why don't we walk through some of this?
Because there's, there's actually some really interesting stuff.
On one note, I would say even more importantly, again, like an air incident,
they've also documented what they're going to do to fix and prevent this.
And it looks like they're actually executing on that.
And that's, that's the biggest thing for me is like, did OK.
Have we learned anything from this and, and
have we applied those lessons? Right?
Because I see lots of organizations learn lessons and then just keep doing things
the way they've always done it. So,
yeah. Um I do have to say this is a beautiful write up. So do you want to start us off?
Cool to kind of start at the top. They, they note from
April 8th to June 27th, there was somebody probing github
accounts,
which
I mean, I don't know, man,
I feel like every github organization probably has a gazillion probes every day of,
of users, right?
I've actually never bothered to look at them
mostly because we generally almost everybody has two fa
enabled and actually we will be forcing it shortly
and, and we'll get to that.
Yeah. OK. So, so we'll kind of start out then. So it sounds like June 28th
is kind of the day
everything happened
right where
it seems like it sounds like an attacker got in with a bad password.
And obviously when we say bad password, we just mean
it's either reused or a really crappy password.
What it sounded like is that this person was
using sort of a password formula to generate passwords.
And so I've seen people, you know, where they're, like, pick a, you know, like,
pick a name and a number and then you, like, append the name of the site to the password
is,
uh, not a, not so terrible if the password is hashed.
Right.
But if the attacker gets that clear text password and see, like, you know,
Jon Snow 1989
or,
um,
you know, then they, then they maybe guess that if they replace Facebook with github
and try to log in at github,
-- then it might work.
-- Right.
No, we're going to say every password that isn't a password manager.
-- Password is terrible.
-- I
agree.
100%.
Ok.
Good.
Just so we're clear.
No.
But, and, you know,
this is an example of people trying to be
clever in ways that are actually not that clever.
Right. Exactly. Exactly. So, anyway, it sounds like then the attacker gets in
and they gain administrative access
because
the
administrative,
that's, that's my assumption. And they don't, they don't say that but
they sort of strongly implied because they
talk about cleaning up old debt accounts.
So, you know,
so anyway, and then they, they create
new accounts, which obviously is exactly the right way to do it because when you're,
when you're mounting some sort of an attack and you're using an existing account,
you,
you run the risk of the individual you're after
or rather the individual you just attack noticing some shenanigans. Right.
So like get in, create a new account. Get out.
Right. I mean, yeah,
actually essentially it's exactly what it is, right? It's a back door, fair enough.
Ok.
So anyway, so m accounts get added and, and the thing,
I think that's the most interesting is it says
they, they add a malicious commit
and this malicious commit is literally 20 minutes
after they first get access where they,
they looks like they, they tell
the, the gen two repository to RM dash RF slash star,
which is
as everyone knows that delete all of the files on your desk in theory. Right.
And
I mean,
I feel like if you do this in 20 minutes, you knew what you wanted to do. Right.
Well, what's interesting to me is that like, there's,
there's way more subtle and annoying ways to mess up a system
than just an RM hyphen RF. Right.
I, I feel like it is the,
the unlearned man's solution,
right? Because everyone knows
you DD garbage to the disk.
-- That's how
-- you do it,
you put that in one of the start up scripts.
So the next time they reboot they're like, oh,
this seems to be taking a while but whatever weird stuff happens and then, you know,
five minutes later they realize they have a brick,
well, not a brick system but
they better have backups. Right.
Did you know, the, the last time I needed to kill a drive, I booted it
and then ID D to the desk while it was running just to see.
-- And it finished. I was
-- shocked because everything is in memory.
-- So as long as you don't
-- write, right?
I, I expected something to blow up though before it finished.
Well, that's part of the beauty, right? If it's running and it's in memory, it should
keep running.
But, uh, yeah, it's, well,
and the other thing is to an RM I hyphen RF is like very obviously hostile.
Like there's no,
right. It's not like
it's
not,
yeah, it's, I mean, well, the, my favorite example being,
what was it like some driver or game that like
did an RM hyphen RF slash user slash something coming,
coming something
and they like stuck a space in there somewhere.
So it like nuked slash user or whatever. Remember
-- it was like steam or something?
-- That wasn't a game, it was,
didn't that just happen with it? Wasn't that MP M's problem or something?
-- Yeah. But basically, I mean,
-- we talked about this in
the past.
I mean, you know, then it becomes more of a whoop.
Somebody, like, made a really bad fat finger. Not like, ok, somebody added RM
hyphen
RF. That's slash
-- star.
-- Yeah.
Right.
Right. Right. So,
and, and now the, the other thing, I don't know how gen two does this but I know
that on many systems. RM dash RF stuff doesn't always do what you think it does
and, and in many
and many modern unixes,
they assume you just did something really dumb and they don't let you.
And, and there's, there have been many arguments whether this is good or bad.
But,
but from what I've heard that command does not work by default on a GEN two system.
So even
even the people who happened to pull down this bad commit and tried to run a build,
it didn't do anything to them,
which is, which is cool. And, and then in
this timeline, literally half an hour after this event started,
the, the gen two people contacted github
basically to say something fishy is going on.
Well, and,
and that's actually something where this is kind of an example
of where the industry fails is they had private contacts with github
because they knew people there, right?
If they had to come in through the front door, like some random schmuck,
this would have taken days or weeks if anything happened,
it, it probably would have
like I for example, I know
somebody who actually uh their
Gmail account,
uh
essentially a pile of data within it got deleted by accident
and they knew somebody high up enough at
Google that they actually got their data back.
That's like you, that's like that's unicorn levels of knowledge of people.
And that's kind of where I fear this thing with github
comes in is that
it kind of sounds because they were able to get github to respond,
you know, so quickly and, you know, with details,
what I'm saying is, don't, don't kind of expect that to be the normal case.
You are correct.
But here's the other side of that I like to think about is
I, if you're a project like, like GEN two or you're,
you're an organization of some sort,
part of the value in hiring good people is you, you're hiring their role
attacks as well.
And
I mean, I, I, I've done this more times than I can count for, for, you know,
my last couple jobs without question,
if something happens and it's like I know this person, let me just go
and in 10 minutes, I get more done than you get done in two weeks.
And,
and I, I do agree that companies need a nice front door.
You know, the front door shouldn't be hostile if it's hostile,
you have other problems.
The problem is when you have a bunch of crazy people throwing poop at your front door
and, and Yes. And I imagine
Github's front door has an enormous pile of poop.
I, I have no doubt because you, I mean, I mean,
I see this all the time where people just,
you end up with,
with, like I'm not saying they're bad people but they,
they come in with requests that are,
are clearly not properly researched.
And when you, you suggest, you know,
maybe you should go and look over here and because
you didn't tell them exactly how to solve their problem,
they start yelling at you and it's like
this isn't a
good response.
I don't want to talk to you anymore person.
And, and when you're paying someone money, it's
impossible to do that
in many instances. However, I'm going to say
if you're an organization hiring security people,
the rolodex is part of what you're hiring and, and I truly believe that
when, when you're in, if you have senior leadership and they don't have a rolodex,
you don't have senior leadership, that's kind of the way I view that.
Right. And someone like Gen Two
almost certainly has contacts up the one
zoo
community
driven organization. Right. Because they're open source
who and what they are.
Exactly. Exactly. And so I, I don't think that's unexpected or unreasonable.
In fact, if they didn't have a backdoor into github, I would be sad for, for Gen Two.
Right.
And that's one of those things. It's like
if you don't just call,
ok, I will help you out open source project.
But anyway, anyway,
and, and like this is,
I'm impressed,
I'm impressed by how fast this went because I've seen many incidents take
much longer than half.
But in fairness, this was a pretty simple
incident. I mean,
let's, let's ok. Now, here's the point where we, I get a little me,
all right. Bring it.
G
two made some really painfully like rookie level
mistakes. So
number one,
somebody had
bad passwords
because no offense.
If everyone has bad
password,
if somebody can guess if somebody can see one of your passwords
and then guess another password for a different site based on that,
you have bad passwords,
right? They should be random.
I guarantee
in, in any organization that is more than 30% of the pass.
-- So
-- basically there, it boils down to use a password manager. Uh Number two github
supports two fa they support phones, they support the, um,
what is it?
Otphotp, whatever the heck the app is, you know,
the QR code and you get the time based rolling code,
they support
printed recovery codes, they support UBI
keys.
I think there might be one other option. I can't remember it off hand.
But the point is they support like all the normal ration.
-- Well, and when I say phones,
-- did you know that I got my first U two F tokens from github
because when they first started supporting U two F, they had a special with UB key
for $5. I bought, I think three of them for $5.
And it's got, I've got the hash cat logo on the back of it even.
And I don't use it anymore because now that I have UB
four it does U two F but yeah,
I still have it and I carry it with me
because funny enough I keep thinking maybe there's some site,
I forgot I plugged this into and I better keep it just
in case and I haven't used it in like a year.
Yeah, it's like back in the day ebay used to do Rs a tokens for five bucks.
And, uh,
you know,
but yeah, so, like rookie mistake number two is not
at least encouraging or required
to fa across the org, especially for admin users.
That's,
that needs to be
II,
I feel like if you're any sort of reasonable sign
and actually look if you're anybody to FA on github,
I think it's like,
so,
and
it's just, it's part of how the world is now. If,
if the site supports
two fa
second two factor authentication,
assuming it's not some really stupid form of two fa,
like my bank has two fa it's two passwords, right?
It's a password and then a secret question.
That's not two fa,
well, it's, it's two factors but they're identical and
the same
failure.
That's
no, that's one factor.
That's one
factor. Two questions. One factor. No, Kurt, it's what's in your head.
Both of them are what's in your head.
So. Exactly. Right.
So, if, if they support anything reasonable now and the other,
my other concern too is like, I think Facebook or I think it was Facebook.
I had to share my phone number with them and of course,
then I started kind of getting spams and I had to figure out how to set my,
don't contact my phone settings in my Facebook account. Right.
But in general, you know, most of these companies aren't that crazy abusive.
So, yeah, I would say number two, if the site supports two fa
you,
you forcibly enable it and if it doesn't support two
fa you might want to look at a different site.
I, I agree with that. I think there's no excuse to not use
to fa like, make it, make it happen.
-- And
-- then the third really massive mistake and this is
one open ssh made that resulted in like key disclosures,
not removing dead stuff.
That's so
hard. I
know. But so, you know, it's, but it's one of those things where it's actually,
it's like flossing. It's actually not that hard.
The problem is you have to do it every day.
I, I do floss every day.
You're the first person I've met outside of my dentist's office staff
that
-- I believe.
-- Yeah, they, they, my dentist is shocked.
It's funny because I tell them they said,
do you floss I say every day and you can tell
they don't really believe me until they look at my,
until they look at my teeth like, oh you do floss every day said I told you I do.
Yeah.
And, and that's part of it like I just, you know,
recently went through account cleanups, you know, with the CS A and
there was one or two old ones that,
you know, needed to be nuked off.
I mean, we'd already suspended them but we just hadn't removed them, removed them.
But,
you know, that's one thing like I am super fascist
about, for example, looking through, uh, the, you know,
the logins because most of these services support that.
Now they'll tell you when the last time a user logged in is
so, you know, sort by age and, you know, anything over six months old,
you, you have to give me a reason not to nuke this.
I was just working with,
with something the other day and I can't remember what this was to save my life.
But it had an option to say that if someone
hasn't logged in after a certain amount of time,
just like lock the account.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
Well, and by definition, if the user isn't using that account, you know,
I also want to close it because it saves us a few bucks every month.
So it's, it's basically, it's, it's like flossing.
It's actually not a lot of work to go nuke an account out of a system typically.
But it is one of those things where, yeah, you have to stay on top of it.
-- But
-- no, it, it, it is a lot of work and, and I think flossing is a great example.
You have to do something about that. And not only that Kurt, I could have,
I could have, I mean, I have a github
account. I use my github account all the time.
And if I was a member of, of GEN two,
does it tell me the last time I used a gen two resource or just the last time?
-- I
-- actually
looking to see if
github
-- hints me that you don't
-- know. So don't, don't be all high and mighty on here.
All right. That's, this is my point.
And, and
I'm going to compare this to flossing.
I floss every day and every day, I think I don't want to floss today every single day.
I don't know why I just think it every day
and this is even worse where it's like, oh, I should look at that. I'll do it tomorrow.
It's
very easy to put this up. This is an example of
this has to be fixed with tools,
expecting people to do this on a regular basis is failure is the only option.
It has to be tools.
Well, the problem is, it's a, it's a much more subtle process even it's, you know,
it's part of the exit process.
And also how, especially with something like gen two,
how do you define what constitutes leaving the organization?
Like, what if somebody goes silent for three months?
You know, it's obviously with companies, it's a bit easier, you know,
when we stop paying them, we boot them out.
But I do agree that, like, I would like to see every
sort of website service thing that I use,
be able to give me a list of all the users I have allowed in.
And like,
when is the last time they actually touched it
or used it or logged in or did something?
So that, yeah, I can flush everybody
more than three months old and ideally make it like
a flag somewhere where I just set it and forget
it just automated.
Yeah.
Well, that's what I mean, like, ideally, right, maybe that's, you know,
something we need to add to the cwe list, lack of, you know,
automated account lockout slash removal due to an activity.
I, I think it's necessary. Right.
I, I think without it, your failure is the only way it's going to end. So,
-- so anyway,
-- anyway, sort of, um,
those were the three main failures I would say that they made.
And I mean,
the good news is that also the way the attacker made the get commit was super noisy.
Right. There's ways they could have added the get commit. There were much,
well, it's not much that would have been super quiet
but the way they did, I think they did a forced merge or something.
So like every single person, you know, would have seen that like noisy get message,
I forget what it says
and they probably like me would have ignored it and be like whatever,
whatever force merge.
Great. Like just work. Damn it.
Um
And uh yeah, I mean, the good news is with get, you know, it's
git is really easy to roll back to a previous state.
So all you got to do is figure out like what's
my last known good state and just roll back to that
end of story.
Well, not only that, the other beautiful thing Git does and other
source code management systems don't do.
This is, let's say I go back in time and change a git commit.
I've now ruined
-- all future git commits
-- or you broke Shaw,
which probably didn't happen.
-- Yes,
-- I could totally do that.
But you know what I mean? It, it's comparable to the Blockchain
in terms of everything has to happen in the right order.
It has very strong internal state
kind of control and reporting
and it's,
and here's the best part, it's really easy to use.
That's the real trick I think.
And it, it has to be, I mean,
I'll, I'll go back to your list.
You pointed out three things, one of which I think you can blame on, on Gen,
which is
able to factor off which they've done.
But like strong passwords, you can't enforce that. And
watching for old accounts again, that has to be tooling. That's, that's github's
fault.
Actually strong passwords you can,
the provider can enforce now because for example, they could use that.
What is it? 500 billion broken passwords?
That's, you know, public now. Right. Remember the thing?
The guy built a cloud flare worker. So you can check
the, have I been pwned? Try
hunts website? Yes.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And well, more to the point,
the guy built like a cloud flare worker with an API so
that you can in tens of milliseconds when somebody enters a password,
say
like, yeah,
we've seen that password somewhere in this list of 500 billion passwords.
So, no, you're not allowed to use it.
And again, I would say that is probably something everybody should be doing now,
if they do passwords,
you know, and not like o
author Sam or something,
maybe,
I mean, it, it's more complicated than that.
Well, ok, let me, let me point out too. Something to remember is github
is also an identity provider. So these accounts kind of matter.
Yes. In their case, I think you could argue that have I been po passwords? But I mean,
the solution is still password managers?
Oh, I agree.
But I mean,
this kind of forces people into using a password manager because literally
pretty much any terrible password a person
will pick has already been picked and used
and ped
and in all the good passwords, people picks
picked are in, have I been pwned? I mean, that's part of the problem is,
and basically at this point, any human generated password is probably in the,
have I been pwned database?
I mean, for real? Right. And, and you know what's going to happen
is
if I
have my password and it shows up and says, oh, you're on this list,
you know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna add a one and all of a sudden, pow,
it's not on the list.
Right.
So, like, even that doesn't necessarily fix the problem two factor off,
fixes the problem,
-- well,
-- enforce two factor off.
Right.
So, so anyway,
and then you continue reading in the list and it's actually
kind of funny because it sounds like on the weekend github
wasn't very responsive,
which happens. I get it. I'm not going to blame him for that.
And then it looks like on July 3rd
gen two basically put all the pieces back together.
So it,
it really wasn't a very long outage.
It was definitely embarrassing for them, but they were very transparent.
My understand, like that's not the true source of their code.
It's like a mirror but just
available via
because it's really easy to do that.
Right. Right.
Exactly. Where it wasn't, it wasn't the one true source.
So that, that, that also helped. I'm sure with with a lot of this. But
I mean, fundamentally
I give them tons of credit. It was embarrassing. They were super open about it and,
and
they, they made the changes that I think they needed to make.
Right. They, they, they've been able to factor off,
well, force to factor off it's enabled by default.
But here, let me ask you a question
of all the organizations reading this
uh gen two wiki page describing the incident and what they're going to do.
What percentage of those that haven't already done this?
Do you think now will like what percentage of people reading this will go? Oh,
I can, you know, I should go enable because I,
I honestly didn't think you could force two factor off on github.
And I remember I tweeted that a while ago and then somebody pointed out that yes,
you can.
And I'm like, oh whoops,
because to put it bluntly like Google has this amazing web page.
It's a two factor off landing page where it's like, why should do this?
Why does it matter?
And then at the very bottom it says let's get started and it walks you through
and it just makes it so easy and pain like my mom could do it.
That's, that's the gold standard, right? Can your parents do it?
And
github, I was like,
I didn't even know that was an option and I dug around the settings and I'm like,
oh yeah, look at that.
There, it is. The annoying part being is I can't enable it by user.
I can only turn it off or on for the whole organization.
90% of me agrees is actually the correct solution.
-- The 10% of you that has to deal with the real world is like, man, that's
-- annoying.
I know.
You know what,
I don't think there's a real excuse anymore to not be using two factor off.
So while it definitely gives a little bit of pain
automated accounts with read only access. Yeah, I know.
And, and there's like the API stuff you're supposed to be doing.
-- Can you?
-- Yeah, I was gonna say, can you just set those up to use API keys?
Yeah.
But I mean, it's just, you know, managing them and stuff becomes a bit more of a chore.
Somebody has to have the two of a blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Right.
Um But like I said,
the 90% of me actually agrees that just make it a switch for the organization
is the correct thing to do.
The 10% of me that is, is annoyed by that because that means I don't,
-- I can't be a lazy
-- barger.
Now, you asked what percentage of people are going to do something about this
-- that
-- have read this wiki page.
I would guess the number is 10% or less.
-- I wouldn't have gone that high
-- because
it's,
I said or less
I learned the answer.
I mean, here is the thing is
there are, first of all this, this page just describes what gen two did.
It doesn't give like real world advice, not like,
not like a high quality security podcast such as
this.
But, and, and we've already told people to do it.
And my guess is we might get 20% of our listeners just because I,
I suspect there's a certain,
we'll say interest in security that is lacking from the general public.
But
it's, it's, again, it's like flossing,
it's too easy to do it tomorrow.
Right.
And,
and I almost feel like this is one of
those things that at some point someone like github
is just going to have to pull the trigger and say everyone's using two factor
off. Now if you don't like it, go find someone else to work. Yeah.
Well, and the thing is, I mean, it's not like,
you know, they nuked your account but you just have to go enable two factor off.
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
Log in, enable to factor off. You don't want to factor off too bad.
Yeah.
And I would say that they provide the options that
don't require you to give them your phone number,
for example, which is,
that's, that's my only concern is places that support two factor off and,
and only support like the phone number. S MS stuff
-- drives me nuts and that's
-- not two factor
off.
It is.
Well, it's even worse now. Freaking Google. Which, which I won't lie.
It's a great feature but with,
with android messages now you can bring it up in your web browser.
And so
the, the irony is someone, was someone, a nonsecurity person I know was saying, oh,
look, now, I can just get my two factor off codes to my web browser.
I'm like that completely defeats the purpose
of two factor on.
Well, no, but it is a separate, it is a separate
-- pan until
-- it pops up in their web browser. Right?
Well, I don't know what CSO R,
what
S and CSO
-- rrf and whatnot protections they have.
-- It doesn't matter.
The point is when you, when you're using something like two factor S MS,
you need like a separate thing,
right? If it's all going to the same machine that doesn't count requiring.
So I just went in github
to enable this on the distributed weakness filing,
requiring two factor authentication will remove all users in the
distributed weakness filing organization who have not enabled it or
on their personal accounts,
one user will be removed from this organization and it is
like I said, it's an internal account or it's like a,
an internal account with read only access for um C I or whatever.
So I guess
-- they're gonna have to go fix that
-- sweet.
So, yeah, I,
I don't like that because I wish it would actually just
lock them out until they enable two fa on their account.
Kind of like what Google does, right?
Google is like, ok,
you have to go enable two fa and once you enable two fa I'll let you see your email.
Right. You know, it's got a gun to the, your email inbox.
But yeah, so that's not the, that's a little bit painful because, you know,
you can't enable it until you're willing to nuke a bunch of people's accounts,
which is kind of annoying but whatever.
Yeah, that's fair.
-- But, but
-- yeah, I, I, I'm getting to the point now where I agree, we essentially,
yeah.
Well, it's like your car,
it has a light that goes on and I think most cars ding or bing now, if you don't put the,
if the driver doesn't put their seatbelt on.
Right. And it will, like, annoy you to death until you do it.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, and, and same thing with the airbags and whatnot
and, and I, I think it just, it has to be like that. I'm sorry,
I agree. I agree completely.
And, and I see no better way to end it than, than just to say that is like,
II, I could tell you all to enable, to factor off many of you won't.
And, and I hope the day comes soon when just, there's no choice it,
it's going to be like that and, and that's the way it is.
It's happening with us selling TLS. Right. Chrome. Is moving ahead with in what
is it this? Oh, it's this month that they will mark all http websites as insecure and
same deal. Exactly.
I, I approve.
I just hope it doesn't take 10 years.
It, it might,
but I think two factor off is the,
it's the next great battle where we're going to see very similar things and
I think it's getting close, man, but at the same time, the day it happens,
it's going to be huge.
I think at a minimum, it has to happen for these ident
identity providers
because
like my linkedin account and my Facebook account,
but you know, those accounts,
they are just too important to people that that's who they are online
and it's how they log into other systems. So like, yeah, I think at this point we,
you know, they have to bite the bullet and do it.
Yep. Yep. Yep. I, I agree 100%. All right, sweet. Well, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com for the show notes.
We'll have a link to this fantastic gen two report
and you can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag on social media to get our attention.
And if nothing else, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.