Hi and welcome to the open source security podcast.
This is Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
-- Hey, Kurt,
-- thanks, man.
So this is an exciting episode.
This episode will go up in a mere couple of hours probably
and it will be consumable by the universe as we announce our podcast and,
and it's gonna kind of be a big deal for us.
So I'm super excited and most importantly is we get to
actually talk about some current news instead of recording podcast,
you know, weeks ago
that we know will be too stale to be relevant today. So that's super exciting.
So I'll tell you what, uh why don't you start out what, what's,
what's new in the world?
Kurt, what do you want to talk about?
So recently I've run into a problem or a design decision made almost a decade
ago that is now coming back to haunt us again and again and again,
and that is on Linux, you got your proc slash P ID slash mem
and you can write to it and this,
this seemed like a good choice at the time
because it allowed debuggers to monkey with their own
programming.
But now it means
virtually any file over right.
Vulnerability can potentially become a code execution vulnerability.
And I've also been reading apparently a lot of user space root kits are using this.
Yeah. OK. So why don't you tell us why that is bad, first of all?
All right, let's, let's back it up even farther.
What is slash proc slash P I
slash mem? OK. What, what is it?
So proc is the process uh sort of memory space
on Linux and it's represented as a bunch of files.
So you've got things like
uh slash proc slash the process ID and then you've got things like
the command line options, it was run with, you've got things like the,
the program's current memory
uh and just a whole bunch of other fiddly bits that if you're not a developer,
you don't need to care about.
And so for debugger, for, if you want to debug a program, typically,
what you wanna do is you want to put like a break point into the program
somewhere so that you can like stop it and take a look at what's going on.
Well, if you can modify the process's memory,
you can insert as many breakpoints and whatnot as
you want and you can even change things.
So
for example, you can stress test a program, you know,
you can change a setting or a variable in memory as the program executes.
So this is incredibly useful for debuggers.
But from a security point of view,
like I said, it means any program that has a file over right issue,
it can now write to itself and it can modify itself.
All right.
So I, I think it's also important to point out here that the, the real danger
is if you have say a web server or PHP application,
there's a special file called slash proc slash self,
which refers to the process itself slash met, right?
And that's kind of the issue is you can have
an attacker overwrite or I shouldn't say overripe but rather
inject code into the process, literally, which is
really exciting sounding when you're doing the red team work.
But when you're trying to defend,
this is this is a terrifying feature unquestionably and,
and I'm familiar with the issue you speak of
and this is something that that's actually being talked about
right now is what do we do with this? Because you're right.
This was something that was said a very long time ago
and the world is changing dramatically.
If you look 10 years ago in the open source universe,
we laughed about viruses when someone would say about, you know,
do I need a virus scanner on Linux?
We would laugh at that question.
And now when people ask that question,
I think that's a perfectly legitimate question.
And this is one of those examples of
we have some work to do
to make sure we do things the right way.
And now I will also say that that's some,
some something I know about this as well is so the slash proc
file system,
Sc Linux
doesn't cover that, for example.
So it poses some unique challenges for us and what we're going to do.
And so the the knee jerk reaction
is, well, let's just mark proc self
mem as non writeable, right?
But that doesn't actually solve the problem because there are some
other clever things you can do with the proc file system.
And so
what we really want to do is make sure we enhance the security of that
and make sure it can do things like be covered by the Linux security module.
Uh Se Linux, in our case is what we plug into that,
but also various other protections built into the operating system. Whereas
instead of proc being a special snowflake, let's make it follow the rules, right?
And that's uh in my opinion, that's totally the right way to do it.
Yeah, I mean, this is just one of those classic things where, you know, 10 years ago,
if you told me, hey, Kurt,
uh Red Hat is gonna run a service where we
let people sign up for free or almost next to nothing
and they upload a bunch of random code that we then run for them.
Uh not in a virtual machine but on
an actual like shared virtual machine with other customers
uh, I would have laughed because that would have been clearly insane.
Uh And of course, now that's the entire business model behind containers.
-- Yeah,
-- but we didn't say it's not insane. Right.
But
no, no, it's
a, I
mean, this is a huge deal. Right. Is,
there's,
there's this crazy convergence in the open
source universe of kind of features and threats
and in the real world, I mean, it,
it's like we keep talking about over and over again open source one,
everyone's using it.
But now the terrifying thing is because everyone's using it.
We have real threats, we have real dangers in this stuff. And
it's not like the good old days when, when Linux
and open source in general were relatively ignored just because they didn't have
a massive user base and now they have a huge user base.
And so from the security perspective, it, it's borderline terrifying.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, we've got situations where, what that, uh, I wanna say that Seagate Nas
Drive thing is, uh,
there's like 88,000 of them apparently hacked
and running some sort of Bitcoin miner
that's not efficient at all. They need to buy some basics.
But so, so that actually leads into one of the,
the interesting news stories that I found this week was that
there's apparently a rise in telnet
activity. People are seeing who run honey pots, which is related to the, the N A
takeover because apparently what's happening is a lot of these IOT devices
are running.
I, I guess Linux
or open source in general,
but they're also using Telnet as one of the ways you connect to them.
And
we all know Telnet was we, we,
we thought it was dead because it's incredibly old and super insecure.
So this is, this is honestly a little terrifying to read a story like this.
It's actually worse than that. The problem isn't so much TNO
because this would also affect systems running. Ssh. The real problem is
a lot of these device manufacturers have
default accounts
like admin 12345.
Yeah.
Um, you know, I, I recently had to reset my,
one of my DS L devices and it took me forever
because they used uh 12345 instead of 1234 for the password.
And it took me a while to hunt that down. Now, the good news is,
yeah, the good news is on, on, you know,
on some of these devices you can change the administrative password
but on many you can't,
you know, they, or, or it's so painful that there's, you know,
no regular user is gonna do this, you know, like your mom or my mom, they're
not
-- painful,
-- man. I mean, I first of all, I don't want my parents
even touching the admin interface and anything they own.
But then
even if they knew it was there, they don't care,
they're not going to go in and change a password.
I mean, it's kind of like the old wifi used to default to open.
Remember where you buy your, your wifi router,
you plug it in and now the neighbors have internet
and this is a very similar problem.
Yeah.
So, I mean, the problem though is, is you,
you have a situation where legitimately you need to ship devices in
a way so that people can log in and administer them.
But how do you do so securely?
You know, and especially when it's a cheap device that cost maybe 20 $30.
You know, you're not going to build some huge
tool chain or some huge administrative thing that's secure.
I mean, this is a 20 $30 device that
uh I mean, it's,
it's at the point now where one of my wi fi uh access points was acting a bit flaky.
So I, I threw it out and
bought a new one,
-- right?
-- Like I, I could have troubleshooted it. But,
you know,
well,
this is gonna be one of the terrifying things about
iot is when something costs me literally a dollar,
I'm not gonna fix it. I'm gonna throw it away and go get a new one
and, and the universe is going to do this.
So now of course, the Bitcoin miners will,
will have a nearly infinite supply of devices they can use.
But, but as normal people,
I mean,
should we care should we just accept the fact
that we're gonna be throwing this crap away for?
-- I, I don't know. It's a weird,
-- not even cheap stuff.
It's, uh,
did you hear about the Sony Bravia 50 models of
their TV S or are losing the youtube app?
What do you mean losing the youtube app?
Well, it's a smart TV that has an app for youtube
and as I understand it there's like the old version of the
youtube app and the protocol or something that Google will no longer support
and Sony is not going to
ship an updated app to people. So
your Sony Smart TV
has a youtube app that won't work,
right? So, they're just turning it off.
Yeah. And, and so, and the thing is even if I,
if I had one of those TV, S and I wanted to fix it,
would I even be able to, I mean, I might technically be violating the D MC A in America.
Regardless of that, I would put a 10 to 1 odds on you bricking your TV versus fixing
what
you do
that.
Exactly.
So, you know,
even if you want to fix these things and even
if you have the technological capability to fix it,
it could still, it's just so
painful to do so that even somebody like you or I is not going to do it.
This reminds me is
I have a Nexus five X phone
and I wasn't getting my upgrade to Android seven fast enough for my liking.
So I decided I'm going to side load
Android seven onto my phone.
It is a horrifying user experience to do this.
And, and I made a comment to someone I work with who has one also.
I, I was like, th this was terrible.
I mean, I, I couldn't imagine a worse experience in this. Like it kept failing on me.
The error messages were cryptic and,
and luckily I, I knew enough that I was comfortable continuing to try.
But then also as it was pointed out to me,
is anyone willing to side load an operating system
onto their phone is clearly not the target market
for easy updates, right?
And additionally,
these are people who are going to be way more willing
to put up with a whole bunch of pain and suffering
in order to side load the new version of Android
regardless of how terrible the experience is. And, and that kind of hit home, right?
Is that it,
it's very much, there's the, the normal people universe and then there's kind of
us where we do a lot of weird stuff and we're willing to put up with a lot of pain.
And so, II, I don't know.
And I look at IOT in this context and it, it, it horrifies me a little bit because
I can't even keep half this stuff updated and taken care of.
And, and so normal people have have no hope. I mean, let's face it.
Well, and I think it's even worse than that, that the,
the economics of these devices are, they get sold and then,
well, there's no recurring revenue for the manufacturer to support it to, to want
them to support it. And
nobody in there, you know,
and if you try and sell a light bulb that has
a recurring monthly charge of $1 or even a penny,
you know, I, I recently, uh, was looking at on
Netflix
now
service camera.
Yeah.
You know, and like, for example, Nest, you know, the Nest cameras,
they now have an outdoor model,
uh, and it's 250 bucks. Ok. It's a little pricey but whatever. But
you then have to pay either 100 bucks a year or
$300 a year to get 10 or 30 days respectively of,
of data and of the, uh, of the, uh, video storage.
Right?
I can't, I can't buy that Nest camera and have it like stored to my local file server.
I
have to pay
Google, wait and
store
-- it.
-- So you buy the camera for money
and then to use the thing you just bought, you have to pay somebody more money.
Well, you can use it, you can watch it in real time.
But if you wanna have historical footage,
10 days or 30 days of historical footage to check,
which obviously is a security camera.
That's kind of the whole point of these things, you know,
is after the event happens you go look back and you're like, oh,
it's the guy in the baseball cap that did it,
you know?
So, yeah, you have to pay 100 bucks a year or 300 bucks a year.
Um, and, and part of it is, you know, that boils down to the,
they want this user experience that is painless.
Right.
And, you know, having people run local file servers and stuff like that is,
is not painless.
It's quite painful.
-- Yeah,
-- that's fair.
I mean, this is,
this kind of comes back to my complaint about some of these
like massive multiplayer online role playing games is either charge me per month
or charge me for the game.
I don't want
both of them, right?
Which is just like one of my pet peeves is I,
I hate that that you want me to pay for your game
and then to pay you once a month to play your game.
It's like, no, I hate that.
So I don't know, it's crazy. Uh But however, let, let's stick to IOT
and some other cool news. 10 million raspberry pies have been sold.
That's crazy, man. 10 million.
Well, you know, I bought two of them.
I, I bought one to act as a firewall and I bought one as a,
as a backup slash
three,
-- you know, one because
-- they're so cheap.
Are off
one of them. Is my, my DNS server in the basement. Well, my backup, my secondary DNS.
But then I, I do, I have a raspberry pie.
When the, the touchscreen came out, I bought the,
the touchscreen with a new pie and the touchscreen is really cool actually.
And, and I'm actually,
I'm putting together a project to do stop motion for my kids because they,
they got interested in stop motion animation at, at a museum this summer.
And so I've got it, it's nearly complete. Funny enough.
The thing that's hanging me up now
is I wanna over engineer this.
So it automatically uploads their videos to youtube and my wife is like,
that's ridiculous.
Just save it to a thumb drive or something like why are you doing this?
And I'm like, but no, it's way cooler if it uploads it magically and,
and so it's done except for that.
And so now I'm, I'm, you know,
busy not getting the work done because I'm trying to over engineer the solution.
Well,
it's funny that you mention that because I was actually there
was a tweet recently talking about a family privacy policy.
Uh and this family's privacy policy, if I remember it was three main points,
it was that
basically what happens at home is by default private.
And if you want to record,
you have to tell people and especially if you want to upload and share it,
say to Facebook or youtube,
you have to get
permission from everybody involved.
You know.
Um, and it's funny because to me, you know what,
you and I grew up in a world where everything that happened at
home was private by default and not recorded except for the neighbor lady.
Right.
Yeah. Or, you know, like a birthday party once in a while be recorded. But,
you know, and, and it's funny to me to be growing up in a world where, yeah,
my kids could record their lives 24 7 with their,
like ipod touch if they really wanted to,
you know, you know, what disappoints me
about this
more than anything else
is we walk around
with cameras in our pockets
and no one has taken a picture of Bigfoot yet.
Well, you know, to me that's pretty much
the
proof that
that's
true now that there are more cameras than ever.
-- There
-- are
-- fewer
-- pictures. Like, like if you're running from Godzilla, you
backwards and you just
hit
-- record.
-- You know,
you know, that
great question is if, if a monster attacked,
how many people would die streaming it to
youtube versus running and saving their own lives.
-- I bet the number would be significant
-- based on the
number of people that have killed themselves playing Pokemon Go,
uh, you know, human nature, right?
It's called Darwinian Evolution Curt.
Anyway. All right. That's enough of that.
Yeah, other, other exciting news
is
so we love our long passwords, right?
There was a really crazy story I ran across
that was talking about the last dot FM password leaks
and some of them are actually really long passwords which got me thinking, I'm like,
how on earth did somebody crack this stuff?
I mean, they're like 40 character passwords, right? Like super duper long.
It turns out
that they used lyrics to songs,
which I guess being a music service totally makes sense.
But at the same time, it really got me thinking that,
you know, long passwords that come from somewhere else are obviously no longer safe
because
if it's written down somewhere, someone's gonna figure that out.
Well, you know, it's, I think it comes, uh, to put it in geek terms,
it's a question of entropy, right?
And the reality is the bad guys have access to, like, the texts of
human
history,
all the books, all the song
ever written,
you know?
Yeah. And, and to be honest, it's not that big, you know, a couple.
Like I have a Kindle and, uh,
somebody was ribbing me for buying a Kindle because it doesn't have an SD card slot.
-- It
-- can hold
more
-- books
-- than you could read before you die. Right.
Yeah, exactly. It can hold three gigabytes of data.
And the average, like, 152 100 page book on that thing is like
one or 200 kilobytes.
So, yeah, I mean, it can hold more books than I'll ever read in a lifetime
and that's without a job or sleep.
Right. You know.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. And
you know, that, that always makes me sad. Is I have, uh, I bought a nook a long time ago,
which I, I still have
and I look at all the books I have and I get sad
because I, I haven't read them all and I know that there are
probably 10 years worth of books I have on that thing right now and it's, it's,
it's crazy.
Right. It's so easy to buy books. Or someone will mention something.
They're like, oh, yeah, I should get that. And then you could buy it
and then you never read it. I feel like I'm playing Pokemon where, where
you catch all these Pokemon
and then you never look at them again.
Well, you know, we've gone from an environment of scarcity, you know,
as a kid buying tapes or C DS was a big deal and now it's like,
how many hundreds of thousands of songs can you get for free
or, you know, if you're willing to spend 100 bucks on itunes?
-- It's
-- crazy.
You know, though, I have not bought
music in an extremely long time just because I now suffer
from the paradox of choice as it used to be.
You'd go to the record store and there were like three records.
Well, or, or C DS in most cases
that I actually cared about.
And now I look at, you know, itunes or, or Google play or whatever,
whatever it is I'm using
and I'm, I'm just mortified by the choices I have and then I,
I give up and just don't buy anything.
So it's,
it, it, I always find it comical that, that we love our choice or we think we do.
But then we're presented with a near infinite selection.
We often do nothing.
Well, I mean, it's, you know,
it's one of the fundamental things human humanity suffers from is
I could have made a better choice.
You know, what if I make a bad choice? What if I, what if I buy the wrong music? If
-- you're doing nothing
-- is safer than making a decision, right?
Which speaking of doing nothing, I, I love the,
the news story I'm most excited about.
And this is the one I'd love to talk about is
there is a, a company that claims to have a hack proof system.
Let, let me pull this story up because I don't, I don't remember the name of them, but
I love it when people talk like this because if there's one thing,
history has shown us
that there are no absolutes.
OK. So the company is calling itself hack proof Systems Incorporated
and they're offering $5000 to the first person who
can crack a server protected by their technology.
And of course,
they're, they're not incredibly detailed at what their technology is.
But as you can imagine, I'm sure it's something
incredibly advanced Right.
-- More to the $0.5000.
-- What
is it?
You know, when, no, when you look at what the average, even like a quote
unquote, low paid security professional makes.
-- That's basically two weeks of
-- income.
Look at, look at bug bounties. Right.
If, if you find a good security flaw, you, you could be talking 100 grand.
Right. And this is apparently this is hack proof technology,
which I would, I would equate would be on the level of say an iphone root kit,
which I know is worth multiple, hundreds of thousands of dollars.
Yeah, these guys are offering five grand,
you know,
things like this really drive me nuts because if they were offering $5 million
and it was, you know, bonded, then I'd be like, ok, maybe, maybe it's legit. But,
you know, it's like I could offer a hack.
Uh, I'll pay, you know, a dollar to break into this box. It's sitting on my desk.
Is it on?
Nobody's gonna do that because it's,
it's gonna cost a couple 100 bucks to get an airplane ticket over here,
you know, very much.
So, I mean, that's why, you know, banks don't get robbed anymore by and large is
you're
gonna get
a bank
robberies apparently are still incredibly common. I didn't know this.
I was doing some research into something else
and
I,
somehow I stumbled upon the fact that that the number
of bank robberies is still quite significant but the,
I mean, these guys are walking away with almost nothing. I mean, it,
economically speaking, you'd be better off getting a part time job,
almost anywhere over robbing banks.
But it's still,
I guess it's probably that mindset right where people think, oh, I'll rob the bank
and in reality you'd probably make more money robbing, you know, mcdonald's. But
it's still,
I, I get it right because historically speaking,
banks had all the money and they still do.
It's just money is now, you know,
data on a computer instead of stuff sitting in the big vault.
Well, I know the last time I looked locally in Alberta,
the average bank robber was making off with something like 2000 $300.
That's terrible. You know, which honestly if you're, if, if you're
well, but by definition, if you're into short term thinking,
that's a pretty good deal.
-- I
-- mean, that is one way to look at it, you know, and
I mean, the reality is the people that commit this kind of crime,
they're not into long term thinking and risk evaluation and, you know,
they're not like, well,
the chance of getting caught is 7% with an annualized rate of this.
And if I make, you know, 100 grand a year bank robbing,
but then I spend two years in jail.
Is it worth it?
No, they're like,
I'm gonna,
and half of these ones in Alberta now they don't even have a weapon,
they just pass a note to the teller and of course the banks are just, like, whatever,
give them the money, like, just make them go away.
Right. Because, you know, we don't want to know they're trained to do that.
Well, you know, I mean,
you,
well, a single medical claim is vastly more expensive.
You know, somebody even gets punched in the face.
So, you know,
I mean, what really makes me laugh here.
I don't know if you have it down there, but in Canada, in the winter all of the banks,
well, most of the banks put up signs in winter saying, you know,
please take off your ski mask
-- when you come into the bank.
-- Right?
No, actually, uh, ski masks are not often worn here,
which
I guess it is a comical problem to have is, is, you're right.
I could see that being in Canada that, that ski masks, uh,
would be expected apparel and, yeah, take it off that,
that's really funny.
If somebody walked up to me in a ski mask, I'd be like, take it and go just,
just leave me alone.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, you know, it's when it's minus 30 outside and blowing,
you kind of have to wear a ski mask even.
And, I mean, I'm talking, like, even going from the car to the door,
you know,
I've had people
travel here, you know, they get off at the airport and it's like,
did you bring your coat?
-- No, we just have to get to the car. Yeah. No, you're, you're going to die.
-- I,
I'm familiar with that every now and then
it will get that cold. It's, it's fairly rare and when it does it is terrible.
I was actually, I was, I was on a plane one time when it was really,
really cold like that and I was honestly a little surprised that the plane, like it,
they had no real issues.
I was waiting for something crazy to happen because it was so cold and no,
it just took off and, and then I landed in,
I think I was going to California that time.
So it was a very pleasant landing coming from where I was at.
Yeah.
But, uh, no, I mean, it's, it's these behaviors that are
in general people don't deal well with strange behaviors,
you know?
Uh, yeah, I mean, that's
thousands of years of evolution on our side essentially. Right?
It's kind of that in order to fit in with society you need to fit in.
Yeah. And I mean, it was a lot like traffic, you know, if everybody,
like, every time I'm in traffic and somebody tries to give way to me, you know,
like for, like
they basically try to give up their right of way. It's like, no,
no,
just
doesn't work.
I know what you mean.
It is a challenge without a doubt
and I see a lot of that in security, you know, we say follow the rules, do this, do that.
But, you know, human nature when it really comes down to it, um,
people share passwords, people pick poor passwords,
you know.
I mean,
and these long passwords are interesting to me because
just looking at that list for a second,
some are just like repeating strings like this one that's all
zeros,
you know, it's like 20 or 30 0 and then there's this one that's like a,
followed by just a big pile of ss,
you know, it, it makes me laugh because like when I, I was setting up my, uh,
an iphone for my mom
and so I entered the pass code is 1234
and it specifically warned me, are you sure you want to use that passcode?
Right?
So it's like, it's, I guess there's a short list of like bad pass codes for your phone,
like
1234 being one of them.
But realistically like with a four digit pin number, it's
chances are if you shoulder surf the person, you're gonna catch it pretty quick.
I mean,
my five year old son does this all the time and I've
actually gotten him trained now to the point where I say password,
you have to turn around and I, I make him turn around and face away from me.
Yeah. You know, I
taught my kids that as well at a young age where they would,
they'd stare at me while I was typing a password and I'd say look away, you can't,
you can't see me do this.
And now, yeah,
they've reached a point that when they see the password dialogue appear,
they look away, which is really funny.
Yeah.
Well,
and this is also the reason I upgraded to
an iphone IE because it has the fingerprint scanner.
Literally,
the reason I upgraded my phone now is so I don't
have to deal with my five year old trying to shoulder sur
which kind of has its own set of problems because so
I have a fingerprint scanner on my phone as well.
And I will occasionally turn it off depending upon
what I'm doing and where I'm going because I found out that
in the US,
you don't have to give out your password to authorities,
but
they can, they can basically touch your phone to your finger
and that's not illegal.
And so that's like it's really something else. I mean,
it, it kind of comes back, you know, tying this back to passwords is
it's one thing when you have a password, you know,
but your fingerprint and you know, legally speaking is not the same thing,
whereas you can often use both of those things to accomplish the same outcome,
which is fascinating to me.
Well, I think a lot of what it boils down to is
-- unless it's in your head, it's not private anymore. Even
-- that,
even
if
they,
even if they couldn't compel true. I mean,
and even if they didn't,
even if they weren't allowed to compel you to touch your finger to the phone,
they could just take your fingerprints and build a 3D model off of it using,
uh,
well, 3D.
And here's what blows me away about 3D printers now is
they have one at Costco for 30 bucks for little kids.
-- A
-- 30
-- dollar 3d
-- printer.
I'm assuming the business model is cheap printer.
-- I
-- mean,
it's like this,
it's this little plastic spool printer.
And, well, have you also seen the pen one?
So you have this pen that extrudes hot plastic, essentially that cools really fast.
So you can basically draw in 3D.
That's fascinating. So, so you're the printer?
Yeah.
Yeah. It's like 20 bucks or something.
It's, it, it just blows me away.
Unbelievable.
Wow. That's so crazy.
Yeah, I, no, the, the, the, what, what really blows me away is,
I'm looking at the toys that are available to my kids now and,
you know, they're the science fiction for us from, well, even five or 10 years ago,
little 20.
Ok. The 3D printing pen I'm seeing here is 9995
but I'm not seeing a $30 3D printer
on the internet.
But regardless, having a 3D printing pen is crazy.
That's amazing to me.
And I think it's,
it's probably worth pointing out here since this
is a an open source security podcast.
There is a very open source friendly printing company called Lulls
Bot.
And we've got a guy at Redhead, actually, his name is uh Spot Tom Calloway.
And he goes to these conferences and he always
brings his 3d printer and he's printing stuff nonstop.
And it, it's just fascinating because everybody just stands there and watches and,
I mean, it, it's not as unique as it used to be
because I remember like 34 years ago he'd show up with
this stuff and there'd be a crowd of people and I,
I was one of them where you just,
it was hypnotic watching this stuff work because it was
so bizarre and unlike anything you've ever seen before,
well, it's like watching a plant grow but, you know, speed it up, right?
It's just this, this,
no, this thing takes shape.
You start with literally nothing and then boom, you have this 3D object that just
magically appeared out of
chair.
It's
a
weird,
weird new problems and, and issues to do.
I mean, it's like when they 3D printed the, the TS a keys
for, for your luggage right now, anyone literally can unlock any
airplane ts a style lock which is crazy
or you can just use a ballpoint pen.
But, uh,
well, I mean, you know, speaking of that, like the, uh, the bidding on the, um,
what is it?
The New York State elevator access keys,
uh, you know, the bidding is how deep the key is cut at various places.
Well, the key is actually called,
it's like the 6426 key or something and that's the actual bidding for the key.
So, you know, it's,
that is fantastic.
I mean, let's face it, man. Security through obscurity doesn't work.
I think that's a given and that is one of the,
well, it works until it fails and then you have. no,
that's,
there's
nothing you can do that
I do. That is one of the things I love
about the whole open source universe is it's very difficult to hide these things.
And so
you kind of when you design it from the start
with the thought that this will be wide open,
it really makes you
think long and hard about how to do it. Right.
Well, that's one of the things I love, you know, working here at Red Hat is
I don't live in daily fear of somebody getting access to our source code.
Whereas if I worked for Microsoft or Apple,
you know, that
would,
I mean, remember when the Windows source code was leaked online, you know,
way back in the day, a bit of it.
You know, it was a huge
debt
-- problem.
-- I, I worked here when that happened
and
I know it was,
we were very particular about do not look
at this code because there's immense legal ramifications.
If you look at the window source code and then you write open source software
because
if you're using any of those ideas that you have some significant, you know,
intellectual property concerns.
Yeah. No, it's just, it's one of those things where it's, uh,
but I mean, I, I, that is a very difficult philosophy to apply,
uh,
to certain parts of the physical security world. So, for example, I mean,
uh, locks, locks are a good example of where the lock mechanism itself,
you want people to beat on and find flaws.
Um, I don't know if you've seen this youtube channel,
I forget the name of it.
But this guy basically is a locksmith and he
takes locks apart and shows you how they work
and then he's got this thing where people send him locks that he then picks
and these people do all sorts of crazy things and, you know,
it takes them on average five minutes to open these locks,
right? Like this person sent him this crazy bike lock from Japan.
It looks really awesome. It's, you know, it looks amazing.
And then the guy like, peels the plastic off and he's like, ok, yeah,
it's welded up really well, blah, blah, blah.
But the actual lock mechanism itself was like, it took him like three minutes.
That's fantastic.
Now, have you ever picked a lock before?
I have picked a very cheap padlock that was
literally like put a flathead screwdriver in turn.
And I mean, that's the real ugly truth of some of these locks is they're so,
uh, like, mechanically weak that you, you don't even, you can just overpower them.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. That's probably,
I know that that's one of the things I love doing.
And in fact, this is for,
for those of you out there in the universe when you go to a hacker con,
there's generally a lock pick village
and you sit down at a table and there's usually locks and picks and all this stuff and,
and I, I love to pick locks.
It's
one of those things that is just fascinating to you.
I won't say I'm a pro at it by any means, but I do enjoy it.
And the beauty of the lock pick village is you sit down at
a table and other people come and you all sit together and,
and while you're like, picking locks by itself is a very boring thing to do.
If that's all you're focused on, you're gonna go nuts in about two minutes.
But it's awesome when you sit there at a table full
of people and you talk about whatever and you meet,
I honestly, I've had some of the best conversations at,
at Khan's sitting at the lock pick table.
You know, it always, whenever I see those,
it always reminds me of like sewing circles.
You know,
it's, you got this thing to like make work with your hands.
It's, it doesn't require all your concentration, but a little bit. And,
yeah, it's kind of
like a
fantastic comparison. Kurt. The lock picking sewing circle.
I love it.
That's, that's awesome.
Oh, man. I can't think of a better way
to put this one to bed
a
lot of picking sewing circle. I love it.
All right, man.
Well, well, it's been fun and I guess until next week when I'll be at my remote,
undisclosed location for recording
and, and with that,
take care Kurt and have a good week and I'll talk to you soon.
You too. Thanks.
Bye folks.