Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and wondering about why things are the way they are.
-- Josh Bresser.
-- I mean, I'm wondering what the heck
the topic really is today because Kurt sent me two seemingly unrelated links.
And I'm like, I don't, I don't get it
-- so.
-- Well, they're related to my brain.
-- So
-- obviously,
which is maybe not helpful.
So, here's a, here's an actual question for you. So, Linux District,
there's hundreds of thousands of them,
they take packages upstream software
and sometimes make quite significant modifications to them.
That's right. Why? Because they can.
Ok. So I, I'm gonna go on a rant here because I can.
So
-- that's the beauty of doing your own sound engineering. Yeah,
-- that's right.
I mean, there's a lot of reasons for this, right. When we were at Red Hat,
you would have customer requests you would have making a certain change would
improve the way the
-- software work.
-- Let's ignore back porting. Sure.
Ok. Yeah. Yeah.
But, but from,
let's assume that they're not doing this because they're back reporting.
Let's assume that they're keeping up to date.
-- Why would they modify up to date software?
-- Right? I wanna pick on Debian though.
Perfect Debian is where my soapbox exists in this space.
Because Debian, historically, the Debian packagers
have often
and
just use the settings they like
for the things they package.
And my single biggest complaint about this is Vim, Vim and Debbie.
And by default like interprets mouse clicks
is like clicks on the screen for something
instead of the usual like I'm just going to highlight text and copy it.
So clicking on a terminal window
with the Vim in de
and by default isn't like you can't just copy
and paste text because it's doing like Vim crap.
And it,
it,
it grates at my mind every time and it's like, why is it like this?
And basically if you read a bunch of issues and stuff,
it just comes down to the developers like I like this feature and it's like, no,
that is
well and because they're well, when you say the developer, you mean the packager?
-- Yeah,
-- the pr,
right? Well, in Debian's world, they call their packager, Debian developers.
I just for the purposes of this podcast.
Let's put developers as upstream and packager as the Linux distro.
Sure, why not, right?
-- Because I think that will make it a bit clear
-- anyway, that's all I'm done now.
So and a perfect example is I ran into this with Pie Curl where I'm using pie curl,
you know, so I can use Python
to grab a bunch of stuff and I get certificate errors.
And I'm like, huh.
And the problem is pie curl is built on.
I want to say something like alpine Linux or whatever.
And it's basically, it's expecting the,
the intermediate certificate packages and the root certificate packages
in a different space in slash UTC than where it is on a lot of other distro.
And so I actually left a trail of breadcrumbs for future
people. But basically I curl has a built in like search this path.
It's like seven or eight common locations for the certificates.
And I basically rele
that in Python in like 10 lines of code. The problem is like you said,
the packager of the Python,
I want to say the wheel, is that what it's called?
A wheel is a type of package.
-- I think
-- it's the wheelchair
anyways.
Does it on alpine Linux. So that's how it works.
And if you want it to be otherwise you'd have to,
well, you'd have to
do it yourself. But the problem is then you,
but you wouldn't have own the name space,
right? So if you do an import pie curl, you'd still get there.
-- And that's just how it is.
-- And this is the same sort of problem.
-- I think we talked about this a couple of weeks ago where the curl on apple,
-- yes,
is not curl.
No, the curl on windows is not.
There's curl on windows, which is totally not curl and there's curl on Apple,
which is different defaults.
That's right.
And the Apple packagers have basically told the
curl upstream like we like it this way
as much as sometimes we don't like this.
I think there are enough legitimate reasons for this
for it to be a relatively common practice. Now, here's my second question.
Then that leads off this.
Why can't we get upstream to, to do some of these things or fix some of these things or
essentially why can't we get upstream
to do stuff so that we don't have to do all this kind of hacking around.
So I think there's a lot of history in that answer because just historically,
this is the way you did it,
right? You, you, if I was a Debian developer,
I would often be involved with the upstream project. That's not uncommon at all.
I mean, that's true of a lot of the packagers.
Well, they're the ones submitting the good buck reports, right.
Yeah, for sure, for sure.
And sometimes you could ask an upstream say like, hey,
I think the new default in the config file should be this and they might say, no,
we don't think so or they might just never go upstream because they
don't think it's important enough to ask or it could be a situation where
depending upon the libraries you're building against
drastically changes what's happening and upstream is just
going to support all of the possibilities.
You know, there's, there's like, I don't think there's a reason for that question.
Well, and that's, and that's actually kind of the answer I was looking for is
like any ecosystem problem. There is no one answer or solution or problem even.
It's,
it's thousands and thousands of
different problems and challenges. Often. There's more than one
and so, yeah. So there's this rich pastiche
of, it's just, it's all a giant mess.
Big wily wobbly mess pretty much because one thing I've seen
is I've seen a bunch of people speak out against,
uh, like on,
on hacker news saying basically packagers should not
modify software and it's kind of like you,
-- it's not going to work. They,
-- they, by definition are like
the, the, the whole process of building and packaging software is modification.
Well, and a stupid question.
But could you even remotely get a system
working by packaging upstream software without any modifications?
-- Yeah,
-- probably.
I bet you could.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, I imagine theoretically it's possible,
but is it practically possible?
No,
no, it's not.
I think
when you're talking about a system like a Debian
or a Fedora or ubuntu or these larger distributions,
you need to carry around weird build patches and you've got
to fit into their ecosystem in whatever strange way it is.
I mean, if you look at some of the more minimalist things,
sometimes they're a little more upstream adjacent, we'll say,
but I think generally speaking, once you start getting larger and larger
the potential needs and problems just get weirder and weirder and, and,
and sometimes, I mean, I remember too where, for example,
tu show up to an upstream and be like, hey,
you should take this patch and they'd be like, we don't like you.
So, no.
Yeah, there is politics at play too.
And I think that's something a lot of people forget is that open sources, people,
-- people do politics and relationships,
-- very opinionated people.
Yeah.
Just ask,
just ask any system in about system D I'm sure
they just really almost have no opinion at all.
So there is a,
uh, an ubuntu conference coming to town in, I think July or June.
I forget exactly when I should get as much Fedora swag as I can
just go hang out
just
because the thing I'm looking at is,
is similar to and so the way this ties in is so
we've seen a lot of work from home during COVID and obviously
you and I are biased because I've been working from full time
since 98 and you've been working from home since the early aughts,
right?
2004.
And again, the work from home thing is not just about, you know,
commercial real estate prices or managers control.
There's, there's many, many, many reasons,
uh, there's even the companies that have realized, hey,
we can use this to do a soft layoff like,
we can just basically get rid of a bunch of people by requiring this or you know,
them, we,
we can't legally make them more a funny hat to work to get them to quit. So
we'll just make them come into the office and
sit in a chair in a horrible environment.
And obviously,
what a lot of places are now discovering is
that their best and brightest talent have left.
Right,
because part of part of it would obviously be is
those are the people that have the most opportunity to,
well, to get a different job.
And the article
you, you sent me the article and I found a, you sent me a pay old one,
but I found a non pay old one from ours, Technica.
And the title is literally Apple spacex
Microsoft return to office mandates, drove senior talent away.
And I think what's really fascinating to me is
there's this double edged sword of by definition,
these people are working from home,
they want to continue to work from home and they'll probably
find some place that will let them work from home.
And like we see this with the CS A where if, if we
only hired local talent, well, for one thing,
I wouldn't work for them because I'm in a different country,
right? So I just, and saying that I just realized, I, I have no idea.
Nor have I even thought to ask where's
Acor based?
So our corporate headquarters is actually in Santa Barbara, California.
-- Is that like a mailing po box or an actual building?
-- No, no, we have an office,
we have a
building. Like,
I mean, it's
small now because like,
it was a bit larger at one point because they had a
-- lot more people working in the office
-- and then everybody went home,
that
COVID happened.
Even the people who live in Santa Barbara
generally don't come into the office anymore.
But it Santa Barbara is literally the worst place to go
to work in an office
because it's basically like Disneyland but real,
it's a super touristy city and every, it's, it smells like waffle cones, you know,
like that smell you get in an ice cream shop, like I'm completely serious,
-- like everywhere you
-- go
-- that like burnt, that burnt sugary smell.
-- Yeah. Right. Right.
And I'm working and no one else is. And it's like, this sucks.
Like I want to be in that shop across the street eating ice cream with those people.
Not in this conference room, watching
people across the street eating ice cream.
But it, it is a very nice place.
But yeah, that's where our,
-- our corporate headquarters is
-- because the thing I'm I'm
realizing is more and more the number one thing
historically that people have demanded for job satisfaction is
autonomy and looking at especially the high talent,
people, they have to have autonomy to do
what
they do right to do.
That weird stuff because, and I think, oh,
I was gonna send you another article but I couldn't find it,
like, essentially talking about, you know, like,
so what's the difference between, like, a local restaurant, you know,
with a chef who cares at a mcdonald's?
Right. They're, they're totally different products.
Like, they're both food but, you know, the one is a chef who goes to market and is like,
oh, they got mangoes?
Oh, they got fish. Hey, we're having mango fish burgers today.
Whereas the mcdonald's gets, you know,
a shipment of frozen foods and they make it exactly the same way
that everybody else does. And so the thing I'm coming to
wonder about is I think there's a space for the software that's
sort of mass produced and stamped out
and there's a space for this, you know,
very unique bespoke artisanal weird software.
But what I'm seeing is everybody seems to think it's
one or the other that they can't sort of coexist,
kind of like mcdonald's and a nice restaurant can't coexist.
-- And yet while they somehow do,
-- I,
I don't think your comparison makes a lot of sense in a lot of ways.
So I,
I'm going to put a link in the show notes
to there's a talk which it's one of those animated
Deos
where he talks about like, why do people do what they do?
And he focuses, there's a lot of open source in it and basically saying like,
why are all these incredibly smart, incredibly well paid, talented people, like,
basically building software for free on the side.
And I think the autonomy is a part of that,
that story, right? Where
I want to do what I want to do the way I want to do it.
And so doing, you know, hobbies are this story where if there's a hobby someone has,
where they want to make a thing,
they're gonna do it their way. Right.
And of course, my favorite is if you know,
anyone will say deep into a hobby and if you get two people together that are,
will say of similar skill levels,
it's amusing to listen to them how their way is better
and the other person is doing something wrong when the reality is, like,
it really doesn't make it difference at the end of the day.
But whatever, it, it's highly opinionated people.
But I, I think this is that, that story, like, like the whole work from home,
work from home, whatever it's people crave autonomy.
And,
I mean, part of, of capitalism
is making people do what they need to do. Right. It's, it's,
there are things a company must do to survive.
And I think there's often this, this specter for management of, like,
I have to be able to see you do the thing I need you to do.
Yeah. Well, and I mean, it, it also ties into the whole, like, for example,
you and I both remember a time where there were like seven Linux distributions.
Uh,
yeah,
they came on floppy disks.
-- I
-- was
-- gonna say they came on physical media and you bought them in a store.
Like there was, well, I mean, eventually there was like,
things like the Walnut Creek software archive,
I think.
And I, you know, like, I'm reminded of beer here in Canada.
We basically used to have three beer companies.
And now we have this rich, like locally,
I
-- don't even know how many beer brewing companies we have locally. It's a
-- lot. Yeah.
Anywhere you go now. So I have a funny story about that. So
when we worked at Red Hat, long ago,
we
hired a lot of people in the Czech Republic
and the Czech Republic is, well, you know,
that whole region of Europe is well known for enjoying and making very nice beer.
It's not a surprise.
So we have all these Czech Republic employees and I
go for dinner with some of them one day.
And
they basically said to me, they said,
why does everyone claim American beer is terrible?
And we were at some micro brew, you know, drinking, who knows what?
And I think we're in Boston at the time and this was,
I would say the start of the like micro brewery, just
everything that's happened.
So anyway, we're there and they say that and I'm thinking for a few minutes, like,
why would you ask me this question.
And then, yeah, I realized like when I was a kid,
your options for beer were Miller and Bud.
That was it.
And, but then,
you know, some 20 plus years later
now you've got like literally hundreds of beers you have, I mean,
I remember
that you would, there, there were bars that would make a big deal.
But like, oh, we have 200 beers on the menu and things like that, you know,
which was unthinkable 20 years before that.
Well, I mean,
I'm even lucky enough there's local hard liquor distillers that make a,
just amazingly wonderful and weird and strange things.
Yes, there's, I have a, a favorite distillery in Madison wis
that uses AAA grain called Sorghum,
which is a midwestern grassy grain thing.
Sorghum
wheat. It's a wheat.
Yeah, it's like a type of wheat.
Do they use like dwarf sorghum or just regular?
-- I
-- don't
-- know. They just say it's sorghum whiskey.
Really good.
I have no idea where they get it from. I don't ask. It's just good whiskey. I buy it.
I drink it, it, it, it reminds me of a good Scotch.
Honestly, it's very smooth but don't tell it.
Scotland. I said that anyway. Anyway. All right. All right. Autonomy.
-- Well,
-- and I think that's part of it is, I have a suspicion
that people that have real talent
must have autonomy because otherwise they can't express that talent.
They can't do it. It'd be like putting
Gordon Ramsay at a
-- mcdonald's.
-- That
would be epic. He wouldn't be allowed to be Gordon Ramsay.
-- I mean, but they don't want Gordon Ramsay either.
-- No.
Well, let's ignore that for a moment.
But I think this is what I'm increasingly beginning to,
to think is that for people to both create and develop this weird rich,
unique talent,
they have to be able to experiment, they have to be able to do different things,
right?
But then, and once they achieve it though, they can't do it without having it.
And if you constrain them or put them in a jail, basically
they'll, they'll be miserable and quit and go somewhere that they can do it.
And, and we see that like you said to the point of there's these brilliant people
who kind of have boring day jobs and then by night they're, you know,
this amazing open source developer who develops a piece
of software that essentially the world runs on.
I, I want to tie this into
the world of application security
because I've had a conversation recently that I
think is very related to some of this.
When you talk to a lot of appet
people,
they want to tell developers what, how they should be doing their job,
right? I
mean, this is just you laugh, but
they're saying, you know, you, you have to use open source in this way,
you have to be coding in this way.
-- You have to do your reviews in this way. You have to
-- pin your dependencies.
No, you have to unpin them. You have to use the latest
or both. I don't even know what the popular opinion is right now.
Like Schrodinger's dependencies.
-- That's actually,
-- you know what Ashley until you look,
you don't know what's going on.
Right.
When you do look, you wish you didn't.
-- There's just a box with an angry cat.
-- That's the thing. It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter which way it is.
Like if they're pinned, it's bad and if they're unpinned, it's also bad. There's
anyway.
Oh man. But, but
ok,
so on that note as well, I I'm also going to throw a link in the show, not Camy Katy.
He's a good friend and, and he, he works with um the Air Force on platform one.
He sent me a link to a prosal
article
where they were talking about their replacement to pseudo,
which is appropriate given we talked about it, I think last week where they, the,
the rust rewrite in pseudo is doing their
very best to not use dependencies because they,
it sees as a potential security threat.
And it's like in that particular aspect, it's very interesting.
Well, and it's also something they don't control.
Again. This kind of goes back to being weird and unique and interesting is that
putting artificial constraints on a problem
-- can result in more interesting solutions. It
-- can sure for sure, for sure.
OK, I want to go back to my story. Right. So we're talking to abs
people telling developers what to do and, and all of this
stuff and it is an interesting dilemma I think because
on one side you can't tell people exactly what to do because obviously, first of all,
they don't want to be told what to do,
you know, and,
and I don't think people generally accept telling them how to do something.
-- But now in the I
-- I would disagree because a lot of
people work at jobs where they have to do things specifically.
I mean,
and, and look, sometimes that happens.
I, I get it like my father worked in a paper mill for his whole life.
He literally had no autonomy like you make paper, right?
Make sure the paper comes off the machine and make sure it works correctly.
Like yes, there are these problems to solve along the way, but generally speaking,
you did what you were told right now on the other side,
there's also something to be said about.
You can't just let developers like wander around
and do whatever crazy thing they want,
right?
There has to be some degree of like consistent understanding
and working together in Cooper
-- and also not doing like crazy, stupid, dangerous things
-- can I suggest?
So one thing there
is that if you have a culture where people
understand what the goals and the rules of engagement are
you don't have to necessarily,
that have all these rules and sort of day to day minutiae
for sure, for sure. Right.
But, and, but having said that that is very rare, like, I'm like,
like not to suit my own home, but, like, working for the cloud security,
that is the biggest thing that Jim puts forth is having a
healthy team culture because if we have that then everything else will be fine.
There are millions of management books that have
been written about this very topic and yet somehow
we tend to screw it up.
Well, you know,
it always reminds me of uh there are many things where we know the good ways to do them,
but people just don't.
Right, because they want to find some local maximum of, for example,
I'm a manager and I want to see people in seats and I want to see
what they're doing and I want to be able to micromanage and talk to them,
which means no work from home.
And, and I saw a funny comic.
I doubt I could find it again to put it in the show notes or anything.
But it was uh like a fishing test where it
showed a person sitting at the desk and they're like,
oh, II, I think this is a phishing email.
You know, I wonder what happens if I click this link in the, in the next frame.
It's like
I don't care about this company. So I'm gonna click the link and see.
It's like, oh, that one
that cuts a little deep sometimes. Like, it's true though. Right.
Like you,
you will have if you're a security person
and you're managing a large number of people,
there are a lot of people that it's an externalized cost to them functionally.
So they don't, they don't care
-- or
-- they hate working there.
Well, sure. Right. Either way.
But I'm just looking at this and I'm, I'm kind of wondering because part of it is,
is I definitely prefer sort of that small, weird local unique store.
But at the same time,
there are people that just want to eat at Subway,
which I find tragic because their food is expensive
and not good compared to other sandwich shops.
But for whatever reason,
especially if you go to a small town Alberta,
that's what your options are at like, you know, four in the afternoon to get food.
Well, no, the reason is because Subway has the lowest franchise start up cost
of any restaurant.
It's like 100 grand. It's super cheap.
Ok.
But here's, here's what I think I find interesting about this whole conversation.
When we look at something like open source,
I feel like all of open source in its own way is like this weird bespoke universe,
right?
And I mean, this is one of the challenges when you hear people talk about security,
open
source and creating like the open SSF scorecard and all this,
like every open source project is functionally its own special snowflake.
I do love that. We talk about open
source the same way we use the word humanity.
Yeah. Yeah. You know, like
there's 8 billion of us.
I'm pretty sure there's not a single pair
of people on the planet that would agree about
more than 80% of what they think.
-- Yeah,
-- for sure. Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And so anyway, it, it amuses me though, that we take this bespoke thing,
this one off snowflake that are,
every single one of them is different in its own weird way.
And then we're assembling them
in these, like giant corporate environments
into, you know, bland, boring corporate things. And it's,
it's kind of funny.
-- Well, solutions, people want solutions. Right.
-- Right.
Right.
And, and it's very reusable. Right. There's a reason
that
most of our automobiles look and act the same way because like,
you need some level of consistency in that space.
-- Right.
-- There's also survivor bias in the sense of uh cars are a great example.
Two wheels is a motorcycle and tips over very easily.
And you can't put four, you can't put a family in there with their dog,
three wheels again.
Very tippy.
Yeah,
four wheels. Very, not tippy, very easy to engineer, very easy to make steering
and it's just, you know, like
same thing in the animal kingdom. We see parallel evolution of
like these animals over here and these animals over
there arrive at the same solution of like sharp teeth
that
just work.
That's
right.
And I,
I can hope but also wonder if part of what really
makes a mess of the open source world is the,
there's so much survivor bias,
which we don't admit because there's how many people have tried to write open source
and do a project to have it fail compared to the ones that succeeded.
-- I mean,
-- OK. No, no, I think this is what makes it special. There's
in many ways you could look at something like curl
or the Linux kernel and no one would say those are unsuccessful projects, right?
Because they're widely used.
But I have countless projects I work on
that are basically my thing and I consider them a success
because they do exactly what I need them to do.
They aren't used by any. In fact, most of them couldn't even be run by anyone.
But me, I would,
the thing I use to
like,
download the ecosystems data and then make all those wacky open source graphs.
I make,
I would be shocked if anyone else could get any of
that stuff to run at all just because it is poorly documented
and it is highly dependent on the computer in my basement
-- running in a very certain way.
-- What you're saying is you should containerize.
I
mean, I did at one point but I got lazy because I'm like,
I'm the only person using this, I don't care.
But anyway. Right?
And so I, I think this is one of the other unique aspects of this is like,
how do we define success?
And in the open source world, there is no definition of success.
Success is what I wanted to be as an open source developer.
I would argue there's no such thing as failure
because
like what does that even mean? Right. If I stop working on something, is it a failure?
Maybe, maybe not, maybe I just got bored and went on to the next thing.
Maybe I don't need it anymore.
And maybe here's where we in the show. But
to put it bluntly,
some people's definition of success is other
people's definition of failure and vice versa.
-- I mean,
-- for sure, for sure. And, and OK,
so I want to tie this all the way back around to the beginning now because
you were talking about work from home and this top talent going to somewhere else.
And
I I there's
there is an angle to this that I think often doesn't get discussed
is
sometimes these big companies,
they don't want like a AAA creative
like lone wolf type, right? They want someone who works in the machine.
And, and I've got, I have a really good example of this, right?
So I remember when I worked at Elastic Elastic had an
amazing corporate culture and this was at the time of like,
everyone talked about like 10 X engineers and you had to hire rock stars and you need,
and it was like,
the environments were incredibly toxic.
I mean, I remember we had people, like,
we worked with that Red Hat that were just like,
they probably had a negative draw on the company because like, yes,
they were amazing programmers, but they were just like a
nonfunctional human beings on so many levels. right? And when I went to Elastic,
they were all about like we like you're not here, like you're not a rock star,
you're not here to be a rock star,
you're here to be a decent person and you're gonna work with everyone else.
And so by,
by encouraging basically everyone to work at a functional level to cooper,
we got way more done than you would have seen.
If you had like one crazy good programmer, we'll say the 10 X, you know,
a hole and then a bunch of people just trying to
mop up whatever garbage they dumped on top of them.
And, and so it's,
there's some weird angles to this and there isn't one easy explanation.
I know
in many instances these big companies are looking to cut
costs and so that's what their actual desire is.
But at the same time, there is something to be said about sometimes having
a small functional,
less experienced team is better than having a
couple of really good people on that team.
Well, and I think, you know, history shows us that even the quote unquote,
lone geniuses,
they had people behind them, they had assistants.
I mean, that was,
was it Isaac Newton said that right where I,
the only reason I can see so far is I
stood on the shoulders of Giants or something like that.
Yeah. Oh, yeah. And,
and I'd say he did all right.
Anyway, I don't know, man, it's been,
it's been a pretty wild couple of years since
the pandemic and work from home and just everything.
I
have a suspicion it's here to stay because so many people
I've seen realize that they can just get their laundry done,
you know, minor chores,
especially,
well,
especially anybody that has Children or other adults or other people
in their life that they have to help take care of.
-- I mean,
-- but now, now I also want to, I want to close it out on,
on kind of a parting thought here is,
it's very easy for us to say work from home
is the best and everyone should work from home.
But, like,
I'm really glad the doctor I go see at the hospital isn't working from home.
Right. Like,
-- that's good. My dentist probably can't work from home.
-- It's funny you say that.
But like, that's a, it's quite common in Germany, for example, for them to, you know,
for actually a friend of a friend, his family owned a building
and the basement, like or not the basement, sorry,
the ground floor was their shop and then the two floors
above it were where the family lived and the grandparents lived.
Ok.
So their,
-- their business was their home. And
-- that does happen for lots of people. That's true.
-- That is very true.
-- But yeah, there are obviously people like firemen or fire people.
What, what do we call them now? Firefighters, firefighters, there you go.
And like posties to use a gender neutral term for male carriers. Oh, posties.
That's good. Yeah, we call them posties here in Canada.
I still call them the mailman even though my male person is not a man.
-- So,
-- you know, I get that not everybody can work from home,
but I feel like a lot more people can work from home
than currently do.
I also feel like a lot of managers could be
a lot better because, well, I mean, I mean,
that's always been a problem.
I've had some bad managers so obviously they could be better for sure.
And, and I think the other amusing angle to this is you often hear
arguments about, oh,
you have less creativity and you get less done and all this
and like open source is running the world and I would say
probably 99.9% of open source is functionally developed remotely.
-- Like,
-- well, it has to, when you, I, I,
I'm pretty sure Daniel can't afford a building to hold 1200 co developers
seeing that his budget for it would be like whatever's in his pockets.
And here's the thing where are the Kel developers located? No idea.
Don't even care a little bit.
Like
actually, now that I think about it,
how big of a building would you need to hold
-- the Lenox kernel developers a
-- very large building and,
and
you would need probably medical staff on site for all the stabbings they want to go.
Oh man.
Anyway.
OK. OK. So it amuses me.
The, the other link you sent me that you didn't even bring up then was the
the Debian
uh open SSL bug?
-- Oh Well,
-- that was just an example of autonomy going a bit sideways but like it's,
but at the same time, well, just again, you know, they, they uh
law of unintended consequences, you know, I fixed a bug. And
um one thing, one thing that always gets me is there,
there's a lot of behavior that doesn't show up until you do it at volume.
Like,
like I was just telling you before the show. So I've discovered I,
I'm doing a lot of work with A I and I put Jason in and I
get Jason out because it's kind of the
easiest way to then programmatically deal with it.
And it's also a good way to structure the data.
Jason for structuring data who could have guessed
and I have a consistent prompt, for example,
that I used to uh evaluate a bunch of exam questions over 1000 of them and it puts out
JSON 100% reliably. Well, no, literally 0.1% of the time.
So for about it was like just around 10 entries out of over 1000 it would put
a single smart quote instead of a regular quote at the end of a string in this giant
JSON file, which of course, then would like cause all sorts of Puca
and confusion to Python.
And
there's a lot of this where until you let people do kind of weird things and do it a lot.
The, the, the bugs and the edge
cases don't show up. And I think that's part of the other reason that these distro
well, to put it bluntly, most people don't use open source directly.
They consume it through something else like
through,
through it, well, through a,
through a distribution or,
you know, through a web
thing, intermediary or whatever, right? They're building a package
and maybe that's part of the secret is that most of
us couldn't even use Openness cell directly if we wanted to.
And most of us don't want to.
-- The
-- API is terrible.
Yeah.
You know, we just
like to, well, it was in the curl.
Uh he sent out that link to that survey and one of the things was how to use curl.
Like do you use it kind of directly? Do you build it directly and,
and I literally read the question like, oh man, I hope nobody really does that,
you know, I hope they use a nicely packaged.
Most people probably do,
you know,
rather than reinventing the wheel poorly themselves.
And maybe that's part of what this is all about is
getting people
to be ok with,
you know,
it's not consumed directly.
That's, we have to put a b we have these intermediaries, we have these sort of,
I don't know what to call them market makers.
Like in a way,
it's almost a market maker because openness of cell on its own is kind of useless.
But openness cell is part of distribution
with curl
-- and W get and other tools is really useful.
-- All right.
So I'm going to end this conversation
because you're on to something really interesting,
I think.
And this,
this harkens back to some of the other conversations we've
had where there is an enormous amount of open source
that is like hidden away.
It's like the more locks of open source that it's these,
these utilities that let other things work.
But at the same time, it's often
they're misunderstood or missed
because I mean XZ was a perfect example, right?
Where like it's in the bowels of the system
and most people didn't give it two thoughts,
but the attacker sure did like they saw the opportunity.
So anyway. All right, I'm calling this one. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for listening. Go to its source Security podcast.com, Head of the
Shoes Pound
Doses Podcast. Hashtag Find us on Mastodon Kurt.
You have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye.