Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast.
I'm with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in
software.
-- No, never mind fraud.
-- I don't know. What do we call this?
No, no, no, no, no, no, not now that I work with the financial industry.
-- Crime is ok, but fraud is not. Ok. Oh, that's fair.
-- Ok.
Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought crime. Josh Pressers.
So, what makes you think? I'm going to take out the first intro.
You did that talks about crime and fraud.
I'm fine.
-- We'll
-- see, we'll see.
-- I stand by my
-- work anyway.
Well, speaking of crime. Yeah. No, it's good. It's good. It got above zero.
So all the snow melted.
I'm wearing shorts today because it's going to be a lovely day.
And if I can wear shorts in November, I'm doing it. So,
yeah, I'm not quite that aggressive. It's only six degrees outside.
That's pretty cold.
Sure.
I mean, look in comparison,
I'm used to 15 to 30 ish Celsius right now and I'm not ready for cold yet.
-- It's coming. I acknowledge
-- that. Oh,
winter is coming
hate winter, the winter of my discontent card.
Oh,
man, this is just going to be brutal. Everybody cooped up inside.
I'm not going. No, we're not.
Let's talk about something way more fun than, than the horribleness of winter.
We'll talk about full disclosure.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, it's, it's,
yeah, I mean, the first thing that always gets me is that
everybody seems to think Attackers are somehow incompetent and
unless they are given details of security flaws,
they somehow won't
find and exploit flaws.
And it's kind of like, well, number one, finding security flaws isn't that hard.
Number two, the skill set to find security flaws is actually pretty widespread now.
And a simple data point would be.
What is it hacker announced months ago that they've
paid out over $100 million in bug bounties.
You jumped right into the deep end of the pool today, didn't you? Yeah.
Well, it's just like I'm so frustrated with these people that just ignore reality.
Ok, let's start at the very beginning. Cart.
And I decided we want to talk about full disclosure.
And the reason we did this is because Google projects
released a lot of details about a very serious security issue.
Well, not just details. They released a proof of concept exploit
that triggers it and in fairness like
it's,
I don't want to say it's a simple bug, but
-- it is a simple bug. It's an integer overflow,
-- right?
-- You just give it a big number and it
-- poops.
There's no patch for Microsoft and there's people have started flipping
out and saying you shouldn't release this information,
but they did release it because this issue is actively being exploited
on the internet
right now
in the wild as it were.
And if there's something we've learned is that if we ignore
-- infections in the wild things will be ok.
-- That's right.
If you just pretend it's fine, it probably is.
Don't tell people about it, it'll be fine.
Let's go back in time before we start this because you're, you're clearly fired up.
-- Well, I just, the reason I'm so like,
-- hang on. No, no, I know
we all know
this is lovely.
So let's go back in time and just talk about what, what does full disclosure mean?
And, and how did we kind of get to the fact that this topic even exists?
So the way it works is back in the olden days and I mean, like,
not just 10 or 20 years ago, but even over 100 years ago,
companies don't like being embarrassed
and companies have a history of shipping unsafe products
or products that make claims sometimes around security,
sometimes around safety
that are just not true.
Uh You know, and some extreme examples of this would be like Ralph Nader,
unsafe at any speed with car safety.
Sure.
You know, like literally we had cars, they like, oh,
you got a little minor fender bender and you're dead
because, you know, your steering wheel impaled you
or, you know, the concept of safety glass in cars.
I was kind of,
I just assumed we'd gone to safety glass a lot sooner
than
the industry did.
Sure.
You know.
But no, anyway, so
companies obviously want to
not have people pointing out that their products kill and maim people,
especially in ways that are
often not that hard to fix,
you know.
Well, I mean, my favorite is there's this one product,
I'm not going to get into the specifics of it.
Um, but
essentially back in the day,
it would have cost 10 cents to properly fix the mechanism.
That's a safety issue.
And now because they've shipped millions and millions and millions
of these products and decided not to fix it,
you've got this huge sort of installed base of unsafe products now
and of course, retrofitting them would be horrendously expensive.
But, but you just proved the point, Kurt,
because you won't tell us what the company is and what the 10 cent part is.
It's a gun thing,
it's a gun thing. Ok. But regardless, you get the idea.
So here's
my take on this is there's always been this historical struggle between, we'll say,
organizations making a thing
and people finding out there's something wrong with the
thing and you can go to the organization and say
I found this problem, you should fix it.
And I would say in the vast majority of outcomes,
the organization says go away you annoying pain in our butt.
Well, or they just threaten to sue you and they threaten legal action.
-- Well,
-- that's step two,
-- that's quite a common outcome.
-- And, and yeah, it happens a lot actually.
And I mean, this is,
uh, well, I'm sure we'll get to it, but, like,
this is one of the cool things about having a
bug bounty is you're basically saying I won't sue you.
But now,
so what happens is you end up in this
situation where you have some sort of researcher,
you have some sort of company,
the researcher knows what the company is doing is flawed for a variety of reasons.
And now you have to decide the company told me to stuff it.
What do I do with this knowledge and information I have?
Well, and one thing too is there, there's subtlety to this because for example,
some flaws are clearly
somebody made a decision at the company and accepted this risk and said,
you know what this is ok.
We know about this problem.
You know, we know cigarettes cause cancer, but we're going to sell them anyways.
And then there's other flaws where it's kind of like, oh, wow, we, we just,
we didn't really understand metal fatigue well enough
or
you know, the fact that like windows in planes need to be circles, not squares,
you know,
-- because the stress points at the corners
-- did
they ever have square windows in planes.
-- I don't know,
-- there were a couple of British models that did, but they crashed a lot.
-- Oh, well,
-- because the windows would fracture.
You'd have an explosive decompression and everybody dies. Yeah.
And that seems like a minor problem.
So, but anyway, the point is
I'm a researcher. I have information.
What do I do now in the context of computer security?
Which is where we're going to frame our discussion.
Basically back in the day, you could go to a company and say, oh,
I have this and like researchers going to
them saying I found a problem with the company
being like, yeah, if you tell anyone we're suing you go away. Right?
And it was, it was horrible. And so what would happen quite often
is people would find something and instead of even going to the company,
there was a mailing list called Full Disclosure, which I mean, this was literally,
its job
was so people could mail it with information like this and just say here it is
good luck.
Generally speaking, it was pretty wild west for sure.
Well, I mean,
it kind of had to be because I remember seeing a lot of people making
good faith efforts to go to these companies and try and work with these companies
and yeah, the companies were not having it.
No, it was, it was very difficult to report security issues.
And the other thing too is is. And people forget this.
If I have a faulty product,
I always have a way to fix it because if nothing else I can choose to stop using it.
Right. And that's something people forget is, especially with software, there's
often a compensating control I can put in.
Oh, you know, this thing has this security flaw. Ok. Let's
add a web application,
firewall rule or let's do some configuration change to minimize it or
least let's let's log and see if anybody exploits
this issue and then we can deal with it.
Right?
And so that's what I'm trying to say though,
is there's this whole full disclosure thing.
It's not just about the researcher counting coon getting their name out in public.
It's actually
there are often things people can do to protect themselves if they want to.
Well, and I think that's part of the discussion today.
I think back in the day, I mean, unless you were someone like the loft,
you weren't putting your name on a lot of this stuff.
You were hiding behind handles and pretend groups. Yeah.
So you didn't get sued, right?
They were going to come after you and they were going
to make your life miserable if you did this stuff.
And even even people like cult of the dead cow in the loft, they were
constantly under fire from Microsoft. It's just
they were phenomenal at manipulating the media to basically get their point
across and the way they wanted it across and made kind of,
you know, people like Microsoft and Oracle and Friends look like the bad guy,
which you could argue maybe they were, but
they
totally
were,
let's say full disclosure,
that's the story.
But you know what they got better.
But OK. Right. And so now let's fast forward to today.
So Microsoft is actually pretty good and I would say they
are potentially the poster child
for handling security vulnerabilities correctly.
And so now we have this instance where Google project zero finds a problem.
They figure out it's being exploited in the wild. I don't know how they found this.
I mean, it is Google, they have access to enormous resources.
So I know Chrome has a bunch of telemetry built in to spot crashes
and so weird crashes get reported back to Google and a lot of security issues,
especially some of the nondeterministic rates.
I type ones tend to cause a lot of crashes and you can.
And same thing Microsoft had a blog post about this years ago where they got
telemetry and some Microsoft engineer decided to
look at the telemetry and you know,
found a zero day.
Yeah, from a single crash report, which is, that's a crazy,
I'll try to find that I'll put it in the show notes.
-- It's a fascinating story.
-- Yeah.
So I mean, and I suspect that's what happened here is Chrome,
something affected Chrome
and
you know, and then Google obviously kind of looks at it, you know, maybe
the organizations contact Google, I don't know.
But the point is Google found out about this, you know,
they kind of have what you call a wide install base.
And so they were able to,
then I'm assuming Google also has like sort of active threat hunting, you know,
with honey pots and stuff
and yeah, they were able to find this thing out in the wild, figure it out,
you know, provide a proof of concept exploit code, which is, you know,
it's a simple like 3040 line script that
basically just shoves it creates a crypto device and
-- shoves a large number into it and you get to watch it kind of
-- go blue.
I think we're getting ahead of ourselves again. So here's the question,
does Google releasing basically full details about this
issue before there is a fix for Microsoft?
Is that giving, is that an advantage to the world or by keeping it secret?
Would they be helping the world by not telling people what's going on?
And here's the argument.
So before you respond, I want to explain there, there's two sides
on one side
you have and I'm not going to lie. Like I am 100% pro full disclosure.
-- I know Kurt is also, I
-- I would say I'm definitely 100% full disclosure,
but I would like for people to try and
-- give the company a chance first because
-- that's different.
That's not full disclosure though.
This is, this is different and,
and we're talking about embargoes so we can discuss embargoes in a minute.
But let me explain the arguments here.
So you've got full disclosure,
we should send all of this information out into the world.
Then it gives the defenders an opportunity to
study what's happening and defend against it.
Essentially on the other side,
you have people saying by releasing all of this information,
now you've given potential Attackers all the tools they need to mount attacks.
-- Whereas assuming they couldn't somehow figure this out on their own prior to
-- this,
there's,
they
-- have
-- and I know has the proof.
-- Well, right,
-- in this instance,
I agree 100 percent.
Well, it's a bit to what I was saying earlier, I would say,
try and give the company a chance,
like because some companies do the right thing and they will move quickly.
Some companies are capable like Microsoft's obviously capable of change
because at some point in the last 20 years,
they went from basically full evil to pretty damn good, you know, and in past,
they would have definitely thrown a tantrum over this and now they're just
like quietly beavering away and saying we'll have it fixed next week,
right? You know, I mean, and they're going to have it out on.
Yeah, they're sure for a Microsoft patch, Tuesday,
it sounds like they're not going to do an out of band one for this.
I think it's important to also every single one of these is so different.
Like the fact that Google has proof this is actively being exploited in the wild,
right?
If I discover a vulnerability,
I have no idea if it's being exploited in the wild,
we don't. This is where the discussion, I think you get more interesting.
So let's assume you find a critical security vulnerability
-- and let's say you report it to Microsoft. Here's a
-- simple one.
My first vulnerability I ever really found and reported was that stupid
izzy.com file being world readable,
which is a problem because it contained a password.
So anybody on the system could read that password,
connect to your ice cuzzy system and read all the data in my mind.
I'm like this is, it's kind of a bad issue, but it's not that bad because, you know,
ch model fix it and then you just change the
password later if you think somebody read it and Cisco who
that open source package freaked right out and just
did not want me going public with this.
And I'm like, you literally just read the file like there's no, you know what I mean?
Like you read a file with a password in it. It's world readable.
It shouldn't be world readable. That's it.
And, and, you know, conversely to now where
I would like to think they'd be a little more mature about it.
Let's use this as our example because I think it's,
it's a super easy one for everyone to understand in their head.
So let's say
you go to Cisco,
you say I found this
and,
and Cisco says, please don't tell anyone about this.
We're going to fix it and release the security update. Now, let's say
Cisco releases a security update that basically says it's possible a local
attacker could figure out your password for your I scuzzy system.
Please update the package. Now,
if I'm an attacker and I read that,
what is the first thing I'm going to do?
I'm going to compare the old and the new packages
and in about 10 seconds,
you're going to see a file.
-- I'm going to know exactly what's, what's happened,
-- right? A very concrete case.
You know, IFC pushes out DH C PE D and bind and all that stuff.
And they're famous for not giving super
super details on uh bind vulnerabilities because,
you know, they kind of want to
keep the internet stable. Literally, every time they would release a bind update
with a security fix and a whole bunch of other stuff.
So, you know, the, the file diff would be on average about 50 to 200 k
of text, which is a lot
and it took me on average about 1015 minutes to find the security flaw.
Yeah, I mean, and that's, that's with source code.
People do this without source code with windows patches, all the time. Oh, yeah.
Yeah. Bin
-- Diff. And then all the DB G and off you go. So
-- here's the thing.
Your adversaries have the knowledge and the tools to quickly figure out
what has changed between two releases and to know exactly what's happening.
And more importantly, they have not just the incentive to do this
but an ongoing incentive to do this in the form of, for example, bug bounty. So it's
the, the thing is this is something where
it's, it's like exercise.
You, you have to kind of keep doing it and keep fresh because there's new techniques,
new exploit chains,
you know, new defenses that you have to overcome.
Like remember when return oriented programming suddenly became
a thing and like all these previous defenses,
we had just gone overnight, right, Rob just
stomped all over them.
So that's part of it too.
Is these Attackers now are not just, you know, coming up with one attack a year,
they're keeping their skills sharp by participating in bug bounties.
I mean, sure,
but they were always keeping their skills sharp because it's what they do.
Well,
-- I'm saying now that they get directly paid
-- well and you could
argue that takes away some of the pressure from the whole,
you know, attacker defender concept because now instead of attacking,
they're in theory doing bug bounty work.
But, but here's the thing, if you're defending
and
oracle just says,
install this patch
because it's gonna
somehow prevent a local attacker from accessing your files.
You're gonna be like, what do I do? Now?
If you're in, in any sort of corporate environment,
you can't just install updates whenever you want because right, you're gonna,
you're gonna be looking for a new job on day three if you do that.
So the question becomes, well, what do I do with this? How serious is this?
What you, what, what am I looking for? What should I be doing? And you don't know
the Attackers know exactly what's going on. You have no clue what to do.
Now, if oracle says the problem is that this file is world readable.
You can be like, oh, well, crap, I can just
-- on this thing and I'm done. Right. Well, and
-- so that was my ration.
I'm like, literally, I'm just like, tell everybody to see mo
you know, right. O minus read, right, execute.
And then if they want to be extra paranoid, change the path work, which is a chore,
but that's it.
Then you're, then you're good, you're done,
right?
You don't need to ship an update for this.
-- I mean, you
-- should, you do but
right. Exactly. And, and this is the thing is
when
you don't have all of the details,
it is difficult to understand what's happening around you.
But it's also more importantly is you also have to wonder
what do the Attackers know about this particular problem?
-- How do you do risk management if you don't know what the risk is.
-- That's right.
You absolutely can't.
And I think part of this part of this conversation is what do Attackers
know and what do Attackers have is definitely something you need to think about.
And obviously you could just say, oh, we'll just assume the worst.
But what is the worst?
-- I don't even know
-- the problem with assuming the worst
though is then you end up with inflated threats.
So a perfect example of this assume the worst is the way the NVD, the
vulnerability database scores CV S scoring for CV S
because they have to take the tact of what like we're not sure about X.
So we have to assume worst case.
And so they end up with these inflated CV S scores because also
they can't
sort of say or guarantee is the software being used safely.
So for example, like, remember at Red hat,
we kind of had the official position of SMB uh SAMBA file services
uh
run on local networks only, you don't expose it to the internet.
If you're exposing it to the internet, you're too bad.
And I would tend to agree with that,
you know, you don't expose it directly to the internet.
But for example, the NVD dealing with the US government, as I understand it,
the US government is what you might call a
large organization without super centralized control and configuration.
-- That
-- is
-- an accurate statement.
They kind of have to assume this worst case scenario.
And the problem is you end up with a lot of,
well, is this really an issue or a non issue? And it takes a long time to
the wheat from the chaff.
It is, it's really hard, especially at scale when you're, you know, at Red Hat,
we as a vendor, we're dealing with thousands of security vulnerabilities a year
and we're a single vendor.
So by definition, the US government is dealing with, well,
-- pretty much the majority of the CV database,
-- all of them, right?
They're dealing with literally every security vulnerability released ever.
Yeah, like the fact that the US government, I remember that one group there,
the big group used to care about PHP a lot
more than I would have thought that they would.
Ok?
I guess they, a lot of PHP apps like, because what else are you going to build them in?
Everyone used to have a lot of
now. It's all. No Js, it's the same problems, new language.
But
so that's the thing, right? Is this,
there is a cost to crying wolf.
There is a cost to, you know, on Microsoft patch, Tuesday as an individual user.
Yeah, I just slam all the updates on reboot and like cross my fingers.
Same thing with Apple, you know,
just hit that reboot and hope to God the system like
I've had and I've done it where it's just like,
oh, that like a major Os update and I, my system, like,
just got stuck
and I had to actually recover it from time machine.
That's
exciting.
That happened once on my laptop and I was, like, whatever,
thank goodness for time machine because I got everything back. But,
you know, same thing, like with my ipads, you know, we have a spare ipad.
I run that one first. If it doesn't break, I'm like, cool kids.
-- You're going next and then mine.
-- That's not the corporate file server.
Well, exactly.
And, and in a corporate world where even worse, a regulated industry,
like say healthcare, like our MRI machine
-- just never update that thing or
-- your pacemaker
-- never update those
-- or you know,
-- your scatter control system that runs the power grid for the city
-- also never update.
But anyway, anyway, so, right. I think you've hit on all the, all the
important points. But I think so there's
the argument here obviously is there's the aspect of,
let's not give people all the details. Let's tell them the potential output.
Let's say we say that if you, if you're using Samba on the internet,
a remote attacker who doesn't need to authenticate, could paw your system like,
is that enough information to
-- tell someone without giving them all the details?
-- I would say it's a set of slides
and the, the thing is the values have changed in that 20 years ago while number one,
there just weren't as many Attackers numerically.
Right. With the internet hadn't connected up the world yet.
Uh Number two, the Attackers weren't as sophisticated or,
you know, the tooling. I was looking it up the other day, Medis
was only released in 2003.
What
I know, hey, I always thought it was like older than that and I'm like, no, it was 2003.
-- I feel like it's been around forever.
-- Well, it, 17 years. Is it
almost old enough to vote? Right?
-- Like, no, seriously. Like, but, ok.
-- Ok.
No, no, I'm going to, I want to disagree with you though.
-- I would say
-- that these, these sliders have changed. No,
there's no slider.
I don't think there's a slider.
Well, no, no, no,
in the sense of Attackers are much more
competent now and they need much less information.
Like I remember back in the day when somebody knowing what Bin Diff and
Ali just knowing what those tools were was amazing.
And now it's just like, yeah, whatever those are things people buy and use.
-- But
-- there were still plenty of people who understood those.
I don't, I don't think a slider ever existed.
I think sliders is a lie we've told ourselves and they never existed.
-- Well,
-- look at Bug Bounties.
Bug bounties have created a market for people who actually either part or full time.
But no, that's, you're changing the subject that has nothing to do with sliders.
What I'm trying to point out is the, the sliders on the values of
how much information really benefits hackers.
And the answer is like,
Attackers don't need nearly as much information as they used to.
They don't need any, they don't need any information.
-- And
-- conversely, defenders are dealing with such a fire hose of stuff.
-- Now, defenders actually need a lot more details.
-- I agree completely.
And I think, but I think this has always been true.
I think we just managed to lie to ourselves for a long time.
-- Heard of it is
-- no, no, no software updates used to be like a quarterly thing.
And now,
I mean,
I could be installing software updates literally daily across all my devices.
Well, sure, but it's still quarterly at a lot of organizations.
Well, yeah, with, except for the things that matter where they have to deal with it.
Now this is where that goes into that extended detection and response.
So for example, you know, OK, we know, for example,
this attack requires the creation of a cryptographic, you know,
essentially device driver so we can monitor the
for creation of that device because to be blunt,
creation of that device should be pretty rare, especially from your web browser.
It probably never happens is my suspicion.
Like I remember reading this one account of uh they detected a pen test
because they had the windows machines locked down to not allow use of powershell
because the only people that should be using Powershell was like the five admins.
-- And so this is the stuff you can do with details as a defender.
-- I agree completely.
And
this is, I mean, so one of the challenges obviously is people will say,
oh just you should disable Powershell, but of course,
there's Attackers can do other things.
Well, no, they didn't disable Powershell. They monitored for use of powershell.
-- Well,
-- no, I, I understand that I'm saying but, but what I hear then is people will say,
oh, just, just disable Powershell in all your systems and then you're safe
and it's like,
you
know,
you're not
and
that's broken.
You get the idea is there is,
it is very difficult sometimes to understand everything happening around you.
-- And
-- that's the point is there's a lot of
security
compensating controls, people would like to take,
but they're very risky and could very much break stuff in very
obvious or very subtle ways.
And that's where these, you know,
where you really want to have the information and understand it
so that you can do things like, ok, well, if we monitor for creation of this device,
yeah, that it may or may not create a flood of events.
We don't know until we turn it on and for all
I know it's like it never happens or it's daily.
But the point is now you can feed that into an automated
system and you can look for other indicators of compromise such as,
oh, you know,
this happens on this system and then the system starts talking to an IP in Russia.
-- Totally fine.
-- OK. Well, now somebody needs to go reimage that system.
Yeah. Yeah. And I think
this is one of the really interesting things I
feel like is starting to happen is historically,
we were obsessed with stopping bad things from happening.
Yeah, prevention. And now
I feel like
the monitoring aspect is hugely important,
especially with automation because now you can just say, OK,
I know I have this problem.
I know this is going on.
I'm going to watch this system.
And if I see this behavior, then I know a bad thing is happening.
It also gives you the ability to detect new stuff.
Perfect example is there's, you know,
there's IP addresses that are known to be command and control servers
and to put it bluntly if any of your systems ever talk to any of these IP
they're called,
it may be a newer version of whatever Trojan Malware exploit thing of a jigger.
It is which then gives you a chance to learn something new and maybe
send it off to your A V company to create a new detection.
And I guess this is part of that full disclosure conversation
as well is let's say you've got a bank of ips.
And
now you could say, OK, if I, if I give this to the world,
the bad guys are going to know we found them.
Right.
But if I keep it secret, then I can only give it to some people and,
and here's my argument here is if you, if you tell the world, yes,
it is very true that the bad guys will find out.
But the reality is
if, if you think you're keeping a secret,
you're potentially not, they may know and just not care
or it's conceivable that they've already moved their infrastructure and
they're just pretending to make you happy and think they've,
you know what I mean? When you do not know what your adversary knows,
it is a very different situation.
Whereas if,
if you know what your adversary knows because you literally told them what,
you know,
now
the conversation is very different and the things
you should be doing are very different.
And so like my, my example is you could focus on specific IP S
or you could say
this is what traffic to a command and control server looks like,
which is going to be more useful long term than
-- saying I'm just going to watch these six IP
-- S.
Yeah.
Well, it's some of these IP S are very long lived or some of them are, you know,
the bulletproof hosting sites in Russia and some of the crazy spin off countries.
And that gives you that chance to, to, you know,
monitor traffic to those IP S and then look at the traffic and go, ok, you know,
this week,
they're using like weird DNS packets or this
week they're using weird http S or whatever.
And the thing is though,
the other aspect of this is this isn't work that scales, it needs to be automated.
And so part of that automation is
that the tool makers and the tool vendors and the service makers and vendors need
to learn like they need to find out about this and they do share this information
so that they can just bake it into your A V or Microsoft Defender or whatever,
you know, I was downloading, what was I trying to download?
I was trying to find a replacement program for something. Uh
and I downloaded an app to Windows
and Microsoft Defenders. Like there's like there's some wonkiness in here.
So I ran it through virus total and it was two out of 56 detection engines, found it.
And I'm like, yeah, no, not using this one.
It was a thing hosted off of Source Forge.
Yeah, ironically it was a threat modeling tool.
Yeah.
But anyways, the point is like,
I'm glad somebody shared that with Microsoft and Microsoft defender, you know,
was like, this is kind of wonky looking.
You sure you want to open this.
I'm not going to let you open this unless you like make me and I'm like,
-- I don't think I want to make you do this, which
-- is cool.
-- I mean, that's, that's a powerful feature for sure.
-- So
I,
I just, I keep coming back to the fact though that
the Attackers no longer not that they ever really, really needed this information,
but nowadays they especially don't.
And like I said,
defenders absolutely need this information because we have a fire hose of issues.
I can't deal with this.
But hopefully my Microsoft defender or my vendor
does deal with this issue and add something
or,
you know,
some other layer of security that I have
kind of gets a compensating control for this,
you know, for the next week while Microsoft is busy fixing this,
even if you wanted to make the argument in the past, that full disclosure was bad,
which I won't agree with.
But I would say you could at least honestly make,
I think the world has changed in such a way
that you can no longer make that argument
in a, in an honest manner because I think
it's just
the people defending and there are and there's also a lot
-- more people defending and we're
-- defending a lot more important stuff.
-- Everything is digital now
-- and there are tons of
vendors that are doing this sort of work.
And I feel like imagine a world where you had a company like let's, I'll,
I'll pick on Sneak just because we talked to them not long ago.
Let's imagine sneak is finding security flaws in open source
and they're providing special secret patches.
And they're saying if you run our product you get our special secret patches,
patches and you're open source.
Well, I mean, that's a,
that's a business model for these various
network layer protection software and services.
It kind of is and it's madness.
Well, but on the flip side though,
every single one of those vendors I know and have worked with or actually worked for
specifically their business model was we find and buy exploits.
We give you ways to block them and we immediately go to the
vendor and try to get them to fix this as quickly as possible.
And so the value you get is you get
faster coverage
-- through us.
-- But imagine they didn't bring it to the event
and that would be a nightmare. It would be ridiculous to be clear.
That's so strongly frowned upon. Like the company I worked for.
It was funny because it was the first company to do this
and they didn't make it super clear that like, yes,
we buy exploits and then we immediately tell the company
and people were just beaten on us and I'm like,
we tell the company they're like, are you sure?
And I'm like,
yes, I'm sure I worked there. Like I've seen these, like,
I've seen us trying
and the best part is this is back in the day, like
trying to contact these companies and get them to, you know,
take this stuff seriously and fix it hard.
Yeah, exactly.
So, so anyway, anyway,
I, I feel like, obviously this argument is like the anti
full disclosure argument to a ridiculous degree.
-- It's
-- people arguing with the tide.
-- I'm sorry, the tide's
-- coming in and you know what? That's how we should end it.
Yes, you're absolutely right.
Full disclosure one.
That's all like
you can argue this.
Who cares? It's not
like
it's too bad. Right? You get your broom, sweep the water, you lose.
And I guess that makes me happy. Let's just say that
of all the things to make me unhappy in the world.
This one doesn't
so good job. Full disclosure. That's it. That's all I got.
Awesome. All right, man. I'm calling it. So I guess. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you ever for listening. Go to open
source security, podcast.com.
Hit up our show note, Suzy Poo
says podcast hashtag do hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.