Hey, this is Kurt Siefried and Josh Bresser with the Open source security podcast.
The topic of the day is, is open source security.
So let's keep it general.
And
when I go out and when I talk to people,
what is open source security is, is one of those topics that comes up often.
And funny enough,
the question of is open source secure comes up way more often than I think it should.
And so let's start there, Kurt, what do you think open source security is?
Well, to be honest, I'm not sure what computer security is anymore.
Um
I mean,
a great
-- example,
-- we have a podcast. We, we have to pretend we know,
well, just in the, in the grand scheme of things, for example, is,
is the iphone Os Secure, right?
So we recently had that human rights activist who was sent some malware
chained together 30 days.
So that if you clicked a link, they could remotely hijack your phone.
Is your phone secure? Yes or no?
Well, some would argue no, because it can be hacked and some would argue yes,
because Apple responded quickly to it.
I think the reality is, as we've learned all software has flaws.
The question is,
you know, how bad are they and how fast do they get fixed once they're found out?
What does that mean in the context of open source, I think is, is the thing
we're looking to really talk about here. Right.
So, so let's back that up.
So I think with open source, one of the benefits is
you are not beholden to a vendor shipping you an update there is
potentially if you have the expertise,
the chance that you yourself can patch your software and fix it
with a closed source vendor, that's much harder.
Assuming it's at all even legal in some jurisdictions,
it's not legal to monkey with software that you've licensed.
Uh So I think so open source gives you at, at a minimum, it gives you the chance.
And then more importantly, it means vendors like Red Hat
can fix it. You know, we have the engineering resources, we have the expertise
and we typically have the experience with this software in
fixing it because the majority of the software has,
you know, a rich history of security flaws.
I love that software has a rich history of security flaws.
That, that's a fantastic quote, man. We should get a T shirt that, that has that on it.
So,
yeah, absolutely.
And one of the awesome things I think about open source and the one that really
just always kind of hits home I think when you start talking to people and whatnot is
the,
so if you look at a typical organization and,
and we'll pick on close source because we can, why not?
Right
is
they're in the boat by themselves
and
when there's something wrong,
they have to deal with everything from top to bottom,
including making the fixes and there's nothing wrong with that necessarily.
Right.
But I think the trick with open source is there's lots of people working on it
and let's face it.
Everybody is using open source today.
There's, it's literally, you know,
you're doing it or you don't know and you should is pretty much
where we're at because I don't think there's a software project on the planet
that doesn't have people going to github
and stack overflow and downloading code.
Right.
Well,
and even one of my bigger concerns with
especially close source software is that institutional knowledge,
you know,
how many people know why something was built the way it was,
let alone even how it was built, the way it was. You know,
and I've encountered that many times in open source where, you know, something is
quasi
abandoned. But you know what?
We have the source code, we have the notes, we have the mailing list traffic,
we have the discussion around, you know, how this feature came to be.
We have context for it,
you know, and I've conversely, I know people who work in the closed source world.
And, uh, this one firm basically had to keep paying this guy 20% more every year.
Uh, because he was the only original architect left for their core product.
He was the only guy that
knew how the whole thing was supposed to work together.
And, uh, the other three guys that had worked on it had left.
That's hilarious for all the wrong reasons.
I love it
now now. Oh, ok.
So,
here's the thing too though is I think you can
easily make the argument that open source doesn't necessarily fix that
because if you're talking about people going out to the internet
and just downloading any random piece of garbage, they find
that's not,
it's, you don't get a magic solution there. Right? I mean, yes, it's open source,
but
you still have maintenance issues surrounding that even if it is free as in,
you know, a puppy.
And that's definitely true.
Um But one thing I'm seeing is people are growing up, for example, we have the, uh,
the No Js security project
where they not only track flaws in no Js products,
they have a website for it.
And more importantly, they have a No Js module that you can then use,
that will warn you when you're using out of date software and it will tell you,
you know, you should update this component you're using because of this CV.
Uh And I also just had another project contact me that does
a similar thing for um I forget which language it is.
So a big part of,
I think open source is that the security side is
growing up and these people are doing public efforts,
you know,
no matter what Microsoft does,
that will only work within the Microsoft ecosystem on their products typically,
except even Microsoft is pulling the open source bandwagon play now,
right where they're starting to release all this stuff in public and in heck,
you know,
they're using open source in their products. There's no way they're not.
I imagine their cloud has tons of it on the backside.
Well, I mean, they publicly admitted to using,
I think it was a Debian variant for their uh network switches because I mean,
you're not
gonna,
you're not gonna ever build networking equipment that runs Windows,
never say, never
say never.
Yeah.
Well, but even Windows has had to, you know,
has had to basically move towards what open source is well established, you know,
strip down operating systems that then
do special purpose tasks.
You know, because, and part of it is not only because that's what works,
but it's also more secure,
like especially in the context of a network switch or
a DNS server appliance or an NTP server appliance.
You know, you don't want a full stack on top of that. You want it stripped down.
Yeah. Yeah, totally, man.
Yeah,
I suppose that's a fair point too because open source kind of gives
you that ability where you can just pick and choose what you want.
But I guess we, we still come back to the maintenance issue, don't we? Where,
where you have to take care of this stuff?
You can't just go out and take it and
then use it forever and declare yourself the winner.
Yeah.
Well, the good news there is the core of open source, like the Linux kernel G, Lipsy.
all of those are very healthy, very large upstream.
Now, granted,
there are some pretty fundamental software projects that have very weak or very
sick or even in some cases just flat out dead upstream communities.
But they tend to be more the exception than the rule, in my opinion
-- that
-- that's probably fair.
And I know like we've seen it before in, in, like Redhead and Fedora
Land is
when you have an abandoned upstream,
you either end up killing that, that library or product project,
I should say from whatever it is you're doing or conversely,
you fork it and make it new
or I guess you just take it over depending upon the situation.
I mean, I know I've run into more than one thing before that.
You're like, hey, I want to take over your project. Like, no, it's mine.
You can't have it. It's like,
but you haven't committed anything to it in seven years.
You know, this is clearly not a project anymore and then, you know,
they stick by their guns and like, no, no, no, you can't have it.
It's like, all right, man, whatever.
But I guess that's, that's the beauty of its sources. Right.
Well,
and the reality is that this kind of
abandonment also happens in the commercial world.
Right.
How many of us have a printer or a camera or something that
needs a hardware driver that's only available for version X of Windows,
Mac Os and Linux
and hasn't been updated in five or 10 years.
Oh, man. You know, there's all this Windows 95 software out there isn't,
I've heard before.
There's a defense contractor that's still running
Windows 95 because some like piece of C
ad software they have only runs on Windows 95 which is hilarious, right?
I mean, that's so pathetically old. It hurts.
Now, I will also say though my favorite story is if Windows 95
could have been containerized, we would still have Windows 95 containers today,
right?
Because people would need it. And that's also terrifying in its own special way.
I mean, it will happen for sure.
It's already been containerized in the sense of virtual machines.
You know,
and I've seen
you can't
have
containers, virtual machines that'll get us in trouble. Don't, you know.
Well, no, but I mean, in the sense of people need old software to work,
especially when they have other old software
or other old hardware that's expensive.
You know, you can't,
you can't justify upgrading ac
ad machine or a computer aided design machine, you know,
for the sake of just updating the US.
Now, now here's a question for you
if
you need old software and let's face it. Like if you need Windows 95 you just
have a copy of Windows 95 run into VM, whatever it is, that, that works.
What happens when you have a cloud service
and it, it end of life.
So it changes the API and you have something talking to it and it no longer, I mean,
I guess this problem sort of exists where
people have gear
that is irreplaceable running, say an application or an operating system.
I mean, it's,
it's a terrifying place to be in.
Well, I mean, I know, for example, in the elevator industry,
uh
the software running those elevators is incredibly
old and
in most cases, you know, buildings have,
have elevator systems that were installed 1020 30 years ago
and until they go through a modernization cycle, that's what you have.
Ok. But now let's let's look at that in the context of security.
We also aren't hearing about security or not security secu
we don't have the problem with elevators like being an epidemic of, of
injuring or killing people even though they're super old, right?
And I think we all agreed that like super old,
say medical devices are going to be a terrifying prospect.
And when I say super old I'm talking probably a year or two. Right.
Not like a 40 year old elevator.
Well, I think it basically, I think the biggest problem here is that as a consumer,
I cannot make an informed decision
around closed
source software.
It's
impossible.
You
make an informed decision around open-source
software.
Yeah.
So for example, and I've written articles on this,
but one thing talking about looking at the change logs, you know,
do they have 100 commits in the last six months?
Do they have 10 commits in the last six months?
Do they have zero commits in the last six months?
You know, are there mailing lists with active traffic? Is there
active support going on? You know, there's projects with very few commits
simply because the project itself is very mature,
you know,
and that shows when you look at the support requests coming in because there's,
you know, all these only weird edge corner cases
and the majority of it just works for people.
-- I guess
-- that that's a hilarious way to think about it is you're right there,
there are mature projects that don't need commits because
they basically do what they need to do.
And there's also projects that have no commits because they're basically dead.
And so how do you, I mean, from the security perspective, that's a huge difference.
How do you tell them apart?
Well, one thing is even a project with no commits can still have a healthy upstream
you know, there's still people and the beauty is,
you can look through the code and email them
and I have in past emailed people and said, hey, are you still working on this?
And they're like? Yeah. Yeah. Do you need a bug fix or something?
Uh, conversely,
I've also had software projects where I've tried to hunt down
the people involved in it and they're all dead or gone,
you know,
-- and impossible to find.
-- How does
normal person
or, or should that even be something they worry about
is, is
finding that out.
The reality is, I think as consumers,
we generally don't make very well informed decisions.
I mean, you look at pretty much anything we purchase,
you look at pretty much anything we purchase
and with very few exceptions, there's not a lot of good info.
I mean, one exception, for example is cars, there's some really good,
you know, consumer reports does, in my opinion,
amazing work around car reviews and safety reviews of cars.
But I mean, that's the exception to the rule, right? Like when you look at
most things fundamentally, is it Ul Certified?
So can I plug it into my house and not burn my house down? Yes. Ok. That's it.
Now, now I'll, I'll pick on that one. Right. I,
I went to college for electrical engineering.
I have friends who went to UL for work.
I know what UL does I understand what they do? I know people there.
I never look for the UL symbol on anything I buy
until it breaks. Then I'm like, oh, this wasn't UL approved.
No wonder it lit on fire when I plugged it in.
Right.
Yeah.
So, I mean, there's at least those baselines in some industries.
Um, and I mean, with software there is no baseline yet,
you know,
-- can
-- there be, I mean,
and so this is, this is a debate that
I, I go back and forth myself constantly, right?
Because it's easy to say we need to certify software.
There should be some, you know,
minimum bar claiming this is the way to do it or this isn't the way to do it,
whatever it is.
But the thing is
there's two things that keep coming up for me is one, number one,
like a dude in his basement can write software.
So how do you, does it apply to that?
And, and let's face it in the way open source works.
Like people are gonna run that stuff in a product someday because
it's gonna end up on stack overflow or it's gonna end up on
github.
So you've got that aspect
but then on the other side of it also this stuff moves so fast.
I mean, you look at like the car industry or the airline industry,
you're talking about like five plus years of,
of features in hardware are in the pipeline working their way to the end.
Whereas in software like if we have a good idea,
we can have a new software thing out by the end of the day,
I think part of it is to remember there are
technically speaking situations where software is certified, for example,
in medical devices and
actually in elevators and cars.
But the reality is the software certification process right now is,
is laughably terrible.
-- I mean, I,
-- I
-- wouldn't
-- even say that you just think it's laugh.
there's nothing there, there's not even anything to laugh at.
Yeah.
And so part of it is, you know,
the reality is
if you could properly certify something and actually say that it is bug free.
Well, you've now solved, you know, turing's halting problem.
Good for you,
go collect your Nobel Prize,
right?
So by definition, if, if we had the capability to do this,
we wouldn't need to because the, the, you know,
the initial developers wouldn't have written code with bugs in it.
Um, I think what will happen though is we can definitely
check the maturity of the overall project and, you know, make sure that they,
you know, even simple. Do you guys have a bug tracker? Right.
How many places don't even have a proper bug tracker?
You know,
uh, if you look at some of these commercial software, you know,
enterprise products,
do you have a build system or does somebody just
randomly build it on their workstation and hope it runs?
You know, I've got a great story about that is
I was working with a project one time.
This was some years back and we were talking about
how security updates get developed. And the topic of BUILD system comes up.
And I said, you know, how do you build your stuff?
Tell me about your build infrastructure.
And they're like, oh, we build it on Bob's laptop.
And I said what? That's not cool. They're like, why, what's the difference?
It's, it's fine.
And I, you know, I give the laundry list, the viruses and malware, whatever,
you know, and I go through, they're like, yeah, we don't care about any of that stuff.
We build it on his laptop and it's fine.
And then I'm like, well, well, how do you distribute this stuff?
And then they're, they're telling me and they're using like, this weird
website not related to their domain
to put software on.
And I'm like, but some of your releases are over here, like, on your download page.
Why aren't you using that anymore?
And they were like, oh, well, our uh our web guy, uh he got hit by a bus and he's,
he's still recovering and like, like, he literally was hit by a bus and I'm like,
what if Bob gets hit by a bus?
And they're like, 00, yeah, we hadn't really thought of that before.
And I'm like, I, it literally happened to you guys and of course, you know, they,
they understood at least, I don't think they ever fixed any of it.
But,
you know, it, it took them a second to put that together in their minds and,
and that's like, it's my favorite story to tell.
Right. Where you've got this instance of people.
I, I think they don't want to believe it could ever happen to them,
which I guess is human nature.
Right. If that wasn't true. I don't think we'd have the problems we have but
-- a man
-- how many,
how many people build their houses and businesses in known flood zones.
And here's my favorite in Alberta. We have a town, the town is called High River.
-- Guess what happens every 100 years.
-- But man, the view is fantastic, right?
Like the closer you are to that river, the better the view.
And so every once in a while,
well, this year it was about,
or this time it was about five years ago and the the whole town is flooded, you know,
6 ft deep and everybody and I'm like,
it's called high, like they call like when the settlers moved there,
they called it high River.
That
is fantastic, man. I love it.
No, it, it's basic human nature, right? We don't.
I mean, life is so full of potentially terrible things that could happen.
If you thought about every single one of them,
uh you would hide under your bed except you wouldn't
accept because your bed might collapse and kill you.
Then you become a security person, Kurt
and we have to live with our reality every single day.
-- And
-- I honestly think one of the most popular coping
mechanisms and I know quite honestly I do this now
is to largely ignore risk unless it's like, literally right up in my face.
I, I mean, that's fair. Right.
If you had to worry about every single little piece of risk,
you find every single day all the time it would be,
you couldn't deal with it, right.
Normal people couldn't handle it and no one could handle it right? For that matter.
Which. All right. So let's tie it back to open source.
How do we talk about risk in the open
source universe when someone comes to you and says,
Kurt,
I don't think open source software is secure.
-- What are you going to tell them?
-- Well, I'm gonna tell them that
if they find vulnerabilities
and report them that they'll probably get fixed for the vast majority of projects.
This is true.
Uh I'm gonna tell them that they can have auditors go through the code if they want.
They also quite often have a choice of code. You know, there's
uh many situations where you have a large project
uh
that then
becomes very feature-rich,
which in and of itself often introduces a lot of potential security risks
and then you'll have some new up and comer that does it very lean and very secure.
You know,
there's a lot of secure alternatives now for
various services that you need to be running.
Uh I would also say that they can participate in the community
and push the security agenda if they want. You know,
the reality is the vast majority of projects would be more than happy
to have people commit security fixes to them or commit security hardening to them
as long as they play nice and, you know, respect the community.
You know, you can't go in there with hobnailed boots and be like, yeah,
we're gonna do this, this and this because it's more secure,
that definitely will not work.
Yes.
Oh, man. The number of times I've tried to do that, I don't even want to think about it.
It makes me sad.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, that's right. But all right. So,
back it up even farther though.
It's, it's easy to talk about, oh,
community and get involved in all this open source stuff.
But let's face it. Most people don't do that.
They aren't gonna get involved because that's the reality of it.
So what happens when
you've got like
an architect working at, at a company, uh,
a medium size company that doesn't even have enough time to do his day job
and he's like, everyone want, you know, I've got all this open source crap.
Everyone keeps throwing at me.
What do I do with this? How do you, how do you talk to someone like that?
That they they, they don't have time to verify it secure.
They don't have time to join communities.
They don't even, they don't want to for that matter.
So I would say there and this is the somewhat cynical part of me.
Do you need to run this software? Yes or no.
If you do need to run this software, then by definition, you have to do something,
you have to run it or find a
competing package that does the same thing that you need.
So you can either run the open source one, have availability, start using it today
or you can start evaluating commercial vendors and good luck with that,
you know.
So part of it is quite honestly,
I'm at a point in my life where take it or leave it because quite frankly,
there's enough people using open source and contributing back to it that,
you know, we're good. We're never, it's never gonna die.
It's just a part of the way life is.
And conversely,
there's people that will never accept open source and will always think it's evil or
strange.
Or those people don't have a choice because it's here and it won.
I mean, let's face it, man. Open source one. It's in everything.
You, even if you don't know it, like you're using open source.
I was uh
uh who is it? Mudge put a thing up on Twitter the other day showing all of the licenses
in, in like a, I forget what car company
was it Mercedes.
Yeah, they're running, like, you know, Lib P and G and Lib Tiff and,
like all these crazy libraries and now at the same time,
you know, that's terrifying because they probably just grabbed a copy of it one day,
you know, five years ago
and that's the one they're still using, which has had, you know,
like 100 security flaws fixed.
But it's,
it's everywhere, man. I mean, so I do.
It always chuckles making me chuckle a little bit when I've got someone being like,
oh, is open source secure?
And
you don't, it doesn't matter, right?
Like you're using it, you don't get to pick anymore.
Well, it's, you know, it's a lot like elevators,
a lot of people are afraid of elevators,
but they're definitely
not.
I have never met anyone afraid of elevators, maybe a two year old. Right.
Actually, there was a little kid once.
Uh I knew he was like one and he was literally afraid of elevators.
But other than that,
-- who is afraid of elevators?
-- Honestly,
I've met one or two people and, but the reality is even if you're afraid of elevators,
you know, if you go into a building 40 stories tall,
you're not going up 40 flights of stairs.
That's fair. And I can't wait for all the hate mail.
I'm gonna get about people who are afraid of elevators that are gonna
tell me about their serious condition.
So that'll be fantastic.
Alright. That's right.
Although honestly,
I think airplanes could maybe be a better analogy
here because obviously it carries pretty significant risk.
I mean, you don't hear about a lot of elevator deaths but when there's a plane crash,
like, you know it, man,
it's, that's news. Right.
But, uh, back to the open source thing, I mean, the reality is
people are using it,
you are going to have to use it whether
you like it or not because something you purchased
has software in it.
And if it has software in it, it almost guaranteed has open source in it because
like you said, there's all these image processing libraries, there's,
you know, nobody wants to spend money reinventing the wheel.
And more importantly, businesses don't have time to re invent the wheel anymore.
You know, if you're on a three month product cycle or a six month product cycle,
you can't spend two years writing an image parsing library.
Yeah, that's fair.
I mean, well, heck, I mean, back in the day you didn't need an image parsing library,
right?
Because there was one kind of image maybe, or you just made your own up,
everything was fine.
Yeah.
And then to the security side of it,
I hate to say it because I don't wanna, you know, call names. But
how do we know the uh closed source world is doing any better?
They're totally not, you know, that it's,
and, and again, open
source one,
there's no such thing as close source software anymore.
You know,
you've got your open source and you might put something on
top of it that you aren't necessarily releasing in public.
But,
I mean, for the most part it, it, you've got open source and, and no, I would agree.
Closed source is
unquestionably no better.
And of course, you have people, I used to always tell people, you know,
open source is better, but that can't be backed up in any way.
I am willing to say that uh
both are equally bad
would probably be the, the nicest way to describe it. Right.
I think the biggest difference is that we just air out our dirty laundry in public.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's fair.
The code, the mailing list,
you know, because to me a big part of what's about open source, the value,
especially as a security person is not just the code,
but the whole having access to the whole community around it.
You know, being like
when somebody finds a flaw on open source,
you can get blame and find who wrote that line of code.
And, and I love that it's called get blame,
right?
Like,
you know, when you're looking, that's why you're doing it. Who do I go get to yell at
and you know, with, I,
I've been in situations with close source
companies where they didn't even use source control
and they literally had no idea who wrote the code.
That's fantastic.
I, I'm going to hope that doesn't happen anymore,
even though I'm sure it does.
Yeah.
Then I'm not gonna think about it.
All right.
I love it.
Oh, man. Is there any hope?
How do we fix it? Curt,
I think,
I think there is hope and, and going back to the certification side,
the reality is you don't have to do an awesome job
to assess risk. Right. It's pretty easy to say that, you know, back to my favorite
metric of security is it's a dumpster fire. How bad is the dumpster fire? You know,
just wheel it away from the building and everything.
You know, you bring this up and I just read a thing,
I wish I would have kept it because I don't remember where it came from,
but it was discussing risk and,
you know, what,
how are you addressing your risk in your industry or your organization?
And
they said basically so obviously, you know, we,
we'll use a topic of breaches because that's pretty easy to understand that
you can estimate what the cost of a breach would be.
And basically they said,
if you're mitigating technologies be it people
and tools and processes and whatever,
if they exceed 37% of the cost of the breach,
you are wasting your money,
which is kind of fascinating to think about. I mean,
iiii I gotta go,
I have to go find this but like 37% is a very specific number so clearly,
or I should say clearly, hopefully someone has actual math behind that
and they didn't just make up a number, which I'm, is a possibility. But
it's, yeah, I mean, and that makes sense. Right. Because
if you're spending more than a breach would cost you,
it would make more sense to just accept the breach. Right.
Well, unless there's a branding issue. Yeah,
-- I mean, if you
-- have, I mean, that's part of it though, right?
I mean, you have to take into account the cost of, you know, brand to
losing,
you know what I mean?
Because there's also, for example, the ST
Jude's debacle currently ongoing, you know,
where that security firm found some security flaws in their pacemaker devices
and then went to Wall Street short,
sold the stock and went public with the vulnerabilities.
And so at that point now you've also got, well,
you've got the potential for some law enforcement related issues.
Um but more importantly, you know,
you have Saint Jude in the press largely because
this is the first time this has publicly happened.
You know, it's something new and shiny.
Yeah. All right. I'm looking at the stock here. I just pulled it up. It's down,
it was at about 82 ish.
We're looking at 78 now.
It, it the lowest 77.8. So it's,
yeah, that's fair.
I mean,
I will be interested to see if in a
couple of months if it's totally recovered because,
I mean, like you look at what happened with,
with Target
and their stock took a hit, but it's basically right back where it was.
So I think you could easily make the argument that in terms of brand recognition,
their incident had minimal long term impact.
Well, and that's the sad reality is for most, especially for breach
style
situations.
I
suspect the majority of the costs are essentially externalized, you know,
onto the people
whose information was leaked or, you know,
unless it's something like an ATM theft or like that, you know,
swift wire transfer fraud where actual money is stolen from the bank.
The majority of these companies don't actually
lose a lot of money. You know, it's not like their accounts are being emptied out.
It's, you know, people's personal information
and unfortunately it was just,
the name escapes me but a week or two ago
there was a chiropractic office in the USA Pain Management.
Yeah. The,
the, you know, had,
this is weird to me because they're big enough to have 200,000 sets of records.
I
mean, that's a lot of people,
uh, and there's somehow it would,
they were breached and all this information is up for sale on the dark web.
And the company's response is we can't afford to provide credit monitoring.
It would bankrupt us. So we're not going to,
you know, and the reality is unless somebody gets,
uh, a lawsuit started and then wins it. Well, that, that's how this is gonna play out
and
I suspect more and more companies might take that
approach of while this offering you credit monitoring,
it is gonna cost us money. So we're not gonna do it.
Right.
Well, and I think that's,
that's part of that 37% now that people are gonna start thinking about.
Right? Is,
is how does like cybersecurity insurance fit into this story.
And if, if the cost of the bad thing is, you know,
much less than they getting insurance and proper security
and that's borderline terrifying in a lot of ways. And I know
like a lot of people pick on things like, you know, PC I compliance and whatnot.
But I mean, in all seriousness,
some of this compliance is good because it
makes these organizations kind of do the right
thing even if it doesn't necessarily make them super secure at the end of the day,
it at least makes them put some of the right pieces in the right places, which is in,
in an instance like that.
A very good thing.
Well,
and something to remember too about risk is we accept a lot of risk in life like 30,000
a
year on the US alone, right?
And in other parts of the world where they have less traffic controls,
you know, it, it's insane.
-- Right. But I'm more scared of sharks than I am. Of cars.
-- Yeah,
and, and you know, cars are a good example because it's something that's, you know,
we actually have data that says if you drive this many miles,
then the statistical chance of you getting clobbered is this, you know,
and again,
so we deal with it through insurance.
You know, we also have people engineering cars better,
but fundamentally we have an entire system around it and
it doesn't have to be perfect and it isn't,
you know, the number of people I know that have been in
car accidents and had their necks screwed up for a year or two.
You know, that doesn't sound like fun,
but it's just something
that happens.
So back to software security,
we don't actually have to have that great a deal of
risk management knowledge around it because we've already accepted the risk,
right?
We're already
in
-- the middle of the forest.
-- Nobody accepts the risk on pur.
I mean, have you ever seen like in EU L A?
The thing, it's a phone book that just indemnifies the vendor.
Well, and so
there the consumer takes the risk on,
you know, whether they like it or not.
I need to catch those Pokemon like I, I can't help it, you know.
So the reality is we've already, we've already crossed the bridge now.
We're realizing maybe we should have built a better bridge or maybe not gone over it.
But it's,
yeah.
Yeah, we're there, there's, there's no going back. I agree.
And I mean, that's one of the great challenges. Right, is how, what now?
And I don't, we, we don't know. Right.
We certainly have no idea what, what's going on now. However, I will admit,
and this is something that almost gives me hope every now and then is the fact that
open source one,
which also means everything is starting to change.
There are things happening in this industry now,
unlike anything we've ever seen before.
And so hopefully, hopefully
we can get some of this right this time around.
Well, you know,
the fact that Microsoft has not only started
using open source internally for products and services,
but has started and not only supporting open source
in the form of Docker containers on windows,
but is actually now open sourcing some
-- of their tooling and their software like
-- Power
powershell man. That's, that's awesome, right?
I can't.
So, so funny enough, I had a conversation the other day with somebody that was like,
oh powershell, that's dumb.
Who wants that? I'm like
there are more Windows admins than probably there are Linux,
if you added a zero onto the end of the number of Linux
admins, like we a huge market just opened up because of this tool.
You know, that's,
that's a big deal.
And
I think it's inevitable that like you said, I,
in my mind, the future of software is essentially people writing glue code
and very few people writing actual services or the
hard to write software like kernels or encryption software.
You know,
there's going to be small groups that do that do it well,
and the rest of us are just going to consume it. Right.
Nobody, nobody writes an encryption library anymore. That's just flat out
saying
that's a topic for another day
and, and people do still write encryption libraries
and they totally should.
-- They're bad. Your
-- famous stunning Kruger curve.
Yes. Which,
yeah.
Oh, man,
don't get me started.
All right. All right. So, so let's take it home Kurt. Open source secure or insecure.
I would say both. You know, it's sort of a quantum thing until you measure it.
You don't know.
But it doesn't matter because we're using it and it's here.
That is the greatest answer I've ever heard of that question.
Schrodinger is open source, right? Doesn't matter. It's already here.
I love it, man.
All right. Cool. Well, that was fun. Kurt,
until next time.