Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Bresser,
-- we're going to talk about what is open source today,
which sounds like a weird and possibly boring topic. But it's relevant
to a talk I recently gave at
the Grassroots Security conference, which I talked about a couple of episodes ago,
I think right after it happened and I learned a lot giving this talk.
And so I thought it would be an interesting topic for us to discuss.
Now. It's,
-- it sounds boring. Right. Because like, what is open
-- source,
-- it's whatever the O SI defines
-- it
as,
right, which I told people that and they,
the audience didn't quite grasp the irony of that or why.
It was funny.
I know it's like
it's what this one central organization defines
this completely decentralized cultural movement does.
Right. Right. And it, it,
it's funny but you also need like some weird
historical context.
So for anyone listening who doesn't know there's the O SI,
which is what the open source initiative, I believe it stands for Institute.
I'm pretty sure it's initiative. It's not, I don't think It's Institute
open
source initiative
initiative. All right. Good, good, good. So
the O SI has like this
lofty interesting definition of open source and
there's like 10 point bullet points.
-- They have,
-- I'm sorry, I have to read this
open source licenses are licenses that comply with the open source definition.
In brief, they allow software to be freely used,
modified and shared
and then,
and then it gets complicated the details.
-- Yeah.
-- And, and the reality is if it's on their list, it's open source.
If it's not on their list, it's not open source.
Which, and, and the best part,
my favorite part of this is like the GP L people don't like
open source. So they're free software.
So the GP L is on the OS I's list,
but the GP L people would rather not be called open source.
So
it's hilarious anyway.
I give this talk right?
And I, I go through licensing, I go through the idea of like how projects work,
like how github
tends to work all this stuff. And now mind you, this was a security conference.
So I, I had some security stories weaved in here and there.
And fundamentally though I had this vision in my mind
of explaining open source to a bunch of security people,
so they could take that knowledge and go back to what they were doing
and
use open
source
or, or whatever, right? And the reality is at the end, it was obvious that
no one really cared about the definition of open source or how open source works.
They were like, how do we use it in a way that isn't insecure.
And I'm like,
that is a completely valid question and should
have been the entire topic of this talk.
I mean, I,
I like, I, I, you and I are both old enough to remember the whole shareware scene,
which was essentially a polite way of saying we're gonna pirate soft where
and
because we technically don't have to pay for it, it's not technically piracy,
but also that guy probably doesn't need to eat.
-- And so that's his problem.
-- No, shareware was perfect. It was like,
you, you could use a,
a
demo. It was basically a demo of the software. See if you like it
-- and then if you did in theory pay for the real thing
-- or how many people paid for
Winrar.
I mean, Winrar
is different. I'm thinking
like Doom or Commander Kane or one of those things, right?
Like, I think games worked well with shareware. But like what PK zip was, shareware.
I definitely used PK zip. I mean, I was young and had no money anyway.
So not like I could have paid for it.
-- But well,
-- and also like back in the day, how did you get money to somebody?
-- Like, straight up some of them were like you mailed them
-- a check, you mailed them.
Yes.
I mean, I remember the PK where, like, I think it was after you ran it,
it would give you the like, oh, if you're using this and you like it, you should
give us money
-- and it had a literal address you would mail money to
-- which is not legal.
-- What do you mean? Mailing money
-- isn't legal?
No, you can't mail cash.
Are you sure
you live in? Canada?
Canada is like a real country. Does, does the United States feels a little more?
We'll say
cowboy in that regard.
-- They amended it recently.
-- I've received cash in the mail more than once.
Well, and you've probably also driven above the speed limit.
I
will not answer that question.
Oh, interesting.
-- Ok.
-- Anyway, no, we are not discussing the intricacies of only cash.
That's not the purpose of this.
They literally changed it a year ago where basically you
have to use registered mail for cash over $500.
So it looks like you could mail small amounts of cash.
PK ware was like 20 bucks.
Like it probably wasn't even that. I mean,
this was what the eighties and the nineties,
it was probably like $7 or something insane.
I don't know. Anyway, it doesn't matter. Ok.
So the point is give this talk, talk about licenses and at the end of it all,
it's basically just how do I, how do I use software more securely?
And
I found
the gears in my brain started to kind of go and we were, you know,
doing the Q and A at the end and hanging out in the hallway and all that.
And
it was, it was really interesting because when you're talking to
like security people or developers, whoever, and I, I feel like I,
I talk to these people a lot.
There was a ton of really good questions and, you know,
there were people just saying stuff like how
do I know what my developers are running?
Which they don't?
Yeah, they don't and you don't like.
Yeah, I OK.
I just found this nice A I fronting called Liber
Chet dot A I it's darker.
I it's like five or six containers.
It uses a couple of major components like Mongo DB and post grass cool.
But
I guarantee you there's at least 100 to 1000
things in there that I am just blissfully unaware of
-- that.
-- No one knows.
Um I mean, this is, this is kind of what like the idea of the S bomb is right where
you have software, you can
in theory get an S bomb for it and then
you can't know it's still in it because you have to
-- have some other tool to read the SS bomb because it's gigantic.
-- But
well, and to know what it is like, my favorite is always like spices and that,
for example, is codes phrase for may contain gluten if you're a celiac.
-- Right.
And So that's actually, that was one of the questions that came up was OK.
So let's say I have a list of all, all the software.
Like, what is it? How do I even know what this stuff is doing?
And it's like that is an excellent question.
-- Like,
-- if packaged food is not a part of some ecosystem like wordpress plugins or N PM,
-- what is fu, well,
-- ignoring that,
I'm not even going down that rabbit hole because I think that's bananas.
-- Well,
-- but I mean, at some point, I can't give you like,
I can't say this is a cashew or this is a Koch,
Koch.
And you're like, what's a Kusche?
Kusche? I'm like, it's Kush.
Kush,
it's, it's yummy.
-- I have no idea what that even is.
-- Well, that's what I'm saying is, it's a made up thing.
So it's like if I say this software contains,
that's the best you could do by making up a word.
So, but that's what I mean.
It's like if this software contains FU and FU is not the
actual package from Pi Pie or N PM or some ecosystem thing.
What the heck is this? Right? And that's why we see that a lot in like Java
where, you know,
it pulls in some Java package and you try and trace it down and it's just,
you can't find
it disappeared 10
-- or better yet. It did exist in an ecosystem, but it's gone
-- now that
can happen but is less common than it used to be.
Well, except we have a lot of 10 and 20 year old software.
Yeah, that's true.
That's true. I mean, if I found PK zip actually, you know, it was wild.
Speaking of that. Sorry, I'm going to go out on
a tangent for a moment. So, the company that made PK zip, like, way back in the day.
PK ware, they were at a conference. I was at a couple of months ago.
I
-- was like, why are
-- they still in business?
I know. Right.
But anyway, that's another story. I'm not,
it
was data protection solution.
They had no swag I wanted. So I didn't get, I think I got a pen from them or something.
But I was like, holy cow. This is like,
I, I just waves of nostalgia washed over me when I saw
him
and everyone there was, looked pretty young.
So I was like, I'm not going to go talk to them about PKZ
because they probably don't even know what that is.
I like that they transition to Z OS in the mainframe market
because those people hate change.
Well, all their products,
either men PK Protect for Z OS or PK encrypt for IBM systems.
-- Oh, interesting. Yeah. So, well, mainframe people have money and they hate
-- change.
That's true. That's why they have mainframes and money.
Yeah, pretty much
anyway.
Ok. Ok. So what is open source? Right.
And so all,
all of these questions, all this discussion
and
it kind of occurred to me that
there is the like technical o SI style definition of open source,
but people using open source, they literally don't care even a little bit,
right?
-- There's
-- de
and de facto,
this is classic dejo
and de facto is there's this beautiful lofty definition of,
here's the O SI licenses and then there's the actual like de
facto definition of like I grabbed a bunch of stuff off like,
oh perfect example, does a code snippet off stack overflow count as open source.
There's no license
on it.
That one.
-- Well, there can be,
-- there are code snippets that have, well,
but let's assume there's no license attached to it and it's just a code snippet.
There are code snips and stack overflow that have
literally cost humanity millions of hours in lost productivity.
-- Zip
-- slip. That was literally what zip slip was.
It was copying AAA
-- snippet from stack overflow and using it and it was incorrect.
-- Yeah, exactly.
So, you know, is that open source?
Well, the source code is there and everybody uses it like it's open source.
So I would say
it's open source.
I I would agree. I mean, and, and this is again
where if you asked a lawyer that question,
you would end up in like a six
hour discussion
about
what like what is copyrightable and who owns copy. It's,
-- it's so complicated.
-- Well, not just what is copyrightable and what is licenses
are also different things.
I'm going to put a link, I will not dwell on this, but I'm going to put a link.
I know I've talked
about this more than once on the show.
There is a, an article written by a lawyer named Pamela Chast
who's done,
she's done a bunch of work in like the open source universe on licensing.
She tries to answer the question like, who owns the copyright on source code?
Because this whole like, oh the authors of, of something
that does, that is not a legal entity that is not the,
the authors of cannot own the copyright to something.
Anyway, so I'll, I'll put a link to it for anyone. Any like licensing nerds. OK.
So anyway, yes, there's the, like,
I don't care what the o si definition of open source is.
There's the fact that my developers are taking this stuff and they're using
this stuff and I'm a security person and I have to know like,
what is this stuff?
And so we ended up in discussions like one of my favorites.
I know a person who works at a company that has a quarterly open source meeting.
They have like a council that has to approve
all of the open source dependencies once a quarter.
-- Is this before or after they're used?
-- Exactly. That's exactly it.
If it's after they've been used, that's a little bit late.
-- That's like me
-- saying, well, it's always after, right?
I mean, so what's funny about that though is I said, I say this and one of the guys like,
oh, that sounds interesting.
I'm like, no, no, please do not do this
because well, here's what actually happens, right?
If you tell developers who you are literally paying to solve hard problems that
they have to wait
a month to get approval to use this library, they want to use to solve their problem.
They will find a way
and they're just going to copy and paste the source code most likely
into their application instead of actually using a package manager that can,
you know, upgrade it and track it and all that stuff.
And see, that's the irony.
Like I wrote some Python software to use some different A I back ends.
And I realized it was actually way less effort to package it
up and put it on pi pie than to like maintain my
own copy of it because it literally to package it up and
put it on pi pi create an account on PP create a project
all of that five minute tutorial and then you run two commands
and it's done. And so now I can pip install my thing
on any system.
And I don't have to like copy a file over and make sure it's the right one I can.
It's,
it's actually easier to distribute it to the world than
it is to maintain my own internal distribution thing.
It used to be.
There's actually for anyone who, who does Python work and doesn't know about this,
there's a new, there's this p project dot Tonel which is like the new way to
in instead of the old setup dot pie and all that crap.
-- This is
-- using the new one but like literally, I don't have to copy for,
you're using Piero
dot
Tomel.
OK. So what you can do then
there is a tool called poetry.
But poetry instead of like using dependencies from pie, pie, you can play it
at github repos, which is absolutely amazing in Chef's Kiss. Very nice.
But I'd rather not, I'd rather just pip install
well.
But if you use poetry, you don't have to use pip,
which is beautiful because poetry will
auto manage your virtual environments for you,
which is amazing.
Well, and this is exactly kind of how open source ended up winning,
I think because they made it so easy to pull down
stuff and grab stuff that kind of mostly sort of often
works
and
you can't stop it without
like massively intrusive firewall
anyway. All right.
I want to pull us back to the,
the actual conversation topic because we're talking about
like how security people view open source.
And I think what, what came out of this really is
like a, a myths and truths
I think would be vastly more interesting in this regard.
And this is where I need to start collecting these.
But like another one was they, these people were like,
how do I know if I can trust this thing?
And I'm like, well, you kind of can't,
-- how
-- do
-- you know you can trust your own code?
-- Well, yes,
yes. That's part of the discussion obviously. But,
but examples being like, how do I know if a project is, for example,
maintained by a maintainer from one of the
forbidden countries where in the United States,
for example, there's countries we legally can't interact with, right?
Well, that's the thing.
So, so here's, here's the the trick and you say, oh, you can't know and that is true.
However,
there is the concept of due diligence with the law, right?
So if I just YOLO and don't look at all
that's different than saying, I
looked at who the authors are and tried to identify their countries of origin.
And this is what I found, right? That is due diligence.
I made a commercially reasonable effort, blah, blah, blah.
Yes, exactly. And so there's that angle of it, right? And so
there's a question of like, how like, how do I know if this project is maintained?
How do I know if like there's people working on it?
And this is where like, for example, there's the open SSF scorecard project
which I think we all know from a strictly security perspective,
generates like nonsense data.
But from a liability perspective, you can probably claim his due diligence. Right?
I literally just went through this again with,
I found a air quotes security vulnerability and it is
technically a security vulnerability and that it can reveal the,
you know, valid or non valid accounts.
And I literally went to develop,
I'm like, is this technically a security vulnerability?
However, for me, it's more of a GDPR compliance thing,
like it's a compliance issue first, a security issue, second.
And he's like, yes, I agree. You know,
and it'll get fixed at some point. It's not a big deal.
And I think that's a big part of so
many security people make fun of compliance driven security.
But the reality is at the end of the day,
the compliance driven stuff is probably what's gonna bite me more.
Oh
for sure. I mean, this is where I think I forget who's, who wrote this.
Someone unmasked it on pointed out though, you know, when,
when Microsoft announced their recall feature,
which was going to take a screenshot every five seconds or whatever.
And the security people were, of course, are losing their minds.
And this person said, look, don't talk about it in the context of security,
talk about it in the context of, of lawyers
because if you get sued,
the legal counsel on the other opposing side is going
cause all this recall data and now you have a screenshot of every
five seconds of everything that's been done
on every computer in your organization.
Holy crap. Someone's going to jail. Probably.
Discovery might find some.
Well, I remember my mother when this is
decades ago was, had a spam problem with her government email account.
Ok. And I was like, well, you know, you're gonna, this is way back in the day.
So I'm like, you're gonna have to get them to, like, block spam for you.
And she's like, well, they say it'll take weeks or months and I'm like,
do you want them to do it tomorrow?
And she's like, yeah, and I'm like,
tell them you got pornographic spam and it's making you uncomfortable and it's,
it's a possible
place, blah, blah, blah, legal issue. And she's like, that's,
oh,
and then she comes home the next day and she's like, yeah, they fixed it.
So it's funny you mentioned that.
I think I've told this story here before, but I don't remember for sure.
I remember when we worked at Red Hat,
if you wanted like
a logo or something for a special event for like making shirts or coats or whatever,
like, and some sort of swag,
you'd have to contact the marketing people and they put you on a list
and then you'd have to wait like some amount of time.
Like it was usually months, then they would get to you and help you.
But instead if you sent them an email that said, hey, I'm sending this logo off.
I made to the printers tomorrow
just so, you know,
they'd be like, you can't use that.
And I'm like, well, it's, the order has to go in tomorrow.
They somehow find a way to send you the correct logo.
So,
yes, it's very, that, that very much feels like the, what is it?
Don't ask for permission, ask for forgiveness sort of thing.
And, and I think there's a lot of security that even works that way anyway. Ok.
-- So back to
-- if you want to get anything done, that's how you do it.
Because if I ask for permission, I'm gonna have to wait a month or in your case,
three months for the council of open source tribal elders at this company to,
to even look at the paper.
You know, this is like dealing with the V
the
Vons
Vons.
I don't want to stick an extra
-- anyways
-- because you obviously haven't read the book enough.
You should read it again.
Your punishment is to read Hitch Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
-- That's not punishment.
-- I know. Right.
But like straight up, I don't have three months. I need to get it done now like,
well, you don't,
-- but
-- this
-- is like the
thing
we needed,
we needed a front end for an A I
like in, in, in a week. So I
went and tested a bunch of them and found one and deployed it and here we are like,
and yes, we know you keep talking about it,
it's just, it's such a nice, lovely, well written piece of software.
Like, I'm really happy with it. So,
so anyway,
this
is kind of the discussion about what open source is, right?
Because that's supposed to be what we're talking about.
It's easy to rat hole on this one because it, there's just so many weird intricacies.
Right.
It's wild to me that security people think developers care about
anything beyond getting their job done as like priority number one.
No, I, I disagree with that. I think developers want to do the right thing.
But
the first most important thing is my manager said, go do X or Bill and
I
need to
and I will try to do that within the context of
doing it securely and safely in GDPR compliantly and all that.
But at the end of the day, none of that matters if I don't get it done.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly. 100%. And, and I think that's,
that's likewise the problem the security people have is
on the other side of that coin is security.
People don't want to be in the way of,
right. They don't want to slow down product.
Well, there are some, but the people I was talking to are,
they're like legitimate in the trenches, good security folk
that just that their problem is their, their developers are using
whatever they don't know what it is and they don't know what to do.
Right.
And,
and I think that is a vastly more common problem than the
security team everyone hates because they just say no to everything.
And those do exist.
-- But
-- I also think it's a maturity thing.
Like I realize now as a security person at best, I'm a concierge
because people come to me and say I'm hungry and
I better offer them a good restaurant that they like.
Or else they're gonna walk out of the hotel and go find a restaurant
whether I like it or not.
And I can't even make the argument now of like, oh,
we can control spending and prevent them from doing it through, you know,
spending controls because
-- they can just use free stuff.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
Like you can't, and that's the thing with open source. Like you can't,
unless you firewall pretty much the entire internet that's
necessary for developers to access, like stock overflowing github.
That was, what was it that came up? And there was some, some security standard.
I forget which one it was.
But they suggested firewall developers,
workstations and everyone laughed at them
-- because it was like, this is stupid. No,
-- I've seen it.
I have straight up, like, I remember dealing with somebody who,
like all they had access to for an ID was notepad because
they wouldn't install any software and it was so firewalled,
it was a US federal government thing.
And he's like, you know what, I get paid hourly as a contractor kind of like it's,
and it's heartbreaking but like
I get
paid
is a cash,
right?
Yeah.
OK. So, anyway, anyway, I mean,
so, so again, we're going back to, you know,
this particular discussion people talking about,
you know, asking good questions about kind of the open source usage.
The XZ discussion
I thought was pretty wild because so this was, I mean, I'm in central Wisconsin,
that's where this conference was.
So we're not dealing with like, you know, people that were in, in,
in the middle of XZ for months and months, you know,
dealing with all this kind of crap, like a lot of us were
and from the perspective of the folks that was there,
it was very much like, ok,
so Xe happened, like, what do I actually need to care about because of this?
And it's like, fundamentally, do you have it?
Like,
that's really all you need to care about, you know,
because they didn't care about any of the details.
They didn't even care if they had it and it wasn't affected, right?
It was just a matter of like, do I have a bad version?
-- How do I know?
-- Well, that's, I mean, that's true.
Like there's, I've got that letter from Kia that says, you know,
park your car outside because it might catch fire and set your house on fire.
It hasn't so far,
well, just burn your house down. Sue Kia get a new house, how you know, works perfect.
I don't think that's how it works.
Once they've sent a letter and told me to park outside they've met their diligence.
Right.
Right. That's
true.
I mean, but yeah, because here's the thing,
I don't have time to deal with all the possible false positives because
I literally have, well, a million of them because
software
and, and so that was a huge, that was another big discussion point was the fact that,
like,
so let's say you have a scanner, which a lot of a lot of organizations do
I scan the software? I get back 700 findings.
-- What do I do with
-- this?
Like I just looked, it's using an eight month old PG vector container
which is, it's got to be out of date and have some CV S, right? It's eight months old,
but at the same time, it's only available internally, kind of who cares?
So like again,
right.
Yes, that, that's where some of the risk conversations come from then is
OK. I have 700 vulnerabilities.
How do I start to try to figure out what actually affects me? And that is a
hard
problem.
Actually, you're asking the wrong question. They all technically affect you.
It's which ones actually matter
which ones are likely to be exploited
and cause problems, right?
Because perfect example,
there's a ton of cross site scripting and remember we worked at Red Hat and I,
I loved it.
Uh There's a cross site scripting product vulnerability, sorry,
in a product and there was one that was reported and I'm like, ok, cool.
Assign a CV. And that person was like, sure, whatever it'll get
when it gets fixed. No big deal.
I'm like, yeah, you know, it's a work around.
Just use a separate browser profile, right? So you're not
clicking on weird stuff.
And then I had another organization submit another cross site
scripting in this product and they were like flipping out,
they wanted updates daily and I'm like, no,
like we'll fix it when we do. It's a, it's a low moderate.
And ultimately, what got them to
stop harassing me was I, I showed them look,
here's another public one like this is cross site scripting is,
it's, it's a web interface.
Well, it can be very serious. I mean, you can,
you can't blow it off. It depends what, how you're using it and what you're doing.
-- But
-- this is like owning a house and saying like there's a loose floorboard,
-- that's how floors work.
-- Yes, but it also
cross site scripting is one of those interesting points because it could be
a loose floorboard or it could be like the rotting foundation beneath you.
Absolutely.
And
my job was literally to check that.
That's the problem with all of these security vulnerabilities is
we don't have a nice way to be able to say like this is foundational. This is
a squeaky floor.
It also depends like if this PG vector is only provided on
an internal docker interface through a very limited piece of software,
probably really hard to attack.
Whereas if it's a post cress SQL database running at a web hosting company,
yeah, that might be a problem.
-- But
-- you know, and so this is so this is what's funny, right?
There are are security tools and products that claim
they can do this kind of,
you know,
inspection of your application and understand reach ability
and all of this sort of stuff.
And
none of them can
completely,
it's an unsolved problem and anyone who claims it,
like there's some things you can do, but for the most part you can't.
But like this is an example of where
when we develop software, when we build things,
we don't attach metadata that says something like this particular container
is only internal, it has zero network we'll say or, or whatever, right?
-- There's a million things we can do.
-- You're bringing back something
I tried to do at Red Hat 10 years ago.
And actually Red Hat bought a company that had a product that did that
this product would actually like take incoming requests
and so you could track the request as it hit databases or cash layers or whatever
anyways, it ended up being folded into openshift and that,
that tracking bit of the technology just went away because it was just too
complex
and expensive.
Nobody cared
and nobody really cared.
-- Well, I think people are maybe will care
-- well.
But the thing is you have log files so you can, you can do that after the fact,
-- painfully retroactively,
-- some of it.
I mean,
this is actually where the observable space has some really cool features you can,
you can leverage.
But anyway, it doesn't matter. The point is back to the like original point, right?
It was talking about, I've got all these vulnerabilities, what do I do?
And I mean, this is also where
you can start talking about like
understanding what you have and,
and building like this is where s bombs have a cool thing.
Um It's called the relationships, I think in SBO
talk. But it's basically just dependency graphs, right?
Of saying like this one, dependency is pulling in 700 things.
Can I get rid of it? Do I need it? What is it doing?
You know, and some of them, you can, some of them you can't
every time I install I think what is it?
Emac keeps pulling in Postgres SQL or something?
That is epic. If it does.
Actually, I found out the other day someone wrote a thing, you know, LD
D, the linker,
whatever. I forget that what LDD stands for.
But it's the like linker on Linux,
I can show you what other libraries are linked to by the thing you have right
there
being linked, that's not being declared.
Well, no, no, no, it's, it only shows you, the things you are linking against,
but those other things link against other things.
It's very, you know, the typical dependency problem.
Someone in the,
in the example I saw on Mastodon they did that
the LD tree or whatever it was called against Vim
and then is linked to AG
VBS like Liv Vor.
I'm like, what, what the heck is that?
But you know, it's because one of the things,
it links to links to a thing that links to Livor
and it's like
-- the
-- knee bones
to the nuclear submarine.
Right. Right.
And so, but like uh it's just, it's such a and that,
that alone could be obviously its own talk.
I think the point is right, when you use a vulnerability scanner now
it, it almost all of the findings are open source, right?
That's like, basically what,
well, what else would they be?
-- Well
-- be. That's true because you're not running closed source.
It's kind of a, the
pathology of like,
unless it's
the only close source, basically,
the only close source vendors that are doing a good job are
also all CV numbering authorities and there's like 100 of them.
Yeah, there's not very many
Microsoft. Absolutely. They're doing a good job.
Oracle.
Yeah. But when you're, when you're doing development, I mean,
-- there's um
-- I've seen developers pulling in a copy of Adobe to do PDF shenanigans.
Probably
true.
I wrote some Powershell scripts that use word to convert
word documents because I tried converting them with Python.
And
that did not go well, not even a little bit. And I
sadly discovered you convert from word to simplified html and then you feed
it into Python to turn it into even more actual simple html.
And that works because all I wanted was the tables. I just wanted the damn tables.
But anyway,
-- so like all of this, but
-- this is how developers think and work
well.
It is developers solve problems, right? That's what they're fundamentally doing.
I
mean,
and word is a dependency.
Good luck,
right? I know it makes perfect sense.
But my point is like all this stuff put together, right? There's, there's,
it was fascinating to me that and, and I should, I should have known this.
I mean, I really don't have a good excuse.
Other than that I had like this grandiose vision in my mind of like,
oh we're going to talk about like the big open source question and then obviously
everything else will just trickle out from that when the reality is.
I mean, no people just they have their problems,
they don't really care what open source is, they have problems they need to solve,
they want them solved.
I just realized, does anybody anywhere teach how to use open source?
-- And I'm guessing,
-- no, that's part of the, that's part of this conversation as well.
And so I guess most there's like tangential references in computer science.
-- Courses.
-- No,
-- I don't think
-- there are well tangential anyways.
What that means though is that everybody discovers and
learns to use open source on their own.
-- So, it's also like the blind people in the elephant. No,
-- it's not that at all.
So this is, this was, this was one of the discussions I had as well. Right.
Where
people don't use open source,
they use an ecosystem, they're using Python, they're using go,
they're following how
tos.
And
if you read a, how to, of like getting started in Python,
it just has you pip installing crap right away.
It doesn't explain
what's going on why all of this stuff is available for free. Who is working on it?
Where do these people come from?
It's just
run this command
and then paste this code into like test dot P.
You want open source on Mac Os, you run curl space pipe, brew. Sh
Right. It's fine, you know,
and like, but that's what I mean, it's like
everybody discovers open source kind of on their own. And so it's up to them to,
they get to sort of
-- fine and decide what it means to them. But,
-- ok. No, no, no. Here's the thing.
I don't think they even discover it. Kurt, I think the, like the, the single,
oh, I see what you're saying. They're like using it and they don't even,
-- they're
-- using Python. They don't even understand,
like open source is the thing they might have heard the term,
they might kind of get it,
but like they're just using Python,
I think actually. Yeah,
I think you're right. And that, my comment still stands is stats.
Then they're using Python
and
they don't even,
like, like I use a car and I'm told to put oil in it and keep that between the L and the F
right. Too high is bad, too low is bad. And also once it's like
black, black, as opposed to like dark black,
probably get more fresh oil in there. Somehow
I don't even do that.
My car puts a thing on the screen that says go get more oil and then I bring
it to
that. It's like too late.
-- It's an old
-- car, right? But by the time the sensor trips it's just like, wow. Yeah.
Sludge.
That's fair.
-- That's fair
-- again. So if everybody has sort of a different,
you know, people also have different experiences of it.
Like,
my experience of Python is guaranteed going to
be different than somebody else's experience of Python because
I actually have some understanding of what Python is and I know,
-- well, no, like I use virtual environments and stuff to like,
-- I've seen your Python.
It's a very different experience
and not in a good way. This is the, I found my sandwich on the ground way.
But hey, my co works,
you know.
That's right. I'm not starving to death.
Oh, you should see the PHP script I just wrote.
-- No,
-- I don't want to, I'm going to completely avoid that.
And that's the thing is security people maybe need to sit down
and talk to these people and kind of understand or at least
make sure they're speaking about the same. No, no, let me finish.
Make sure they're at least talking about the same
thing because if you have a security person talk,
like if you had me talking about Python security 20 years ago,
I would have been in a totally different
world than the actual developer using Python.
I don't have a good answer for what you're saying
-- right now because I think, I
-- think communication
-- start by talking
-- sort of,
but I also think we need to make sure we frame the problems correctly.
I think just by definition, that's what I
mean
us and anyone listening to us
have a,
we'll say,
probable level of experience and understanding in this
space that it eludes a lot of people
just because that's how, that's how Bell Curves work, right? I I
don't want to brag,
but we're going to say everyone listening to us is on the top end of that Bell Curve.
Well, just knowing that this thing exists already puts you
exactly like you know what open source is.
And so this is where I,
I feel like the conversation and the way to talk about this and what I'm,
I'm now morphing.
Also, I'll put a link to my original deck in the show notes that I presented that,
that what I'm working on now is going is like, not even comparable.
But I think the way to talk about this isn't to talk about
open source isn't to talk about like dependencies and all this stuff.
It's really just to say like, so you're a Python shop,
what does that mean?
And they don't care about licenses.
I mean, look, your lawyers are gonna care and they're like, obviously, like,
if you're full of GP L there are requirements, there's things you have to do.
So it's not like you can ignore open
source licenses.
There's a lot of companies that seem to think about
most probably do and, and, but again, that's a problem for the lawyers.
I'm not tackling that just from a security perspective.
It's really about like, so you're running Python, what does that mean? Right.
Because like a generalized open source talk has no value.
But talking about like, this is what Python does
that has value.
And I, like I said,
I think talking and just figuring out even if
you're talking about the same problem or question.
Yeah, for sure, for sure. So anyway, I,
I learned a lot. It's funny because I, I definitely,
I learned more giving this talk than I've learned in a long time,
which is amusing to me because I was the one
who was supposed to be bequeathing knowledge upon the audience and
-- they definitely turned that around on me.
-- This is how research happens.
This is how advancement happens. Right? So,
goes there.
Oh, I,
what we, what, what used and it's, it's not that you're wrong. It's just that
it used to be correct, but the world changes a little bit every year.
Yeah. And eventually
you go from like all these horror movies that literally now
boil down to take out your cell phone and call 911.
No, I'm serious. Like pretty much every horror film prior to like 1990 boils down to
take out your cell phone and call 911. Don't split up, don't run away. Just
no split up. Everyone go into the dark woods. It'll be fine.
Right. Your movie sucks. Kurt. No one wants to watch it.
All right. So with that, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to social security podcast.com for the show. Not Su
Podos
says podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.