Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode 140 with myself and this other guy.
What, now,
what's the deal with that intro? Who are you?
I wonder that a lot prove to me that you're Josh
Reser. Uh How about you? Prove to me you're Kurt
Siefried.
I can't,
I, you know, you want to know a funny thing.
I, I can't spell your last name still.
We've been doing this podcast for how many years and I still have to look up how
to spell your last name just to give you an idea of how a difficult identity is.
Well, in fairness, I, I do have to check if your last name has that last s or not.
It does. And I am quite often referred to as Josh Bresser,
which is what
I
called
anyway.
Anyway, so for those of you listening,
we're going to spend some time talking about identity today
and we're also going to kind of use it in the context of good enough security.
And
I'm gonna, I'll, I'll kind of
think of a sliding scale in your mind where there's no security on one end.
There's perfect security on the other end. Perfect security.
It basically just wraps around no security because it's impossible.
And then there's, we'll say a security theater and there's
enough security.
Maybe security is on a sliding scale. But it's like a Mobius strip.
It's a Mobius strip. I like that. Yes.
That's right. That's right. It, it, man, that,
no, I'm not going to go down that red hole,
but I don't think you're wrong anyway anyway.
And, and the kind of the, the thinking being
that the,
the reason this all comes up is Kurt and I
talk a lot about just security in general and obviously there
is the kind of traditional way of looking at security
of it has to be perfect if it's not perfect,
you might as well not do it, which means you just don't do it usually.
And you look at many of the things happening today
and
there's,
there's kind of a level I'd call good enough
and in some places we're getting better at that.
Like, I think password security is getting there where you look at the N
Guidance and I think it's approaching good enough
versus it was just like crazy before.
Right.
Well, I,
I think a better example of good enough
security are mechanical locks on like your house.
Yeah, that's a perfect example actually because
like the lock picking lawyer can get through those in about 10 seconds, 20 seconds.
Anyone who's ever picked a lock before can get
through most of those in less than a minute.
The locks on our houses are terrible.
This is one of the reasons I got a ring doorbell is at
least now I have video to show the police and my insurance adjuster
that, that is fair. That's true.
And, and again though, that's,
I would say, you know, from kind of just the context of security,
that's what we'd call a compensating control.
Right. You know, that you have this other security control that is
insufficient,
but you have a secondary thing
that will
not so much fix the first one, but at least make your life easier in the event.
The first one fails. Right.
Well, it's a classic case of, I've chosen to accept the risk. I'm insured.
You know, I have house insurance
like most people
and, um,
because realistically
I could put on, you know, a $500 door lock on my door.
Um, but then I'd have to like what break over all my windows.
It, exactly. Exactly. It, for what it's worth.
It's kind of one of those situations where just having
a regular door lock is going to be good and,
and it's going to stop the vast majority of just simple opportunistic crime.
And what was surprising to me is I was,
I was binge watching some firefighting videos on forced entry into buildings
and there was a really fascinating set on forced entry through walls.
So, like where you just go through a wall
and the techniques to go through different kinds of
walls and things like how you avoid cutting power lines
because, you know, walls contain power lines,
right. Yep, wiring and stuff.
And, and, but more to the point like with manual tools,
so not even with like air tools or pneumatic tools,
these guys were like bashing their way through walls in under five minutes.
I totally believe that,
you know,
and how many industrial areas and whatnot have places where
you can make a ruckus at two in the morning
and nobody will notice or care physical security cracks because
fundamentally somebody with a sledgehammer can get into the building.
Right. Right.
Yeah. I mean, and you think most houses
in North America
are built with,
with wood and plywood and they don't even use plywood on some of them anymore,
at least in the US.
Yeah. They, it's, it's really shady.
They use like a, it's a, like an insulation board kind of, and it's,
you could easily get through it with a hammer.
00, that synthetic stuff.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And so what happens is if you wanted to get in, I bet, like,
34 whack with a sledgehammer and there's a hole or just bring your
saws all which by the way is my second favorite tool in the world
because it saws everything just like it says.
What's your, what's your first favorite tool in the world my crowbar. Ok.
That's fair
because honestly trying to do something that needs
a crowbar without a crowbar is impossible.
And a crowbar makes it easy. That is true.
And it's just such a great, simple tool, like leverage.
Right. Who knew physics class was? Right. Right. Half life too.
And you can bash your head crab in with it. So. Exactly. Right.
It's good for everybody and they're cheap and they never break,
they never run out of battery.
It just works
right now. Think about it. Right. It is true. It's a great tool.
Can you imagine life before crowbars,
I would bet you crowbars were probably the second
or third tool ever created after a rock,
used to bang things.
Well, crowbar is much better than stick.
But anyway, back to good enough security and identity. So,
yeah, because I, I've had this thought before is like, how,
how do I prove?
I'm me and outside of, I think some very constrained cases, like, for example,
I just flew to the US and back and I have a nexus and to get my nexus, I had to go to
not the TS A, the, the DH S
office here at the airport.
On the Canadian side,
you get a retinal scan and on the US side they take your fingerprints,
all five fingers on one of your hands or both hands. I thought
I, I seem to remember doing both hands. Did they do? They might have done both.
I, I had to get it done when I got my TS a precheck. And
yeah, I think they did do both hands now that you say that I'm remembering
not just that, but I also had to bring photo ID, you know, passport blah, blah, blah.
And I was just thinking like outside of a
situation where like a border agent has access to those
back end systems to actually make sure my fingerprints
and or retinal scan match up with this record.
And you know, I look like me the photo in the thing
outside of that very specific case,
it's very hard for somebody who's like checking my documents or whatever
to actually with 100% guaranteed certainty know that I am me.
I have a hilarious story for you about this.
So a long time ago, my wife worked for a company
that employed
it. Kind of anyone they could get to work in a warehouse, right?
And as part of that,
they would always photocopy the I DS that people brought into them.
Oh Lord.
And one day they photocopy an ID and it has a void written all over it.
They're like, what is this?
And
one of the other managers looked at it and said, oh, that's a real one.
And they said, wait, what?
He's like, yeah, the ones that don't say void, those are all fake I DS.
So they're like what?
And they were basically were these driver's licenses. A government ID, right.
Which is meant to prove citizenship. So you could get paid.
And so it was clear these were essentially illegal.
You know, people had, had fake I DS and were using it to get jobs and
it's like, holy cow. That is crazy because that's one thing in Canada.
It's interesting to me is,
is we have basically really two choices for identification
day to day. It's, you get a driver's license and if you can't get a driver's license,
you can get uh like a, a citizen ID card.
And what's interesting is you can't have both.
If you have a driver's license, you're not allowed to get a citizen ID.
That seems fair though because that way you only have one ID card at a time.
Yeah, I guess I don't really see the point of that
because here's the thing, whenever I renew my license,
I get that wonky piece of you get like a
little strip of paper with your name printed on it
saying that this is now your ID.
It's like literally like, it's, it's a tear off sheet from an 8.5 by 11 sheet form.
And it's only good for like a month and then they
send you a real card and then that's what you use.
And, but here,
so here's where we need to bring this back to the concept of good enough security,
especially in the context of identity
is if you have one of those cards,
the bar is fairly high and in most instances you're ok
and you're, you know what I mean?
It's good enough. The problem I found is that
how do I validate an Alberta driver's license? Let alone, how do I validate?
Um, you're in Wisconsin,
right.
I can't, I can't even spell Wisconsin.
So if you presented me a fake ID,
I, I would have to like double check that the state name is spelled correctly.
And here's the question for you though is what do you need it for?
Right? Why, why do you need my ID?
Well, for example,
I'm now getting involved in a thing where we're essentially
providing some identity management to people so that they can
associate and claim
certifications and activities with their identity with their name.
And so what we found is interesting is
identity is essentially a story,
right? You're born, you live, you die. And throughout that time period,
um things happen to your identity, for example,
maybe you get married and your name changes or maybe
you legally change your name because you don't like it
or
you decide, for example, I don't have my middle name on any of my ID,
right? I just,
I never really kind of understood what middle names were for.
I was like, is it a spare in case I
lose my first name?
I don't really get it either.
It's very strange.
Ok, so I'm not the only one. Yeah.
And then some people have multiple middle names and
some people don't have a middle name and,
yeah, like Elvis Dumbledore.
What? Uh, so in, in Harry Potter, Elvis Dumbledore's name is extremely long.
His middle name, he has like,
six middle names and I don't remember them all at the top of my head.
Which,
which I'm shameful for not remembering as I've read those books like 100 times.
But
uh
yeah,
it's, it's very cool and I know a handful of people with, with multiple middle names.
Yeah.
Well, and there are people with no first name, no, last name,
people who are a single letter, all sorts of shenanigans,
the artist formerly known as Prince.
Yeah. Or the, what was it? The ANC symbol I believe, I don't know.
And there's also things where, for example, my Reddit account or my
email address is that part of my identity? Uh Yes, it is now.
Well, it's part of my identity at that time, but for example,
I used to work for Red Hat and I was KC free at Red hat.com.
Well, what happens when they hire, hire Carl Siefried?
That's a great question and give him KC free at Red hat.com.
So I, I don't know what they do for that.
Well,
let's assume that they recycle email addresses
and that's something to point out is that
I,
we, we always, it's funny that we always make the assumption that like your name.
John Smith is not necessarily unique
and that even your name and date of birth
and place of birth may not be necessarily unique.
You know,
I'm guessing at some point in history,
two John Smiths were both born on the same day in New York City or some other big city.
I would be shocked if they weren't. So actually funny enough, you say this is when,
when, when I worked at Red Hat is
there were two people named Matt Smith,
I would have to talk to on a regular basis and I remember one of them
jokingly told me one day was,
he said this is the first company I've worked at where there were only two Matt Smith.
That's
terrible.
But I get it. I mean,
it's how it is.
I mean,
that's where I think you and I are spoiled because I think
we're the only people with our names that we know of.
No, there's another Kurtz
seafood. There are four curtsy foods in the world and we all work in it.
Oh, that's great. I guess you're the only one I ever run across then.
And we all roughly
look like
the same basically. Are you the same person? Are you just doing seven jobs?
And no one of them is German,
one of them is in America and the other one is also in America.
So I see. I see.
Well, then lucky for me,
I'm pretty sure I'm the only person named Josh Bresser on the planet,
which is convenient.
So that's, that's a great example of, you know,
things that are part of my identity and a very personal part of my identity,
like my email address kit
cre.org
that may not necessarily be me in five or 10 years. Uh
It's possible this is actually something that concerns
me always is I obviously own the Domain breast.net
and my email address has been Joshua breast.net for like freaking 20 years now.
And I keep telling my son I'm like,
pretty soon I'm going to need to make you an administrator on this just in case,
like I kick the bucket one day so you don't lose the domain
because let's face it, it's a good domain
and since it's, it's not widely used,
like my kids have email addresses that are normal, it's not like, you know,
something, something 123795 at gmail.com, which is what all their friends have.
I actually know a
lady. Uh I'm not gonna, well, her last name was Smith.
Her first name is very common and she actually had her first name,
last name at hotmail.com and at gmail.com, she was early enough, right?
That's when, you know, you're an early adopter. That's, that's a unicorn.
Well, and you know, it's, you know,
it's kind of funny about this to actually just kind of to bring it all together is
from the, like the topic of identity is,
you know, we, we own the domain open source security dot IO
and there's a block there, there's not a lot on it.
But anyway, any time I run across an instance to claim the name,
open source security,
I often will just for our nefarious purposes and
I don't want someone else like squatting on it.
And, and I mean, I think identity is kind of part of that, right?
Is if,
if you know there are other people with your name
and you have an opportunity to grab your user name,
do it, you know.
So and that's part of what we realized is that identity is kind of like a,
it's like a bundle of things, right?
It's your name, it's your date of birth, it's your social security number
now to be clear at
the cloud security lines.
We we don't want any of that because that, that's just a GDPR nightmare,
right?
So,
and what we realize too is we don't
actually need your information, right? We just need
your information temporarily to maybe validate it and then provide
you with a validation record that we keep and,
and we do like a zero knowledge proof type of thing with a validation record because
it's ask me what my data security strategy is for personal data in our,
in our Blockchain products.
You don't store any of it.
Exactly. But I know because you've told me,
yeah, and, and even better than that,
we can prove we don't store any of it because
of the way we do hashing and nonsense and stuff.
So we actually mathematically,
even if you try to get your personal information into our Blockchain,
we can mathematically prove that it isn't, you can't,
you know, because we do some transformations on it.
What's interesting then is that
uh and we're working on a wallet client.
So what this wallet client will allow you to do, for example, is to say things like
I am Kurt
at
Siefried.
OK, great.
Or I'm Kurt at siefried. And here's a notarized record of somebody who checked my ID.
Maybe because I it really matters because maybe I want to go work for
some company that really cares deeply about, you know, validating my photo ID.
Conversely, I'm Kurt
at
siefried.org and you know,
we validated that you had control of that email address and we were talking earlier
and you mentioned
the magic word, which is control. The reason this came up actually is my, I,
I have a Mac that I got from work and the disk died.
I had ac file system and bad things were happening. And so I had to reinstall
and as part of that I had to reinstall key base
and I didn't have like any backups of key base or extra devices or anything.
And key base basically flipped out and I had to like recreate my account which is
taking a sledgehammer to it and deleting pretty
much everything that was associated with it.
I, I have the same user name but then I, I had to verify it again.
And it's like I, I was thinking that the verification key base uses is
in a way it's kind of silly because for example, I created Gist on
github. And what does that prove? Does it prove? It's me.
Well, no, it just proves I have access to that github account.
Well, it proves you have control of that github
account.
And see this is what's really interesting is when you think about it,
that could be the account owner or somebody at github could choose to do that,
they totally have control over that.
And that's fair. I mean, in those instances now, of course, I'm sure
K
Ace will tell me, well, you should just do this on multiple places,
use Twitter and github
and, and I don't even know what else they support. And it's,
but at the same time, kind of,
one of the things I keep thinking of is if you have access to someone's email address,
you're,
you're pretty much home free at that point for these services. Yeah.
And see that's, and that's what we realized is for example,
control of an email address.
Yeah, I mean, that means you have control it.
Well, it's kind of like doing domain verification for SSL certificates.
Like if you control all the email addresses, like host master root at whatever,
or you control the DNS for that domain or you are
able to do whatever you want on the web server.
I, I can't really
disprove it because
you have, you have such a deep level of access as a potential attacker that I just,
what can I reasonably do to actually
make you do something that would prove you're not an attacker
and that you are legitimately the owner of that domain.
And so, and that goes to the good enough piece of, you know,
realistically if you control
cre.org, you control courtesy
free.org.
Right. You could be sending and receiving emails me and I wouldn't know.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And this is where I think I,
I kind of chuckle sometimes because people
will complain about let's encrypt and say,
oh, you know,
anyone can get TLS certificates and now they're not
secure and it's like they weren't secure before.
I mean,
if an attacker has that level of access into your infrastructure you've lost.
Right. They, they could have already gotten certificates as you.
It was just honestly, it was slightly more work,
but now your life is 100 times easier too. Well, it cost a bit of money,
which was really annoying
and funny story.
It looks like I won't be able to recover my key base dot IO because I
used a GP G key a long time ago that I think I got rid of,
uh, you don't need to do you still can you log in,
you can just like si can log in but it says, OK, a situation is special.
Oh, how exciting.
Oh, well,
yeah,
you chose to manage your P GP private keys yourself. Nice.
And you don't have any key bases devices yet.
I see to prove your first install is really yours.
You must use a computer one that has GP G installed
and two has access to your private key key base.
We'll ask GP G to sign its first device key.
If you lost your GP G private key or would rather not use that key,
you can reset your account, however, you will need to
your social identities again.
Oh, so I could just reset my account and just be done with it. Oh, that's easy.
Oh, I'm doing that. Oh, right. Yeah.
Yeah. And that's what I had to do too is I had to reset my account
and I don't, I don't think I tied my GP G key to key base because I don't care.
And GP G sucks. And I don't want anyone to ever send me anything with GP G.
So that's, that's another story though.
But someday I could, we could do a whole episode on how I used to protect my GP G key.
It's still pretty bonkers but it's, it's more sane than it used to be these days.
But
anyway, anyway,
so good enough security and, and this is the thing I keep thinking about,
especially in the context of identity and passwords and what key base is doing
and
where do we draw our lines?
I mean, like, one of my favorite examples is when I log into one of my banks,
they have this thing that I log in and it shows a picture
and says, I have like, I forget what it even says,
but it's a stupid picture and it's some little phrase I made up and they're like,
you know, click here to verify it's you.
And I'm like, oh my goodness, what does this even accomplish?
This is the dumbest thing in the world.
Well,
basically it allows them on the one hand to say
they have multi factor authentication and notice I said,
multi factor authentication and not.
Yes. Stupid is one of the factors, right?
Yeah. Well, it's, it's multi
or it's, it's basically, it's two factor authentication,
but they're identical factors.
They're both still a password basically.
And the other thing is that in theory it's supposed to prevent,
there were some certain malwares that this
helps prevent from hijacking your connection.
But I'm guessing that those guys have moved on
and here's part of the problem,
you can do all the identity
management security you want.
It doesn't matter if a bank will be like, oh, you say you're Josh B
Sure, here's a home loan. See, that's part of the problem is that there's,
it goes back to my story about you know the whole, how do I prove?
I me and I can really only prove, I mean to a very small set of people
provably who have access to these like retinal database scans and stuff
because I can't like you could give me your driver's license,
your passport, your sin.
Uh What is it in the US? Si social insurance number. Social security number.
No social security number. SSN. Sorry SSN is America?
You could give me all of that. Your fingerprints pictures of your retina
and what would I do with it? How would I validate that? That's you.
But, but why do you even really need it either? I mean, right. Let's face it.
The purpose of providing identification in most instances is really about
having some minimal level of risk. You're taking out a home loan.
When you do that, they're going to ask for a variety of I DS which are,
you can totally copy them.
But at the same time, banks have insurance to protect against fraud.
And if it happens to me, I have the ability to submit claims against
my credit score saying this isn't me and we need to take it off.
So there there's kind of avenues and this is one of those places,
let's say the bank needed my retinal scan to like really prove.
It's me.
The cost of verifying me is now 10 times more expensive for them.
And I'm betting that it would have a minimal difference in the amount of fraud.
They see there's actually a couple of use
cases where that actually works really well.
So,
back to the certification thing,
certifications are worth money. Right.
Like, there are certain certifications where you get them and,
and you can easily earn 1020 30 grand more a year.
Sure. Sure. From when you didn't.
So
how do you get a certification if you're not able to get a certification?
Well, you can pay a test taker,
right?
You can pay a professional test taker to get some fake ID and show
up as you and take the test and get it in your name.
So what's happened is some of the higher end certifications now take a biometric
fingerprint or retinal scan of the people taking the test.
And it's the similar reason as a lot of the
of the DM of the driver's license place is doing this
and it's to ensure one per customer,
right? It's not about identity and it's not about
who are you? It's about ensuring
this guy with this set of eyeballs
only took the test once,
right?
That you can't be a professional test taker or for example,
with driver's licenses when they now that they take, you know, the face,
the the fingerprint, whatever
people are unable.
Like they, they did this in Australia where they started taking,
I think it was fingerprints and also
the uh the doing the the face,
the facial recognition stuff and having humans review it,
you know, and they were finding people with seven or eight passports,
all different names and they're like, yeah, that's, that's kind of a problem,
right.
So that's,
that's one case actually where this is really interesting is where
we now we have this sort of Venn diagram of,
we have identity
and we have an overlapping circle that's, it's identity related.
But
in some ways,
we care less about who you are and we care more about properties like saying,
you can only take this test once and if you try to take it again,
we'll know that you already took it and failed or passed.
Sure. Sure. You know,
I mean
that,
so part of me says that makes perfect sense.
And part of me wonders if that's technically necessary. Is it that big of a problem?
Yes.
Yeah. For some of these certifications there, there has been
some of these certifications are worth a lot of money and, and I would point out,
for example, the Berlin Airport
is a couple billion dollars behind and
years behind schedule because the quote unquote
engineer that designed the fire control system
uh turns out he's not an engineer.
Yeah, I heard about that,
which makes me sad because the current airport in
Berlin is the worst airport in the world.
Like they need a new one. So bad dude. They built it in like 1920
but
even worse than that, just Google, Google C TV, building collapse in New Zealand,
the last earthquake they had the C TV building, the, the
television building collapsed and it shouldn't have
turns out the engineer that designed, it
wasn't an engineer.
And what he had done is actually stolen the identity of a retired British engineer
so that he could practice as an engineer and make a lot of money. Interesting.
There's some real world examples where, you know,
we're talking about costs in the tens of hundreds
of millions of dollars and in some case, potentially over a billion euros
between delays and extra costs for the Berlin Airport.
So some of these certifications, like, are you an engineer or not really do matter?
Oh, totally. Yep. Yep.
And what we found was interesting is number one,
it's really hard for me to prove my certification.
And number two, it's basically almost impossible for anybody to validate it
because that's, that's the dirty secret.
How, you know, you claim to have a university degree. Correct?
Yes.
How do I validate that?
Some random phone number, register's office and ask
you can. Yes, I've, I have,
I'm trying to remember. I don't know if I've ever sent my,
my diploma into anybody. I know I have transcripts
that, why have I ever,
I needed those for something too because I have two copies of them in my files
and I don't know why I needed two,
but I know I needed two
and
huh. That's, it's interesting, you say that.
So,
and what's interesting is there's,
there's those online universities that will provide you with a fake degree and
they have a phone number that they will answer and be like.
Yeah. No, Josh totally has a degree in, uh, you know, nuclear physics.
Well,
I remember when I was in college there was one of the guys I went to school with had a,
and, like, doctored in,
in something that he sent $10 into an online program and he made us call him doctor,
which was really funny.
But it's,
yeah, I mean, that, that's a really good question.
Actually I'm trying to think and yeah, there's, there's no really good way.
And in fact,
I know I've heard of instances where like politicians
and celebrities and other people caught where they say,
oh, I graduated from the University of blah, blah, blah.
And the university says, no, you didn't.
You went here for two years, do we booted you out? And now, you know,
so that's, that's what we found to be a really interesting problem. Is, is not only
can you, is it very difficult for you to prove who or what you are and what you have?
But even if you have a good system to prove it, it's,
it's commonly very hard for people to validate it.
You know, a great example is we've tried very hard with the CCS KV,
the certificate of cloud security knowledge where you take your exam,
you get a nice PDF and on that PDF, it has your email address and a validation number.
You can go to the website,
you plug in like Courtesy for.org and you plug
in my validation number and it says yes,
courtesy.org got, you know, the CCS K
A earned it back in.
It was like 2012 or something.
And that's great except
people's email address changes.
Yes,
that is true. People move to different countries.
Uh, companies, their name changes because they get married, they get divorced.
You know, I remember that was one of the biggest things.
Uh not to bring up redhead again.
But remember Red Hat,
they couldn't change your login name and that drove people crazy who, like,
spent a lot of money in the divorce and then had to type in that
name they didn't care for anymore every morning.
Yeah. Right.
Or I know this is a problem with, like, transgender folks where obviously they,
they want to abandon their, their old name and in an instance like this, they can't.
And in fact, I know this was actually, I don't remember, I,
I read an article about this where there,
there was a company that actually it was not trivial
for them to be able to do this for people.
But obviously it was really important for them. So they did.
And well, even simpler example, I, I had a friend who uh he's from China
and his daughter, he introduced me to her as, like, Jennifer or whatever,
uh, one day and then, like, you know, I didn't see her for like, a year or two
and then he shows up with this
other daughter whose name is Cynthia.
And I'm like, oh, I thought you only had one daughter. He's like, yeah.
No, I only have one daughter.
I'm like, but wait, Jennifer, Cynthia, he's like, oh, she's trying out a new name
because she had a traditional Chinese name,
which was, you know, like, yeah, that's just not going to work so well. So she was
trying on different names.
I thought, you know what, why not? Like what you shouldn't?
People are allowed to pick nicknames. Well, why not?
I mean, legally under documentation issues, whatever or if you're unlucky,
you don't get to pick your nickname.
We just did a show be
o'rourke
and I'm like, that sounds like a really funky first name like,
you know, and I Google it and it's Robert Francis o'rourke, you know, like, yeah,
so actually I talked to my wife about this.
She uh
apparently if you're named Robert in
most will say uh Latin American countries,
it would not be uncommon for Bedo to be your like
nickname the shortening because like obviously what you call me,
Josh, but my real name is Joshua
and like, but you told me to call you
and I don't care for Joshua.
The only time I hear that is when I'm in trouble.
So if I hear Joshua, I'm like, uh, oh, I look around to see what I've done.
What happens when you hear.
Yeah, when you hear your full, like, you know,
sri
time to run,
like, don't even look, just go.
Yeah. So, ok, I, I did. Yeah, I guess Roberto be,
yeah, I guess, I mean, who's to say right? It's kind of like
you call people named Richard Dick or people named John are often called Jack.
So I used to, I worked for a guy called Richard and I did not,
that dick was the common nickname for Richard. And so people
essentially thought I was
a
moron or something because they would ask me where's Richard?
And he would like, literally be in the next room and they'd ask you where's dick?
Yeah, sorry, where's dick? And I'd be like, I don't know who dick is.
I don't know where dick is
and they'd be like, but, you know, like,
yeah, so that wasn't covered in school.
I feel like they should have covered these calls.
Like,
like, ok, what's the deal with William? And Bill?
Who knows?
It probably has some 300 year old reasoning behind it that
nobody understands and that's how most of these names work,
right?
It's, it's from some like English King in,
in 1024 decided that he wanted to be called this and now everybody does it,
it's like, you know, what I always think of is, you know,
when you wear a suit coat and you have your buttons like you always,
but in the top button,
you sometimes but in the middle button and you never button the bottom button.
Do you know why you never button the bottom button?
Because King Henry was too fat to button it.
And so that became the style like for real, like what the WTF but that's,
that's the world we live in.
Yeah. So, and that's something. So that's one of the reasons when
in, in architecting all of the identity stuff, I've been working on.
I want to let people claim what they want.
Yeah, I, I like that.
It's, it's not up to me to decide that you're Bill or William or whatever
and more to the point depending on the jurisdiction or the culture you come from.
I have no idea what the rules are
and I don't want to. And, but more to the point, I don't want to know what the rules are.
And so we leave it up to the user,
you claim what you want,
you deal with the people you deal with, you provide them the proof that they require.
Yeah.
And I think this is where, I mean, just kind of to bring it all home now is
this is where you go from.
Essentially perfect security, which is impossible to what's good enough.
And I'm sure if what you're doing today
we talked about that, say 10 or 15 years ago,
people would say that's idiotic.
It's not perfect. Right. When you're dealing with identity, it's got to be perfect.
One more important aspect, which is
we need to let users dial up and down their security because some
users will want more security and some users will actually want less security,
more convenience.
And that's totally fair. It's kind of the way I always look at this is
if you work for, say the intelligence community,
the kind of opsec you need on your computers is much
different than the opsec my parents need on their computers,
right?
Because you have very different adversaries coming after you. And I think
that's one of the things where good enough is also a big deal is there,
there's a lot of people that need just barely good enough
and there's a lot of people that need really good,
good enough, right?
And we historically just put everyone in the same bucket and it doesn't work.
I mean, I think that's part of our just complete failure in
a perfect example of this. The Windows 10 gaming PC I got for my kids
uh to log in, you log in.
Well, it wants you ideally to log in with like your Windows live account, right?
Which I've set them with really long passwords
because they never use the manager.
So, and I also looked, you can set a pin number with letters.
So you can basically set a classic password and I'm like, still kind of annoying.
Did some research Windows? Hello, you log in with your face.
So I'm like, ok, I bought the little webcam for it and now, but here's the cool thing,
you basically sit down in front of the computer
and it, the,
the, it unlocks the desktop to your desktop. It's awesome.
And I'm pretty sure I could print out a good quality picture and fool it.
But you know what this is for my kids play Minecraft
and now they don't have to remember a password.
They don't even have to type anything like this is,
this is great. Exactly. That's exactly right.
I mean, when you put it in context it's, it's good enough even more.
We get the convenience of you sit down and you get your desktop. I love it.
It just works. That's really cool. I should, I should look into that for my kids.
They,
they have a windows gaming PC downstairs and
it's like 80 bucks for the cheapest webcam.
It's the, that's the one where I had to download that dot R from that dodgy IP address.
Oh,
yeah, I saw that on Twitter. That's awesome.
Yeah,
it was, but it was, it was just the real tech driver.
So they just took a copy of the real tech driver and put it on some random
laptop. It was a really slow download. It's
awesome.
I love it
anyway.
But it works
all right. No, I love it.
It's good.
It's good enough that, that should be like the new motto of security.
It's good enough.
Which sounds like I've given, we've ever done
better.
Good enough is, well, it sounds like a low bar in the security world.
It's a pretty freaking high bar right now. Well,
you know, I look at how I've been ped and the guy has how many records now?
It's, it's billions. Billions. It's like mcdonald's hamburgers, right?
Billions and billions.
We just,
yeah, we took the, we took the numbers down.
Indeed. All right, I'm calling this one. So thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com,
hit up the show notes so you can use the
Pound Os S Podcast hashtag to hit us up on Twitter
and yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.