Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
-- and my partner in shenanigans, Josh Pressers. That's
-- right. DW F is back baby.
-- The
-- distributed weakness filing project.
We should probably start at the beginning because I'm sure
there's lots of people who don't know what this means.
But Kurt and I are super excited and this is like
the first real time we're talking about this in public,
but it's something we've been working on for a really long time.
So Kurt,
why don't you give us the history lesson and
then we'll talk about what we're doing today.
So the DW started quite some time ago.
I've basically been involved with CV for going on 20 years now, you know,
things like notifying them of duplicates or asking for clarification
on CVS ever since it was handcrafted and still is.
And what I started working at Red Hat, uh obviously, Red Hat is big into CV S.
Uh They do pretty much exclusively open source
and they very aggressively have a policy of,
is it a security vulnerability if yes assigned CV
or make sure it has a CV, assigned,
which I think is great because
it just makes tracking these things a whole bunch easier
and,
and aggressive to the point where there was about
two or three cases a year where I'd assign
a CV right away and then it would turn out actually not to be a security flaw.
But anyways,
one of the issues was the
Red Hat
ships,
mostly other people's software by volume, right?
Because they ship open source, right?
They, the Linux kernel, they, they contribute very heavily to the LINX kernel.
But obviously,
there's far more other people doing the Linux kernel than just red hat.
Same thing for, you know, all the user space Apache blah, blah blah.
Now, as an aside on that point,
Red hat did this
a long time ago. Everyone does this today.
Oh Yeah, everybody ships all the open source now like your dependency chain,
set that out there for everyone to think
very few people actually care about CV.
So
we'll
get to
that.
So
anyway, so it was part of my job at Red Hat was getting all these CV S
and to put it bluntly, the CV system was built in a different time
and it kind of has a culture and technology from 1999.
And so, well, I, I basically kind of tried to
push them along a little bit and that didn't work.
So I basically help metaphorical gun to their head and started the DW project,
which is CV,
one CV,
plus one. So if you take the letter C, what,
-- that's the letter after CD, what's the letter after V
-- VW
E? Right.
There you go. So it's CV
edw
F so I basically started assigning DW
IDS
and,
and CVS because, well,
we needed these CV identifiers like we had to have these numbers, right?
We were, we were drowning in vulnerabilities with no CV. And we still are. Yeah.
Well,
absolutely. I did two things that I'm very proud of. Number one was, I got a
JSON data format and number two, I got them into github.
Now see,
the way CVE traditionally works and still does is
miter has this internal database at their end.
That is the true source of truth.
-- I
-- have a suspicion calling it a database is a,
-- it's
-- a text file or at least it used to be a text file.
It's probably a database.
-- Now,
-- I don't know, I would not be surprised if it's, I don't
even know
and I was on the board and I don't even know they
never really told us or made it clear what it was.
And so my
hope was number one to get a better data format
because the way CV data was published was either,
you know, a CS V file, an XML file or
like a text file
or, you know, web pages, right? So processing that with a computer was kind of a pain.
And
JSON, I think strikes that really perfect middle ground of very human readable,
like super human readable and machine pars
very easily and more to the point. Most of the
JSON parcels are not full of security flaws like the X
parcel
that is 100% correct. You know,
because that was one of my other questions people kept asking me, why don't use XML?
And I'm like, OK, go go search the CV database for XML versus
JSON.
-- Not
-- just that look, I've done
an enormous amount of XML parsing.
I mean,
I wrote an XML parser in C a long time
ago when I worked at a company called Progeny Linux Systems
-- and parsing XML is a terrible, terrible task.
-- It's true and complete.
-- It's self modifying. It can
-- be, it's, it's a nightmare. Jason is loving
-- because of its
-- simplicity. If it's on the back of a business. That's right.
-- That's right. OK.
-- So anyway, so and then my hope to get them into github
was also to open this up a bit and get it a bit more of the public involved
and get a bit more transparency, right?
Because I'm a really big believer in transparency
because part of the challenge with fixing something is to fix something,
you have to understand how it currently works, correct.
I mean, you can sort of blindly try fixing it. But
uh
yeah, good luck on the first count of the Jason
basically
succeeded and then it failed because essentially the format got modified a bit
into a way that basically they were trying to turn it into XML.
The current format is hideous, would be my polite description of it,
-- but
-- it's better than nothing.
I will agree with that. Yes.
And it's certainly better than just being pure XML. Yes.
And as far as getting them into github,
that was a complete failure in that when you contribute something to the CV list
repo in github,
that CV list
repo is the actual repo of the CV data. You basically push data
it
and then Miter takes that data, shoves it into their magic back end
and then spits it out of their back end, back into github
-- and actually commits it.
-- Right. It's a strange two way process.
Well, it's essentially, they're not using
github as a G
repo, they're using github
as a text publishing platform.
-- Right. Right.
-- The other challenge too is, is I failed to change
the culture of CV, right. That stuff is still handcrafted.
They still overly rely on the human readable descriptions to the point
where it's now comical a bit because some of those descriptions,
I don't know if they got mangled or dropped
or something like a computer dropped some text,
but you've seen some of them, right?
-- Yeah,
-- I post them on Twitter all the time. There's some absolutely hilarious ones.
They don't have version numbers, they're just like
this package has a vulnerability and is affected
like that is literally word for word,
some of the descriptions.
Right. Right.
Or I love, there was, there was one I just posted the other day that was like,
it was,
it was an XML problem and it was like a xxe
flaw and it's like the worst possible type of flaw.
It's like what? That's ridiculous.
So the problem with CV is that it's still overly relies
on humans to generate the data and to consume the data.
And that, that is not a long term winning strategy.
-- And
-- now I want to, before we, before we start getting into some of the problems,
I want to also clarify.
So Kurtz started DW F and Miter even blessed DW
F.
But it was almost exclusively a one person
operation where you'd go to a website called Iwant
tove.org and would fill out a form and it would end up in a spreadsheet.
And then Kurt did
the work of the people by taking the spreadsheet and turning it into DWD.
There's an embarrassing thing there.
I actually wrote a little 30 or 40 line Python script
that turned those once the CV entry was basically vetted,
I ran it through this Python script that literally constructed sentences.
It was straight up machine written text, that was very simple
-- and you know what? It worked great because it had all the facts. Right.
-- Exactly.
And, but anyway,
so you did all this, you did all this work and obviously no one was supporting you mier
wasn't supporting you, the community wasn't supporting you.
It's like the time zone thing, right?
Everybody uses it but nobody really thinks about it.
And like the DW was an official CV numbering authority.
-- So
-- this is one of the challenges I
think though is because you were official authority.
You also had to conform
-- to miters, artisanal
-- rule. Yeah.
The CN A guidelines which are actually rules but they're called the guidelines,
right?
And they're, they're like many things in life. They have good intentions but
they're,
they're from a different time. Yes, I agree. That's,
and I think that's the biggest problem with CV is that it's the world
we live in now is nowhere near the world we had 10 years ago,
let alone 20 years ago, like just the volume of vulnerabilities, right?
Even though the majority of vulnerabilities are not
really all that actively exploited in use.
I mean,
the numbers I've seen are like two or
3% of all the known vulnerabilities actually get
used.
And I'm assuming it's actually less than that because that
was two or 3% of cds were getting abused.
I assume it's actually like, I know people in the pest
community and they're constantly finding stuff right
now before we continue down this path.
-- Why don't we explain like, what are we doing? Why are we talking about DW F
-- today?
I looked at was I being very effective or useful on the CV board?
As far as helping CV, in the community.
And the answer was no.
So I resigned on January 8th of 2021 because where I had
been effective in moving CV Fords was as an outsider as essentially
a well intentioned person who kind of did things.
-- That's it, like went and did things
-- and that's OK.
That's the most important part of this whole conversation.
I want to focus on that for just a second and explain it.
I have a blog post,
I've talked about at length on this
podcast which is kind of committees versus communities
writer. And CV E are a committee.
Committees don't get things done.
Committees write white papers and waste time and consume money,
communities get things done.
CV E is a committee. DWF is a community.
Yeah, like I'm,
I'm thinking of uh there's a couple of projects I was involved in with them,
but
-- as far as I can tell, I've never moved forwards.
-- Committee.
It's all committee stuff. It never will. Committees don't get work done.
And what's interesting is the board kept getting
-- larger and of course
-- it did committees.
-- That's what committees do.
-- I'm not really clear on why, but
committees
because it's a committee.
Well, in fairness, part of it was getting some more viewpoints from the outside,
like different stakeholder views, which is important
because that's one thing CV has been infamously terrible at is actually
engaging with the community and even knowing what the community is,
I agree.
But getting four more people on the board isn't going to do that.
So, basically what we're doing
is,
uh, well, simply put, go to, I want to cv.org, fill it out
and you get your CV,
end of story because here's the secret about a CV. You know, what makes VA CV?
And everybody's like, uh, uh, because miter signs it, I'm like, well, no,
miter doesn't actually assign most of these.
That's the CV numbering authorities. They're like, oh
it's in the database.
So I'm like, well, it's, it's nice to have it in the database, but
most CV ES get published publicly and then end up in the database. So that's not it.
And some things, you know, LA by weeks or months in some cases,
mostly that's, it's gotten better. But
what makes VA CV?
And the simple and short answer is
because somebody you trust says it is, that's it.
And so like the traditional version of that is, you know, Microsoft says this is CV.
Foo. Well, that makes it CV foo,
you know, a red hat. We actually had the case of, I think it was uh what was it like?
I forget which company it was.
But they, they literally typo a CV E number and stole one of ours
from our pool, right? Accidentally.
And I was like,
you know, and, and so Miter contacts me and they're like,
why are you assigning the CV?
For this, you know, not your product. And I'm like, what are you even talking about?
And they're like, oh, let's go ask them
and they straight up, made a typo
and we hadn't used the number. So it's like, ok, cool done.
And that's the thing. So it basically is a CV. Is a CV. Somebody you trust
says it's a CV.
-- And you believe that, but
-- there's an even more important part of this story.
DWF isn't a committee. DWF is a community.
Yeah, it's a github
-- repo that everybody can go poke up.
-- There's, there's kind of two parts to this.
There's the DWF list, github
repo, which is where the actual CV E Jason will live.
And then we also have the tooling we're using to drive all this and
the intent is like our goal is no humans and we're not there yet.
Obviously, we have work to do come help, please. We love your help. But
this is the biggest part of this is that the
tooling is public and how it all works is public.
There's no secrets here and anyone can suggest whatever they want.
Well, see,
and that was a big reason I wanted to move them into github was public issues.
Poll requests.
Yeah.
And if you go look at the CV, if you go to github.com/cv project,
which is the quote unquote official miter
CV organization
slash CV list, you can't even file issues against
it. For example, if you want to, if, if you find a problem with the CV,
you have to go to their web form and fill it out and,
and then it just disappears into a black hole.
No, that's it.
And again,
I was on the board and I didn't even know what the
status of this stuff was or even more to the point.
I, I wasn't even entirely sure how, like, what was the process that was handling it?
And again, back to transparency and openness,
it's really hard to get involved in something
when that something is a building with locked
doors and security guards who essentially tell you
write it down on a piece of paper and
I'll see that something is done with it
probably.
But I agree.
And I think when you're dealing with these, I guess,
identifiers that need to be in the public space,
it is, this should be a public project,
this should be a community driving this effort.
This shouldn't be
some weird committee that no one understands.
Well, again, it's historical, right? The Department of Homeland Security Paid
-- Meter to do this and Miter does a lot of good work.
-- Oh, absolutely. Meter
is a great organization.
-- 100% problem
-- is this was built 20 years ago and it hasn't significantly changed.
And again, the world has changed so fundamentally in the last 20 years, like,
like literally the first
way that CV S were done is they were initially assigned as a candidate number
and then the entire board
would vote on each candidate whether or not to make it a proper CV E.
Now, that will absolutely work if you have about 10 to 20 vulnerabilities a year.
Right.
-- Well, now we have about 10 to 20 vulnerabilities an hour.
-- Do we?
-- Actually, I mean, so this is, this is part of the story, is
-- my,
my back of the envelope calculations for English written software are
1 to 10 million cvs a year for stuff that matters.
Oh You mean you mean that should be because right now there's 16,000 divided by,
let's say 365 is,
-- yeah,
-- it's, it's a comically low number 40
three C vs a day.
Yeah, but still too much for people to vote on. Oh, no.
Right. And this comes back to that whole trust thing. Why is VA CV?
Well, part of what the board did is said, look, you know,
if the vendor says there's a CV in their product,
we're going to trust them because
who else knows this better?
So what happens when a vendor decides it's not a security issue? But
I was gonna say that's the flip side of this is conversely
if a vendor says it's not a CV in their product,
unless you can really somehow prove.
Uh and there is an appeals process that ultimately ends up with MI
R as the sort of Supreme Court of CV, where you can argue for and against a CV.
But ultimately, unless you can really prove it's a CV, like,
I guess you would have exploit code or something.
The, the vendor basically gets to say no.
And that's a big problem now is because the majority of,
of CV numbering authorities that are vendors
realized by being AC N A, they get to control the message.
Yeah. Yeah, 100%
they get to control the supply of CV. S. For example, the vast majority of them
no longer assign a CV for internally found issues, they just fix them.
Microsoft has done that forever and I don't, I don't, I don't agree with it at all.
Microsoft oracle. All
them HP has gone so far as to say,
essentially this product contains a forced like auto updater.
So there's nothing actionable from a CV perspective.
So there's never going to be a CV for this product.
-- Again,
-- it's worth pointing out that D
WF won't fix that problem because if,
if only HP knows about it and they don't want to sign a CV,
like there's just no way for anyone to even know,
but there is a lot of stuff that comes out in public later after the fact and it is sure
useful to give that stuff.
CVS because here's the thing that really makes me
angry is one of the cornerstones of CV is
that we want to provide an actionable data feed
so that you can do something about your vulnerabilities.
Yeah, that's the big one for me.
People keep forgetting that one of the things you can do
is to stop using it and replace it full stop.
Like I'm going to call out Google here.
I'm a Google based kind of guy, both personally and professionally.
I no longer fully trust Google, to be honest, not to kill off Google works suite.
I know
like I, I literally look at it and I'm like,
they probably won't.
-- But
-- Google's core competencies are selling ads and killing products.
-- Like
-- that's exactly.
And so I literally am at the point where I,
I'm making plans to transition to office 365.
Like, and I am a diehard Linux sell it. And it's like anyways,
it's just, it's,
the world has changed in 20 years so fundamentally and it continues to change.
And that's the other big problem is it's I, I tried to drag CV forwards,
kicking and screaming, made a bit of progress.
But there's been like,
if you look at the CV list repo and the workflow and everything,
it hasn't changed since day one.
And
-- you know, here's the way I like to describe
-- this.
It's, it's essentially, it's a legacy system at this point.
It's completely legacy. I mean, imagine you're in a boat
and you're paddling,
let's say one kilometer an hour
upstream.
But if the river is flowing three kilometers per hour downstream,
you're not going forwards.
Yeah, basically we're doing DWF, we're giving out CV identifiers
and most importantly, we're actually doing it
in the open. You can file issues against us, you can,
-- and you will get a response from us. You can
-- come, help, come, help, don't file issues
and, and chances are
Josh and I will argue with each other.
-- We, we argue with each other nonstop and we'll
-- do it in public quite
happily.
It's going to be marvelous.
-- I'll
-- be blunt, me and Josh, we're not as bad as the legacy CV system,
but we do have our biases coming from, people come from, you know, the vendor side.
And so that's another big aspect of this is we want other men
of the community involved so that we don't end up
with cameras that don't see anybody who's not pearly white.
-- Right.
-- Right. There's, there's so much room to grow here.
Like one of my,
one of my favorite examples and you and I have
talked about this in public more than once is Mia
refuses to assign CVE
I
to documentation where let's say you have example code in
a in a in docs and the example code,
not even example official do this to make the product work code, right?
Or configuration, right?
Like copy and paste this and then it'll connect to our database
and do queries except it's got a SQL injection bug in it,
right?
Like what the heck? That's ridiculous. I mean that totally needs
some sort of identifier so people can recognize, don't do this, you know.
Well, and again, back to the action, ability point part of this too.
Part of that action is educating people 100%. Yes. Right.
Not just, and I don't mean just kind of a loosey goosey like, oh,
we'll teach everybody about SQL injections.
But for example, this specific book has a flaw but, and here's the workaround,
-- that's part
-- of it.
-- Absolutely
-- right. It's raising that awareness of these issues.
There's another super important point related to this that I want to talk about.
And I will put
a graph
in the show notes.
If you graph the number of CVE I that have
been released there is we have clearly hit a plateau.
And my suspicion is this is just as many
as meter can do using their artisanal legacy internals.
It's actually worse than that because the plateau also reflects
the CV numbering authorities and there's essentially on boarding CV,
numbering authorities is horrendously slow and complicated to the
point of there's barely 200 of them right now.
So I actually just got an email earlier today at the time of recording.
-- I think it's 156.
-- Oh jeez. OK. I thought it had gone higher, but apparently not.
And then
the other challenge is again,
many of these CV numbering authorities are incentivized against assigning CVS
unless it's like a truly a public issue which again,
we can't really fix that.
Well, we can fix that because we are fixing it. It's called DWF.
And we're giving the power to the community.
We can't fix the incentive structure for these companies.
Well, we don't have to.
-- Well, exactly, that's the beauty of
-- this. We can make it better.
And part of my hope is to normalize cvs because people
still have this thing where CVS are bad and it's like,
no, these are good.
these are public health warnings.
These are,
but they're mature enough to have slapped a yellow warning label that saying, look,
if you open this up and stick your hand
in the electricity in here will kill you slowly,
it will hurt.
-- Right?
-- And it's, it's a sort of situation. Zero, CVS and 1000
CV
are the same problem.
And here's the thing, if we actually had good CV data,
we could track the velocity of them.
I want the vendor that has a million cvs that are all fixed in 12 hours.
That's true too.
And that's not, I mean, that's something that's difficult to track as well.
-- No,
-- it's
not because if it's in a public repo and they update it.
-- Well, no,
-- it is today we're fixing it. Yeah,
exactly.
And so
like,
I know what the numbers were sort of internally
at Red Hat for fixing CVS and getting them
door.
They were actually pretty good.
Red Hat does a great job and Red Hat publishes all of this data.
They put out like a CV report every year. It's awesome.
The Bugzilla entries go public and you can look at, ok, this
bil entry was created on, you know,
day one and by day three people were like running
around screaming with their pants on fire and then,
you know, day seven or eight or 12 or whatever, you know, that the packages,
the Red Hat security advisory went out.
-- Yeah.
-- Which is, which is amazing.
And that's, this is the beauty
when you have to work in public.
When you know you're working in public, it changes the way you work and it makes you,
I think, pay more attention to certain details.
You can just sweep under the rug when it's
-- all hidden behind a curtain and
-- even better.
One of my hopes is there's a lot of security flaws that just aren't that
important and if they take six months or a year for the developer to fix.
-- Yeah. Fine. Who
-- cares? I agree. And you know, what else is driving me nuts right now?
Is there's like sneak is one of the, I think worst offenders for this sneak will find
bunch of issues. Some are bad. Some aren't like if they vary in quality greatly, but
they don't get cve ids, they just have these sneak ids.
And then I've got, so I basically, I get a report from Sneak.
That's like, oh, your program is vulnerable to these dependencies.
And I'm like, oh, crap. Like, what does this even mean?
And then you've got to go track them down and then
look at their website and you know what I mean?
It's just so much more convenient when there's one
source of stuff I have to go look at,
it's so nice
and I think that's a second problem that might
hopefully get solved when I worked for eyesight.
And I defense,
I remember we had a couple of customers that said your data is wrong and we're like,
huh, what do you mean wrong?
And they're like, it doesn't all have CVS and we're like, yeah, no, it doesn't
because you know, we cover 800 vendors and they're back in the day, there's like 60
CNAs. So
do the math. One number is bigger than the other.
And these customers literally wanted every single vulnerability to have a CV.
For the simple reason that the same reason every database admin in the US
expects everybody to have a social insurance
number because I need that primary key.
-- Yeah. Yeah, sorry social security number in the US,
-- right?
And,
and
it it makes it easier. Now here's another example that that really drove me nuts.
So sneak released a they
they released a CV E and the description was wrong. They had the version range wrong.
So obviously some customer of mine was like, oh,
you're vulnerable to this horrible issue.
And I'm like, no, I'm not because we're fixed like,
oh but the description says this and I'm like the description is wrong.
And so I remember I sent a note to Miter and it was like, hey,
this description is wrong.
It should be this.
And they replied to me with, oh sneak owns that you have to go talk to them.
And I was like, no effing way.
Like I've already done more work than I should have to hear.
Like screw all of you people.
-- And the reality is now, I could just submit a pull request and it'll be fixed,
-- but no,
even better.
Now. There's a place to have that conversation that too. Yes. Right.
And see, that's the biggest thing that really frustrates about the CV,
current ecosystem that this legacy ecosystem is that where
do I talk to these people about this?
Oh, go fill out the CV form? OK. And then what?
Well, I don't know, man, like, and I'm on the board and I can't even tell you,
I'm sorry.
And that's, that's a really poor answer.
So, like I said, I quit because it was just clearly not working out. Right.
And that's the biggest thing is you have to give like, where do you go
to complain or talk about or improve or to help with this nowhere. And
that place has to be in public and archived. It's a community.
So yeah, there will be good conversations that
like there's been some really good
email threads on the CV. Board list that are sort of archived but
nobody else can interact with them.
You can maybe read the archives, but that's it.
And then if you have a great idea,
I guess you could have emailed one of the
board members directly and asked them to post it.
Right. Which is ridiculous.
This is artisanal legacy handcrafted process from, you know, 20 some years ago.
And that doesn't scale and back then it made sense. Back then.
It absolutely made sense. But again, we're here.
It's 2021 guys and girls and everybody else
people. Yes, it has to change because we're
and vulnerabilities and open source one, you know,
your supply chain whether you like it or not now is at least a couple 100 things,
if not a couple 1000 things.
And,
and the thing that's driving me nuts is now there's
all these scanners and they all have their own freaking ids
and you know what, you know what really just burns me is when I find like, OK,
so this company has this ID and it has a CV and it has a github
ID. You know what I mean? Like I have, I have
trees in my internal elastic data set which will go public someday,
mind you because I believe that's important.
But like it's got like six identifiers in
it cause they're all the freaking same thing
and it took me probably an hour to put that together and it's like Oh,
this is ridiculous.
It's infuriating to me.
-- Currently,
-- CVS are, have to be perfect handcrafted artisanal entries because,
-- except
-- they're not,
well,
they have to be because they had no database. They had no mechanism to push them up.
CV.
Yeah, that's true too.
Back in the day CV S were published and done, they were never updated.
It was very, when they were updated,
everybody ignored the updates because there was no process to, to, to notify them.
Like we literally, I built a script that downloaded the CS V file D it
and, and then mangled the diff a bit to turn it into something human usable.
There was no tooling around this. There were no scanners, I mean, whatever.
And for example, by putting it in git
and using git properly, it's trivial to see. Oh, these, these files got updated.
-- I care about these files. All right. All right.
-- So we are nearing the end of our time.
And so I want to end this by just explaining what will happen
if you go to. I want
ad.org today because it's not completely,
we're working on the web page is hideous if you have any web design skill.
Like please please help us. I am begging you. I did all of the web design
and as you will see, I think calling me a web designer would be
-- a incorrect statement.
-- Honestly, you did a better job than many.
Would you at least move the tool tips out of the way. Thank God for that.
And I did move the tool tips.
So anyway, you go to, I
want
cve.org
and it's going to make you log in with
a github
id. This is a nonnegotiable step.
And the reason being we need to attach a request to
some entity,
right? We don't want people like spamming the system. Obviously, if you get a github
ID, that is a certain bar you have raised up to
that we feel like is acceptable for identifying humans.
You log in, then you go to the form and it's got some things to fill out.
And this is very free text today.
We're going to make this easier where if you start typing in company name,
it doesn't like try to prefill in or guess what you're doing like it
is very dumb today and I'm sorry for that and whatever it is,
this is how this is how communities start though is we don't,
we don't start with perfect.
We start with something functional.
And so this is very much a if you, if you can help us, please do, we want help.
This is not Josh and Kurt, this is a community, right?
So you fill this out,
you hit submit and what's going to happen then is it's going to open a bug
in a github
repo
and it's going to send you there
and it's opened by the DWF bot
in that repo. Then you'll see, there's all of your data
and the DWF bot will, then it runs about every 10 seconds. Give or take.
It's, you know, computer magic. It's going to look for all the brand new issues.
It's going to commit the data into the DWF list repo, but here's where it gets,
here's the stage we need to discuss a lot more is if you are on the allow list,
you get a CV E immediately. If you're not,
you're going to get a candidate ID.
And the purpose of this is we don't
want people like submitting trash or submitting tests.
Well, and also to put it bluntly submitting A CV the first time,
like almost doing anything the first time,
you're probably going to make a mistake for the first time.
And then,
well, we'll help you out and, you know,
gently and show you what's wrong with it or what
needs to be updated and then you'll be like,
-- oh duh, ok, I get
-- it right.
And if you're competent, we're going to add you to the allow list.
Like that's the plan
then then, so what happens now, let's say you have a candidate,
someone on the allow list which is just curt and myself as of this moment,
someone on the allow list will look at what you've done
and then they just add the assigned or the, what's the label called?
Accepted approval?
You prove this man. I know it's been,
you know,
I know, I know or professionals I
approved the approved label, right?
It's literally I so far most of the tooling I think is my fault.
So blame me for how terrible it is.
But anyway, at the approved label, the bot sees it, it says great.
-- It's a CV E and it bumps it over to CV E and like
-- that's it. And more importantly though
by submitting CVS that get approved,
-- basically that gets you on the approved list
-- probably.
Well, it doesn't automatic
-- but I think no, no,
-- not automatically.
But essentially if you do three or four good CVS
OK,
-- we're
-- going to trust you because we don't want, we don't want to do any more work.
You get to help in long term.
Once we have a nice corpus of data,
we will just automate the crap out of all of this because
in theory, it's going to be pretty easy to look at the data.
I had already done that with my spreadsheet. It was very simple.
I would scan the spreadsheet and if it was like missing entries, well, OK,
that you know, you need to put a version number here.
So the beauty of it is the web form makes you fill it in now.
Yes,
I know you can cheat and use like weird little html magic in the just fill in garbage,
right? Whatever.
But in theory, assuming you're like doing this honestly, the web form would be like,
hey, you forgot a field, fill it in,
which is,
-- that's great
-- because the number of people I've met
that can actually properly request a CV with about,
I don't know, maybe 4 to 5 minutes of instruction
is essentially everybody that can find a security flaw.
Like literally the Venn diagram of people who can find a security
flaw and people who can request a CV is essentially a circle.
Like it's a, it's a single overlapping circle.
And that's part of the challenge with the Legacy CV process is cool.
You found a security vulnerability like good luck.
Like it's to the point where it's so difficult and frustrating that I hate to say it,
-- but the majority of people I've met have given up on it and I
-- don't blame them at all.
-- I think it's, it's
-- atrocious.
Well,
and part of the goal here is to grow the community
-- because right now there is no CV E
-- community is now.
So we're going, it's time, it's time to go.
We've, I know we could talk about this for like hours and hours,
but I won't subject anyone else to this.
So here is
the call to action at the end there is go to, I want
a CV e.org
and that has, that can get you to the DWF project on github.
Please let us know what you think.
There are public repos, we open issues have discussions.
This is,
this is something Kurt and I hope will
leave us at some point and take on a life of its own because I think this
is a super important problem and it is
something that is holding back the entire industry.
And so I, I have no doubt this could turn into
something amazing, but only if the community makes it amazing.
Yeah, I just,
I look forward to this being so much more efficient and painless because
the number of people I've met that have written off CV
-- is essentially all
-- of them. It's a lot. Yeah,
except what, 100 and 56 companies.
I'm ending this. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to opens
social
security podcast.com. I'll have show notes for all the stuff we talked about.
Use the Pound
Oss
Podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media and please, please please
join the DW F community.
We're very excited to accept help and I think this will be awesome.
So, Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. We will see you soon.
The