Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
So, what's new?
You know, it's like proper summer here. We've actually had heat warnings,
which for us, hang on a sec. What is that in,
in
uh
°F, which I know is comically not hot by most us standards.
But that's ok.
That's ok. I would say
that is a normal temperature in the summer where I live and I live pretty far north.
If you go down to Arizona, it
is
winter,
right? They would laugh at you for the heat that's hot.
Although it is always funny where
I will go to the southern part of the United States.
And if I go in the summer, I look like I'm going to die and they're all fine.
And if I go in the winter I'm wearing shorts and a T
shirt and they're all bundled up and they're looking at me like,
where is this freak from?
That's my favorite memory. I went down to DC in January
and I checked the forecast and the stuff and I'm like, oh,
I'm not even bringing a jacket
and number two. And I'm like, oh, this is where all the Canadian geese go in winter.
Yes, they all go south.
-- Yeah. To DC.
-- I hate
-- those geese, man. I hate them so much, dude.
-- We hate them too.
They're, they're like, they, they won't get off the road.
Like, if you're driving on a road and there's geese on the road,
-- they won't get off the road.
-- They're, they're like the meanest creatures ever.
It's lovely.
I
haven't heard a story in a long time but
for a while it felt like every spring there were
stories of geese attacking people coming out of stores because
they would build their nest next to the door.
And of course, then they, yeah, anyway. Ok, what are we talking about today?
-- Well, I was thinking about necessary evils
-- and
I'm interested in this topic for a variety of reasons.
So it's, I mean,
it was inspired by that politician that said something
I can't even try to repeat because it's so horrifically
horrible, stupid. But I was kind of thinking about, do we,
you know, like a great example is like, printers are a necessary evil.
Like, I love that. It's 2020
everybody still complains about what a pain in the butt it is to print.
Is that a necessary evil though? I don't think so.
I went to IKEA to get a quote on my kitchen cabinet stuff. And this poor lady,
she's like, ok. I just got to print it now and I'm like,
ok, and then like, two minutes later, I'm like, what do you like?
I'm just curious, like, what are you doing?
And she's like, I'm looking for the printer
and so she had to scroll through a list of every
printer in the building to find the one next to her.
She told this story a couple episodes ago.
I'm buying a new computer because this one, the video cards failing.
So we got a nice little purple line up and down my monitor. Honestly, I realize
the operating system doesn't matter because the one app that was specific
to Mac Os is now available as a web version as well.
So like literally the only app I need
it. Well, two apps I need is a web browser and an SSH client that's San
and something that'll run Linux like in a Docker which, well, everything will.
-- I
-- like how you added is San. If you have SSH, you don't need something that runs Linux,
you just SSH to Linux
and I realize I just,
the operating system is essentially a necessary evil at this point.
-- I don't care
-- is that there? I mean, so what's the definition of necessary evil?
I feel like we have a disconnect here.
Think about how much time and effort I'm going to spend maintaining and setting
up the operating system and tweaking settings and stuff just to get it going.
Like how much time do you spend being angry at
Mac Os Audio before you gave up and used Linux?
I more than I wish. Yeah.
Ok.
So here's a definition of necessary evil and this might, this,
we'll set the stage here.
It says a necessary evil is an evil that someone believes must be
done or accepted because it is necessary to achieve a better outcome.
So, printers,
I don't think printers are evil if I was going to, I mean, you can joke about that,
but like
in all seriousness, printers aren't evil.
I,
so the fact that they sell the ink jets now
with performance cartridges that like dry out and only have,
you know, like 50 pages in them.
But that's, that's the printer company
and they make printers that are evil.
This sounds like an episode of Futurama
our printers evil.
So,
but like the operating system is a great example because I think about like,
how much time did you spend setting up and
tweaking the operating system on your mobile devices?
-- Like almost
-- zero.
It was pretty low,
like
with a mac device as far as I can tell I logged in.
-- Uh oh, and I turned off the clicking noise when you type
-- on the on the phone,
I just leave mine on perpetually silent mode.
So I,
-- I don't hear any noises
-- and that's like literally all I did versus
like my desktop where I probably spent a good 10 to 20 hours
initially customizing it and then,
you know, every week or so I spend, what, half an hour updating apps,
updating the Os Docker.
-- Oh my God. Docker updates and then eats
-- itself.
That's because you're running a Mac if you run containers on Linux,
which is the whole, that is literally the reason I switched to Linux.
-- And
-- how much time do you spend running them?
I run containers for almost everything I do.
-- But
-- what I mean is how much time did you spend setting that up and getting it working?
I mean, almost none
almost
worked
seriously. Containers on Linux
are
-- beautiful
-- but like do you have them backed up and everything?
No, because I don't care. I use them as containers are meant to be used where they are
like, yeah, I spin them up. I do the things I need to do and then I throw them away
-- like most people are just, oh cool. I've reinvented vps poorly.
-- Right. Right.
No, no. II I try to use them
in a very containery way.
And actually the thing I love the most about them
is so obviously I work at elastic and there's elastic
search and cabana are like the two big kind of
things I have to deal with on a regular basis and
I consistently have to spin up all different versions all the time.
-- Yeah, that's one area where yeah, containers
-- I, I have,
I just have a little script like if I need to run version, let's say 7.5 0.2 I just,
I type run stack 7.5 0.2 and like magic.
And then like 10 seconds later I have running
well, but in fairness on the back end,
somebody did the heavy lifting of building containers that work properly.
Yeah, we did. And that's the whole point of containers.
That's why we have them.
No, I, I was trying to like,
passwords are a good example of a necessary evil where they passwords do
accomplish a lot of good right to keep people out of my account.
Right.
They,
they generally allow people secure access to their account and especially
if you use a good password and a password manager,
you're
honestly, it's,
you're not going to get like, unless you get fished,
they're not going to get into your account.
Generally speaking through you unless they
like hack Twitter's admin control panel.
And then,
well, it doesn't matter what you did.
Ok. So
I want to reframe this, I think because you're saying necessary evil.
But you know what I'm hearing, I'm hearing relic
-- of the past
-- and I think that's part of it, right?
Is things that were once good and new and shiny, you know,
tarnish over time and then turn into a necessary
evil where a great example is fax machines.
Apparently,
fax machines are still really big in health
care in the US because they're essentially,
they get a hipaa exemption,
right? There's all kinds of law.
So II I found out about this when I bought my first house.
And the reason is there were all these documents I had to send to the bank
and I was like, can I email them?
And this was back when like emailing documents was not something everyone could do.
Like I would email PDF S and people would say, how did you make a PDF?
And it's like I'm not telling you because
I run Linux
and I don't want to get into this,
but
it was a big deal. And I remember I said, can I email them?
And he said, no, you have to fax them or mail them to me? You can't.
Yeah, they don't have the workflow for that. Well, no, it wasn't workflow. Kurt.
It was, it was legal like the law specifically said mail.
In fact, it did not specifically say email.
Well,
because there's no precedent yet because people haven't used it enough
to actually end up in court where a judge is like,
yeah, I'll allow it.
Well, it's not even just that just like the law literally said it mail
-- facts. It did not say email like it was madness
-- on a complete tangent.
I just found out.
So in Italy,
85% of banks are now using the Korta Blockchain
to exchange data because back in the seventies and this
is quite ahead of its time for the seventies they
mandated that the banks would interchange data using tapes,
which back in the seventies, like, how else would you do it?
Right.
So the average time for reconciliation was between 3050
days. Right. And
I would, you know, well,
-- if you're swapping bank tapes around and you need to confirm stuff,
-- but 50 days is
dude,
ok,
money transfers from the US,
depending on what kind of money transfer it is can take a, you know, a couple of hours.
But if I get a check from the USA, lot of places want up to 20
sometimes 30 business days to clear it.
Because the U uh up until recently,
the US banking system was so slow to clear checks properly
and you now allow electronic images for clearing checks,
right?
Whereas before they literally had planes flying bags
of checks around the US every day,
which blows my mind.
But whatever,
like I literally remember getting paid by a check from the US and like
the bank sat on the funds for 30 business days is a long time.
That's a ridiculously long time.
Yeah, but that's how long it takes the check to actually clear,
you know,
back in the day nowadays, no big deal because you can use the electronic image,
right?
The bank images, it sends it off to Wells Fargo.
Wells Fargo is like, yeah, we, yep, that's a legit check,
clear it, you know, and that's, I think that's part of the biggest thing is
so there's the necessary evils that are like unnecessary evil from day one.
And then there's the necessary evils
that become necessary evils over time for, you know, either because it's, well,
mostly a relic of the past, like you said.
So I, I think
it's worth focusing on the relics of the past, especially in the context of security
because
I feel like, and I, man, I have so many stories I could tell about this, but
I feel like there's a lot of organizations, especially when it comes to,
I'll pick on passwords because they're easy where you can say things like
Nist said, don't do this.
And people will say, well, I don't believe them.
And it's like,
what?
Well or even better Nist did say this but then recanted because we have better data
now and we learned not to force people to swap their passwords every like 67 minutes.
-- The
-- thing
-- that kills me is
I will show people the statements by Ness and the
research even that says this is a bad idea.
And people will literally say, I don't believe that.
Well, people,
this is the central thing about the scientific method that drives me
nuts is that one of the most fundamental premises of the scientific method
is that we have a framework and methodology to
sort of determine reality and interact with it sensibly.
And as part of that framework,
-- it's self modifying. Well,
-- so I don't think everyone understands that.
Exactly.
And so like,
there's lots of things where it's like, well, we used to say this but then, well,
we found out new data and we were wrong.
So
I have a great,
you know what my favorite example of this actually is I have another side project.
I'm not going to go into just yet because it's really early, but it's,
it's the same problem of,
I look at my blog post, I wrote about CV S S3 scores and like,
I started out looking to disparage NVD.
Like that was literally my goal was basically to be like,
these people don't know how to use CV SS.
And by the end, I'm like, wait,
it's not NV, D's fault at all. Like CV SS just sucks.
Well, it's, it's the relic of an, of a, of a more gentlemanly time. It definitely
is.
But it's one of those things where it's like
over the course of extracting my revenge. Like
I ended up in a completely different place and you think about that.
I could have easily just said, screw it. I don't care. NVD sucks.
I'm going with this written a Rage post.
And at the same time, I'm like, part of me, I'm just, every time I think about it,
I laugh out loud because I,
I ended up in such a weirdly different place.
And so, like,
my other project is I'm working on
something to basically measure container scanning.
Right.
And
it turns out the numbers are nothing like I expected them to be because I thought, oh,
this scanner is going to do really bad.
I'm like, no, they're all the freaking same. They
-- all the same. They all suck, but they're all the same. I'm like, this is
-- ridiculous.
Any scientist would go wait. You found weird data.
That is totally at odds with your conceptions. That's awesome.
-- Yeah.
-- Right. No, I agree.
It's very exciting when something isn't what you thought it was,
but a normal person would be like, I don't like those results.
I'm throwing them away.
Right.
A lot of people do that.
-- You
-- know, I just, I don't like these results. I'm going to ignore them.
I mean, we, we suffer that now with just the, the politicalization of, you know,
reality. I agree with that.
We have anti mass protesters up here in Canada and I'm like, really,
-- uh
-- we, we have plenty of, I,
I know people man that are talking about how none of this
is real and we're all wasting our time and it's like,
all right, look, here's the deal and this is even true of security is
there are actions you can take
that.
We say
the worst case scenario is they don't work and so nothing matters.
The best case scenario is they do work but not doing them can have a negative effect.
So here's the thing, I would rather do something
that maybe doesn't work for a net zero effect
than not do something that ends up being negative,
right.
The problem is traditionally,
is a lot of those things did have a cost associated with them.
And if you did all of them, you,
you'd kind of like waste a bunch of time and effort doing nothing of use,
especially if it worked.
Right. Your management is like, well, we didn't get hacked.
Why did we spend all this money on firewalls?
But the problem is now a lot of those security measures are dirt cheap.
Like firewall is
built in, like to Amazon and Digital Ocean and everything.
Like there's a control panel where I don't run firewalls on my hosts anymore because
it's done at the Amazon level probably five or six years ago.
I stopped doing firewall on all my servers because
I do it at the Amazon level. It's better.
It is.
-- The management is much nicer and you can control,
-- well, and I don't have to accident,
like hands up who here has locked themselves
out accidentally by changing a firewall rule.
And like, you know what I mean?
Like, it drops your SS a connection and you can't get back in.
I think it's been at least a week since I've done that.
Yeah.
You know,
and I love the fact that like all my servers are SSH
only allows specific IP S and then when my IP randomly changes.
Oh, ok. I just log into Aws and change the IP. I'm not locked out of my server.
Yeah, I've done that too more than once.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
So, I mean, so, no, no, this is,
this is a good topic and I think this is a good context to kind of explore it is.
I, I always imagine
there is
II, I like number lines in my brain. I don't know why that is.
It's just something about me. So imagine there's, there's zero cost, right?
In terms of what happens?
And you can imagine that
spending money we could think of as, as being a negative cost, right?
-- Obviously, so you spend money on security.
-- I would say it's worse.
You spend attention and time because I can always get more money,
but I can't get more attention and time.
-- I mean,
-- that's a good point,
especially these days where hiring anybody is a freaking nightmare.
And I mean, that's a good point. But
you get the idea where there's that we'll just say resources, right?
You spend resources on security.
I would just say that there's,
there's some resources that are horrifically fine out.
Like both I and Jeff Bezos only have 24 hours in a day. That is very true.
Now, monetarily, obviously, yes,
he's got a little bit more money than me and you can buy time.
I'm guessing he's never, you know, unloaded his dishwasher this decade.
I, I
don't know,
-- you know, I don't know,
-- I mean, it's funny,
some of those people are strangely normal.
I don't know if he is or not. So,
the funny story I have there actually is. So
there's a story from Melinda Gates when Bill and Melinda gates',
Children were young, she would make him drive the kids to school.
I think that's awesome. Yeah, it is.
-- It was part of being like a father in a normal house
-- because
that's actually one of the things I enjoy most with my kids.
Yeah. Yeah. So the funny thing though is because he did that.
All the other parents dropping kids off would tell
your husband's,
you can bring the kids to school if Bill Gates can do it, you can do it
when you, when you look at the opportunity cost on his time.
It's just like, I imagine like his car odometer, like, just like a spinning,
you know,
it's like that number spinning.
So $17 million you have the kids out.
But anyway, anyway, here's my point. Here's my point. Right. So
as humans,
we, we always think, oh,
I spent money on this thing but we sometimes it's very difficult to justify like, oh,
so you spent,
let's say a million resources we'll just use as
our made up term a million resources on security.
But you saved 3 million resources by not getting hacked.
-- But how do you prove something like that? Right. That's super
-- hard. Number one.
How do you measure that. And number two. Yeah. How do you prove it?
Like a great example of this is Garmin. Right. Garmin just recently got
ransomware, they're saying.
And I love, yeah, they're like, no data was stolen or got lost.
It's just, you know, all of our products haven't worked for a few days and,
and, and, you know,
ok. Fitbit, whatever. Yeah, it's annoying. But
like, they,
they make software for the aviation industry and
so there's pilots who can't file flight plans.
Oh, I suppose I didn't even think of that.
I was only thinking of their, like, human devices.
No, no, no, there's like they make, um, like a really nicely integrated, like,
it's not just an ipad app but it's also like flight electronics, gps, like
the whole, like you got a nice little Cessna or whatever and you want to, you know,
they call it nextgen equipment, blah, blah, blah.
And it, it is nice stuff.
Like, it's, you know, I've, I've seen some videos where these
pilots are using this stuff and it's like, wow, that's actually really nice. Yeah,
-- none of that stuff works.
-- That's something, man.
The part of the problem too is,
is not only how do you measure that you didn't get hacked or you
did get hacked or what the efficacy of this security controller or strategy is,
but how do you measure it against a new one?
Like, do you do a double blind trial,
run both separately at two different companies for
a year and see which one gets hacked,
sort of.
So there is actually some I've done, I've started doing some reading.
There is at, at work,
we have some,
we'll say lawyers on our security team that
are becoming very interested in something called the
Fair Institute and Fair is all capitalized and
it stands for something I don't remember.
But fundamentally what it comes down to is it is a way to start
kind of quantifying your risk and assigning monetary values
in many cases to it to say that.
Ok, so if this thing gets hacked, it's going to cost us a million dollars.
And let's say,
and,
and obviously the million dollars accounts for
reputational loss and things like that.
Right. I'm just oversimplifying
here. I love when we do this reputational loss and like, I've never actually,
-- as far as I know it, actuaries
-- have like data for that.
They, they actually do, which is mind boggling to me because in my brain,
I'm like whatever.
But I mean,
because garment obviously right now is suffering
reputational loss for what's happening to them.
I always wonder about that because it's not like, you know,
somebody's going to just ditch on their flight software.
I mean, probably not, but when it comes time to buy my next flight software device.
Oh yeah, I, I specifically ditched on Fitbit because their stupid area scale won't,
it will not import my data into Apple health, but I can buy an $8 app. That does it
right.
That's stupid.
But so anyway, anyway, the idea being
there's ok.
So if this gets hacked, it's going to cost us a million dollars, let's say.
And
-- so if we invested, let's say, does it
-- also quantify the chance of you getting hacked?
Uh, yeah, there's sort of, there's some of that, it gets really complicated.
I don't totally understand it yet.
I'm like just getting into this and it intrigues me
because I have been harping about measuring security for decades now.
And this is literally the only I think quantifiable solution I
have seen to date that I would say wasn't garbage.
So
I don't know, I don't know if it's going to make sense or not.
Well, so the thing I've always seen is getting the data to feed into that system.
Right. Right. So here's where it gets cool. Right.
Here's where it gets cool is so there's obviously actuarial data for part of this,
there's a security team can offer certain data as well based upon things like,
you know, this is how effective this particular tool is.
Like a great example is a firewall.
We know firewalls are extremely effective, right?
And then it is up to the legal department at your organization to basically say
this is how valuable we think this is.
And obviously legal departments have that skill
because legal departments are always making,
I don't know if I'd call it an estimate.
But, you know, like part of their job is saying this is what the risk is.
How likely are we to get sued?
Right. Exactly.
Money.
Right. And what is that worth to us?
And so this is an interesting melding of security and law and insurance in ways
-- I honestly never thought of
-- that makes sense
because having the legal department handle it,
like they are kind of the adults in the room for that kind of risk management.
Well, not only that, look, I'm,
I'm gonna say this out loud and it's going to sound funny,
but
I don't want to get blamed. They will. Right.
Well, and that's part of their, I don't want to say that's part of their culture
is
they accept the blame and they,
and, and it's not,
yeah, that's something I find interesting because that's,
that's one thing I do appreciate about lawyers is, you know, they, they,
they offer a vigorous defense or offense and they,
they own their failure of their success.
Right. Right. And, and, like, look as a security person,
we already have enough pressure and enough problems
accepting unnecessary blame
is a stress I rarely want.
And I mean,
this is something I'm always mindful of is I'll work with someone who's like,
brand new and they're like, oh, I don't know about this.
I'm like, look, if it goes south, blame me
and it's like, I know, I, like, I can I can stand up to this fire if it happens,
like you won't.
And that's part of the challenge too is like, you know,
constructive blame versus just
-- anger
-- blame.
Right. Well, and lawyers also, they know how to talk about things.
So if you show up and you start yelling at them,
they're going to probably make you feel really bad in
a couple of minutes because it's literally what they do.
So we've decided that lawyers are good.
Lawyers have always,
passwords are dumb. They're not bad. There's a difference.
Passwords have always been dumb. It's just they're dumber now than they used to be.
It's
well and in fairness though 20 years ago, we did not have good alternatives.
-- But now
-- we know alternatives.
This is like,
you know what my comparison here is always
is you look at like developing nations and they often have
horrendous environmental policies and in some ways you can argue,
well,
they need that because like you can't build a solar
panel until you build a coal fired power plant.
And like
that is correct.
I play a
of a factorial.
So yeah, I'm just actually in the process of transitioning from steam power
and coal based, you know, smelting to solar panels, energy accumulators and parks.
But the downside is man, my, my oil processing plants and my chemical plants are like
that's a dark red spot on the map for pollution
like it's bad
-- and the biters are getting angry
-- and, and right, I,
I understand this and I think that right, passwords are
the, the oil powered,
you know, electricity plants of days of Yore.
And we've reached a point now where we need renewable energy.
Not your, like, oil soaked passwords. Get rid of them.
That's not, that's not healthy.
And
it, it,
it,
it's like anything. Right.
There's always these transitions and I feel like in security we are on the verge
of the next thing.
And I think part of that though is you can't,
you can't make progress until you have a scientific method.
Essentially. That says this is good.
-- This is bad.
-- How do you make progress? How do you know it's progress?
Exactly.
So, and I mean,
I think the one ace in the hole we have right
now is we've magically got a computer in everybody's pocket,
right?
-- Smartphones
-- for you mean multi factor authentication
for,
I don't know what the future is but everybody's carrying around a computer now.
And that makes a whole pile of stuff possible. That just was not before.
Like I don't even ignoring multi factor authentication, stuff like
sending and receiving messages data.
Like it was so frustrating when I was so I injured my thumb
and I'm talking with health link, you know,
which is 811 on most phones in North America now.
And I'm like, oh, you know, I'm trying to explain to her and I'm like, no,
there's not like a drill in my thumb.
Like no, there's not a screw in my thumb. It's, can I just send you a picture?
Like, really? It's, if I could just send you a picture, this is
so much easier and she's like, unfortunately we can't yet accept that.
And it was like, well, ok, yeah, that's our, you know,
but I know the police locally, for example,
are they now have a dedicated email addresses?
You know, where they're like for this case,
send your stuff to whatever eps something,
something at Edmonton police service dot C A or whatever their email address is.
And so you can actually send them, you know, links or
a photograph
because I mean, quite frankly, like,
well,
how often now do the police say there was
an incident at this time and date this location?
If anybody has dash cam footage, can they please send it to us?
-- I have never heard that. Oh, well,
-- that happens all the time here in Canada
and more to the point,
especially as a cop,
I would way rather have your dash cam footage than like you try to
explain what happened and what you think you saw at three in the morning.
Eyewitness testimony has been proven time and time again to be worse than nothing.
Pretty
much. I mean, it's, it's useless. Ok, so I want to back up for one second.
You said something. Uh
So you said you dialed 811
that's like what non
emergency,
it's health.
It's the, the, the health care,
like you talk to a nurse and they're like, yeah,
like their advice was you need to go to see a proper doctor in 3 to 4 hours.
We don't have anything like that here. I, I,
11 is who you call before you dig a hole in your yard to come mark out the,
we,
we don't, the slogan here now is click before you dig.
It used to be dial before you dig. But then they got a website.
Yeah, that's fair.
-- So, it's
-- literally click before you dig because,
yeah, why would you use? The phone?
Phones are dumb. I agree.
Like, man, my phone has been going crazy, stupid politicians.
That's all it is. It's like surveys and political ads and I'm like, I'm gonna,
-- I don't answer my phone anymore. It's, I hate it. It's useless.
-- Yeah.
No, there's a bunch, like 411 is the director. I think that's pretty much universal.
Yeah, we have that one. Although even that, I don't, who uses that? Like, I don't,
I did use it once. I was out in the boonies and didn't have a good data connection.
I haven't used it in probably 30 plus years is my guess.
Well, and the funny thing is now it's automated
mostly
that you talk to a computer and then if you ask something tricky enough you hear
the human go tap, tap tap, tap, tap. Did you mean this? 00, here you go.
And then, and, but the best part is the human doesn't answer. She's like, bye.
-- And then, like, the computer voice reads it out.
-- Ah, interesting.
-- So, they basically turned it into mechanical Turk work.
-- That's cool. That's cool.
Anyway, anyway, we're, we're in a rat hole, which is,
which is the only thing we're good at.
But, ok, ok. We are running ourselves out of time.
But I feel like I want to try to sum all
this up because I think we've covered a lot of ground,
not necessarily on purpose, but that's part of the fun.
How do we measure stuff so that we can know what forward progress is.
I would go even farther back in the discussion and say, like we started talking about
necessary evils and then we talked about kind of wrapping the old way
into the modern, which is often viewed as bad
or unacceptable in many ways.
Well,
because you end up with fax machines and test
results that take like days or weeks to process,
right?
And so I feel like
the,
the real challenge for us and when we look at all of this stuff is
we just need ways to say this makes sense for these reasons.
And something like obviously being able to
measure what you're doing is hugely important
because let's face it.
-- If you, if you can't measure what you do, it's basically just voodoo and
-- witchcraft.
How much stuff have we seen on Twitter and whatnot with people, you know,
basically being asked to come back into the office so that they can, you know,
so that their boss knows they're working.
And it's like,
wow, you're, you know, if, if you have somebody doing work for you and you can't
me, like, especially white collar work and you can't measure it remotely.
You have to have to, like, stare at them doing it and make sure they're doing it
that's broken.
I know people like that that are in those kind of positions. And now I would argue
that in that situation,
what that really means is you have ineffective or managers that don't need to exist
and people claiming, oh, we have to open the office. People have to come in.
I have to watch what they're doing is one of those situations of
people are going to figure out I don't have any work to do
and they're going to fire me if I don't do these things
and that's a whole different problem by all means.
But I, I agree fundamentally if, if you're working from home
and people don't know what you're doing, like what,
what's going on here, right.
That, that's bad. Management is what that is.
And unfortunately the management rarely gets blamed,
but whatever, whatever, that's a whole,
that's another can of worms we're not going to touch today.
So.
Ok. Ok. So
let's bring it all home. Right. We are in a place in security today
that I think
things are going to get better.
But I don't know if they're going to get better in the way we think they are.
I would say overall the trend has been to better,
but with these sort of legs where things got a bit uglier for a while
and then started to get better again. I mean, that's probably fair
and that's kind of normal. But I think overall we're,
well,
we're starting to gain the benefits and reap
the reward of cloud computing and other people like
handling basic infrastructure, stuff like backup power, you know,
where just stuff is way more reliable than, you know, you can do it on site
without a lot of effort.
And even then look at cloud computing,
I remember probably a decade ago there were loads of people that were like, oh,
the cloud is just someone else's computer
-- and there's people who still say that even if,
-- yeah, and you know what?
It's true and it's fine like that car
manufacturing plant is just someone else's manufacturing plant.
Like I'm not going to make my own car parts. I'm gonna go to Napa or Canadian tire.
I won't argue.
There are times when running your own gear
makes sense and there's times it doesn't like,
you know what I mean?
I don't, I don't generate my own electricity. I
don't, I don't have a, well, in my backyard that I pull water out of, like I would,
there's more, there's easier ways to do this
and, and I think, yeah, it, this is how everything goes. Right.
And, and I also,
I guess 11 kind of thing to add to this is I
was having a discussion with someone just the other day is,
I think security teams are historically notorious for.
That's my job. Go away.
And
sometimes we have to be like,
you know, what, if you want to do this,
go do it. Good luck. It's hard.
And that's ok. Right. Sometimes it's ok to say
I'm, I can't be in charge of everything.
I can't control everything and I, I don't think we're good at that.
Well,
traditionally we got heavily punished for stuff going wrong
whether or not it was under our control.
Yeah, that's,
we're going to blame. Right.
And, and I suppose if, if something did go wrong and you told people no,
or you just did nothing.
You're like, well, you didn't give me the money to, to buy that firewall.
So I told you this would happen
and,
or I, I told them they can't run that website but they did anyway.
And then we got hacked. So, not my fault.
That's an interesting topic too. We should talk about someday.
It's just kind of that, that security mindset and how we got to where we are.
One
-- painful, well, meaning decision at a time. I mean, yeah,
-- that's fair.
Like I really, as a child,
I never really understood the hotel was paid with good intentions.
But now having seen like government process and had it explained to me, I'm like,
oh God, yes.
Yeah,
-- to see how we got there.
-- I mean, that's probably fair.
That's probably fair.
Anyway, that's a topic for another day. I'm not, we're out of time.
All right, I'm going to call it. So, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
social security podcast.com. Hit up the show note, Susie Pound.
Oh, it says podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the.