Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and
trying to figure out what names mean, Josh Presser.
That was a strange pause between open source security.
I literally was like open source.
What comes next? Oh, yeah.
Well, in my defense, it's been,
we've only recorded one podcast in seven or eight weeks.
That's true. Ok. I'll give you that
and, you know,
words are hard as well.
And also I haven't slept longer than three or four
hours at a stretch in the last eight weeks.
That's rough, man. That's really rough.
Well, it's funny because I, I remember reading this World War Two book, um,
a Canadian sailor wrote about Life on the Corvettes,
the flower class Corvette that Britain gave us that were not,
they were, they were designed for like the Caribbean,
not the North Atlantic in winter.
Those are basically the same thing,
basically. Right? Like heating.
What's that?
Um,
and
you know,
the whole port and starboard watch system where you're
on for four hours and off for four hours,
for days at a time.
That's something.
Well, I imagine it's not like you're getting a good sleep on these things anyways. I
don't know. I feel like
if you were on a boat
enough you would figure out how to sleep in that environment.
But I, I can't say either.
We also get woken up because there's all, you know, torpedo attacks and
air attacks and, well, look, if there's a torpedo attack, I, I want to be woken up. Ok.
Like
I'm ok with that.
Yeah.
You know,
they talk about how the ice hitting the outside of the hole wakes them
up at night because it's just on the other side of their bunk.
So it's funny you say that I watched a documentary about
Antarctic
Antarctica, Antarctica,
like research
and they were showing an icebreaker who is paving the way to one of the research
stations and they had the camera in the boat while it was like breaking the ice.
There is no way anyone can rest on that boat.
Like the whole boat is like vibrating and the
noise is out of control and it's just like,
holy cow.
And they're basically like, we're going to be doing this for the next 48 hours.
No one's going to get any sleep.
There's nothing we can do about it.
I'm like, oh my goodness, I can't imagine so. Yeah, back to, to name spaces. So
I've been
doing a
lot
of thinking we have to set this up first. So in the last episode,
we
briefly discussed name spaces.
And we, in fact, I think we, we made a comment like, you know, github
solve Typo squatting or something, which not get up do?
They didn't name spaces don't exactly.
They change the attack against typo squatting. They don't solve it.
And we say a lot of stuff so, whatever, but
it exploded into this gigantic threat on Mastodon
that I don't think it's available to the
general public to see. Oh, that's why I couldn't boost it. It involves Toma De
Pierre
and Carol Nichols, both of whom have been on the show
and neither of which
likes name spaces we discovered.
And so
it,
it resulted in a very interesting conversation.
I, well, no,
let's not say they don't because we don't know that they don't like name spaces.
I suspect they don't like the current implementations, maybe of name spacing.
And also I think like a lot of people like a lot of technical solutions,
we were promised a lot of things that were never delivered or can't be delivered.
So a great example of this would be like DNS E a lot of people hate on DNS Sec
and you ask why and they give a bunch of reasons like, well, yeah,
DNS EC doesn't really do that that well,
but it does these other things that are helpful.
So maybe it's not evil.
And then of course, once in a while it breaks dot New Zealand,
I want to
framing it in the context of DNS tech is perfect because
when we were discussing with this, with Tama and Carol,
I think we were all discussing
the solution aspect of name spaces and not really
very much of the problem portion of it.
And this is the same with DNS SEC because I think when
you try to explain what are the problems DNS SE solves,
I think it becomes a less compelling story.
And I think name spaces are similar where there are certain problems
name spaces help with and there are certain solutions they don't.
And I think Toma and Carol are correct
to
disagree with us. I'll say I, I would say it's actually
more difficult in the sense of we're all correct and wrong
because there's what name spaces can and cannot do.
There's what the solution side of it is.
And then there's the expectation side. What do we ask
anticipating or expecting?
Because I see a lot of comments saying things like, oh,
if we implement name spaces with some form of validation,
then that will lead to a false sense of security.
And my and I'm like, well, do, do we actually know that like is that what people think?
Because I, I don't know,
you know, if I go to like for example, if I go to get oh a perfect example.
Well, my, my one example is gonna be Burger King.
Like if you go to Burger king.com dot A U, it's,
that's Burger King except Burger King in Australia is not Burger King.
It's, it's a Burger King.
Burger King in Australia is Hungry Jack's because there was already a Burger King.
But a good example of this is if you go to github.com/red Hat, that's not Red Hat.
It's really not Red Hat.
And that should be very obvious because it's one of those, you know,
you commit this year. Yeah. The person squat. Oh, my goodness, you're right.
Oh, they do one commit every year or two or three?
Oh, no, there was no commits for anyways.
The point is github.com/red Hat is not Red Hat.
It's somebody who squatted the space back in 2010.
And I guess because of how
github
works and trademarks and abandon or not abandon recounts, whatever Red Hat,
the company
was never able to get a hold of it,
you know,
and I mentioned it once or twice because I was like, oh,
this is not great because almost worse in ways Red
Hat had something like 100 plus orgs on github.
Like at one point I tried to track them all down and it didn't go.
Well, one of the challenges of namespace is what is the actual expectation here?
Because for example, if I go to a namespace, let's say for the sake of argument.com.
Well,
the.com namespace, Burger king.com, what is that? Well, it's, it's Burger King.
But if I go to the.com dot A U
namespace, it's, well, it's not
Burger, well, it is Burger King legally in Australia,
but it's not Burger King.
And I actually, now I'm curious,
I'm gonna check if they have a presence on Github because it wouldn't be shocked.
Burger King.
Oh, my goodness.
04040, I should go grab that
anyway. Oh, don't do that.
We'll see how long it takes after the show goes public.
Someone's gonna grab it now, I think. But that's the thing, right?
So when you go to a name space and you look at a name,
if it's something like Google or Amazon or Aws,
I think the expectation is that it is Google or Amazon or Aws, which is
one of the reasons I keep going back to.
Well, let's just do domain names and be done with it. Well, and, and so that's
where I think a lot of the conversation ended up with Toma
and Carol, both kind of mentioning.
Why not?
Just, for example, let's say you want a name space in for N PM packages,
why not just run an N PM registry
with your domain?
And then your stuff is in that. And II, I think that makes a lot of sense.
And even better than that, for example, then you could actually do a very
easy central discovery protocol of when you go to N PM.
Js.org/red hat.com for the sake of argument,
it redirects you to red hat dot com's actual service
and,
and see that's the thing I this is one of
the things that spacing does solve is it allows you
to have multiple things in one space which for example, searchability,
you have a like sure
people go to N PM js.org and are clearly searching for things like security.
Because N PM js.org/security,
the security module hasn't been updated in um what was it?
Four or 10 years
and it gets still like 2000 downloads a week, 1386 is what it says right now, right?
If you search packages for security,
it's
yeah, last published 11 years ago.
Version 1.0 0.0 weekly downloads. Yeah, 1400.
So like roughly 200 downloads a day for 11 years
and it's horrifically out of date and people are like,
hey, this provides security.
So, ok,
so here's kind of what I've been thinking about in the context of this
whole discussion because I'm not done putting
all the thoughts together in my brain.
So my opinion may have changed by the time this actually lands,
I feel like there are a couple pieces to this name Space Story
and we're
bring them all together
things like a name space on N PM, which do exist N PM originally was completely flat,
which is why you see like name space dash package name in certain packages.
And now they have the like Ampersand
name space slash package.
Name is the new way, but a name space in a service like github
or N PM or something else.
I don't know if that's really a name space because you can kind of own it,
but it's not yours.
But I would argue you don't really have control over any name space.
Ultimately, then by that definition, because for example,
even DNS, somebody could, you know, have the sea
as a trademark and come after me and,
and threaten me with legal action and take it away from
me and which has happened to people with their domain names.
It can ultimately any word or trademark or name we use in this sort of business,
technical world can
probably be taken away from us, right? There's even been, let me rephrase that, OK.
When you own a domain, you have a certain amount of control over those resources,
right?
When you have a name space in N PM,
you are almost entirely at their mercy.
And that's only because of their licensing terms being different than say
the DNS registrar N PM, for example,
could have different licensing terms that do give you a lot of control.
They could choose to do that. I mean, that's fair.
They could and I suspect some of the open source ecosystems do N PM.
So maybe a bad example because it's controlled by a company, you know,
you could look at like
the
like
they're not gonna go out on a limb to protect you like
no really, I mean, because it is a business that would be insane. Absolutely.
100% you know, whereas some of these other, ok.
But now here's where this starts unraveling in my mind
when we look at the context of something like
crates dot IO for rust or pi pie or whatever
these are open source services
provided at no cost to really the developer or the user pulling from them.
There's, it's, it's, these are foundation run, right?
They run on a shoestring budget and like if they don't, it's a
nonprofit backing it.
Right. And if they don't want name spaces, like I think that's fine.
And that makes sense because I know like Carol works with the,
the rust stuff and they don't like them and I get that well,
I would simply say their playground, their rules.
But
for me, what gets me is number one. So there's clearly problems with
allowing people to choose package names
because
Attackers are, you know, like if you search for Aws on N PM,
there's a couple of legit ones and a whole bunch of maybe legit, maybe not legit ones.
Here's where I think that gets even funnier in tech.
We have never had an ecosystem last for more than
maybe a decade or two at most at this point.
And
when you think about like names are not just naming packages,
like N PM has millions of packages.
We're running out of words for package names in N PM. Well,
exactly. And,
and that's the other reason I think name spacing is important because there's
probably a good case to be made for more than one security package.
Right. Like
there could be a company that wants to have
a security package for their service or some protocol,
like an HTTP S security package or maybe an FTP security package or something.
Right.
And that would be the other benefit of name spacing is that
it allows us to have sort of different countries
with different flavors and different cultures rather than.
Well, all the good words have been taken. Now, what do we do?
Here's a thought. Why do we allow people to choose names at all?
Why don't we just simply assign them
on a unique, globally, unique ID? And if they want to have like
a description of what it is that is searchable, like this is an Aws SDK,
allow them to put that in.
But otherwise it's just a UED and that's what you type in,
that's what you put in your config files and you
could put a comment there saying what it is,
I mean, look, the the user experience of that would be ridiculous.
OK. That's one argument against it.
But for example, you could allow them to set an alias
of this is the AWS SDK.
And for example, multiple people could set that alias,
they could say this is described as like R PM packages, right,
R PM packages have a file name
but then they have other information like you know
the description and so on of it that well can
be the same between different, completely different packages.
Uh Perfect example being this is an email server and you can choose send
mail or post fix and they both implement like I need a mail server.
So like
install one to meet the requirement.
I mean that's how Debian works where you can specify,
I forget what they call them, like virtual dependencies or something.
But you can say like I need a male server and then things can be like I am a mail server.
Yeah, like
exim or whatever you want. Right.
So
my one thought there is, I think part of the challenge is letting
people pick arbitrary
names
that they may have
or may have nothing to do with.
I think you are technically correct.
But I feel like
from a practical standpoint, this is a ridiculous suggestion.
But there's a simple.
But then, OK, so,
so we've agreed that having these completely
random name like assignments would be terrible.
Yeah, I, I would be inclined to agree with that. This is how Discord
works.
Like, well, and I would be,
I, and I would say that on the,
having that on the back end is one thing but having it on the front end.
Yeah, that's terrible. So we're agreed that that's probably not a great solution.
So then, well, then that means we have to let people pick names and here we are,
we do have to let people pick names.
And I think
there's the human aspect of this
that
I think Carol and Tama were focusing on and you and I were not,
and the human aspect should not be discounted because fundamentally all tech
is for humans
at the end of the day. Now, here's a second thought. Ok.
So we're agreed that we should let people choose names. That is the same way to go.
Yeah.
Yeah. Well, then how
do we let them choose names that they have no control or any legal standing of?
Like, for example, with github.com/red hat,
I mean, this is where things start to get a little more dicey, I think.
Well,
they get messy because clearly the Attackers love that because they're
picking names that are like Aws official SDK or whatever.
So now we get into the discussion about like do name spaces improve security?
I don't think we can say yes. Well, let's dial it back one.
No, no, let's, let's ignore name spaces right now. So
we're agreed in principle that totally
random strings are purple monkey dishwasher.
Terrible idea. Purple monkey dishwasher is a great name.
It's from that documentation thing from ages ago.
Anyways, it's an Easter
egg. It's been on the show before anyway.
So,
and we've agreed in principle that letting people
choose names is good but leads to problems
because for example, they choose names like
Aws official SDK and then they harvest your keys. So here's a question.
What names can we let people pick
that are? And I'm making air quotes here safe. I mean, historically,
we haven't
because
we've just assumed all names are equal and there's
not a concept of safe or unsafe names.
You have typo squatting
and,
you know, imposter stuff.
Like I remember when my ISP back in the olden days would let you pick your host name.
And I tried like male admin, all that stuff was reserved and blocked. Yeah.
Didn't you use like local host,
local host and like my cable modem tipped over and I, I had to phone Kevin and tell him,
you know,
first of all, I can't change my host name because my internet's down
because I'm getting flooded.
And secondly, you need to put this name on the reserve list and he's like, oh God,
you know, damn it,
Kurt, like, stop it.
That's also when I discovered that they would
route 10 dot Star traffic down their network.
And again, my NFS traffic caused problems. But anyways, I digress. So, ok,
here's the thing. If we let people choose names, then
what are names
that we can let people choose that we can
establish that they have some interest or control in.
And I would suggest there's three big ones, URL S email and domain names.
I mean, how does URL not just fall into domain names
because proving control of a domain name is
very different than proving control of a URL.
In the proving control of a URL, you have to put something on the page which is to
very messy and difficult versus proving control of a domain.
There's several ways that are generally accepted as secure to do that.
OK?
You know,
like you have email as host master at domain.com or you can set up a DNS record of,
you know.
All right, I'm not gonna, I'm not gonna argue with you on this,
but this one feels sketchy.
Ok? But in general, right? So let's let's
let's avoid URL S because
they're just kind of messy anyway, right?
And
emails are very easy, you know,
you send an email with a magic link to the person saying click this link to review
manager control or whatever this email address.
I mean, that's how every time you sign up for a service, right? Yeah.
Yeah, that's fine. I get that.
So in principle,
then we could let people choose domain names or email addresses or possibly URL S,
although it's a little messy and use that as the names face and they,
they are
able to prove that they have control over that domain name,
email address
which all fundamentally boils down to.
It's either a domain name that they control or it's a domain name
like github.com that allows people to set up web pages and so on.
And so forth typically within a name space that's clearly identified, right?
If you look at a github,
like one thing I love now is when I'm browsing documentation and stuff,
people will just put something slash something.
And the assumption is that it's github.com something slash something.
Well, that's their mark down does that.
And I, I mean,
that would happen on any site I'm talking about stuff that's just like random.
I'm reading docs on the internet and they say the source code is available at bla
slash F
and well, the assumption is bla slash F
lives in github.com because where else am I gonna look?
I see. Ok. Anyway. All right. I don't,
I don't see where this is going in a helpful way. Well, so the, the point of this is
is that if we allow people to pick names,
allowing them to pick names arbitrarily clearly has problems.
So what if we only allow them to pick names that
they can prove they have some control or interest in?
Now, Attackers can't pick red hat.
Like for example, now you can't pick Red hat.com, you can't pick amazon.com.
He just lost me. I think
trying to impose these restrictions
in the name of security.
It's not just, here's just talked about Attackers. Ok.
But the other, well,
what I wanted to get to though was one of the benefits
of domain names is how do we interact with things online,
domain names right now?
Yeah, with our web browsers for sure.
I mean, I agree with that and email, if you want to email somebody,
it's kind of dependent on their domain.
I
mean,
well, for
example,
I used to work at security portal
site partners and I would email developers saying, hey, can you, you know,
I'm trying to get some information about the security vulnerability.
Could you
talk to me about
it?
No response
when I started working at Red Hat
immediately getting responses all the time because of that Red hat.com Domain.
I mean, I'll agree with that. It definitely carried a certain amount of respect.
You didn't get elsewhere. That is fair. But I don't feel like
this necessarily addresses the name space discussion
in the context of software packages. Specifically.
What I'm saying is I haven't gotten to name space yet.
I'm just saying when we talk about,
we have to allow some form of name because we established that if we just assign
uh globally unique I DS, that will be terrible and horrible.
There's a reason people don't refer to products by their barcode number,
right?
You know, I or for example, go get me some 4011. I have no idea what that means.
Get me some bananas or is that the plu for bananas?
The code for bananas across North America.
It's like one of the few codes I know I also used to know one of the brand of apples that
we used to obsess. I used to know some of them. I worked at a grocery store long ago.
Exactly. Right. Like everybody is like, oh, yeah, 4011 that's bananas.
Everybody knows that. But nobody ever says it because,
well, you use the word bananas.
Duh.
And software is the same way. We use names for software. We don't use a hash.
It is.
Right.
Well, because it's for humans. Right. Names are for humans.
Well, and we need to be able to talk about this.
We need to be able to say I am looking at two different packages.
We need to pick between them
or I need a package that does X and well, thanks to
reasonably named packages. If I'm looking for a package that does a hash function
generally, if I search N PM or crate or whatever for hash, I will,
I will get something hash related, hopefully.
And then I can look through those options and you know,
pick one. So here's something interesting for you. I just typed hash into N PM
6872 packages found and, 00, my goodness. This is terrible.
The first one is a, a package named hash
that was updated five years ago. Exactly.
And this is my point about letting people choose these names,
even if it's not an attacker not malicious.
Now, you have somebody squatting the hash,
you have somebody squatting the security word that hasn't updated or anything.
With it in half a decade or in the case of security in 11 years
and maybe we should take that back and
update it. This is ok.
So here's the discussion and I think this is a different problem
than name spaces because I don't think name spaces necessarily fix this.
Exactly. But this is an interesting discussion.
So there's a package named hash on N PM
hasn't been updated in five years. Right. If we go look at the github
repository, I assume it hasn't been updated in five years.
Uh Yes.
02 years ago,
there was an update to package that JSON which apparently hasn't made it to N PM.
More to the point. There's eight commits, the whole thing has eight commits.
This is where I think the discussion gets interesting.
You know, name spaces are a possible solution.
But I think the problem hasn't been identified deep enough yet
is there are these terms
in these packaging ecosystems and they are flat.
The name hash is gone forever and you could say, oh,
let's just give it to someone else.
But here's the thing.
There is
an enormous amount of difficulty,
confusion and security problems in gifting away these names to someone else
because
how do you know the person who wants it isn't like, you know,
an adversarial government just like waiting there knowing like one of these
will get one of them and someone's going to use it.
Then
I have good news for you.
That's a problem with everything online, an email address, a domain name,
everything at
some level now and with packages is just a bit
more kind of directed in your face of like,
well, perfect example, uh hash gets 2600 downloads a week a week.
So like couple 100 a day. So if you want to go compromise a whole bunch of
systems, well,
this would be a really easy way to do it.
I mean, there have been other things,
I know there were certain things in N PM at one point
that had millions of downloads a day that the,
the authors had abandoned and no one knew what to do with it.
And I, I remember talking to some N PM people and they were like,
we can't give this to anybody like it's too,
it's too big because how do you trust the person saying I'll take care of
this?
Can, can do it.
You know,
the thing is ultimately we have to allow for that trust to be built because ok,
story time when I was at Red Hat,
there was somebody with and it was actually an N PM package who was freaking
out because they get 10 million downloads a week or a month or something.
It was a big number and there was a really bad security flaw in it.
And this poor guy,
21 years old, I remember that specifically
was freaking out. He's like, am I gonna get sued? Am I am I am my toast.
And
what had happened is he had started
fixing some of the documentation,
fixed a few things in the documentation.
Then he noticed a flaw in the code or a bug in the code. Fix that
and then like basically six months or 12 months later. It's kind of like cool.
Uh I guess it's like
it's yours now,
you know, you touched it,
you touched it last.
And so the,
that's the thing like we,
we need
people maybe
foundations like tide lift or something or the Linux,
sorry, I thought,
ok, which one am I thinking of then? That's like tide lift.
But a foundation, whatever, it doesn't matter.
The point is we need to allow people to build trust somehow
because, well, we already have that.
Like everybody implicitly trusts Linus Torvalds
and his cabal because,
well, we're all running Linux
but everyone trusts N PM,
right?
Nobody, nobody vets anything on N PM.
They just install it like a drunken sailor and they go
to town quick question who's actually in control of N PM?
Like what I want the names of the people who,
how many people at N PM would it take for them to
subvert N PM and just serve malicious code all day long?
And that is we have no idea.
Uh We kind of do. It's, I mean, you have to be on the inside but
how many people is that,
I think, I think I could do it with one.
I know, I know a person that I'm pretty sure could pull it off and I don't, but I mean,
look, it's, it's controlled by Microsoft.
It lives under the N PM umbrella.
There is
a lot of pieces to this and you could maybe argue it should be a foundation,
it shouldn't be a foundation, whatever.
But at
the end of the day, I don't think
any of this matters because people are just
gonna blindly install whatever solves their problems.
And I think that's the thing as security people, we keep forgetting.
Developers don't care about name spaces, they have problems to solve.
No, no, it's worse than that.
It's to actually do a proper like risk assessment and audit of N PM and how it uh M PM,
js.org and how it's run and who's in control of it
and how many people it would take to subvert and how safe
it is is basically expensive to the point of damn near
impossible and more to the point it doesn't matter because yeah,
what are you gonna do?
Not use
PM? If you wanna use N PM, you have to use N PM, gs.org. There's no sane alternative,
right? If you wanna use Pearl, you gotta use CPA.
If you want to use PHP, you gotta use pear. So here's where I think
I've just landed on all of this as security people, especially security people.
And this is why I'm so thankful for people like Toma and Carol who,
who hold their feet to this fire
is we have this obsession with trying to warp
the upstream of open source to do our bidding.
And the reality is we can't, they aren't listening to us. They don't want to.
It's not even that they're not listening. Is that a
lot of this stuff they can't do.
That's a
stupid question. Is the person that did hash, are they alive?
We have no, we, we don't know. We, we, I don't know. You could probably look at their
github profile. Well, trick question. Do we even know the person?
A
no
is an account on?
But I don't know that that's a person they, they had to commit, um, what,
three months ago,
like you could be a
triggered off a server
function.
I don't know. Anyway. Anyway, here's the point. Here's the point of all this I think
is
as security people, we need to do a better job of
warping our expectations to the world instead of
trying to warp the world to our expectations.
And I think that's what it comes down to.
I think when people like Carolyn Tomas say, name, faces are dumb. Don't use them.
The immediate reaction from us should have been.
They're probably right. Why are we wrong?
Instead, we had this lengthy discussion where I think that's why it ended at the end.
But like
here's my thought and argument on this, I'm not even
name space point yet. I'm just at the, how do we do naming at all?
That, that conversation's done, Kurt, like we decided people just make crap up.
Then we actually, once we do name spaces,
now we have additional problems is what I'm saying.
Right. We have the original problem of choosing names and having names.
And now we also have this problem of like, for example,
what is the expectation around a name space?
Well, I would say, for example, if I go to github.com/,
Red hat.com,
the expectation is that darn well, better be Red hat.com.
Now conversely github.com/red hat. Well,
again, my expectation is that would be Red Hat.
And luckily, the person who or entity or the,
the thing that owns that account has made it pretty clear that that is not Red Hat.
Like if you go to there, it's really clear, it's not Red hat. It's true.
Now, let me, let me ask a different question. Let's say
N PM has name spaces. They do have
names.
I know. But OK, let's say everything shut up. Let's say everything is in a name space.
I search for the package hash and I, I get back 2000 name space
hash packages. Which one
is the package I should do. Here's a really concrete example,
if I search for Aws, I get AWS dash
SDK slash credential provider node.
Now what is
AWS SDK? I assume that's the official
A
w how
do I,
how
do I like? They don't say what it is anywhere on this web page.
You should sell an EV certificate. And then,
well, and, and, oh,
actually that was one of my other things I wanted
to talk about was we've clearly landed on domains matter.
That's it full stop because domain validated certificates have taken
over the world and Evie and OV are basically dead.
The only thing that with a slight wrinkle is BMI the um what the heck is Bey
stand for again, I should know this because I bought one the uh
brand indicators for
me, message identification. So that's the thing we're on your email.
Like if you get an email from me, you get the S A logo
because we have this certificate and this thing with an
SVG or whatever PNG file that shows our logo,
same with Air Canada and a bunch of other companies,
Amazon just got one actually about six months ago.
And so the idea is that when you get an email from, say Amazon, well,
the real one has the Amazon logo and the not real one doesn't have that logo, right?
And
it's
mediated by your client and only shown if they have the correct record,
the attacker.
The idea is the attacker can't do it short
of subverting a very comp uh relatively secure process.
I'm gonna say like where you,
you have to go to a public note,
they basically validate that you own the trademark that you are on behalf of
the domain that you are allowed to be on behalf of the domain,
blah, blah, blah.
You know, we basically, they emailed the CEO and was like, can Kurt do this?
Yes, Kurt can do this. And then Kurt went to a public notary and
they looked up our trademark in the US patent office.
So
it costs about 1000 bucks a year. And that's basically what real validation costs
about
a year.
So that's not gonna work for N PM Js.
No,
no, not at all.
But on the flip side
to actually Thomas and Carol
pointing out that some of these big companies, like,
maybe they should spend a few bucks.
I agree with that.
And that's the part of the conversation I I'm not willing to have right now,
but I do think we need to think about is
an enormous amount of big companies are just like free riding the crap that
source.
And that's,
they also don't really have an alternative because remember we talked about this
with the whole security and what can your company do for security?
Uh Remember with the German thing about what, 56 years ago, it's been a while.
They're just, they're like here like we're,
we're just gonna allocate some money to bug bounties
because that's legally what we can set up and do.
But yes, that's what they could do, but now there's the Sovereign Tech Fund. Right.
Well, and,
but it took half a decade to get there. It did, it took a long time.
So, I don't know, I need to think about this more. I just feel like
at the end of the day,
uh trust the
smart people, we're not the smart people.
And the other question is,
has anybody done any research at all asking people
what is their actual expectation of name spaces?
Like what do people think name spaces mean? Or do I doubt it? We just make this crap up.
I mean, let's face it.
It's all made up crap, right?
Because to me the name space Aws SDK, I would have gone with Amazon
or at Aws.
I don't know why they were with Aws SDK is they were probably the 700 meetings
to pick that name.
Like I just,
I look at this and I'm like trying to figure out
what is that here if go to the root of that?
Does that take me to a thing?
No.
So anyway, as much fun as this is to listen to Kurt navigate N PM,
I'm going to call this.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to
open our security podcast.com. Hit up the show. Not, it's easy pound
do
podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye. Bye.