Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in thinking about stuff that may or may not matter.
-- Josh Bresser's
-- does anything matter.
Lunch.
-- Lunch is important.
-- It's true.
Lunch is coming up after I'm done talking to you for me.
But anyway,
so I, I have a, I have a funny personal anecdote to tell.
I am in
a great deal of pain right now
because it is a Wednesday
and
the weather was very nice on Monday and Tuesday and I
took my actual real road bike out and overdid it.
And so now I really heard
you exercised.
Why did you exercise?
I ride like thousands of miles a year on my bike. I, I love riding my bike
and I ride a stationary bike in the basement in the winter because it's cold and
I'm not one of those people willing to ride outside and the ice and snow.
But the,
the problem I realized is it keeps me just in shape enough that I can overdo
it when I get on the real bike and put myself in like excruciating pain.
So
that's
at
least it was raining today and so I couldn't go ride outside this morning.
No, it's important to exercise.
It is. I agree. I, I like riding a bicycle. It's
a, a,
it is something I enjoy.
I listen to podcasts and I get to look at all the neat things as you ride past.
I love riding bicycles, but I've been hit by a car
-- and locally that's kind of a normal thing for cyclists.
-- That is a problem.
Definitely. I, I put a lot of effort into staying off of roads whenever possible.
So I've mostly been lucky I don't think,
-- have I been hit? No, I haven't been hit in a long time. I had some run ins
-- in a long time.
Wow. I mean, that makes it perfectly safe.
Well, that's when you're, if you bike a lot you're gonna get, you're gonna get hit.
I mean, it's just how it goes.
It wasn't anything hard but I, I didn't need like, medical attention.
-- Yeah.
-- Just a, just a little bump.
-- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. But no, I mean, that, that's definitely a concern.
It, it's one of the issues I think with being a bicyclist in the city.
It's unfortunate. It annoys me but it is what it is
anyway. So,
speaking of pain.
So, I, it's funny because I haven't, like, I run two windows machines locally. My
desktop and one of my sons has a windows desktop for gaming and
I
don't really pay attention to Microsoft patch Tuesday anymore.
Other than, you know, I do update eventually
within a day or two.
And you had mentioned that this patch Tuesday was particularly bad.
You were not kidding. 117
vulnerabilities that they admit to.
And, and here's the thing I know for a fact, Microsoft will not give CV S
to issues they find internally,
like if they find a security issue internally and fix it internally,
they just, that's what they do. They don't bother attaching a CV to it.
Well, it, it's a little more complicated than that. I, I talked to someone there.
-- I, I disagree with this mind you, I'd like to preface it with this,
-- but, well,
-- this is what I was told by them a few years ago
-- and, and well,
so here's the way they view this.
It's not that they don't give them to internal things. It's
imagine for example, this XML or not XML,
this uh Windows R PC critical issue that's probably going to get wormed.
That is just remote code execution. No, off, no, nothing. Right.
If you can, if you can basically see a Windows machine
that has the
R PC port, which is what, like 445 or something maybe open,
you can basically paw the machine.
OK.
-- No, that's CF si don't
-- know who cares.
II,
I
doesn't matter.
Anyway, you, you can look that up. I tell the story.
The idea is so they find, let's say they find two R ce s,
they're only gonna claim it's one because in their opinion,
you already have to update it for one R ce, what's the difference if there's two?
So they'll like because they obviously rewrite huge portions of code
and they do a lot of things to,
it's not intentionally to hide these but it's harder to see.
And so that's their view of it already has one critical.
Who cares if it's fixing five other criticals? One is enough.
I don't agree with it, but I understand their argument.
Yeah, I was gonna say,
I also don't necessarily agree with it because
I would like more technically correct data.
But at the same time,
here's the, you know what, this reminds me of Cisa issuing in the last two weeks,
they've issued like what three or four bulletins about Google Chrome updates.
And my take on that is either you're running Google Chrome up to date
or you're not.
There's no in between. There's no like, oh, we're going to patch it in 30 days. No,
you, that update button shows up,
you hit that smash and like update button
and same thing with windows, especially like on the server.
I can be like you can maybe you can slow down a bit but on a desktop
you just,
you keep your fleet up to date or else you, you lose.
Well, so here's where I think it's more complicated than that.
I think it's easy to say that it's not always practical in many organizations.
But I think more importantly is we exist now in this space where there's all this
detection, software and technology.
And so, for example, you've got what you call indicators of compromise.
And so if Microsoft says here's the bug we fix that's critical
in R PC,
people are going to figure out what it really means.
They're gonna understand how to exploit it and then they're
going to look for that particular signature in network traffic.
But if there's another thing
that is also exploitable, it has a different signature.
Are you going to even know that's there?
And are you going to miss that particular vulnerability if it gets exploited?
And that's my complaint over trying to
bunch these together and hide behind one thing
and, but like I said,
it really boils down to either you keep your stuff really up to date
or have a ton of other compensating
controls which you can't really realistically do
for a lot of these bugs,
not on a desktop.
I I know it's not quote
unquote realistic or easy to keep these things up to date, but Attackers don't care.
Uh And the second thing is this sort of leads to the kind of the cultural
ecosystem history of windows, which is
it
fundamentally came out from, well, the mindset came from D OS to Windows, you know,
to windows server.
But fundamentally, it's, it's all about a single user system
with no real controls.
And that culture shows in even something as simple as the
way it handles file permissions and spaces and file directories.
You know, like if you,
if you load something from like program space files slash blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, the first thing it tries is CF
OOL and programs
with the rest of the stuff is like an argument basically,
you know, unless you properly escape the path and everything, it just,
it handles it really dumb.
And I mean, that's what we're seeing with. Git,
right, today
or yesterday, I think. Was it
whatever?
Oh, it says today.
So today the get project released new versions which drives a pair of security
loans and they're so stupid basically,
if you can drop a dot Get config into like this into the root directory.
Well, get, well, it looks for it and
opens it up and does whatever it says in there.
Well, that affects all operating systems. That's not a Windows problem.
There's one problem that's Windows only and that involves uninstalling.
But,
but I was going to say that the big difference here though is Linux takes the tact of,
hey, that's my root file system.
Like if you pseudo you can touch it but otherwise don't know.
Right. And so it's, it's better protected by default. Whereas on Windows,
I can scribble all over the C directory by default.
Well, I mean,
not necessarily like here's an example it is
potentially a problem on a multi user system.
And I have a perfect example is,
so let's say when I do stuff, I put like garbage in temp all the time, right?
Where I'll create like
maker
slash
temp slash A
and then I'll like, download a bunch of crap into a and unzip it and it just like,
I've got garbage all over and I don't have
to care because I know it'll get cleaned up later
automatically. Right
now. If I, like,
have a directory called A
and I run git in that directory, what git will do is get, looks for it,
basically just starts going backwards up the directory tree looking for a dot Git.
So if I run a get operation because it's just a habit, I do it, you know, I'll run, like,
get log or something all the time in weird places.
And it's always like, oh, this isn't a get repo, what are you doing? You idiot.
But if, if say an attacker creates a dot Get directory in slash temp,
which they could totally do.
And I'm in slash temp slash A and I run git,
it's going to make its way into that dot Git that's attacker controlled.
And that's kind of the problem because in that dot Git you can make it run scripts,
you can make it do all kinds of wacky things.
Yeah.
-- Right. Right.
-- Yeah.
But I mean, the difference being is that on a Linux machine or whatever,
more typically you'll have like, you know, tilda slash temp,
like you'll have your own personal temp directory.
I
hope is there, does that exist? I don't know, there's, there's things you can do.
-- I never,
-- it depends on the distro and I don't use
any of that crap.
-- That's like part of
-- the challenge. Well, and there's polly instantiated temp.
Right.
Anyways,
the point is Windows has this cultural legacy of being a single user system.
And so, for example, for me to use my desktop in any meaningful useful way,
I have to log in as an admin user because to update a software to, well,
I have to within the software, I have to update it.
It's not like R PM runs in the background, updating stuff,
you know,
um on
a machine,
I have to go to system updates and I have to go to the Microsoft Store
to do updates and I have to within certain apps like Chrome does its own updates.
And I was actually just looking at github
desktop
and it
II, I actually don't know how to update this. I look under help.
I look under a bunch of stuff and there's no
check for updates thing that I'm seeing.
It's
magic.
There's
I, I
mean,
I'm not,
I'm not even clear on what version of github
desktop I'm running anymore because there is no,
there's no show version or oh about github
desktop here. We go. I'm running 2.9 0.13.
Ah, there is a check for updates button hidden here. Ok.
-- So it's sort of hidden in the standard check version and hit
-- the updates
anyway.
The
point is to have a comment on that.
But on a Linux machine,
I very commonly just log in as a regular user, do my stuff until
I maybe need to install some new software package,
which is pretty rare because I basically
just slap everything in at the beginning and
that's it. Right. Who cares? So it's, yeah, I don't know.
I feel like it's like two factor authentication. It has
real organizations have to be moving to hardware keys.
No more of this software based authentication. No more of this S MS stuff.
It has to be like UB keys or Google Titan or whatever because
there's just too many failure modes with the other ones and it's 2022 and I'm sorry?
But
it's expensive and it's kind of a pain, but
that's just how it is.
I mean, I don't think that's a helpful attitude
in any way
you're not wrong.
It's like cars,
you can't buy a car without a seatbelt and airbags pretty much
anymore because we decided that that is the bare minimum safety needed.
And I,
I literally have met people who complain about having
to spend money on that that they don't want.
And it's like
now too bad.
There's an important distinction, I think
that you're missing. When you make a comment like that is,
cars don't come with seatbelts and airbags because
the auto manufacturers think it's a neat idea.
They come with seatbelts and airbags because a
regulatory body said you have to do this
except for
there are companies like Volvo, which one of their big stick is selling safety.
And
I think there are niches for that.
But I think fundamentally,
I mean, it doesn't, I think Schneier
has a whole piece.
He wrote about this, what the security market for lemons or something.
We might have even done a podcast on it like years and years ago.
But
I think
security is a, is a good example of that is,
it's easy to say
that we're doing more security and that's why
it costs more and there's always going to be
consumers that understand that and they're willing
to pay a premium for more security.
But I think the vast majority of people don't care.
Pause. I'm not talking about consumers, I'm talking about businesses,
whatever businesses are just consumers. It's the same thing.
And that's, there's
a,
there's a difference there.
I, I disagree.
I think,
I think there are loads of businesses that
if you said here's a computer that cost $4000
but it has
90% security and here's a computer that costs $3000 and it has 50% security.
They're going to be like three grand. It is.
I guarantee it
most small and medium businesses. That's what they care about.
But basically what I'm saying is businesses have a
bit more responsibility than say a consumer does.
Right. Well, they should,
I
don't think they always do though.
Well, they certainly don't behave like that. No.
I mean,
they'd be putting lead in the baby milk if they could make a
-- dollar doing it in some places
-- that's
literally happening in China where they're finding
baby formula and milk and things like that that have been laced
with awful things because some company made a little bit more money.
And I mean, this is what was happening in the United States
where there was, I watched a documentary, I forget the guy's name,
but it was like this
basically mad scientist person who ended up, he was like,
he found volunteers to slowly poison to prove that like
all these additives and food were bad
and it's a completely banana story for sure.
But it's still even with all this evidence and even
with all the research and everything that was going on,
it took decades to see real change.
But I think fundamentally places have to get better at this.
Otherwise you're going to have events, you know, where like some r
some
worm comes through your infrastructure and,
and destroys your company potentially.
-- I
-- mean, maybe it, it's, I, I think about this one a lot.
-- I mean,
-- so let's let me put it this way.
Can you you can't get a business lease without insurance.
Nobody will lease you a space unless you're insured because
it's just, that's a thing.
Right.
Right. Well, well, although why is it a thing?
It's a thing because the owner of the property wants to understand that
their risk is lower if you have insurance. Right.
And I think that's what it comes down to
and when we think about things like cybersecurity,
I mean, let's frame it in the context of this, this ridiculous windows update.
Right.
There's going to be loads of people who don't install this particular patch
set because maybe they don't know or they're not paying attention or whatever.
There's a million reasons, right? And so who's going to say you have to do this thing?
Nobody.
And if they don't do it, maybe they have a bad thing happen.
Maybe they don't, who's to say?
I guess what I'm saying is I'm past the point of feeling sorry for them.
-- Oh,
-- I don't feel bad for them at all.
You know,
when these companies get hacked and it turns out they have terrible infosec.
It's like,
-- yeah, that's, that's literally what happens. I agree. I
-- agree.
If you get punked because you did a dumb thing that's on you.
-- You made a mistake like that was just dumb.
-- Ok. This is wild because I'm seeing
sorry when I said 100 and 17
1 site says 100 and 17 1 says 100 and 21 says more than 100 and 21 says 100 and 26.
And how come we can't get basic agreement on this fact?
That blows my mind.
-- Which fact is
-- this
-- on how many CV S are on Microsoft Tuesday this month?
-- I don't know.
-- I haven't, I didn't count,
-- I'm seeing different numbers all over the place.
-- It
-- could be. I mean, again, this is, these are hard topics,
whatever.
Um
I just,
I don't know,
I,
I feel like again, if you're using, if you're trying to use Windows as a,
as a true multi user system, you,
-- you can't safely do that. I'm sorry, it just doesn't work
-- that way.
No, nothing is multiuser anymore.
I think it is clear that using anything multi user is just dumb.
We've had so many security problems that only affect
a system that has multiple users.
And now we have so much virtualization and containerization technology,
it's foolish to even try
to put more than one user on the same logical system or virtual.
-- I don't know what you call it, virtual system,
-- whatever.
And again, people, you know, that's an extra cost, that's extra hassle,
that's extra expertise.
And people just aren't going to do it because we've had stuff like that.
-- Hell, even in the Windows world for decades,
-- maybe. I don't know.
Well, I, I've seen it deployed like it, it does exist,
I don't know anything about Windows. Like
you could you could just make up lies to me and be like, oh, ok. That sounds neat.
Like, literally no idea.
I,
no, I, I don't know. I just because part of like, I, I've been seeing to segue
the topic of smart contract security audits has come up a
lot recently and I basically apply the knowledge I have from,
you know, standard source code auditing, which is,
you know, given a billion dollars. Would you bet your life it's bug free.
Well, of course not. Right. You want to live
and even if your contract is bug free,
the system it's running on might have some flaw
that then can be exploited through the contract.
And so what I've been trying to tell people is
that you have to plan and build for failure.
Right. So a perfect example of that is fire insurance.
I've done a variety of things to make my house fire safe.
You know, I've got to buy a whole bunch of smoke alarms.
I generally, you know, I do my campfires outside the house, not inside the house,
-- you know. So that's an important safety tip right there.
-- What is that a problem like?
Um, well,
uh uh uh quite a few derelict buildings locally have been burnt
down by homeless people setting fires inside to stay warm in winter.
I see.
So,
yeah,
and I do have a fireplace which I actually did get a
chimney sweep out to clean and make sure it was correct.
And he, you know, he, he put one line of beating of, uh,
to make it more air proof on the bottom.
Like, literally it was like
a minor thing, but, you know, carbon monoxide can come out of there.
And that's not a happy gas. It's a sad gas,
but I still have fire insurance
because despite everything I've done,
I'm still planning that there's that small possibility that my place burns down.
And
the thing I realized from having my garage be hit by a neighbor's
car is it's also not just about the money but it's ok.
It's 3 a.m. on a Tuesday. Your house just burned down. Who do you call?
Yeah. Well, I have no idea.
But my,
my insurance adjuster knows a guy who knows a guy called Noah who
shows up with a load of lumber and fixes my garage in like,
seven hours.
Right. Right. No. And, and that's, I mean, that's one of the reasons.
-- Yeah, I think insurance is beneficial. I mean, well, for
-- them it's Tuesday.
Right. Well, yeah, they do this every day.
For me it's a major life altering event and for them it's Tuesday.
I mean, so here is where I want to pull this back into the realm of, of security.
There was also something I saw on Twitter where obviously everyone's like, oh,
what are we going to name?
The new Microsoft worm that's inevitably going to come out for RDP and someone says,
oh, we should have a list of names just like the National Weather Service
hurricane
names. And another person says we can't even agree on what major events are.
How are we possibly going to start naming them?
And it's like
none of these people are wrong in any way
because it is a very strange and difficult problem.
But now, I guess at the same time,
the National Weather Service has very specific metrics
that dictate what is a hurricane and what is not. And like, you can measure wind speed
-- and
-- categories.
Right. Right. All that stuff
in the world of security.
What, what's an event?
I mean, one of my favorite examples is so there was log for Shell, right,
which was like a big to do and it was,
none of us will forget it for a long time.
Then a couple of weeks ago,
there's this thing called spring for Shell that comes up in the spring framework.
And to be perfectly honest, Spring for Shell is a dud,
like there's a bunch of organizations trying to make a big deal about it,
but the reality is like,
no one's really affected and I don't think I haven't heard of anyone being exploited
by this because it's one of those like these 10 insane things have to be done
in order for you to be vulnerable and no one has done that.
And like,
so it has a name,
it shouldn't,
but who, who decide, you know what I mean?
I hate to do this. I'm going to read a slide. I just wrote yesterday.
-- Coordinations of vulnerabilities.
-- Oh,
-- yeah,
-- this is still terrible
in the open
source world. The distro and Linux
list
are still run by sor
from a single server,
right?
There's this one guy named solar designer who's been
like running this for 20 plus years because,
-- well, thank you. I don't.
-- Yeah, he's an awesome dude.
Uh Twitter hashtags were successful with hashtag log
for
shell, but relying on spontaneous self-organization
isn't exactly reliable.
Very certain organizations exist that can help with regional response.
And here's the kicker, this is a very hard problem due to lack of standards,
infrastructure and so on eeg secure messaging.
Like I was looking into this the other day. So we've got things like Sam L and
Oath for authentication between providers, right?
Like so I can use Google as my sso to access
mail gun or Sendgrid or whatever. But
let's say I want to send a piece of data from provider A to
provider B that says like this document is classified as X severity X,
whatever.
There's no way to do that. And so what we're finding is
within an ecosystem of like Amazon or Microsoft or Salesforce.
You can take your data classify it, restrict access to it and do a good job there.
But the minute it leaves that ecosystem, it kind of loses all that stuff
and there's no way to protect it, you know.
So like this one company had red, yellow, green data,
like really sensitive sort of sensitive public,
kind of like once the red stuff leaves and Microsoft,
it's like the Microsoft ecosystem.
It's like, you know, we put it on a Linux server to serve it out
through the web securely
that the data that defines what we want to do with it can't go with it.
And I'm like, yeah, those standards don't exist. I'm sorry.
Um, and we're seeing this increasingly because it's so bizarre, but
most of these large companies don't want to be locked into a single vendor.
It's very strange.
-- Well,
-- yeah,
that
might have happened before and it didn't work out real good.
Here's a real simple example. You find a massive vulnerability.
How do you communicate with all these different organizations?
And I don't mean, like,
process wise, I mean, like, do you use email? Do you use text messages? Signal?
Telegram, whatsapp?
I mean, we historically used Twitter and like
you and I know how to do this because we've done it a lot.
But I think, imagine a, someone who, who a new researcher
who doesn't have a rolodex full of contacts,
what would they even do?
And I was about to say that
when you say use email, do you mean, like, I just
randomly pick a list of people to email or is there like a mailing list? I can use,
we know who to email.
That's what I'm
saying
is
this is,
this is why like, solar design is so hard to replace because
even though he has like a public list of who's on the thing, it's still like,
do I, it's like maintaining the host file? Right?
Like, do I maintain my own host file with who I trust?
No, God, no, I want to outsource that to somebody.
And it's just,
it's ridiculous that we, we don't even have like I'm gonna say it,
we don't have a good secure messaging standard and I'm sorry.
But if somebody says P GP or GP G, no, that lost.
I,
I stopped doing it one day with like I used to
religiously sign all my email and then one day I stopped
and nobody noticed or cared to tell me and asked why did you stop signing your email?
Right.
I was a third of the traffic to that, you know,
uh oh, it's a sec list and
nobody cared to notice. So
it's, we're, we're lacking just even basic stuff of like if I want like,
how do I physically get a message over to Bob?
I
-- email?
-- I've got to reframe this discussion.
I don't think it matters. I think
the problem I see is you're complaining about secure messaging,
secure messaging isn't the problem because we just
don't even have like the vernacular and capability of
bringing the right people together and having an
honest and real discussion messaging is step 12.
We don't even have step one.
-- Well,
-- I,
sorry, that's kind of what's implied here is it's,
it's a very concrete example of like you, we can't even do that
quote unquote, simple thing of sending a message to the right person.
Yeah, let alone who is the right person
-- or
-- what are you going to tell them?
And how are you going to coordinate it?
And I mean,
this is why Google Project Zero has taken like the hard stance they have of
90 days because this is what happens is you send a message to someone like,
oh, well, we have to tell these people and then these people and they're like,
you have 90 days
figure it out.
You know what I mean?
Because if you don't, otherwise it turns into, you know, two years later,
we're still trying to figure out who to email about this.
And that's essentially my argument about you
got to install your patches quickly or else
that's, it's the same argument, right? You just, yeah, it sucks.
And it's tough and it's, but you just got to do this.
It's like I have to do laundry otherwise I'll smell weird.
I mean,
yeah,
but
like, I want to take advantage of all this technology safely.
Here's the biggest thing is for me, I just want it to be reliable and honestly
keeping up to date is generally more reliable than not keeping up to date,
ignoring security issues. Even
that's easier said than done.
You don't work for a company that's heavily regulated. You don't work for a company
that if your server crashes, someone dies,
you don't work for a company
that you have literally thousands of other businesses depending on.
And if you install an update and the system crashes, no one gets paid this week like
that is, it's not as simple as saying update or else nerd.
I mean, I think there's a lot of nuance in this.
The problem is at some point you're going to have to
do emergency updates because there is a worm stomping around,
-- you know, and you need to patch for
-- it.
Not necessarily like this is what compensating controls are for
-- if they exist. But
-- I think so, here's, here's my complaint.
I think there are always people on each side of this argument.
Some are gonna say update now or else some are going to say
I can't update because my systems go down and they crash and stuff.
But I think
like all problems, there's something in the middle
where
yes, you definitely want to install these updates.
But obviously, depending upon what your situation is,
you might not be able to do that.
So if you can't,
here are the other things you should be doing in the meantime,
not as a long term solution,
but just to get you by until you can install these updates. And I think
taking either stance
is absurd and I think we end up in
situations where people on each side of these discussions
just end up talking over the top of each
other because they don't want to hear anything.
And then you have just the schmuck stuck in the middle who are trying to do their job.
And it's really hard though because the noisy people are on each side.
Yeah. I, I, what you just said help.
I think part of it is
I would prefer to see people do patching rather
than compensating controls who wouldn't get their patching down
and get that under control before doing compensating controls
and trying to do magic stuff around that.
Of course, no one would disagree with that statement.
But it's also
not practical.
This is like saying Kurt, that the solution to poverty is don't be poor.
Like, no, it's not.
That's not the solution at all.
Well,
but I think part of the challenge is statistically the people who
aren't patching are also not generally doing a ton of compensating controls.
They're just neglecting their it.
And that's another problem
that is well outside of our ability to discuss or,
and, I mean, this is even true of fire safety. Right. There are
good of the people that have piles of oily rags in the corner
and like, don't do that.
There's a building a few blocks away from here that just burned down, right?
Uh, 43 or four story apartment thing.
And apparently it turns out most of the people there did not have renters insurance.
I feel like I heard this story on the radio or something.
Well, no,
it's a low income area and so a lot of these people don't have fire insurance.
I doubt that they can really afford it. You know, with the rise
with, with the way the cost of living has been rising here, especially in Canada and
I feel bad for them. But at the same time, it's like
we can't, I, I don't know that we as a society can, like,
cover all those insurance costs.
You know, because I also worry then that people might have more reckless behavior.
Right. That moral hazard aspect. Right.
And I don't know what the answer is because I don't want to see the people suffer.
But at the same time it's like, but can we as a society afford to make them whole, like,
in the long term?
You know, if, if everybody gets free fire insurance,
are people going to be less fire safety?
I don't know.
-- I doubt it because people generally don't like burning their stuff down.
-- But
I,
I don't think, you know, the case at all. And
no,
but I think your,
what you hit upon is a social topic I do not wish to discuss because it is,
it's complicated and difficult we'll say.
But
anyway,
it even varies significantly within a city.
Let alone with, between different countries.
But this is even true of it. Security.
Right.
Where you can look at
what it, security looks like across
a billion organizations and
it, it's the same problems you can, you can map them into
societal issues of,
you have the gamut of, can't afford to do this thing.
They know they should do to, don't care because they're incompetent to.
I'm doing everything correct and I'm spending loads of money on this and
it's going to save me tons of headache someday because of it.
You know,
it's all the same problems. And I think in summary,
humans are squishy bags of meat who do dumb stuff.
And that's exactly why I'm,
that is actually my biggest argument for getting the
hardware two factor authentication keys out is like I
keep going over all the failure scenarios of everything
else and it's like we remove the meat bags
whenever
possible. Yes. I mean, that's,
I think if you look at the,
the vast majority of successful, almost anything in the world
when you can take out human mistakes, things get better.
I mean, this is true of like automation in general. Right.
Where less humans, less problems.
Well, passive safety measures like airbags.
Right. Right. Exactly.
Anti lock brakes, airbags, you know, crumple zones,
the ton of things, uh,
that are probably very subtle in your car that we don't even think about that.
Some engineers like, yeah, we spent 17,000 hours on that, you know,
to reduce something by 0.07 of a percent of risk.
But
-- by the
-- way, oh, perfect example,
uh, when you're doing wiring, you know how the wire goes into a metal box.
Well,
you have to have something around that to protect
it so it doesn't chafe and then short out,
you know, things like that.
Right.
Because I was redoing some wiring and I found one or two things that were done wrong.
Well, everything I've done wrong
anyway. Anyway, II, I agree. I agree. I think
anyway, in summary, update your systems, everybody.
Yeah,
and maybe go for a bike ride but don't push it too hard.
Yeah, that's true. I'm really, I'm hurt and I stand up when I recorded like,
I'm feeling it, man. I'm gonna have to go lay down after this. I think
I, I really, my back really hurts like I'm not gonna lie to you.
So let's, let's end it so I can end my excruciating torment. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
Easy
Podos podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.
The