Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in talking about printers
and the crimes that they commit upon humanity.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- It is true. Kurt and I were just whining about our printers.
Anyone who's ever had to like feed and care for a printer,
-- we know exactly what we mean
-- and worse like you
and I have both found a printer that works reasonably,
not terribly,
but
one day we'll have to replace it. And I, I fear that day enormously.
I know, man, it's like in my top 10 anxiety inducing problems that could happen.
-- Like
-- I spent, I think three months shopping, like,
researching printers before I bought this one
because like, topics like,
do I have to install dumb software that'll like
root my system so I can print a document
that
can I,
you know, the toner crutches? Can I put the chip out into a new one?
So I don't have to pay 100
and change for a new toner cartridge.
Uh
Anyways, which is kind of actually the theme of today's episode.
-- It's like, uh, the C programming language apparently has pulled a printer did
-- they?
This is just C like, ok,
so
-- Kurt found a document. Well, someone I think sent it to us on Mastodon,
-- right?
I saw it on Mastodon
in my feed. Ok.
Mastodon is the new, uh
-- I was going to say Twitter, the new X.
-- Oh, my goodness.
I will never call it that like my brain just won't let me.
So the,
the title of this paper is C and C++ prioritize performance over Correctness.
-- Lets do most
-- devs,
I mean, as ac programmer, I read that. I was like, well, yes, yes, they do. And like, I,
-- this is normal
-- and people forget we come from an age where computers used to be slow.
Like 20 years ago, computer
were slow and performance matters.
-- They're still slow at certain things, but they're
-- OK.
But like I was gripping a data set that it took like seven minutes to grip,
but it was a data set that was so large 20 years ago.
You couldn't have had it.
-- You didn't own enough disks. Like
-- literally,
I was working with a 2.6 gigabyte
JSON file just
casually throwing it into emacs and hitting. Yes when it warns me that.
Oh, it's a big,
it's more 10 megabytes. Oh,
and I'm like, you
like
64 gigs of ra M 24 gigs of video memory.
Uh I think I have eight cores or maybe
12. I don't know, don't care. And a two terabyte Western digital black SS SD which is
rated for, what is it? 1.1 million
write iops per 2nd and 1.2 million read. Iops.
I mean
like OK.
-- OK.
-- Build me a like build me a disc cluster 10 years ago. That would do a million iops.
-- And the answer is sure if you give me like a billion dollars,
-- 10 years,
probably 20 years.
-- No.
-- OK. 20 years. No,
no, I remember working with some of those Giant Disco.
It was, man,
I,
I don't,
I don't want to dwell on old man, hard work stories today.
I want to, there's a bigger aspect of this see thing and I want to,
there is a person I've come to know and respect named Nisha.
I will link to Nisha's
toot. I don't know what to call it anymore because I think they renamed it
where
-- you can't rename it. It's decentralized. We decide what it means.
-- OK?
I guess I don't care anyway.
And
they, they used the term I really liked,
which was frustration reduction in the context of security
because it's obvious that we can't scare people straight like
we've tried, it doesn't work.
And I think this C document
kind of talks about that a lot and it's
partially because C is old and just partially because
it's kind of machine language. I, so when I, OK,
when I program in C, I don't think about C,
I think about what it's turning into the
machine code underneath essentially because I'm so old.
Like I had to actually write machine code at one time because
it's the only way to program microprocessors back in the day.
Like you couldn't write C
there's crypto libraries like open SSL had stuff written in assembler because,
and they still do, they still do.
There's still things that are written in assembly like
in the Linux kernel to go faster and whatever.
Now the point is.
So when you're like C and C++ and assembly, like they just do what they're told,
right?
There's no assumptions that
a variable will be empty before you use it. There's no assumptions.
-- There's no safety nets.
-- No, absolutely not. Like
the
-- compiler maybe tries to
-- help you with, it's better.
Now a lot of compilers check a lot of things like, for example,
let's say you have an uninitialized variable, that's the one I'm gonna pick on.
It's the first one in this paper.
It's the one all of us know and love from C programming day. So like in Python, right,
if I create, let's say a string,
can you even make an empty, like an uninitialized string? In Python?
I don't think you can
make
um when you say uninitialized,
you can make a variable and it can be blank like
you can initialize an empty list like fu equals square bracket,
-- square bracket,
-- right?
-- And it's just an empty list, right?
-- Or an empty string or an empty D
-- we
-- use an empty list. A list is good because in Python, I can say this is a list, right?
The variable is an empty list. Now, in C
if I say I need an array, we'll use the word array because they don't have lists,
they have arrays.
I need an array that is 10 things long, right? It says great.
Here's a block of memory that can hold 10 of those things
-- and
-- you better tell them how big that thing is correctly.
Yeah, that too
-- dictionaries in it.
-- Right.
Yes, I have a list that contains strings, integers, dictionaries
and everything else.
-- I can
-- think of binary objects, another computer and
yeah,
Python doesn't care at all.
-- Right. I love that, you know,
-- a running copy of Minecraft.
It's really funny because a lot of go developers especially,
they detest that about Python.
It's like my favorite thing,
the fact that I can literally put like any garbage in it and it works.
My favorite thing is that
the way Python handles
Json is you take the
JSON and just convert it into a Python variables.
And it's like,
and then you walk the list of lists and dictionaries and
-- whatever the hell, whatever it is. Yeah.
-- Who knows what, who knows what it is.
It can be.
I have some hilarious code where I had to do that one time and I'm like 20
layers deep and I it's like I'm not and I have a comment at one point.
It's like I'm not even sorry. It's just, it's so hard to follow anyway.
So now in CN C++,
if I tell the compiler, like give me an array,
it just gives me an array and whatever happened to have been
in memory at that time is what is in the array.
So it's up to me to clear the memory or fill the memory with actual data
or know that it is full of uninitialized data, right?
In modern compilers, if I do that, the compiler will at least say, hey,
you're using an uninitialized variable, like you declared this variable,
but nothing has been written to it.
And now you're reading from it, something is wrong.
But back in the day, none of that existed,
right? Like the compiler just did what you told it to do.
-- And that was that like
-- I'm trying to see,
I know windows now does zero initialized memory.
But
I mean, it didn't always do that obviously
does for some, it doesn't always. And the problem.
So the reason we don't do that by default, usually I know you can,
I believe you can tell the compiler
to do that now by default, the modern ones.
But the reason you didn't do that is computers were too slow.
And so you couldn't trust that they would, it would allocate
the memory and then zero it fast enough for whatever it is you were trying to do
which to us now
sounds absurd.
But like
when you're talking about a machine running at Killer Hertz,
that is a big deal.
Well, the latency on that. Yeah.
And memory was slow and disc was slow. Everything was terrible.
I mean, the fact that anything worked at all is an absolute miracle. Yeah,
it was, it was bad. But anyway, so the point is right.
So this is where if we put on our security hats and we think about
the whole security versus usability argument, you know,
where we're frustration reduction as, as we'll call it.
This is where
as security people, we love to say
that you should do this thing because it's more secure,
-- it's more correct and better
-- and it might be more correct.
I mean, technically correct is the best kind of correct, right? And
the reality is when you're working with users
and developers and people who aren't security nerds,
they literally don't care.
Their job is to add the feature and make it work, not make it secure.
Well, here's the thing I keep coming back to
even if you have a giant glaring security flaw,
it may not get exploited. Uh For sure
I have on multiple occasions accidentally left my front door unlocked
and come home and it's ok and I know nobody came
in because I have a doorbell camera and all that stuff.
But fundamentally
user interaction with the system
on security may or may not happen but on performance and stability
and features that they want
absolutely will happen.
Yeah, absolutely.
If the system is slow, that will hit the user guaranteed every time.
And not only that, how many security features get in the way of users.
I mean, I'm gonna pick on Se Lennox as our favorite whipping boy here, but like
Se Linux gets in the way a lot and it's really hard to fix.
So the solution for virtually everyone is turn it off.
I was about to say, is it enabled or disabled in my VM? Uh It's not even there.
If you're not running a red hat system,
-- you probably don't have the
-- cli I ran the command Gettin Force and
it said command Getin Force not found but can be installed with.
There you go.
Does this thing even happen?
Se Linux?
What, what, what VM, what are you running for your operating system?
It's
ubuntu, whatever came from the Microsoft store, Ubuntu, LTs. Ubuntu
likes App Armor like you can, I believe you can run Sc Linux in
Ubuntu, but App Armor is definitely their side
and App Armor has a whole other set of weird problems that I'm not even going to touch.
But
and I mean, App Armor is a great example of App Armor. Tried to be
-- App
-- Armor module is not loaded, not
loaded.
They tried to be slightly more user friendly than Se Linux.
-- That was Crispin Cohen's stuff, right? Originally,
-- Crispin did that
and and they, it's funny because the Se Linux people, like, oh, well,
they don't do it this way and it's less secure and, like,
-- you're
-- not wrong and everybody's like, don't care.
-- I can actually configure up armor
-- but they can't anyway because it's still too hard.
So no one leaves it on
and it, it's kind of one of those instances. Right.
This is, this is again where we come back to, like, usability versus security
is if you make something secure and I'll put secure in air quotes,
but it's really hard to use.
People get annoyed and frustrated and they just
turn it off because they can't be bothered.
You're also making a major fallacy that assumes that
what you're doing will make it more secure.
And I would actually say I would not make that assumption because I've seen
people do things and they make that argument of this will be more secure,
a little less usable.
We can make that trade off. And I'm like, this actually doesn't make it more secure.
It just makes it more unusable. That does happen.
And a great example of this is session, time notes, session,
time outs don't matter anymore because what's going to happen is like L TT
found out they opened up a PDF and it hijacked their live session,
session, time notes
no longer matter what you do need is step up authentication. So
Kurt wants to change his password. Ok. Put in your key Kurt wants to delete the organ.
-- Ok. Put in your key and answer a physical snail mail with a pin code. Right.
-- Exactly. I
mean, that, that's exactly right.
But again, so this is where I also like to pick on like voodoo security
where there's a nontrivial amount of what we call security,
best practices that aren't actually best practices.
There, there are things a smart person thought was a good idea
or they might have been good practices 20 years ago.
-- I don't think they were then either, but
-- a
lot
of them probably weren't. But
like, that's part of the problem too is they might have been valid 20 years ago
and they're not anymore. And there's
like, in the medical world, there's so many things like that,
like the way they do c sections cut vertically or horizontally
and vertically,
like it's much better. I forget which one is the correct way. But I don't know.
But I
heard that before there was like, this commonly accepted ulcer, like the whole,
you know,
oh, you have like an upset tummy. It's stress, blah, blah, blah.
And this one guy is like, I think it might be bacteria. And so the ulcer guy. Yeah.
And he, like,
got almost drummed out and they got a Nobel Prize.
OK.
I want to explain this because anyone under the age of old
has no idea what, what we're even talking about.
So, when Kurt and I were young there was a medical condition called an ulcer,
which you got in your stomach.
-- And it was very painful and it was very
-- disruptive.
It's an open wound in your stomach,
basically. Yes.
And they, they could literally like kill people if they got bad. Right.
-- And the assumption
-- was that someone firsthand that
had their stomach removed due to untreated ulcers.
Oh, man, that's
so they have
a
pouch now and they eat like 10 times a day because they have no stomach, right?
It was a huge deal.
And so, but when we were young,
ulcers were caused by stress and poor diet and all this stuff.
And yeah, some researcher was like, hey,
-- I think, is it a virus?
-- No bacteria? It was bacteria
because
it was a 10 day course of antibiotics and
boop done.
And, and so anyway, this guy,
he did all this research and it was funny because people were like, you're crazy.
This isn't real.
It reminds me of the guy who is like, oh, you should, everyone should wash their hands
-- and, and they like, drove him insane and he literally, they
-- had him committed
the bacterium.
He uh helicobacter
pylori.
But, right? Like this is an example of ulcers don't exist.
No one even talks about this anymore.
And they were an enormous problem.
What, 30 years ago?
Well, I mean, it's,
it's like,
it's in all the movies and TV shows the fifties and sixties like the man's like, oh,
I got, ok, I can't get angry. Uh, my ulcer.
Right. Right. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And security reminds me of that sometimes. Yeah.
-- Like
-- somebody like Barry Marshall,
that's the guy who did this research and got the Nobel Prize.
They come along with some reasonable proposition and even better what I love is.
And they're like, I'm pretty sure this is correct, but you know what,
I'm not 100% certain.
I think we should research it and everybody's like, no,
the witch.
Ok. Now, on that note, I want to bring up the rust binary
debacle. I don't know what to even call it.
Um, I think it didn't rise to the level of debacle.
I would say it was a, a solid seven on the kerfuffle scale.
I, I would give, ok, I'll, I'll agree with that. So what happened was
there is a rust crate called ser
S er dec,
right?
And anyway,
ser
whatever
it.
Right. So they have this crate that a lot of people use. It's very, very common.
Um, a lot like damn near everything that does serialization and deser.
It's one of
it.
Well, well, the conversation will go there.
Yeah. And, and Saturday is cer deserializing
is my assumption of what it stands for. But I don't, I can't prove that. But anyway,
so
they had a bug opened
a couple, a couple of days ago at the time,
maybe a week at the time of us recording and basically
it was uh I think it was a packager for Fedora
noticed there was a binary blob
inside of this package and he was like, hey, uh I can't ship this what's going on.
And the developer was like, this is the this default now like deal with it
and
hilarity ensued.
And one of the arguments was people saying, oh,
how can we trust the binary blob in this pile of source code?
-- Because you totally reviewed all that source code. Well, and
-- that's just it, right?
Like, ok,
so you're gonna say the binary blob is maybe dangerous but
you're already installing probably a million lines of source code.
-- You didn't look at reviewer
-- rights when I type pip install or
whatever. The other ones are like
a whole pile of stuff goes flying by.
Yeah, no idea
-- of it is
-- my favorite is I, you know, I,
I type in something and it's like this will install 246 megabytes of packages.
Yes.
Go get a coffee.
Well, some and so that's a funny thing too. Python ships. Binaries.
-- Oh, I was talking about like apt get. But yeah, Python also. Well, there's
-- apt
get but even when you do a pip install of Python,
there are, if there is a prebuilt binary for your architecture,
it'll just install that and use it.
So like Python's already doing this.
It's just
obviously in the like Fedora Python world, they don't build the Binaries,
they use the binaries and Python has this ability, right.
They have wheels that know what to do.
And it, it's all very complicated and whatever it doesn't matter.
But the point is using security as this argument
is
not going to work because anyone who thinks about it for five minutes is like, oh,
I guess that doesn't really matter.
And here we go, here's the funny thing is, it's explained here, but basically
it was to do with compiling and building it and that
it was taking for damn ever because of its dependency chain.
-- And so by doing the binaries, it
-- just boop. Do you know how long forever is?
I don't know,
10 seconds,
nine seconds, they did this to save nine seconds.
Yeah.
But I mean, honestly, globally, carbon footprint wise, that probably matters
and that's fine. It just amused me that
from my history in compiling things, nine seconds is zero,
like anything under five minutes is zero.
I just,
I remember when I finally got my DX 266 tune to
compile a Linux kernel in less than a couple hours.
I,
I remember building a kernel one time on a 386 computer.
It literally took like three days.
Yeah.
My friend would actually compile on my system and download his
updated Linux kernel over 9600 bond from my computer at night,
man. The old man stories.
Anyway. Anyway.
Ok.
Well, then that's kind of ridiculous to save nine seconds,
but still nine seconds is nine seconds.
Well, I don't, I don't think it is nine seconds matters to people
and the point is like, nine seconds or not, it doesn't matter. Right. But
their intent was to do this in a way that makes the user's life easier.
-- And I have a suspicion, security
-- people do not like that.
No. No, they don't.
And I have a suspicion many of the users
would rather save the nine because here's the thing,
if,
if you install 300 rust packages and every package can save nine seconds.
Now, you're talking about real money, three quarters of an hour.
And so this is where
it's not nine seconds times 300 that's not three quarters of an hour.
Is it 2700 seconds?
Is it? I don't know. I can't do math in my head.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna get out my, my calculator here,
out of my pocket that I walk around with every day that my math teacher said I wouldn't
uh nine seconds times 300. I said
20 divided by 60 45 minutes. It
three quarters of an hour.
That's
bananas.
Ok. So that's ridiculous because most rust things compile pretty fast.
But you get the point right.
And, and obviously most rust things compile in under a second, I
think,
or most of the, the crates, but whatever.
Well, on a modern machine. Sure. But you get the point right.
Is this is one of those examples of if
your argument is gonna be security versus usability,
security is already lost.
Like there's no argument here.
Now, I will say, I think you can easily make an argument about reliability here
because one of my complaints and I'm sure you're familiar with this
is when you would get like some random binary from somewhere,
like back in the day and it wouldn't run.
And then you were like, let me install this library and now this library, you know,
this library like, oh good, it started running.
Oh, it crashed.
I'm in CLL health. There's a word for that in windows,
right? And
this is the, the concern I have isn't the speed of the compile.
It's the fact that I have a binary now
that in
a year or two or three or whatever
might just start randomly crashing because they changed something in
Glib C or whatever
and no one knows why. And it's hard to figure out,
but again, not secure.
-- And
-- that actually speaks to, well as a sideways and this might be a separate episode.
But the dod
essentially wanting people to work on, take this binary blob,
turn it back into source code.
And I would have said in the past, that's damn near impossible.
But now with generative A I, I'm like
-- probably
-- even with a generative A Iii
I know I've talked about this in the past, but like
Mario 64 the Nintendo 64 game.
They have reversed engineered the ROM and they have
C code that when you compile the C code,
you literally get exactly the Mario 64 rom.
So they can prove like this is a reproducible build.
They can prove the C code they have
generates the rum and now people are making amazing hacks
and fixing bugs and doing all kinds of wild stuff.
-- So this is very, very
-- doable.
I think that might be an extra episode because that really raises like for example,
the member Ibmib MS Bio
was
essentially reverse engineered by having some guy take it apart and document it,
implementing a
non nation state
sanctioned firewall. So it's a private firewall in between the two of them.
All right. So basically, like this guy
produced the spec, this guy implemented the spec and so technically,
there was no copyright or trademark or whatever shenanigans.
No, it's not technically like this is called Clean Room. Reverse engineering.
-- It's used all the time.
-- Clean Room implementation.
Don't say reverse engineering because
that will not go well in front of a job.
But like this is very reasonable.
And yes, that is exactly what compact did to the IBM Bios and it worked.
-- Was it
-- compact? I thought it was Microsoft,
I thought it was compact. I don't know,
-- doesn't matter. No
-- Microsoft was friends with IB at that time. The
fact that
yeah, I the fact that these big companies have friends like Sony Suit itself,
look, their friends in the regard.
They're not actively trying to stab each other in the kidneys. Like that's,
I was gonna say they're like friends in the,
in the sense of nation states not having a nuclear war.
Right. Exactly. Exactly. But the point is OK.
So this reverse engineering thing I can relate to this.
So the first job I had out of college
we had
this life insurance software that was written
in Cobal obviously because every uh probably,
I probably still is written in coal.
But
they had a ZL
binary. They linked into their Cobal
and it was a binary. No one knew where no one even knew where it came from.
Like they literally had a binary in their build that got linked in to give them ZL
-- for compression
-- came from a developer workstation
or a website.
Yeah. Where did this come from? Nobody knew.
In fact, they didn't even know what it was like. I figured out it was Z
Lib by running strings on the binary because it was, it had a weird name.
I'm like, oh, this is just Z
Lib and they were like, what?
Now I'm like, oh my goodness, why, how are you people using this?
But the thing, yes, someone added it probably 1520 years before that.
You know, I don't know if Z lib existed 20 years before that. But,
-- but you get the point
-- right.
-- Zip's been around a long time. But
-- anyway,
this is an example of the government is full of crap like this. Right.
The government is filled with binaries that they don't know where they came from.
They have no idea what they do.
They just know if I don't copy this file into this folder,
-- nothing
-- works.
And even better that they're required by law to
run that piece of software to do that job.
Right.
Exactly.
I mean, this is, what isn't it?
Boeing has to run Windows 95 for some, like, software they need that.
Built the 747 or something like that.
-- Like, probably,
-- yeah, I mean, I just,
I remember always when the BC corporate registry,
a lady wanted to name her company in her
native language and the BC corporate registry is like,
yeah,
cool.
No,
like, and everybody's like, oh, why are they such jerks? And it's like,
because the BC Corporate Registries Act that they are governed by says they can't,
like, it can only be in English and French
and assuming you change that act,
all the software has been written assuming English or French and not,
it certainly doesn't support unit code because it was written in the eighties
and everything downstream of it will break and like, just, I'm sorry, but no,
without, you know, essentially rewriting a massive chunk of our infrastructure.
And
so we found an OK solution for her.
But, but fundamentally, it's kind of like we're not trying to be jerks.
But, you know, and there's so much government stuff where it's regulated and it's,
yeah.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, for sure. 100%.
The thing I find fascinating is in, here in Canada,
all federal government forms are required by law to be
in English and French because we have two official languages.
Right. In America. That's not the case.
It's just by, it's just by common practice that they're all in English
and maybe other languages,
-- right?
-- But there's no law that says that.
Right. No, no, there is not. And they're almost universally English
when I used to do my ta like back in the day
you'd go to the post office to get forms because they had forms
and they would always have like three copies of the English tax
form and then like a giant box of the French ones here.
Sure. I mean, that makes sense.
-- But
-- anyways, yeah, it's, I think that that reverse engineer because yeah,
like I was gonna say that
Zed Lip is probably not a security problem until it is.
And like there was just that thing with Winrar where you unpack an archive
and it
arbitrarily executes code. Oops,
that's normal. It's fine. It's a feature, it's fine.
But right, and, and look, I ignoring that, right. Just the fact is again,
the dod, well, the government, the US government,
they're using all this binary crap
and it's, they don't care about the security aspect. Of it. Right.
That in some cases they might do things to, to firewall it off or sandbox or whatever.
But fundamentally,
and they, they don't want the source code for security purposes.
They want the source code for usability because if they
have the source code now you can recompile it,
you can move it to another architecture, you can incorporate into other stuff.
But
Sed Lib was 1995
95. I would have started at that company in 01.
So
there you go.
Yep.
And what's more wild is the PPP deflate protocol is from,
-- guess which year
-- PPP deflate PPP is from what?
-- Probably the late
-- eighties
96. How's that?
The PPP compression protocol? Oh, because they would have to do Z Lib first. Right.
Do
well,
they had compress and there were other compression
algorithms but ZZ Lib was by far the,
I guess,
easiest to use and, and best,
and we still use it today. Right.
Like we haven't come up with anything better, which is wild.
Well, no, it's not that we haven't come up with anything better.
The problem is we haven't come up with anything better.
That's better, better enough to actually replace Zed
Lip.
Right. Right.
-- And, well, not only that.
-- So, no, we have better things.
We have B zip, we have XZ, we have a lot of things that are faster and
-- squishier.
-- No, they're not. I don't think they're faster, are they?
-- I think
-- uh some OK. Um I think B zip
and
said are slower to compress but faster to uncompress.
And so for like the software distribution
thing where you compress once uncompressed.
Many heck yeah, that's what we want, right? Like pay up on the front end and then
save money on the back end.
Um But fundamentally like
there are things that are faster and make use of CPU instructions
in clever ways
that are just faster.
And so, um but fundamentally
like if you get a 5% per
performance improvement in like compression time or something
that's not worth rewriting your software. And it's the problem is always
you're not rewriting just your software.
There's somebody else that you're talking to.
Yeah. The world runs on Z li
like it's everywhere, literally.
Yeah, that's like English one and at this point,
English one,
-- sorry guys. Yeah,
-- it doesn't matter how bad it is. Like
-- everyone uses it
-- like that. That was that comic con. How do you pronounce? Ouh.
Well, like cough brought Trough Fought like it gave like seven or eight examples.
And then the summary was like,
just don't even try just force br memorize how these words are pronounced
and like, ignore the rules because that's how that works.
-- Like, welcome
-- to English.
Nothing makes sense.
I'm not going to lead you on to the lead mind because I was led there by
-- I'm like, which, which
-- is,
which
whatever, whatever
all I wanna, I wanna bring this one home but with some more sees
because we can.
Right.
I,
I just want to run through this document and explain kind of some of
the things that are hilarious because we don't have to deal with these anymore.
Right there.
Uninitialized variables is where we started. That's the first one.
That's all we got to.
There's also arithmetic overflows
which when you're dealing with.
And this is funny because things like Python and stuff, they don't even, they don't,
this isn't a thing, right?
But
in the world of CPU arithmetic, you might have
an integer.
That is a known wi with number of bits.
So if you have a four bit integer, you'd have four is what?
124888 would be seven would be the largest number you can represent
because
you have to start counting at zero.
-- Right. You start at 00 is a number.
-- You should probably mention that
-- because a lot of programmers forgot.
-- That's true. That's
true.
Let's say you've got a four bit integer, it can make it to seven.
What happens when you add 1 to 7? You get zero,
it wraps around.
Right.
And, and that's unsigned and that's a whole, they're signed and unsigned and,
and there's right, there's two compliment and, and
there's so much weird stuff going on and, and they're all different.
Big Indian, little Indian, whatever.
And
-- I
-- finally read a good explanation of why
big Indian and little Indians sort of matter.
And from the being able to do arithmetic by bit
shifts and it's just like instant and I'm like,
whoa.
And so that's the thing. Like, back in the day
again, doing arithmetic on computers was horrifically slow.
And so you could do these clever tricks where you literally
just shifted bits up or down one to get the answer.
You can,
you can aa number by just shifting all the bits to, well to the left or right,
depending upon which direction you're going.
But towards the,
the most significant.
And now
it doesn't matter because we all have CPU
the
gigahertz.
But anyway, when, when you have an arithmetic overflow in C and C++,
that's what's known as
um um
oh crap. What do they call that undefined behavior? That's
right. And now there's also applications of that
and I love that it's undefined. It's like, well, no, it's wrong.
-- Like,
-- well, no, no, no, no, no, no, it's under,
well, there are,
there are architectures that,
that relied on this behavior to do certain activities
and actions like it is not unheard of.
But the problem is every,
every computer architecture would handle it differently.
Like today, virtually everything is X 80 six.
But like 3040 years ago, you had dozens of architecture.
-- It's back to
-- arms. Well, OK, I mean, arm, whatever
arms making a comeback.
Well, of course, it is. But you get the point right.
Like you could have a 31 bit IBM mainframe.
And what does that do with an injured overflow?
And some of those had traps in hardware that would catch this kind of stuff.
It was all completely different.
And so you couldn't rely on it,
but now
I'm going to keep going
for a sec, but
defining
the behavior and then deciding if it's correct or not,
you might
like, it's like, kind of like deciding to drive on the right
hand side of the road.
Like at some point, it matters less if it's correct in the sense of like optimal
and more in the sense of correct,
we just all agree to do that so that we all kind of know what happens.
And that's the other problem here is with the
way the words undefined and correct are being used.
I think that might be confusing some people
that's fair, that's fair.
Uh Infinite loops if you have an infinite loop that never exits,
it
is undefined what the compiler could do.
And there are compilers that would optimize
out infinite loops that never returned.
Well, no, I think we, they, they say it here. I think it's C++
yes, it says here, the problem C++ defines every side effect free loop.
Infinite loop can be assumed by the compiler to terminate
and so undefined behavior, right?
And, and this sounds again silly and it is, but
the fact that you don't know what's going to happen in this instance is the problem,
right?
Like that's the issue.
Uh null pointer usage. Oh my goodness, null pointers. Those are my favorite.
So a null pointer is
in C
you have a concept called a pointer which is
the variable just holds like AAA memory address,
right?
And it points to memory, right?
And you're basically saying, OK,
don't
worry about what's in the variable.
I want you to go to this location in
memory and that's the thing we're gonna do stuff with
what happens is you, you have a memory address, right?
Well, what happens if you're not pointing at anything?
Right?
You point at nothing null, right? You said that you said it to zero, you zero it out.
Now when you have a system, if you try to do something in the null
pointer space,
the reason that's undefined is because we like to think of, oh,
I'm just going to try to
address memory address zero.
I'm going to try to, to, to figure out what's that memory address here? Right.
And things would usually crash.
But what happens when you're trying to get the third thing in this array?
You go to zero plus three, right?
So now you're at that memory address and every
system handled the zero page as it was known
a little different.
And there are many, many when, when you and I started our career,
we thought null point or D reference bugs were harmless crashes.
And then I think, was it, was it Tavis or, or Chris Evans? One of those guys like,
or one of them basically figured out, oh, these bugs are real, like,
this is a big deal.
And then there have been countless instances where a null
point of D reference is used to actually run arbitrary code
which it's like, it's like when, when,
and the double free was found to be exploitable.
It like changed the world. It was hilarious.
This goes back, well, this the, the official of this goes back to 2002.
But well,
what I was trying to get at was basically is the no pointer de
run is a great example of trying to get people to do memory management.
People just,
it's like trying to get people to drive and use their turn signals consistently.
It's just not
right. And I mean, this is, this is the poster child of why
no one should use C or C plus ones anymore
because like
the programming language can deal with this crap.
So let it and it's just not an issue.
I
know.
Yeah, see, I would never argue that you shouldn't use C or C++ for a security reason.
I would say
you should never use it because you can be way more productive in other languages.
And
to put it bluntly for the vast majority of us, we don't need to optimize our code.
And by the time we finish optimizing our code Moore's law will have caught up.
I
-- mean, there is an aspect of that for sure
-- for the majority,
like are there a few corner cases like say crypto or the Linux kernel or whatever?
Yeah, but
I mean, this, you know, yeah,
like the majority of us build a house by throwing a bunch
of two by fours and plywood together and that's close enough,
you know.
Yeah, if you want to build the Hoover Dam,
you might need a structural engineer and a bit of concrete.
But fundamentally
for me, what always gets me is,
well, there was a study like if you write this line of code,
how many machine instructions does it result in?
Right? And obviously like going from assembler to C to like PHP to Python,
you know, you write like one line of Python and it pulls in
like a web browser, you know.
And so for me, it's just more about being productive than anything else. Like I,
because that's the thing, I feel like the people that are
the people who have ac code base,
they have ac code base.
Sure. Sure. And, and they're stuck with it for now. Absolutely.
And, and I get that I'm sensitive to that.
I'm not saying if you have it,
get rid of it because rewriting things often creates new
-- and horrible bugs
-- but never write anything new in it.
Yeah, if you're, if you're doing something new, like
literally anything else.
Php like I take PHP over C like,
-- well
-- and I love that people are like PHP is not performing.
I'm like, Facebook would say
no one cares.
It
doesn't matter
anyway. All right.
And then the last one on this document it says crashes out
of sorts and this is around doing comparisons in the sort.
Operator in C++
it's overly complicated.
I don't want to explain it and just know that like sorting sounds easy,
but C C++ made it hard.
Sorry
if, if C++ can do anything, it's making easy things hard. It's a good job.
C++ I raise my glass,
I was gonna say it makes things potentially very dangerous consistently.
-- I
-- mean,
it
-- is a language from another time and so fundamentally
-- how many C security bugs
are less than 10 character patches?
A
-- lot of them, it's usually like
-- a greater than, or a less than symbol or an equal symbol
or, or it should have been less than, instead of less than, or equal to or,
or a zero and a one or
whatever, very, very common. But that's the thing.
It makes it easy to make very small and simple mistakes and so fun of
the point of this whole episode. What I want to go out on
is throughout time,
there has never been an era where
people prioritize security above usability or features
or, and you know, the, the lovely words of, of Nisha is frustration reduction. Like
if your security
it, it can't just keep the, the level the same.
It actually has to make something better
and if security isn't making something better,
-- no one's gonna care.
-- Well, and that goes to that.
I've seen a lot of people trying to use the
security as enabler of X and trying to push security
so that we can then do something else at all like, or shut
them safely.
And I think that has the potential to work. But the problem is,
or you can just do it without the security,
-- which a lot of companies have done
-- for sure.
Because what is the,
what actually happens when you don't have security in most instances,
in most instances? Nothing happens.
And that's the problem. So you end up with this survivor bias
where people are, like, I don't have to care because it's gonna be fine.
I did this at my last job and nothing happened and it's like you are correct.
-- But
-- I,
I think it's worse than that because there's also the
survivor bias of all these companies had security incidents.
And like, so what they paid a fine,
it was probably cheaper than that.
They probably
-- didn't even pay a fine,
-- like, or, you know, it was, uh, if, if there was a fine,
-- it's still a lot cheaper than setting up a security program
-- and, and look, we're,
we're, uh, ok.
It's incentives, right. It's all about incentives.
Sometimes incentives cost money. Sometimes incentives are ease of use.
What is the incentive for security?
And in many instances, we don't have it,
which is why we try to peddle fear and
peddling fear doesn't work like it fails every time.
The way to go is insurance is tying this stuff to insurance
because the insurance companies then have the incentive to not pay out.
Yeah, they have incentive, which is money.
Like that's the thing. They have an incentive.
For example, it has to be insurance companies.
It can't be like, audits are tough because, well,
the audit companies like we want to get hired next year, we're not going to fail you.
Right. Oh,
-- of course.
-- You know,
and that's the thing. Insurance is slightly different
because
they, and they don't care about things that do or don't work.
They're going to look at the data and be like if, if this, then this right?
Insurance is,
I can't working for a life insurance company and
working with like actuaries who did this stuff?
It is
when you're a young person who's never really been in this field and you enter that.
-- It's like,
-- it's horrifying.
Yeah, it's, it's, it's a horror show.
It's a, it's a spreadsheet, it's a spreadsheet.
-- The number says X
-- literal death in a spreadsheet like it's bananas
and, and that's what I mean.
That's what it comes down to is security is if, if we want people
to listen to us, we have to give them a reason to listen to us and saying,
you'll be sorry if you don't listen to us isn't a reason
if it worked. Like,
I can't even imagine how easy parenting would be if that line of reasoning worked.
If that,
I mean, that's, if I want my kids to do something, I'll tell them not to,
like, people would wear seatbelts and stop at red lights.
But seriously, like, there's so many human behaviors that if they listen to,
you'll be sorry if you don't.
No, they, they, they aren't whatever.
-- And survivor bias says I don't have to care because it's
-- fun
because everybody that didn't listen and went through the front windshield,
-- they're not around to talk
-- about it.
They don't get to talk and I,
I'm fine because I didn't wear my seatbelt and I
hit a deer or whatever and it doesn't matter anyway.
All right, I'm ending this. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to
Paar Security podcast.com. Head up the show notes, T Podos
Podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt. You have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.