Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner enjoying in, enjoying buttered toast.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- I mean, butter toast is ok.
But why, why would you even use that as your example at the beginning of the show?
-- I'm confused.
-- Well, because I used to eat my toast dry like I put jam or whatever on it.
But then I,
-- I started buttering it again and it's just so much better.
-- Ok.
So you're gonna, well, you think I'm weird anyway, so this won't,
this won't shock you in any meaningful way.
But if I'm eating just a piece of toast with,
say my breakfast with my eggs or whatever, I'll put butter on it.
But if I'm putting jam on the toast, I don't put butter on first.
I prefer just jam on the bread versus jam and butter on the bread.
Well, see, and I'm sort of the same way,
I will only put jam on a piece of bread with butter if it
is toast and the butter melts, like I don't want a layer of butter and a layer of jam.
-- I do not want that.
-- I mean, that sounds awful. But I don't even like melted butter.
-- I know a lot of people that like it that way and I'm not one of them,
-- whatever.
Anyway, we have an interesting topic. So I want to get cracking.
So, Sonatype released a report. Uh, I don't know, like a week or two ago from the time.
I don't know.
Anyway,
it's called the ninth annual
State of the software supply chain.
And it's, I, I'm gonna, I wanna start out and I even I sent, uh,
Brian Fox is like their CTO.
I think I sent him a message the other day. I'm like, holy crap.
You didn't put this behind a web form where I have to, like,
fill out all my information.
Like,
thank you so much.
-- I just realized that when I opened it, I was like, it, it,
-- that's, yeah, exactly.
II, I like,
it's funny because I call them information paywalls
and then people get grumpy at me.
I'm like, but that's what they are. I'm,
I'm giving you my information.
Well, but ok, just not to segue for a second. But
there are also times where I want to give them my
information and I actually do want their newsletter or whatever.
Like I do, actually, I want to sign because if they have good information in a report,
chances are I might want to like,
-- like when this thing comes out next year, tell me, I'm
-- sure
sonatype has a sign. Up for our newsletter link somewhere on their web page
for
it.
-- I'd never
-- look
whatever. No.
Ok. Ok. I'll give you this.
I would be comfortable with a website that said you may optionally give
us your personal information or click this button to download the report.
-- Well, anyway,
-- I know a lot like ours. We, we, I think we force you to
do a log
thing,
but you also default to not
spamming you.
I get a lot of CS A email.
-- So click
-- unsubscribe,
I'm lazy and some of your stuff is all right.
So
I, I
actually,
I just today unsubscribed from OS S security because I realized I've
been filtering it and not reading it for like five years.
I think I'm still subscribed to that actually.
Well,
all of it goes to spam anyways because like they
don't have their DKIM and SPF and everything set up,
right?
Like they don't rewrite the from and all that
for A R C.
Ok.
-- Off track already.
-- Which kind of ties into this open source thing where
basically everything is the same but worse but better.
OK. So
I have one specific data point I really want us to talk about because fundamentally,
I think
nothing in here should surprise anyone.
Like open source use is going up, the open source development is going up.
-- I was actually shocked to see it apparently dipped a bit like
-- what the use or the,
-- yeah, the growth rate the
-- growth
-- rate of one
-- of those,
the growth rate dipped because like we have 95% of the market.
Well, and, and it might be that I think the growth rate they're talking about
is the, like
the, the speed at which new packages are being added to the ecosystem is my,
my understanding I could be misreading that,
but I'm pretty sure that's what that is.
I'm not shocked by this just because
there's a lot of freaking open source right now.
It's
pretty, it,
it's getting mature and I think you're just not seeing the volume of new stuff.
And now I do have some of my,
my graphs from like N PM and stuff. I started pulling my data from the
ecosystems dot E
ecosystem
S, I'll put a link in the show notes. A
guy named Andrew Nesbitt
runs this site that has tons and tons and tons of open source metrics.
And it was funny because at one point he's like, oh yeah,
you can hit my API it'll take it.
And like a week ago he emailed me.
He was like, can I just give you some files to download instead
of
-- I'm
-- like, this is,
this is the thing I love about
github is
if you have your data source in github, not only can I just go go
the whole thing.
There
-- is
-- like, this is like 10 gigabytes of data.
I
know.
-- Well, you pay for those one gigabyte data packs.
-- Why, why would anyone do that?
-- That's, that's, they're shockingly expensive.
-- Actually,
I guess S3 is a good,
another good old or I guess the Amazon R two or Amazon Cloud Flare R two or whatever.
Now, like the one thing that gets me is like, remember when serving
100 megabyte file took,
well, how many people did?
And Red Hat have working with a comite to serve those files. Like,
but anyway,
so the data point I actually think is the most interesting in this report and the one
I want us to talk about because I don't have my thoughts fully formed on this.
Only 11% of projects are actively maintained.
I'm actually shocked it's that high.
Like if you look at the app, no, go to N PM, js.org.
Yeah. Type in a random word
and start
up
million.
Well, ignore all the one like there's a gazillion tutorial upload one.
So it,
it get rid of all like let's be kind and get rid of everything that's
only been ever updated five times and is
clearly like was some little experiment that got
but still like even stuff that's downloaded thousands
or even millions of times a week.
-- Now,
-- lots
-- of
-- stuff is downloaded millions of times a week.
Like we were talking about this the other day, like there were some,
I I did a quick spot check of the most kind of popular ones
and there was a couple there that, well,
one was officially deprecated and said go use this other one.
But the deprecated one is still being downloaded. It was over 100,000 times a week.
There was one
that is in the millions of downloads a week
and hadn't been updated in over four years.
And it was like the core one. What was it called again? I forget the name of it.
-- But like this is normal.
-- Yeah. No, no, it is. Ok. Well, so
here's the thing I've got in my brain
kind of around all of this.
So
we have
all of these foundations and people and companies
and everyone talking about supply chain security and
how we need to worry about our CV ES and we need to update our,
our dependencies as fast as possible and all this kind of stuff
and 11%
is what we and, and no one even knows this.
I mean, I suspect most companies don't even know what all the open sources they have,
but even fewer
are gonna even know about 11% of the things you're using
are. It's probably not 11% of the things you're using. I I should clarify.
There's one I think important data caveat here
is like you said,
there's a lot of stuff that is functionally dead or never going to be used,
right?
And there's also a lot of stuff that's done like that.
Like my favorite example always, I mean,
-- like it converts a normal national date into that month, day, year thing.
-- And,
and yeah, that, that doesn't need an update and there's, there's a certain amount of
let's,
but here's the thing, even if we
were generous with how we organize the data and we filtered
things out and we did a whole bunch of work,
I think it's still going to be less than 50% of the like actively used open source
is actually maintained at this point.
And then comes the difficult part of how do we know
like CV SS style, assign a temporal score of how important is this software?
Because for example,
there's a big difference between a package that is a
well loved and used web server public facing eating attacks
versus
something that doesn't
like uh
uh a config file parser where it's running on relatively trusted data.
That's right. That's right.
And then there's of course,
a lot of stuff in between where it's kind of like it turns out like
uh what was that one with the file?
It was like the file data for CD roms or something that when
Gnome parsed it
-- the Q thing.
-- Oh The Well, so the
gnome one lit lib
QQ. This is a good example because
when you open like a file manager,
this is true of Windows or Mac Os or Gnome or whatever.
When you open the file manager, it gives you that little preview
of what you have.
And
if you had a Q file, which most people probably don't anymore.
But let's say you downloaded one from some random place,
you get a zip file and there's one
that's
like,
I,
I just had somebody send me a zip file and there
was that Doc Mac Os Blob in there and I'm like
a
-- little thumbnails and stuff and I'm
-- like,
but anyway,
I mean, like lib Q
and it's a weird package
that probably won't actually affect a lot of people.
But if it affects you, it does affect you,
-- it'd be
-- very
useful, for example, for targeted attack or, you know,
but the thing is the problem is there's a lot of these,
there's a lot of soft
where thought
ultimately,
I want to say Ken.
Yes, Ken is the correct word, parse attacker supplied data in not super exotic,
crazy ways, like for sure, mission impossible,
-- whatever stuff.
-- Here's what I have in my brain though, over all this,
let's say 50% of open source is functionally unmaintained. Right.
-- And I'm gonna be generous with that because the,
-- oh, it's more than that. But sure,
the report says 11.
Let's pretend it's not because I think like one
of the things I saw was people nitpicking.
Oh, I don't know if you can actually measure 11% accurately and it's like
the number isn't important
because
it's a lot. Right.
This is like 123, more than three, we're dealing with more than three
you know what I mean?
The reality is if here's a perfect example on your system,
look at all like on a Linux system, I'm saying, sorry,
look at all your packages installed and what version they are
and when the last time they got an update is,
and I'm guessing for some of them it's like, never,
like you install that package with
-- Debbie Inversion, whatever. And it's never had an update.
-- Oh, for sure, for sure.
There's,
yeah, I mean,
unless it has a very serious security vulnerability in it
that is known
you're probably not going to see an update to
the vast majority of this software because quite frankly,
it just,
it doesn't need tons of updates. Right.
I mean, it's not like a web browser where you have constant and consistent updates.
Uh, some of this stuff, like,
if you have a JPEG parsing library, if it doesn't have a critical bug in it,
why would you update that?
You know? However, however, I don't think that's the case
for most of this software. I think most of the open source is
someone released it,
it got used,
they probably updated it a few times
and now for whatever reason
they can't or won't update it.
Well, the thing to remember too is ok,
let's say I build a piece of open source and I scratch my itch.
Right. Sure. Sure. Sure. Well, I'm done scratching my itch.
I have other itches to scratch. Yeah. That happens all the time. No,
people forget this.
People forget this, that, like,
I have other things to do with my life and other software.
And so, unless for me personally,
there's something I need for my software that I need to update or
somebody files a bug report and I'm super nice and awesome.
Right. Right. And I decide to fix it. Like, unless somebody reports it to me. Like,
and that's the other thing I'm seeing is I'm seeing a lot of,
oh,
what was that thing I was talking about the other day where there was
a feature request that I'd asked for and I was like the fourth.
Oh Yeah. Sorry. OK.
So static website generators beginning to hate them because holy cow.
Did they ever make generating a simple website?
So I was using Jenkins with its um
default theme of minimum.
Um Hang on a sec. Where is it on github?
I want to actually check the state of the uh here we go.
Minima is a one size fits all, check a theme for writers. And what I would like to do
is put the CS, a logo
on the top left hand corner of the website.
OK.
This seems like a reasonable thing to want. Yes, I would agree.
Yeah. No,
no, the answer is no, I'm not totally surprised.
Like you can't do it without hand editing the
CS S that it generates and stuff like that.
And so I asked for it. Oh, did they close the issue?
So there was an issue, ah, how do I add a site logo?
And somebody else asked,
I'd like to add the site logo on the top left of the site title.
How do I do that context
github pages?
Anyways, blah, blah, blah.
And then it gets auto closed. But the thing is if you Google search
like Jekyll
ad logo,
millions of people asking probably, I mean, look going back 10 years.
But this is a great example, Kurt of someone needs to
build that functionality. It's open source hatch is welcome.
If the author doesn't want to do that.
Ok. Like they don't have to.
No, no, they certainly don't.
But it's just, it's interesting to me that
like because to put it bluntly, the, the minimum theme is kind of on life support like
there are this year
012345, basically five sets of commits for this year. I mean,
I
like again, it's a mature project but does this count as unmaintained?
I mean, it might,
it, I don't know if sonatype,
I don't remember them saying how they measured that.
Like I would guess this council supported because there is activity in the last year
and I'm guessing if there's actually a severe
like security flaw that they'll fix it.
So you just rattled the cobweb in my brain is
the
the metric they used for updated was basically got
an update in 2022 but didn't get an update
in 2022 like basically one from over the span
they measured the previous year had an update,
the current year does not.
And that's a very reasonable way to measure this stuff. But
like you said, in the context of a mature, mature package,
it, it doesn't matter, right?
Because it's mature and you, you maybe won't see updates.
However, however, I don't think that matters either.
I think the thing I keep thinking of is there is this like obsession
with supply chain security and knowing what you have and updating your stuff.
And the reality is
we generally have no idea what things we're using are maybe mature
or abandoned
-- or being like maliciously not maintained or, or
-- does the attacker talk to it?
Because
remember prior to that, like, remember bash shells shaw came out and we're all like,
oh flaw and bash, OK, that's
whatever
like, OK, what do you mean Apache is what? Like
I remember looking at that thinking like
this has got to be a mistake.
Like somebody has some weird version of custom bash Apache that they,
no, that's just how it works. And it's like, oh, well, today I learned
like, no really like I'm open to learning because as we've discovered from like,
like there's all sorts of wonky
interactions on a Linux system. But
if you told me 10 or 20 years ago, I would have been like, that's completely insane.
That should never happen. That's dangerous. And
-- that's how things work.
-- Right. Right. But, but
ignoring, ignoring that point, let's pretend
everything is critical. Right. Because it doesn't really matter.
Well, everything is interrelated. It's an equal
system.
It's
a rain forest and you
affect one thing.
Sure. It's an, it, crowd reference
is it, I don't remember. I haven't watched it crowd in so long
-- when
-- they let, what's his face out of the room? No
fielding, right.
I forget what his name. He's the vampire, right? The goth guy.
-- No,
-- he's not a vampire. He's just very pale and listens to a lot of death metal
of filth.
I love
-- through some hard times.
-- I love that show so much.
I love,
oh, it's so good anyway.
OK.
So
all of this obsession with supply chain and I feel like there's all these unknowns
and I don't even think there's a way to measure a lot of this stuff.
Like, how can you tell if a project is mature versus abandon?
See, well, I was about to say number one, you have the data aspect of it
of like
looking at the
github
commit history, right? That's data.
But
I would argue also maintained is even worse than that because maintained is not just
sort of a factual state, it's an intentional state. And by that, I mean,
you could have a piece of software
with no commits for a year
but with a developer who is eyeballing it every week and just waiting
for someone to file an issue that they're going to fix right away.
-- That's fair. I mean, and, but there's no way to know that. Right.
-- Exactly.
And that's so that, I think that's part of it too is.
So I think what we can do is we can bucket it into three groups
super actively maintained,
you know, things like Apache engine
-- X,
-- which apparently is 11% of open source.
Well,
and in a lot of cases, it's the 11% that matters. It's the public facing 11% right?
-- And then
-- there's
I
would say
that
well, and then there's the bucket of clearly dead.
Like we can set some metric for no updates in 10 years,
no updates in five years
or the developer is actually dead. That also happens.
And then there's everything in the middle, which is like 80% of it.
So this isn't a very helpful set of buckets.
That's, that's part of the problem, right
is we,
we kind of inherently know it's super actively maintained and we kind of know it's,
well, the debt is often surprised. So I'm just gonna again, I'm going to go back to.
So I looked at what was I the 10 most popular N PM packages
and like express
a
slow dash moment. We pack Redux babble just and typescript.
So babble is my favorite because the last published babble was seven years ago.
And it says like
don't use me use Babble Dash. I forget the name of it.
Oh yeah. Use Babble Dash cli it
gets 100 and 24,000 weekly downloads and on github
-- it's used by 16.9 million.
-- Yeah, I mean Lo Dash is a similar story.
We just talked about Lo Dash. What, like two or three episodes ago.
-- It's
-- basically dead as far as I can tell because
I
Lo Dash
might be coming back to life but
it hasn't had an update on N PM js.org in three years.
It gets 50 million downloads a week.
It's like, so hopefully it's just really well written and mature.
It's not, it's had tons of security issues.
Yeah.
And the thing is if some attacker,
I promise the reason there haven't been any in the
last year or two isn't because people aren't looking,
I have a suspicion. It's because
there just isn't,
it's not maintained and I think a lot of them would fly under
the radar and it's just our broken CV E system at work.
Well, and that's the thing.
Like, it's, it's hard to, if you find something good and publish it,
like you put out a tweet and if it doesn't get traction, like it's,
it's like if a tree falls in a forest and you know,
falls on the lumberjack and kills them,
nobody knows where the lumberjack is.
What really gets me is if you look at low dash for example,
they only have eight issues in github
and
some of them are new because it was dead. But the fact is
-- people filed issues in the last two weeks. So people care,
-- everyone uses it.
-- I think lots of people
-- care. Everybody uses Lib. Jasper. Nobody cares.
Here's what I think I find interesting about care
because I care about my stuff working. But how many people care enough
to actually give money or help
to an open source project. And I think that number is exceedingly small.
Well, it's effectively zero.
Like if you take a big enough number and
-- the ratio is 0 50
-- million
versus
50 million
-- a week.
-- Right. Right.
You know, and I feel like we've had those developers where they're like, you know,
my software is used on like 70% of the top 100 websites on the planet.
And I've gotten exactly a cup,
a cup of coffee at a conference once from some nice old lady.
It wasn't a company
and,
but from the company's point of view, it's like,
so the license says I can use this for free open source.
-- It, it does
-- and that's how open source works. That's fine.
And it's not like, actively catching fire.
So, like,
why would we put resources into this when
we could put resources into marketing or sales or
my bonus?
Well, here's the other thing
if I am a company
and I pay someone to work on lo
dash
is that going to impact my sales at all?
No, absolutely not.
But if I pay that developer to build features into my product,
will that impact sales?
-- Probably? Yes.
-- Yeah.
See the thing I keep coming back to is I'm looking at this from like the supply chain
and I say security, not in the terms of information security,
but security in terms of like availability more.
Where
now what's interesting to me is in traditional classical physical supply chains,
stuff can just
go like it's just not available like the factory burned down, sorry.
No more ra M chips for you, right? That happened once, remember
the Samsung factory burned down and ram prices went to the moon,
not a metaphor or like when hard drives
got expensive because there was flooding in Thailand,
right?
And then all the hard drive for six months
afterwards were pretty dodgy because they had to sell something
they needed cash flow, right? No cash flow, no business. So
in software terms,
the software can't really go away outside of
like some really bizarre corner cases like postfix with
that wonky IBM license where IBM is like we can revoke your usage of post fix and
you know,
but double promises swears these will give you something
of equal or better value to replace it.
And everybody was like,
I like postfix but like II I just can't deal with that kind of weird ambiguity.
So
ignoring
like those seven weird corner cases,
software can't really disappear. Especially if you, like,
just grab a copy of it and fork it or download the Tar Ball or whatever. Like,
software. Absolutely does.
Like archive.org is a great example of stuff can disappear. Right.
There used to be a nice website at sun.com.
Yeah.
That's right. Yeah.
And then one day it went away, generally speaking, if you're reasonably competent,
you don't have to worry about your, your software supply chain suddenly going
kof.
Right. That's right. You know, and I think that's why it gets ignored a lot. Right.
I mean, even the supply chains, we have physical supply chains,
there is actually a really good podcast.
I'm going to put a link in the show notes. Um, it's called Reality Two Point. Oh,
it's, uh, Doc Searls and Catherine drunk.
And they just talked to a supply chain guy.
I don't know what
in my feed I listened to it yesterday.
I don't, I'm way behind those so I don't know how long ago it came out.
But anyway,
like this guy had some really interesting stories.
This is a, a, like, literal brick and mortar supply chain person.
Right. And
you think prior to a year ago or two years ago,
no one thought twice about supply chain stuff because it all basically just worked.
And now he's like, now everyone wants to talk to me. Right.
I mean, that's even one of the things they talk about is like, you know,
a year or two ago
this podcast would have never happened because, like, cares,
-- it's
-- like pop tarts and plywood.
-- Like, nobody cares until there's a hurricane coming. Yeah.
-- That's right.
And fortunately though,
like Walmart and all those big giants have weather teams that monitor the stuff and,
like, premo,
everything they've been doing that for decades
because then they sell stuff.
Yeah. Right. Right. 100%. But you, I think you're right.
This is where software doesn't comply to our existing rules. And so much
it is so common now
to try to like pound the
open source square peg into the supply chain round hole
and the parallels just don't make sense.
-- Well, again,
-- I am not your supplier.
That's the, I think that's one of the core,
fundamental problems of this argument is that we call
it a supply chain and we are inherently framing it
as a supply chain and it's not, it's,
I
found this book that had some helpful text that
somebody wrote for free and distributed for free,
like baking instructions and now
like I expect support from it or something like it's, it's, I, I don't,
I'm beginning to not like calling open source of supply chain because it just,
it pigeonholes it into the traditional
supply chain metaphors and responsibilities and everything
and some of it I think should overlap.
Like if I buy food, I want to know what's in it and not
even just for allergies.
But if I'm buying food from you, I want to know that you have the competency
to know what's in the food.
Perfect example, there's a house
about seven or eight houses down that put up a sign in their front yard
saying Somoza is for sale
and a phone number
like delicious. I'm sure the the picture looks good
but like
samosas, you know,
samosas,
so they're selling samosas out of their house. They have a phone number.
-- What is
-- a samosa for people who don't know,
it's like a
pastry dough style thing with the filling
and then you fry it.
Everyone has
-- and
-- they're delicious.
Anyway, they are good.
I don't know what kind they are like. Could be. Ethiopian could be Indian.
I don't know.
Right.
It doesn't matter.
-- Fried bread with filling is good no matter
-- what fried starchy substance.
But so the thing is like
with software again, if I'm consuming some software,
I kind of want to know that you have the competency
to know what's going in there and you have some degree of
control and Q A and you're not just throwing random junk in.
It's less about the security side of it and
more about you having some basic internal controls.
Like I made this argument a long time ago
with Excel
having a flight simulator in it.
Remember I don't remember this but old versions
of Excel had a flight simulator in them
and I, yes, no. I'm making this up. Yes. Really? I don't know.
You went to a certain cell type, a certain value, blah, blah, blah.
And you got dropped into a flight simulator with a joint tape and stuff. All right.
II,
I basically wrote an article basically talking about how software
Easter eggs are kind of cute and fun and all,
but they show a lack of control and discipline and if you have these going in,
what else is there?
And the answer is you don't know, maybe,
-- I don't know.
-- Ok.
Do you think the dod wants to buy F-35
control software with a surprise Easter egg in it?
I mean,
I'm,
I
like to say they don't use Excel for that, but they probably do.
But
I mean, ok, here's where you lose me in this conversation though
is you're talking about controlling your software
and there's kind of two pieces to this.
If I'm working with a vendor,
I expect the vendor to take responsibility for
all the software and the thing they're shipping.
If I'm consuming open source to build a service or something where I'm the vendor
that's on you, buddy, then, then it's a very different situation.
And I think both of those situations are viewed in a very similar way,
even though they're actually very, very, very different.
And I think it's worse because there's a third way,
which is the more common ways you do not directly consume that open source.
You are directly consuming Kernes
and then Kubernetes is like, hey, me and some friends,
I mean, is that any worse than a flight simulator in Excel or is it any different?
-- I should say.
-- Well,
in theory,
Kubernetes knows what they're actually pulling in
and isn't pulling in any Easter eggs.
They, they do, they do
-- like, they're pretty good about it, but not everyone
-- is.
And I think that's the problem again, is framing this as I consume open source.
No, I don't, I'm consuming the tip of an iceberg.
I don't know about the iceberg under the water. No, I really don't
like I use open source all the time.
And oh, perfect example.
I was um I just wiped my virtual machines on my windows, uh my, my Linux,
whatever they are WSL two things, right? Because
I copied in like 300 gigabytes of data into one and then
I deleted it and it, the file size didn't shrink and I'm like, well, ok,
time to spring clean.
So I deleted them all and created some new ones.
And of course I've been, you know, apt get installing like, oh crap.
I also needed uh poplar for doing some PDF work and this and this and this
and of course some of them like poplar, you, you install that and it's like,
I'm going to have to install poplar and these 124 megabytes of stuff.
And I'm like, that's very common. Yes,
because what else am I going to do?
Like, I don't even bother reading it.
I just did that the other day. What did I install?
I installed something and it pulled in like, literally 700 megabytes of crap.
And I was like,
oh, well,
yeah, I, what was the thing?
I, I wanted to pull an X and some other stuff and I was like, sure
you do. You buddy,
I just need this thing to work so I can extract text from a PDF or whatever. And so
the thing is like
there's a, there's a degree of trust and sort of compensating controls in that.
I'm like running this in a container and I'm also using anyways.
But the point is that is the more common way of consuming software is I want that
the thing I want, it's like I consume a car.
Ok.
Well, I also need to apparently buy windshield wiper,
food and oil for the damn thing like, ok,
and like tires, like I, I guess it needs tires they wear
out or something. I don't know, man. Like they, they told me I should buy new tires.
But the point is
that is like three things that are physical and kind of in your face. Whereas
software could be pulling in 1000 or 2000 dependencies.
-- Look,
-- here's, here's a, here's maybe an example.
I don't think it's a good example, but how many screws are in your car?
You have? No idea.
I know for a fact there's a lot of plastic clips because
when I watched the diagram of how to replace the headlights,
I was like, well, we're never doing that.
-- Yeah,
-- I know that terrifies me because every time I touch a plastic clip, I,
-- it's like,
-- please don't break, please don't break, don't break,
please don't break.
And please also
did I weaken it?
Oh, for sure. Yeah.
-- Exactly.
-- Because I was only meant to go in there once.
Exactly.
So anyway,
and this is,
but the screws in my car
randomly catch fire and fall out.
-- Like most of the time,
-- usually, usually,
I mean, look, I feel like we've been talking about this for like half an hour now
and I don't have
any more insights into what it means.
-- If only 11% of open source is actively maintained.
-- Here's the thought,
what if in S bomb
instead of just having
contains food also had,
for example, here's the head end project of food,
like here's the github.com or the wherever it lives officially,
right?
And for example, had some information about like, OK, here's like,
well, basically you're running food 2.7 and like upstream has like food.
And so you could go check upstream and be like, oh, there's now like f
17.4
or whatever
and you could start to
gather some data in an automated fashion about like what's the delta between what
we grabbed and where it is and is there stuff in between that matters?
And that's obviously what your company does with CV stuff? Right? Like, yes,
yes.
But what if it was more like also it would go upstream and grab it and say, hey,
you know,
there's been no updates in six months, like maybe it's a problem. Maybe it's cool.
I don't know.
So the, the open SSF scorecard project is trying to capture some of this data.
But I think the problem is
-- like does, is this data meaningful? Does it matter? Does it work?
-- Not yet?
Because the problem is we don't know if it correlates, let alone
causes anything.
-- And
-- I, I think that's the question
but without the data, we can't start to begin to
-- figure it out
-- and, and OK, OK,
here's how I want to end this because I think I think you're on a good point.
Sonatype says 11% of open source is actively maintained, meaning 89% of it is not,
that feels like a bad thing
but is it
no, everything seems to work? OK.
It does work. And I think that's the challenge is starting to unwind the question of
like, is this OK? And if it's not OK, what part of it isn't? OK?
And I think this is where we there's, there's boring,
horrible work that needs to be done that isn't going to
be can make a headline on the register or something,
right?
This is going like
11% of open source is maintained. That's an exciting headline.
Everyone's going to latch on to the the story behind.
-- It is not going to be exciting, but it's, it's important,
-- right?
Well, like what we need is a CS V file from github of all the public
github.com/blah/bla
with how many forks, how many stars,
-- what uses it and you know, publish
-- that, you can get that easily
and
well, and then,
and then you need to start processing and
figuring out what if anything it actually means
-- and it may not mean anything,
-- someone needs to do that work.
And there's going to be a lot of false starts.
There's gonna be a lot of like, oh, this feels important but, oh, it turns out it's not
like I have no doubt the number of stars a project have is completely meaningless
because there have been so many times I've had people say like, oh,
you should go start my project.
And I'm like,
I don't want to,
I actually had that happen where a Dev was like, this project only has one star.
We can't use it. And I'm like, what
I mean?
One star is
maybe questionable. I don't know.
-- It's hard to say. Does it matter? I don't
-- know.
It's for kind of an obscure thing.
That's just it too. Exactly.
-- Like,
-- so among obscure things, one star might be pretty damn good. Yeah.
Yeah, we don't know.
Anyway,
says podcast, like, what's our rating.
-- Like no, seriously. Right. Like we're kind of a niche thing.
-- So we are very niche.
I have a suspicion.
We do. Well, so I, what, what are we at now?
We do like 6000 downloads a week, basically give or take.
-- So between five and six we'll say to be generous.
-- Ok.
So that means we have approximately,
uh, what's, uh, I can't do these big numbers in my
head.
But remember some people are downloading the whole back catalog in one go.
Right. We have hundreds of episodes at this point.
I
don't
know what that means.
And maybe it's a lot. Maybe it's not, I don't know. Luckily we don't have to care.
We have approximately
0.0013% of the global podcast listening market.
I mean,
maybe II, I
imagine it's not huge, but I don't know.
Well, 6000 out of 464 million, that's the thing.
Even like with podcast data, I, I tried to look up one time of like,
what's the average, like, what is normal for podcast downloads?
And what does all this stuff look like?
-- Well, it's going to be a Power Distribution Law. It's,
-- it, I, I have no idea.
I can't figure anything out.
I don't, it doesn't make sense. And luckily we don't have sponsors. We don't care.
Like,
and somebody pointed out this is one of the problems
with Spotify and like a lot of these streaming services,
why the streaming services don't want to give the data to like the se
and the Writers guild and stuff is because
there's probably shenanigans going on with the
numbers where they're telling the advertisers.
Oh, yeah, like a gazillion people looked at that thing.
So here's your bill and then, you know, to the writers and the IP owners, it's like,
oh, it's kind of sad, like only four people watch
your
show this week. Sorry.
Well, and that's the beauty is we, we have so little data,
the meaningful data that we could just make stuff up.
That's right.
Exactly. It's, I mean, this comes back to like, what's the old advertising saying?
Half of your advertising money is wasted. You just don't know which half
like I feel like that's what all this metrics
-- for open source and everything is or
-- even better.
Uh N pr just, they left Twitter.
Yes, apparently didn't matter
-- 1%.
-- So I could have told you that like, this is one of the things,
you know, I've been publishing a lot of blog posts and podcasts for a long time.
So I have like years of evidence behind this.
And I can tell you now that when we had like
an episode tweet or something that blew up and got like,
you know, like thousands and thousands of retweets and likes and stuff,
the amount of web traffic I saw barely moved.
The only thing I see that makes web traffic go up like crazy. Is hacker news?
That is the only site love it or hate it.
But, like, that's the only thing I've
seen to meaningfully change our
web traffic for, for open social security dot com.
Well, but also we're small enough that it can mean, like,
if we had a million listeners, hacker news wouldn't statistically
true. That could very well be.
That
thing is,
yeah.
Yeah. Anyway. All right. All right. So I guess this is what I'll say.
I'm going to end. The show
is
11% sounds bad because we're like humans and we don't know better,
but we honestly have no idea if it's good or not and someone needs to do the
research and the research is going to be boring and it's not going to get a headline.
So it may, it may never get done
academia. Hopefully, I, I hope academia latches on to this because
like this, this date is really important. Is it? I think it is.
Here's, here's an example, I'll, I'll leave on
it. I would say it's kind of like testing screws, right. Our cars are full of screws
and there are what probably millions of pages have been written
about how to test the durability and strength of a screw.
-- Do you think it's ever made a headline?
-- Know a scary lot about this?
Oh, you want to talk about sheer strength of screws?
And there's these new things called hurricane
nails that are not technically a screw,
but kind of like a screw.
-- But like, seriously their po strength is insane. They're so cool.
-- You get the idea.
But how many of those are making headlines
in the news? It doesn't because, like,
unless you're in the obscure universe of really caring about screws, which there,
there are a lot of people who do and thank
goodness there are because society wouldn't function without them.
-- But you know what
-- I
mean?
Like the international Fastener show, like,
seriously some of the stuff coming out of there is um I watched a youtube video on it.
It's insane.
I bet, I bet it is. But you know what I mean?
And I think a lot of this open source stuff, the data we need is similar.
It's, it's, it's interesting to people like us who are like weird open source,
you know, security nerds,
but for literally everyone else,
-- well, it's plumbing if
-- we do it properly
and it works, it just
-- people call a plumber once every 10 years. And like, that's
-- right.
-- Don't have to care anyway.
-- All right, it's time to go. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for listening. Go to it.
Our security podcast.com hit up the shout
out its Easy
Pound of Os S podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.