Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Episode number 30 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
30 episodes, Kurt, because we have 10 fingers. That seems like an important number.
So, yay for us.
Yeah. Well,
I'm turning 40 this year so I can sympathize with this power of tens thing.
It is a powerful concept and ironically it only exists because
we have 10 fingers and so we use base 10.
Whereas if we use base 12, it would be totally different.
And I'm sure the base 12 fans out there would assure
us that all of math would be much easier and better.
Yeah, I've always wondered about that. What happened?
-- If we had nine fingers or seven,
-- we have base nine math then,
I mean, that's just kind of the reality of it.
And in fact, there's, I, I read some articles one time talking about how, when you use
different bases, you end up,
the math is slightly different in some ways, it's easier in some ways. It's harder
because like, for example, in base 12, I guess, like a third,
which is what 0.3333333 that
repeats forever is not, it, it's actually a nice number.
Well, 12 is a very
nice number and that you can divide it by 12346.
Yes.
Which when you think about it,
like for dividing among a group of people is a pretty optimal, like, you know,
that's why we have 60 minutes in an hour.
Right? Because it's 123456,
you know, 1012 like that,
that gives you a lot of flexibility on how you want to divide this up.
Sure. Why not?
-- You know, I have no
-- idea. I've kind of wondered about that.
But, uh, anyways, well, so this kind of raises. Well,
um,
is there a metric second where there's 100 seconds?
And it actually works out reasonably close? Right.
Having 10 hours with 100 minutes.
I think it's 10 hours with 100 minutes with 100 seconds.
And I hope the French created this because I would expect no other group to do it.
Uh, I don't think it was
the French. It was hang on a second.
Uh, they don't,
uh, science fiction
uses it and then,
um, but it looks like,
yeah.
Anyway, it's nice.
Ah,
yeah, I'm done. I'm tired of talking about time and leap seconds.
Just
mess that is
it, whatever. I'm not even going to go there. All right. So, let's today instead,
talk about machine learning and security because machine learning is a super hip
topic these days and security happens to also be a super hip topic.
So let's put them together.
Yeah.
See, and this,
the weirdest thing I find about this whole topic
is the whole premise of the it industry,
the information technology industry is to automate
tasks and work with computers and software.
That's literally the premise of what we're doing
and yet people are resistant
to automating it work.
I don't know if they're resistant. Necessarily.
Some people might be, but that's, I mean, that's human nature.
We've had people resistant to literally all
change throughout history in every possible way.
But I, I mean, you look at the best Cis
Edmunds, you know, and they're also the Laziest human beings, you know. Right.
-- Because they've like literally turned their entire job into four pearl
-- scripts.
Yeah.
No, I'm always reminded of that XK CD comic,
which we should post a link to where he basically talks about the um you know,
if an action takes X number of minutes or seconds or
whatever times how many times you do it a day,
you know, how much time should you spend automating it to get the payoff?
Right? Because you shouldn't spend like a year automating a task.
It only takes say one hour per year to do.
But things like, for example, a great example, spam filtering of email, right?
Clearly, that needs to be automated and there's a payoff.
I don't think you could not spam filter these days.
Well, that goes back to your law of large numbers. Right.
If I get 10 spams a day I can handle that as a human being.
But when 99% of my email is spam,
you know, and it's like 10,000 messages a day.
I physically can't even click fast enough to get rid of it.
Yeah. That's probably fair.
I don't even want to think about how much spam I
actually would get if there was no filtering of any sort
on my email. I bet it's horrifying.
Oh, yeah.
Well, I mean,
I still run mail servers and just the amount of stuff I'm able to drop right away.
Why do you do that? That's because of the mailing list. We have to still, it's, it's,
let me put it this way. We looked at a variety of mailing list providers
and they're like
by and large, they're just not good,
you know, they're, they're ok but
for what they charge it's honestly we just,
you know, it's just honestly we run, um, so on the incoming email, very simply put it,
it goes through spam Assassin and Cli A V which gets like 99% of the low hanging fruit.
-- Do you allow unsolicited mail to your lists?
-- Some of them we do and quite
well and, but interestingly we only get probably like two or three spams a day.
Um,
and honestly there's a couple of repeat offenders who
keep trying to post like conference calls or like,
you know, kind of industry
related spam to these lists
and, you know, and I quite often just block their domain,
right.
You know, the amount of actual spam spam, like, um, for,
for a long time I was getting a lot of spam about boat lifts, like to lift, you know,
like you drive your boat into it and lift your boat out of the water.
I
don't know why or how I got on to these lists.
But yeah, I was getting a lot of that spam for a month or two. And um,
the reality too is, I mean, most of the stuff,
it's just instant pattern recognition of my brain.
It's like, oh, it's an email in Chinese with pictures
that's not work related,
you know, I can just delete that.
Um,
you know,
so if I'm only spending like less than a minute
a day dealing with the spam to these lists,
it's like, you know what?
That's, that's ok.
Alright.
But long term I do want to kind of, you know, we
want to get rid of these lists for other reasons, like, you know,
integrating them properly with some other of our services.
Everyone knows that crappy web forums are the future Kurt.
Yes,
they are. We need more and, and even bonus points if they're written in PHP.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, you know PHP. It's, it's, it works.
I had a discussion the other day with somebody
and they started picking on PHP as rightly.
So it deserves.
And I pointed out that I suspect Node is the new php.
So we have years of fun ahead of us without
a doubt for ridiculous security problems that nobody will fix.
Well, you know, that's the beauty of all these
things that are successful is one of the reasons they're successful quite often is
because anybody can contribute stuff and you
get that critical mass of like libraries and
software. So it's just like easy to do things.
But let's face it.
Most of these are not written by
like super competent professional software designers.
They're written by people who have an itch, they itch it, you know,
they scratch their itch
and then they publish it to github
or, you know, whatever now and it gets pulled into whatever,
essentially whatever package management system that language uses, you know,
like C
A for Pearl or
-- uh node for Js
-- or whatever. No
is N PM
PM.
Yes,
I remember, I read a thing that Larry Wall wrote.
This was,
oh my goodness. I bet
is that
people who might not know.
So there is a computer programming language called Pearl.
And if you use Pearl on purpose, you are a bad person now because Pearl is terrible.
But Larry Wall invented pearl like a million years ago and this was back when
kind of open sourcing your your magic language just wasn't really a thing.
And Pearl was one of the first and it quite frankly took over the world
and it was literally driving the internet for
a significant amount of time where every sic
a man on the planet was writing Pearl scripts because it was,
it was Shell and Pearl were pretty much the only two games in town back then.
Now
the other thing was, and this is something, you know,
for those of you that probably don't remember but like
parsing strings of text
in C and Well, C++ which was like actually a new thing back then was a nightmare.
Even in shell, it's terrible you need
in
a and, and the way the shell deals with
separators because it could be spaces, it can be line breaks.
It's, it's just a huge freaking mess man.
It's such a pain in the neck and yet
regular expressions are what really made pearl amazing.
But regular expressions are like pearl is terrible because
now you look at some of this old pearl code and it's,
it's designed in such a way that you can
just like literally put regular expressions anywhere you want.
And
so the this old code is a nightmare to deal with.
It was it's very easy to write, it's impossible to maintain.
So anyway, anyway, Larry Wall created Pearl, right?
And at one point uh this was when PHP was getting hip
because obviously PHP was becoming the dominant force on the web.
Which Pearl kind of used to be.
I remember writing Pearl CG I scripts, which is,
and you had Mad Pearl was like the big thing then with Apache.
But, but anyway, so PHP is becoming a thing
and obviously all of the snobby programmers are looking down on PHP as the, you know,
crappy, worthless language that only idiots would use.
And Larry Wall even says at one point that
you wouldn't want to read a book written by an amateur.
You wanna read a book written by a professional.
And I, I remember even back then thinking it's a good
point,
you're not wrong,
but
the reality is PHP is going to win and
it's going to essentially destroy Pearl's market share.
And I think between PHP and Python, that is exactly what happened
and you can be that snobby guy and we see this
in security constantly where you have these snobby people that,
that are like, oh, I'm too good for that or,
or these people are dumb or this isn't gonna work or that.
And in reality it, nobody cares,
people want to get their job done and they're
gonna find the tool that does it for them.
Whether it's written by a professional author or a dude down the street,
that's just how it is.
You know, honestly, yeah, people need to get their stuff done and,
you know, this always reminds me of like the, the hamburger argument, you know,
uh I like a good hamburger.
I do not like mcdonald's, but I get that there's like, well,
several billion people that do like mcdonald's and they keep buying it,
you know, and
it's just, the reality is, you know, people need food,
people need scripts that work.
So, yeah.
And as much as I hate PHP myself, I've used it, you know,
because quite honestly getting something done in PHP quite often will take like,
20 minutes.
Well, there's, there's easier things now, but back in the day,
it was by far
the best option
and also what people forget too was getting it up and running on a web host.
They all supported PHP by default and my
QL by default,
anything else and you either had to install it yourself or beg them to install it,
which like let's face it, hosting providers,
they may get around to it, they may not get around to it. But, you know,
the reality is if all you have available is like a weirdly
shaped hammer called PHP and a big rock called my SQL.
You can build a house. It may not be a very pretty house, but,
you know,
it'll keep the rain off your head
and,
you know, you look at things like wordpress.
Wordpress is, you know, is the epitome of PHP and my SQL, you know,
b lodging it together.
Um
But it powers like how much of the web now
all of it, it's in the double digits. I know for sure by number of sites.
Right. Right.
So
yeah, and going back to automation, I mean, that's the thing, right is
I think we're still at this, like honestly,
I think we're at the entry level of automation and it,
because what always gets me is when you ask somebody, how do you build a system
that to me like right there,
I'm asking the wrong question like you, you have to build a system.
No,
you should just have like a program with like a manifest
and the manifest should say something like I need a,
I need a database
and I need it to be like geographically redundant for, you know, safety
and I need like PHP and this and that and the other
thing and then just you shove it into your system and boom,
the system makes things magically happen, right?
Which is what cloud providers are doing.
It's even easier than that in a lot of instances.
I mean,
you look at something like elastic beanstalk and it's just kind of
an an API you write against and then things magically work.
I mean, it's amazing.
Well, that's the next step.
And the problem there is though,
you have to rearchitect a lot of systems because like wordpress is a great example,
Wordpress expects to live on a pos
compliant file system that it can read and write from
and store uploads and cash files and all that other stuff.
And it gets
very grumpy if that's not the, the,
that's not what's there, you know, same thing with the database. Right.
It must have a, my SQL database,
not post
SQL, but my SQL or something, my SQL compatible, which, you know,
there are some options.
Now. There's a lot of options.
Yeah.
You know, and, and the reality is like we,
-- but
-- here's the other part of it is we're still talking about automation.
We haven't even really gotten to
machine learning or even artificial intelligence,
which are not the same thing.
And if you confuse them a machine learning or a I person will hit you on the head
with something heavy.
Can you actually just give us a 12th rundown on the differences between the two?
Yes.
And I will apologize to the experts because I'm certain
I will get some of the nuance wrong here.
I am. I'm certainly not an expert, but I've, I've been yelled at by experts. So
that's as close as you're going to get the
transitive yelling property. That's right. That's right.
And I, I'm, I'm sensitive to this because I've done it to a lot of people myself.
So essentially you've got two concepts,
machine learning is where you essentially,
you feed your pet a bunch of data and you kind of
nudge it in the direction you want it to go, right.
Whereas artificial intelligence
doesn't necessarily have to be taught,
it has the ability to adapt and grow on
its own without human intervention to nudge it along.
And so
logically kind of, if you, if you think about this on a,
on a graph of automation is kind of on the left,
machine learning would be closer to the middle and then
artificial intelligence is all the way on the right.
And so
it obviously true A I is very difficult, machine learning is hard but more dual,
-- even
-- limited A I which we currently do have in some forms is hard.
Right. Right. Well, I,
I don't know if you pay attention to this,
but I know I love reading stories about the Google A I.
And
they were saying for like Google translate the
A I basically invented its own intermediary language
because it was easier than trying to directly
translate things from one language to another,
which is that kind of stuff is amazing
when, when you have A is that do that because,
and that's fundamentally what an A I does is it,
you don't tell it how to solve a problem.
It figures it out on its own.
Now, on the other side, though,
you need obviously substantial resources and time to get your
A I to a point where it is actually usable
as opposed to machine learning,
which you can have up and running in a very short period of time.
Yeah.
Well,
and the thing I've noticed really with machine learning
is part of the challenge with machine learning is
you really need to understand the problem you're trying to solve with
machine learning so that you can feed it the appropriate data and
point it in the appropriate direction, right? Because
it kind of reminds me of, you know,
where you have these incentives for people to behave a certain way and you end up
getting something completely the opposite of what you wanted.
You know, my, my favorite always being call centers and call time.
They would, you know, measure, call center, call time.
So like you'd literally have people just hanging up on you,
you know,
like,
yeah, three minutes and 59 seconds into the phone call,
they would just hang up on you,
you know, so they didn't mingle their
me.
That comes back to we,
we discussed this early in a prior episode is you literally get what you measure
whether it is right or wrong. The results you want are what you will get
with machine learning
in general.
But,
and, and my, my example here is always
if you've ever run, well, I don't know if it's so much anymore,
but there used to be something called Bayesian
filtering for SP
where you would have ham being non spam
messages and spam obviously being the spam messages.
And I remember running a bay
and filter at one point when I, when I was foolish enough to run my own mail server
and
you essentially,
you know, you tell it OK, here's a bunch of ham and here's a bunch of spam
and that way it learns what to do.
And of course, invariably I would get the two mixed up at some point
and I would, I would feed it. The spam is ham or? Right.
And then you start reading your mail and you're like, something is very wrong here.
And it, it's totally like that right where you,
you also have to be very careful with machine
learning because if you feed it the wrong thing,
you're going to get the wrong results.
And so that's obviously one of the many challenges. Whereas A I,
I,
I'm, I'm certain this is a possibility
but in theory,
if you have a good enough A I it will realize
you're dumb and it will do the right thing instead.
Well,
and part of the challenge too is um there's a
good ted talk on A I and machine learning and hiring
and, you know,
these companies are trying to optimize their hiring
process for a variety of perceived things like,
oh, we want people to stay a long time and
you know, we want people that work hard and things like that.
And you know,
the concern is do they end up excluding large
pools of candidates because of a variety of reasons,
like maybe women because they get pregnant and don't work
or people who are depressed and have medical problems.
All right, ladies, you make sure you send all that hate mail to Kurt
at
Kurt
Seaford.
I'm against this to be
my concern is
see, and, but the bigger concern is not just that these systems may do this.
We, because of how A I and machine learning sometimes work,
-- we may not know that they're doing
-- it.
It is certainly a possibility and that can definitely happen where things
you have unintended results.
And so, all right,
let's tie this into security though because this is
kind of the whole purpose of this topic.
Yeah. So a few hours ago, uh
it's now being reported that
China. So for those of you that don't know, I,
and you've missed about
20 years of news.
Um China has a firewall essentially surrounding, you know, all
the internet in China
uh that they used to filter incoming and outgoing traffic
are good at walls, aren't they?
Yeah.
Well, you know, historically, they do kind of work,
sort of for certain values of work.
But, um,
and so what's happened obviously is, you know, you,
you put a wall up around the internet and block access to say, you know,
Wikipedia or whatever.
Well, people who want to read it are going to find a way to read it.
And typically that involves a virtual private network, you know, a VPN.
And of course, there's a lot of legitimate VPN users.
Like, well,
basically every business user on the planet
who's working remotely should be using a VPN
so they, uh,
they've been kind of playing whack a mole with VPN S for a long time and
then apparently today or yesterday they basically just
-- shut down access to all unauthorized VPN
-- S
and we assume unauthorized means VPN S they don't have the key for. Right.
Yeah.
Or, well, VPN S that, um, you know, aren't like some, for example, you know, they may,
I'm assuming be allowing access to like, maybe major corporations,
VPN so that their workers can get work done in China, right?
So essentially VPN S that would only be used by foreigners, you know,
because that's less of a concern for them.
Sure.
So what's interesting though is obviously, you know, it's like
Tor the, the onion router project,
you know, people have,
you know, people keep playing whack a mole and trying to block to r you know,
various governments and various network, Kennedy.
And of course, people keep finding ways around it, you know,
like a common thing now is, is to put your VPN traffic over, report 443 TP, you know,
http S like secure web.
Um you know,
and then of course they do things like
up the antibody doing deep packet inspection to
look at that and see if it's actually web traffic or VPN traffic and block it.
And now one of the nice things you can do with Google Compute engine is essentially
you can use google.com as an end point for like your API or your service.
So, unless they're willing to block, like all of Google,
-- you can get stuff out through Google, for
-- example,
-- they did block Google at one point, didn't
-- they?
-- They have?
-- And
I would imagine the reason they're unblocked is
because they're playing nice to some degree.
Well, I suspect that's part of it, but also I suspect the reality is Google is
so important. I mean,
you can have your homegrown search engine and that's awesome. But let's face it.
The reality is when it comes to search Google one.
Yes. Now what does this have to do with machine learning?
Well, for example, machine learning, um I know they've done
uh security studies and attacks, for example,
on V uh VPN traffic to identify voice traffic versus like web traffic or to look at
your web traffic and be able to actually identify
kind of which sites you're going to based on
the size of the data, right? Because for example, going to,
you know, cnn.com has a kind of a distinctive fingerprint,
you know how it loads and what it loads
and kind of the, you know, the timing.
And I, I remember I read a paper one time about this as well that you, they,
they were watching the packets from an SSH authentication session and, and
basically the cadence of packets that was going across the wire,
you could determine what keys a person was typing on the keyboard,
which is there's a lot of info in that metadata
and, and anyone who ever tells you metadata doesn't matter is,
is a lying fool to say the least because
you're absolutely right.
And I suppose this is a place something like machine learning could provide
immense value to a regime that is very interested
in keeping an eye on what's going on.
Well, and it's less about keeping an eye on what's going on and actively shaping it,
right?
Because we have,
you know what I really find it.
I mean, you want to talk about the ultimate machine learning and a I
you know, China's talking about rolling out essentially a social credit score.
So it's kind of like a a financial credit score, but it's a social credit score
in the sense of kind of how good a citizen are you, right?
And there's a, there's a really good episode of Black Mirror.
Yeah, we'll put a link to that in the show notes.
But
what's very scary for, you know, a lot of us Westerners,
this concept is that this social score will really
uh not so much shape and impact your life
but control it flat out because it'll affect,
you know, do you get to go to school? You know, do you get that job? Do you get to move
um things like that? And
it becomes that sort of ultimate scenario of we don't have to have
people policing you because we'll just get you to police yourself,
you know, like to put it
bluntly,
Josh and I have agreed that we are not
going to be talking about American politics for centuries.
It's just, it's,
yeah, there's for some reason.
Yeah.
You know,
it's just something that we've decided is not going to happen on our podcast.
And we've self censored that for a variety of reasons for some
reason.
Yeah.
And so, you know, this, on the one hand, I, I'm actually quite pissed off about it,
but on the other hand, I don't want the hassle
and this is
crazy to think about because you're essentially going
to have computers making decisions about a person's future
with something like this social score, right?
Although,
although now is this really that different from like your credit score in,
in? I don't, I don't
use the same kind of credit scoring. The United States.
We
use, we
use
FICO
and
you
know, on
Equifax,
they, they pay attention to a huge
number of indicators in a person's life.
And so
-- really any different. Well, of course, well, they are,
-- I have a $500
credit
entity item on my credit report from when I was like 20. And I'm like, what is this?
And I went, and Experian was like,
go to your bank and I went to my bank and my bank is like, I don't know what this is.
Go talk to Experian and I'm like,
-- ok, then
-- I isn't that stuff supposed to come off after seven years.
Uh, yeah, I'd have to check but, I mean,
it was there for a long time and nobody knew what
it was and there was no process to deal with it.
You know, I do know that
some years ago that was very true.
But my understanding is it's become significantly easier
to deal with this. Now, granted, I, I haven't had to so I can't say if it is or it isn't.
But
that's just from my, my mild understanding of this and,
but yeah, I mean, if you have a crap credit score,
you've got,
I know a lot of job,
uh, a lot of jobs now are asking
or flat requiring your credit score when you apply.
Um, and I can sort of see that maybe with a financial controlling position
where you don't want somebody with terrible credit who has
like a history of going bankrupt every two years,
you know, in charge of your finances,
although you should have checks and balances regardless, right?
But it worries me because, you know,
you get a bad credit score and it now impacts your ability to get a job.
It already impacts your ability to get other financial products.
Like if you have a bad credit score,
you don't get as good a rate because you're seen to be more risky. So
my concern is once you fall down that hole, how do you get out of it?
You wait seven years.
And like, that's actually the answer is you just have to wait for
your terrible credit to
just kind of uh time out or, or expire.
I don't think that stuff is happening as I
think there is that technically that seven year rule,
but my understanding is that data is there for a long,
I would totally believe that,
you know, or at a minimum,
they would have your credit score from 10 years ago and say like,
why did you go from 100 and 80 to, you know, 600?
Like, can you please explain it
because my
maybe, maybe so anyway, we need to tie this back to security because we keep going on.
This is a weird topic. But, but so here's, here's one of the things though is with
you, you have an article here, Amazon bought a place called Harvest A I
Yeah. Harvest dot A. I didn't even know that was a top level domain.
And essentially the premise of Harvest A I is in my opinion. Super awesome. Cool.
Basically, they look at your usage patterns of like accessing your files,
accessing your services, you know, all that kind of
like essentially what you're doing on your computer uh and
talking to your corporate network for the sake of argument.
And then based on those usage patterns, they kind of say good or bad and if it's bad,
then they'll, you know, essentially start the security process rolling a bit.
And so, you know, the classic case being like
Bob is in America accessing his corporate VPN and then, you know,
all of a sudden an hour later,
Bob is accessing the VPN from China,
but that's not, you don't need a I for that, I mean,
Pearl.
-- But you know,
-- that's a simplistic example of, you know,
A I will help you catch all these weird different corner cases
like maybe Bob is sick and he's working from home versus,
you know, somebody is Impersonating Bob from a coffee shop, you know,
so tying in, you know, and different risk factors too, right? Like,
you know, if Bob dials in and starts like, looking at every single file or, you know,
reading and writing every single file, you know, that could be ransomware.
Um, you know, like in
there should never, for example, in most cases,
never be a user who like touches every single file or reads every single file.
You know, that's an indication that maybe they're copying everything or, you know,
encrypting everything
and you're going to have a bad day
and things like these usage patterns too, right?
Like what I find fascinating, for example, like the iphone,
my iphone is now like, I know where you live
-- and it's a little bit confused about where I work.
-- I watch you while you sleep.
Exactly. You know,
and it's also learning, for example that like, oh, you're gonna be driving here now,
I'm going to warn you about travel time because I know like when rush hour is,
you know, and this kind of level of helper is hugely beneficial.
But at the same time, it kind of terrifying.
Um now for something like harvest A I it's deployed with, you know, it's,
it's a company deploying it within their own walls as it were or, you know,
within their stuff on Amazon web services.
But what gets me is Amazon
web services already does like a lot of
analysis of bad behavior and they can do this without
having to even come close to looking at your data,
like even just things like network usage patterns, ra M usage, CPU usage kind of dis
guy or things like that are all
enough indicators with metadata
to kind of say like this is OK, this is normal or you know,
this guy is probably a bad guy.
Yeah. Right. And well, so here's the thing
that I always wonder about when we have these
kind of A I and machine parsing solutions.
So
we don't like people looking at what we're doing,
that's just kind of human nature. Nobody likes to be watched.
But if we know an A I is watching us, does that change?
Because so the reason let me back this up a bit first is
when you do studies on people
and they know they're being watched,
they change their behavior,
right?
And so obviously, if you know someone is spying on you,
you will act differently than if you don't know they are. Right?
And so does this, I, I wonder if this counts for that, if I know my company is using A I
to parse what I am doing,
if that changes the way I act necessarily versus
saying there is a person watching what I'm doing.
Well, that's come up.
So, for example, here in Alberta, we have a uh a government run health system
and obviously it used to be like paper records based,
right?
And they went to what's called Alberta Health Link. It's an electronic system.
And one of the biggest
uh changes and benefits was because it's electronic, they can now log all access.
And so for example, they can set like a privacy sensitive flag.
Uh for example, on famous people's files
and then review those accesses and be like, why did you look at this person's files?
Oh, you're his doctor and you're like,
fix them, right?
You know, that's ok or you're a nurse with this doctor or
you know, whatever.
But and then there's all these other cases where it's like, OK,
you have no reason to be looking at this patient's file,
you know, same thing with banks, right?
Banks, you know, log all access.
So the tellers, you know, it's like, oh, you know,
Kurt swiped his card at the teller station and the teller looked up all his data,
obviously, that's,
that's ok. But then,
you know, versus the teller just randomly looking up Kurt's data.
Oh, Kurt phoned and was asking a question.
Great, totally fine versus, you know, she's just randomly looking up Kurt's info,
right?
And so I would say, you know, part of this is, it's,
it's a little different when you're at work and you're working for somebody else,
you know, versus your, your behavior in private or your, you know, your own life.
I think, I think generally it's ok and it's gonna happen.
I mean, the metadata exists regardless it has to exist, right?
Because I have to access the file server to read a file.
You know, unless we have some like really insanely complicated
zero knowledge crypto
-- thing of a jigger to share our files,
-- which nobody has that,
that would be
the
same.
So I, I would like to think that, you know, knowing that, for example,
all your accesses are logged, maybe people abuse it less.
You know, this is quite frankly, for example,
why I actually still use firewalls is I still use
firewalls so that traffic that gets past the firewall is
much more likely to be something of interest.
You know, I'm basically trying to get rid of as much chaff as possible.
Well, and that's, that's fair.
I mean,
I, I kind of get that and I don't think you're wrong,
but I also suspect there is a
certain group of people
that don't understand many of these rules or what can be done.
And so they're just, they don't think or know
and they still can engage in these activities. But I guess
at the same time these people are probably also your riskiest employees and exactly
the ones you should be paying attention
to because they're opening attachments from,
who knows where.
And one of my concerns with this is that
we,
one of the challenges of some machine learning and a lot of a
I is we don't know how or why it got that answer,
right? But it did, you know the intervening neural network did the right thing.
And it identified that picture as a dog. Yay us.
So my concern is when things start to go a little wonky,
-- can we fix it? Can we even know that there's a problem
-- or is it wrong?
Maybe it's right and we just can't understand it,
which is crazy to think about,
you know, and, and that's what's interesting to me is
humans traditionally have always built machines that we understand,
you know,
and there can be machines with emergent behavior
like machines that are so complicated that like,
you know,
parts expand or contract due to heat in other
areas and then you get like wonky behaviors.
Um You know, my favorite being always is watching, you know,
you see a documentary on like steam locomotives
and these things are a nightmare like, oh my God, do you think your car is unreliable?
And you know, tough to, to operate
like a steam powered locomotive is like,
they're literally, I remember one, they're just like, oh yeah, pressure,
steam pressure is dropping.
It might blow up soon.
Uh I'm gonna start fiddling with the mobs
and then like five minutes later they're like,
ok, everything's back to normal.
-- We're ok.
-- Those things were insane.
How, how much, how much maintenance they took it.
You know what it always reminds me of is
there's always those computer systems that like when I leave on a trip,
I get a call and the kids are like, hey dad, the TV,
broke or this broke or the internet doesn't work.
And it's like,
how does this always happen when I leave? But you don't realize that that
every day
I'm fiddling with something to keep it running and I don't even realize I
do it in many instances and then I leave and three days later,
like, everything stops working and this is, this is how the world works.
Everything is falling apart constantly and people are always, like,
holding it together with tape and, and bubble gum.
Yeah. And I've intentionally at home for my IT systems here.
I've intentionally like, purchased uh like a hardware-based, you know,
small firewall
that I intentionally do not allow myself to touch.
I, I forced myself to set it up
and it's not set up as optimally or as nice as I would like.
And I don't twiddle with it, but it's set up so that it works.
Oh, man.
You know what you just reminded me of, I feel like on this,
on the podcast that a while back I was talking about the gym, I attend
that had their, their IP network range messed up because they were,
they were stealing like all the 172 networks.
So I can't get to Google.
So they fixed that.
Right. And all of a sudden Google's working now from the gym.
But I thought
I, I found out about this app on Android called Fing. Fing.
And it basically does like a wi fi scan of the network and,
and lets you know what's going on and I thought
I'll give it a scan and see what's going on.
Yeah, their whole network is flat.
They, they call it the guest network. No, not the guest network. Like, it's all flat.
I can see every machine in the place
and all the printers, all the computers, like every,
and part of me thinks I should tell them another part
of me thinks they're never gonna let me come back.
Yeah, I bring this up.
Well,
here's the problem if you bring it up and even if they don't shoot the messenger,
something bad will happen at a later point.
-- And they'll be like, hey, remember that guy.
-- Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And I don't need to deal with this. And so I closed thing and I left
and,
and Yeah,
I see that
a
-- lot,
-- you know, with, where
should I point and no, just shut up.
You know,
and that's one of the sad realities of
the universe is when you tell people something,
they, they blame you. We, we, I had this once where
there was a bunch of security guys in this.
We, we had like a little meet up at a, at a pub
and we had a nonsecurity person kind of tag along a coworker of someone else.
And that later that night,
their Facebook got hacked
and they, they were convinced beyond a reasonable doubt.
It was us because we're the security guys she met us and
all of a sudden it's like you guys clearly did this.
It's like,
look, all right, number one,
I don't know what your Facebook account is.
And even if I did, like, I don't care, there's,
I don't want to hack your Facebook account. There's,
well, not only that, it's like all Chinese
crap on it, right?
So it's clearly like just some random foreign hacker that got,
it was probably doing, you know, like Google juice spam linking or whatever.
And it's like, I don't speak Chinese,
I didn't hack your Facebook.
I don't wanna but no, there's nothing we could say like we didn't,
that was our fault.
And this is totally what happens
and,
and I guess though this kind of all works its way back into this whole A I concept now.
Is, if we can measure behavior based upon A, I,
I imagine
there will be probably some false positives,
but I suspect it will remove a lot of false
negatives because when you have a human looking at this,
if, if there's someone you don't like,
you're going to find a problem with them.
Right.
And a is, well, as far as we know,
a is, don't dislike certain people more than others.
Well, you know, you mentioned that
and I would point out all those cameras from China with the face detection software
-- that don't see um African Americans. Uh
-- I
imagine that is poor quality assurance testing on
-- the part of the Chinese company that
-- created the
but more to the point they didn't think to test this, they didn't think to, you know,
go
for extreme, you know, variations in skin color
and what, what problems are we going to have with a is where we're like, oh,
we didn't even think
to have that as a, as a problem
machine.
That could certainly be an issue.
But in theory with A I,
that will not be a problem because A I will
be able to correct such oversight on our part.
But you know what this reminds me of
is I remember when, when Siri came out
and there were all the hilarious videos from
like the Scottish people trying to talk to Siri
Chip.
That's a pretty good accent. I'm impressed.
I I do not have a Scottish accent. So II, I barely have any accent.
I, I, I'm told I have an American accent, which I,
I'm skeptical. I speak English. So
we'll just say I have an accent.
I wouldn't know about that.
That's right. You're Canadian English.
I love it.
Oh, man.
All right.
So,
yeah, I don't know. This is, this is,
I think
around
all of this A I and machine learning is that we,
we are already in a situation where a lot of people
don't understand the technologies that they use on a daily basis.
Like not even a little bit,
but that's the point of the A I I think is
like, we'll,
we'll look at security here is how many people are doing security jobs today
that you could probably replace with a couple of 100 lines of pearl
and like, like looking at logs and things like that.
And this is where I can see the A I having
immense value.
But I guess conversely A I is going to destroy
any sort of, you know, entry level position.
And so where are we gonna get our professionals from then?
I guess maybe we'll just hope the A I
keeps getting better and we don't need people anymore.
I don't know.
Well, and, and it's interesting,
you mentioned the entry level position because
that's actually one of my big concerns,
especially around CV E is that, you know, we don't, I'm,
I'm trying to build some on ramps for CV E so that we can get.
And when I say entry level people, I'm talking to people who are like,
already deeply interested in information security.
You know,
my, one of my bigger concerns now is like, what do we do with, like, you have, like,
let's say for the sake of argument, you have a bright 16 year old who's like,
I want to be a computer security person when I grow up.
So like, what courses should I take in high school?
Career choice kid,
turn,
turn around.
Yeah. So like, what, what should I do in high school?
And what should I take in university? And I'd be like, uh comp
I
maybe,
you know,
philosophy, go take as many philosophy,
you know.
And so, you know, and that, and that is a valid concern. Like, how do we,
how do we essentially get these people to train up
when we take all that easy work and like,
shove it into a computer?
I have no idea.
And this is going to be one of the great questions just with humanity in general.
I mean, look at self driving cars
when we have self driving vehicles,
we don't need people driving taxis or people driving.
Elon Musk is saying that's 3 to 6 months away for the Teslas uh
six months.
-- You know
-- what I'm assuming it's not like full self driving curb to curb,
but it's more like, ok,
like if you're on the interstate, you can go take a nap. Now,
whereas before it's like you have to pay attention
and keep your hands on the wheel and,
like, what's the point of this again?
Right.
Well, and I love that,
even though the Tesla autopilot has gotten some bad press in the recently,
they're still, they, they did, they crunch some numbers and even with its problems,
it's still significantly safer than people.
-- It was 40% less crashes, which I that's, that's a huge amount.
-- That
-- is
-- amazing.
Well, you know, this is so funny enough
when we start talking about like a I
and kind of replacing humans because we're really bad at a
lot of things is there's always unintended consequences and for example,
the unintended consequence of self driving cars
is going to be there is organ donation will vanish,
right?
Because let's face it,
the vast majority of organs donated come from automobile accidents.
And now granted, I'm gonna say this is,
I don't think this is a bad problem to have.
I think it's good if less people are dying, right? Mind you. But,
but there's, there's
the savings on medical costs and body shops and like
just the,
the tens and hundreds of billions of dollars a year in
lost productivity because people are getting bashed up in car accidents.
Well, not only that,
what about parking tickets?
There are a large number of municipalities or speeding tickets, for example,
where these these cities,
like, like the,
the traffic enforcement makes up a significant portion
of their budget and that's going to disappear.
Right.
What I'm really curious about is how this is going to affect crime because,
I mean, committing crime, one of the
tenets of it is you need to be able to get away
Alexa
getaway car.
Yeah.
You know, and,
and more to the point you can still get away but
now all the travel logs and all the metadata is there.
So
they have that anyway because I bet most of
these thieves keep their cell phones in their pocket.
So
it's hard to, you have to get a warrant for that.
You can't just be like go to the cell phone company. You'd be like, I want every,
you know what I mean?
And there have been cases of this,
there was a murder case in Germany where they caught
the guy based on the cell phone records because he,
he was murdered out in the middle of nowhere in a forest.
So they pulled the cell phone records from that
area and then found this cab driver who,
well, ultimately turns out he did it
and, and, but you don't think that we're gonna have the same sort of requirements
for just general ride information from whoever happens to
vehicle.
I, I think we might not at first, but I imagine it will happen. But
additionally, though here's the thing, man,
if we have a I that can do various behavior recognition.
What happens when we have an A I watching,
like what every human being is doing on the planet in terms of where they travel,
kind of what they're buying all this stuff.
And all of a sudden they're like, this guy just bought like shotguns and he's,
he took it car out into the middle of the woods
and, you know,
and then he's traveling there later with, with his wife,
like something crazy is going on here, you know, what do you do then?
Do we have the A I basically say, hey,
please go arrest this guy's gonna murder his wife in the woods
and it's crazy to think about this stuff, man.
I mean, it's very minority report, right?
Well, we already have this to a degree with email, right?
All my email gets scanned for spam.
So it's a very specific use case of like we're gonna scan all
your email and like chuck out 99% of it because it's garbage.
And I'm like, sweet, I can live with that.
And then people get upset, for example, because you have, um,
ad insertion based on what your email content is,
right?
And so there's these varying degrees, you know, versus like, if, well,
remember when Yahoo was found out to be running their, um, their email,
you know, snarling project,
you know, for, uh, on behalf of the
organization,
you know.
Um, and so the, you know, it, it reminds me of, um, like in, in Britain,
they have a stated goal of having a N pr automated number plate
recognition cameras and they've put them on all the major highways and everything
with the ex, like,
one of the explicit goals is to deny the use of the highway system to criminals.
Right?
Uh, if you watch the British equivalent of cops,
now they actually have motorway cops that are dedicated to like,
uh one of the main things they deal with is like you get an A N pr
hit on a vehicle of interest and they go chase it down and see what's up,
you know, and
uh quite often there is something up, you know, this car is reported stolen or
um some of it was really interesting to me was this car is of interest.
It was reported to be associated with this address where, you know,
this person lives that is maybe accused of this crime or
is a known drug dealer or it's a known drug house.
So in some countries, we've already got that going on,
right?
And apparently people are ok with it because, you know,
I haven't heard any mass protests or
-- any changes in the law in Britain. It's tricky
-- man.
I mean, I, I can see it both ways where the,
the eff loving,
you know, ac lu in me says
this is terrible. We shouldn't do this because
we're going to catch
somebody not doing anything wrong
and get them in trouble.
But another
side to me.
But,
so here's what
-- I think
-- the self
cns
piece is even worse than that.
You know, we're going to get people to just not do behaviors that
are not a problem but they're going, you know,
that's exactly part of it.
And I guess in a free society we have to recognize that the rights of the people
outweigh
any potential benefit we could derive from these sort of A I behavior programs.
Well,
we've already in some ways crossed these, you know,
-- things. Um No,
-- we have, but this is not uncommon
for humanity to make a step forward with some new technology and then to see it
abused and then have to come in and somehow regulate that for the benefit of society.
I mean, that's basically
-- the story of humanity,
-- right?
See,
one of my biggest fears is we're getting to a point where it's
becoming very easy to track and measure and stifle like political dissent.
And part of having a healthy government system is,
is having those healthy outlets for political dissent.
Like I can go and protest and say rude words
and then I feel better about it and I don't, you know, feel the urge to blow stuff up,
right?
Because I can't, I have no outlet, right?
And the reality is there are parts of
the world where things have escalated such that,
you know, people think blowing stuff up is a valid form of political expression.
-- You know, and I don't want to live in that part of the world or in that
-- kind
of society because they can't protest or
what it boils down to. I think a lot of it is, is when you have
outlets for, you know, like, let's say,
for the cigar and you have 10% of the
population in your country wants things a different way
and they feel that they have no outlet for that and they have,
they're not being heard and they get pissed off and frustrated about it, right?
Like the American election is a great example,
not everybody's happy about the outcome,
but they feel that they were heard by and large, you know,
same thing with when I vote in most elections.
I,
you know, don't get the outcome I want,
but I participated and I was heard and, you know, as ugly as the process was,
it works for, you know, various values of works.
So while I may not be happy about the outcome, I'm at least,
uh you know, sort of ok with it. And I don't feel a need for example to, you know,
go overthrow my government because I didn't get the government.
-- I want, we're going
-- to get a visit
enforcement.
-- My next trip to the US is going to be an annoying
-- fun time,
which is Rs A.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, they're already, you know, asking,
um apparently they were asking people to show them their social profiles.
And again, you know, there's a great example like,
you know,
if you're traveling to the US and your social profile
consists of like some really strong anti US rhetoric,
you know, should they let you in
uh anyone with any sense will create a Ringer Facebook
profile where you post nothing but pictures of kittens.
And then when the border control says, Kurt, show me your Facebook page.
You can be like
here it is. Aren't these some neat looking cats? I really like them a lot.
This little one here is the cutest,
I mean, but, and this is, I mean, I guess this is part of the challenge as well. Is,
well, is, is it part of the, no, it's not really part of the challenge.
This is, this is a place a I will be interesting because
it will be much more difficult to hide.
Well, and, and that goes to hiding and masking, right?
You, there's the difference between hiding and a difference between masking.
You know, where you, you, for example, you take up, uh,
gardening as a hobby so that you can buy large amounts of fertilizer
-- without looking suspicious
-- for
some
reason.
Yeah.
Um,
again, it comes back to, you know, on the one hand,
I don't want to live in a police state, but on the other hand, I don't,
II, I like
having a society that is relatively crime free.
That is a nice thing.
But do you think you can have
relatively crime free
without police state, like behavior?
I think, given certain
economic systems where there was more equitable,
equitable distribution of wealth we could certainly get, you know,
because a lot of crime is based on, you know, people are desperate.
Right. Like,
um, there's people in my neighborhood that will basically, you know,
take anything that's not nailed down and then try and sell
it at a pawn shop because they're just economically desperate.
I don't like that. They're stealing stuff.
But at the same time, I, I get that, you know, when you
say, for example, are on welfare and only get, you know, $627 a month here.
You know, the incentive to steal stuff to get an extra 50 bucks is pretty strong.
Yes. This episode has delved bizarrely into countless social issues.
Well, and that's, and,
but that comes back to security. A lot of these,
we're trying to solve a lot of social and human issues with technical controls.
Like, for example, why should it be unsafe for me to accept an email from anybody?
There is no way me accepting an email from anybody should result in like,
my life being destroyed because my accounts all get cleaned out.
I agree completely and I blame email.
I, I believe we,
we went out of our way to make it
convenient and my favorite whipping boy here is attachments.
Email attachments shouldn't be a thing just period.
And, and you can say no, you're wrong but I'm gonna say no,
just look
security report. I sent you a few weeks ago about the um
it was, it was about high value targets
and what real security can we do for them? And they actually had data
and for high value targets,
they don't use attachments anymore because it's a known thing.
Yeah, obviously you email somebody
like a PDF saying, hey, here's a copy of my resume or hey,
here's some data that you might be interested in or hey, I'm having trouble,
you know, opening this file.
Can you please help me?
And of course, the file is infected with like some, you know,
virus to hijack the guy's phone.
And so a lot of these like human rights activists, for example,
no longer do email attachments, they'll do you know,
use a file service like say dropbox or box or whatever.
Right.
Exactly. And then it becomes very easy from there to, you know, handle the file a lot.
Say for like, so for example, with PDF si, don't open PDF S on my system anymore.
I upload them to Google Drive and I open them in Google Drive,
which is totally the right thing to do.
But,
and here's what it comes back to though is
we have done a very poor job of creating resilient systems.
And I think there's a variety of reasons for that. But I think fundamentally
we need technology that is trustworthy to the point.
You shouldn't have to worry about attachments or you
shouldn't have to worry about downloading and executing things.
It should just be,
this shouldn't be a problem.
And it is,
and I know it's easy for me to say it shouldn't be a problem and it's really hard to
solve because we both know how much work it
is to actually get this stuff to work correctly.
But
that is really the, the bar we need to have.
And unfortunately,
I think people have just come to accept the crappiness of everything.
And so they don't demand
the, I guess quality
that, that we, we need for society to function correctly.
Well, I suspect this is one of the reasons that mobile phones have become
and, or, or are in the process of becoming more the de facto compute platform.
You know, it used to be desktops and then desktops and laptops.
And now it's, in my opinion, from what I've seen,
it's moving to cell phones and tablets
and, you know, basically you have two players in town,
you have Android and you have Apple's IOS.
And while technically
have Windows,
-- Android is way ahead and it's totally a security nightmare man
-- because, well,
the challenge with Android is is
if you are able to run an up to date version of Android from Google,
then, then you're really quite secure.
The problem is all these weird incentives by carriers to lock
down the phones and not allow you to update them.
And so, like, that's why I'll never buy an Android phone because in Canada,
most of these carriers do a terrible job of providing
updates or supporting them for more than six months.
I, I can't be using a phone that's like two years out of date. Software wise.
No, I agree. And I bought a Nexus phone for this exact reason is because I,
yeah, it's an, I bought
it from Google where it's, it's unlocked
and
it's updated once a month. I get my security update
and everything is fine
-- in theory.
-- Yeah.
And I think I'm hoping more carriers will pull their heads out of there.
-- You know what? I,
-- here's the thing though, people don't know or care.
People are still buying these crappy phones
and until there are economic demands that say they have to change their behavior,
it will never get better.
Right.
And this is the same deal with email attachments
and downloading and executing crap you find on the internet,
like there is no economic incentive to do it.
Right. It is just the sad reality.
Yeah.
Well, I'm hoping that's why, you know, some companies like, well, for example,
you're a Nintendo run example, you know, from last
I still can't download, come
on,
get it
together.
-- There's a
-- placeholder
so you,
you can't play this game either.
Yeah. So,
II, I think the good news is, at least we have two major platforms now that are,
you know,
um, well embraced by the public and reasonably secure because God,
can you imagine how terrible it would be if phones ran the equivalent of like,
like a default windows install from five years ago?
They kind of do, man.
It's, I think the thing that saves them
is the Play Store because they've made it easier to download apps from the Play Store
than they did to just go to dodgy internet sites and find them on your own.
And let's face it.
That is the fundamental problem windows had was you could,
the whole ecosystem was built around finding dodgy
crap on the internet and installing it where?
Oh,
yeah. No, it's, I ran into that last week. I was looking, um,
I started playing a computer game and I wanted to check like,
what are the requirements
hardware wise.
And so I was, you know, searching for like Hearts of Iron for, you know,
hardware crime.
I was trying to figure out basically, I was like, trying to price out, you know,
what video card can I get at a minimum?
You know,
uh, CPU that kind of stuff.
And I get to a website and it's like, oh, you know, it,
it has these requirements and we have this helpful little like dot exc which you
can download and run to see if your system meets the requirements and I'm like,
no,
definitely not running that. Like, there's no way this is legit,
you know.
Um Conversely I had to do this because uh the, that laptop I bought and loaded up the,
the fan was acting wonky on it.
So I had to go to Lenovo and download some
utilities from Lenovo, which it came from their website.
-- So I'm, I'm hoping it's legit.
-- Was it signed?
Uh No,
-- but
-- it had their brand,
it had their logo on it so that,
you know,
-- like bad guys never do that.
-- Yeah.
So, you know, anyway, so I,
I downloaded their diagnostic program from their website.
It has their logo on it. But yeah, it was, it was unsigned if memory serves
and windows of course, is like you really want to do this.
And I'm like, no, I don't, but I have to,
you know, and this is one thing I look forward to actually is I've been
um
there's actually a lot of Android apps I would like to run,
but I don't want to get like a second phone, you know,
and apparently now chromebooks are going to support Android apps
this year. It's gonna be awesome.
Yeah, I mean,
because quite frankly that means I can get a chromebook and
for sure there's like the whole software ecosystem is there,
right?
-- Everything I need, there's
-- just kind
of stuff. Definitely,
I look forward to it.
-- Yeah.
-- So, you know,
just,
yeah, I mean, if you make it easier for people, they,
they will do the more secure option if it's easier.
Well, right. And I think that's kind of the whole idea. Right. Is
we need to make security default and easy. And we've not done that and
-- I, we may
-- never
gone out of our way to stab people in the eye with a four.
We've done amazing acrobatics to be very terrible to people. Yes.
Hopefully
a I can help with some of this, but I will not claim it's going to save us all.
But I think if anything is,
it probably is our best bet at this point because I think it's, it's fair to say
people aren't going to fix this stuff.
I think it's a lot like crime. I mean, for example, if you get rid of 90% of crime,
that's a huge improvement.
You know, if we can get rid of, um,
you know, 90% of attacks that would have succeeded in the past now,
get blocked like ransomware type stuff, you know, imagine like you,
you get a ransomware thing,
you start encrypting all the files on the server and the server goes.
Whoa, that this does not seem right.
I'm going to block your access for like 20 minutes and go alert it,
you know,
right there. Like all your ransomware attacks suddenly become like
annoying. Not like, oh, the buses don't work or?
-- Oh, was it some public library got nailed.
-- Uh, I
say,
I think
ST Louis public Library and I guess they paid the ransom because they
apparently had backups, but paying the ransom got them back online
much, much faster.
So, I mean, you know that right there, I mean, how much did they pay
10,000?
Whatever? It wasn't cheap.
Yeah. So,
you know, if these A I systems, I mean, the,
I guess the good news is we're seeing attacks now that are
painful enough to be a problem but not so painful that,
that, you know, people aren't dying
and
people are dying
yet.
Take comfort in that everybody.
All right, let's,
let's wrap it up, man.
Uh
Thank you everybody for listening. It was a
very philosophical rambly episode. So if you hung in this far, well done,
I congratulate you
if you want to get a hold of us,
we have show notes as well as contact info on open source security podcast.com.
There is the Pound Os S hashtag Os S podcast. Hashtag
You can use as well as links to a Facebook group.
You're welcome to join, to chat with Kurt and myself.
We have obviously Twitter. We love, feel free to let us know.
And
I guess if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You
-- too, Josh.
-- And thanks for listening again, folks.
-- Thanks everybody.