Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 29 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
Kurt, if I said to you a long time ago in a galaxy, far, far away,
-- what would you think
-- of probably leaving the room?
Whatever man,
today, we're going to discuss the security of rogue one,
which is the latest Star Wars movie.
Well, it takes place in the Star Wars Universe.
-- We'll say it's the
-- most recently released Star Wars movie.
And so if you haven't seen this movie,
you should probably stop the podcast now because I'm fairly certain
we will ruin it for you in every possible way.
So you've been warned everybody
and just for clarity, this movie
essentially takes place.
What is it minutes or hours before
the
uh fourth film, which
was the first film to ever be released of the Star Wars series,
right?
I would assume the ending is similar between
hours to days before episode four starts.
Yeah, because they,
well, let's start spoiling.
They, because they redid the entire hallway scene,
the
beginning,
the hallway scene, they,
they
didn't
do it, but they essentially copied it Right. And they, they, they,
the way the first film starts is the way the last this film ends except on a, I,
I assume a different spaceship because they have to get
away or ready to
escape
on the giant ship.
And then they get in the little corvette ship and speed away with the, the plans,
the,
the X filled data. But we'll get to that, we'll get to that. Why don't we start
at the beginning? Because
there is a lot to talk about here.
Well, so let's,
well, you know, and starting at the beginning,
why don't we start with sort of one of the biggest
points of the film, like literally the whole point of the film, which is
the death star is engineered by this guy who hates the imperium.
So I'm not sure why he works for them because
-- so this guy is living as a farmer with his wife and kids.
-- No, no,
no. Let's,
-- it
-- makes no damn sense.
None of it does because it's a Star Wars movie and let's not obsess on plot
because
if you want to talk about plot holes, we're going to be here for a week.
We're going to talk about
cinema sins will do this better than we can.
We'll
put a link to that
in the show notes where
a
professional can eviscerate the movie.
We're just going to focus on security.
Yeah. So the Death Star has a reactor to power it Right. That, that makes sense.
Right. You got to have batteries or something
and there's a flaw in the reactor that if you basically blow up the reactor,
the whole thing blows up.
But, I mean,
that's
every power station.
This is
a,
-- this is a plot hole and,
-- well, it's a secure,
-- they should have put some armor on the
-- damn
thing.
A sheet of plywood over the hall. But that's not the point. right is that let's focus
-- nuclear
-- vessels, nuclear reactors,
four inch thick vessels.
And those things, even when they go bang on, you know,
three Mile Island in Fukushima and Chernobyl as bad as they were.
Well, Chernobyl had no containment vessel but even as bad as they are, you know,
-- they don't like go completely kaboom
-- because a rogue engineer didn't design them.
Right. They were designed by competent engineers. We will assume.
Well, yeah. Anyways. Yeah.
So, so I would say that's sort of the, one of the biggest,
uh to me security flaws is like you have this enormous power supply,
you should probably like put some shielding around it.
Ok? We'll get to that. All right, we'll get to that. Let's start at the beginning.
But I think
the first thing I noticed in
this movie is they,
they rooted their, their android, right?
It was an Imperial droid, right? That big black robot
-- sidekick. Right.
-- Right. Big black Robo
sidekick. I, that's, that's a fantastic name.
So, yeah, so they they,
I wasn't clear on that because my understanding is these robots are
self-aware like C three po and R two D two and stuff.
Right. They are basically self aware and they can have conversations and stuff.
-- I would say they are legitimate artificial intelligences.
-- Exactly.
In a robotic mobile body with some sort of magic power source that runs the thing.
We'll ignore that.
And, um,
but, yeah, so, you know, at first I wasn't clear on like, did this, you know, robot,
you know, kind of gain a conscience and join the rebels or?
Yeah, did they root
they,
they reprogrammed him
in the movie. So my assumption is they somehow captured the robot and
basically rooted it, as I would say, all the third party
or,
I mean, it could be a physical, like, you know,
like adding a chip or bridging something, right?
-- Which
-- kind of whatever, whatever it doesn't matter.
But the point is the robot didn't defect seems to be what was suggested,
which would be very interesting if you had uh robots in the Star Wars universe or any.
Well, I mean, other universes have, have done this but
where they have a concept of, of morality,
which doesn't seem to be the case because the
robots seem to generally just do what they're told
even if they don't want to because like three po complains at length and,
-- and even this guy K two, like they complain about everything but they
-- still do
go off script a couple of times.
I don't know. That's, I, I can't,
he shows initiative.
He, he shows initiative but I don't think he's ever, he, I
think he
put him
back in the trash.
That's his job is to be annoying.
At least this robot wasn't as annoying as three po because he was the
-- least annoying character in the movie, but it
-- does get shot
and killed. So I'll, I'll, I'll take
II I will accept his annoying
because
that's the only character when it died. I felt bad.
-- Like everyone else, I didn't care.
-- I just felt
relieved. The robot.
I'm like, oh, that poor robot, everyone else is dead.
-- I'm like in
-- fairness to the storm troopers.
I mean,
that's actually one thing I would like to see is somebody
tally up how many storm troopers die in this thing.
I bet you that is somebody did that. I guarantee somebody did that.
And I'm not gonna look right now because
I don't care.
But, well, how many storm troopers must have been on the death star? Right?
When it, when it blows up in episode four.
I mean, the, the, the genocide committed there is gonna be incredible
and weren't they? Ok.
So here's something I'm not clear on in the or like so the trilogy of trilogies,
the middle trilogy being released first and then the first trilogy being released
in the first trilogy, they're all clones of the what's his face?
The bounty hunter dude.
Uh, Django Fent, his name,
they're all clones of him.
And his
quote
unquote son is a clone of him
but didn't have that sort of, um, mental programming put in.
He was more independent,
right?
He's like a legitimate clone as opposed to some sort of reprogrammed robot clone.
So, at what point did the imperial Republic or whatever
stop using clones and start using normal people?
So I'm sure there's something written about
this in the official Star Wars universe.
But from if, if you only watch the movies, which is kind of what I consider
the canon and I hate all this extra crap people like to write.
But after the sixth movie,
before the seventh movie, which there's like 2030 year time span, it,
it would appear, they started using people.
And in fact, in, in episode seven, they,
one of the characters even
makes a reference to if you're like regular storm troopers can't handle this,
maybe I'll get clones to do it suggesting that clones are inferior
to the people.
But the people obviously have some level of willpower that can make them.
Yeah, whereas the clones will march across minefield happily.
Yeah, we'll get to that one
so
much wrong with this
here.
What drives me nuts too is we see these, these are like combat robots
essentially or not.
See that's the other thing I'm not clear on these,
these robots are they meant for combat or not?
-- Because you mean
-- the K two robots,
that's the big black one.
But there's a bunch of them in the film and as far as I can tell,
like, they're always just sort of stomping around not doing anything.
Like you don't see them with guns. Right.
At least I don't remember seeing them with guns.
I don't
recall. They, they gave K two a gun at the end. Yeah.
Yeah.
But other than that, it,
-- I, I don't see because
-- I'm kind of wondering maybe after the clone wars, you know,
with that robot army from the trade federation that they
kind of realized giving robot guns was pointless because they,
they, they suck at this.
Uh
Maybe so according to
Wikipedia,
this is a KX series security Droid.
-- So I would assume they're capable of some level of violence.
-- Stupid question.
Why don't they have eyes in the back of their head?
They only have eyes in the front.
Why they don't need eyes? They should have some sort of liar.
So they know what's going on all around them at all times. But
that is
a plot hole
in my opinion
-- that we can, it's a
-- technology hall, right?
Like, I mean, if it was me, if I was building security robots,
they would be like essentially of a 360 field of view with a variety of sensors,
you know,
thermal, infrared, night vision, you know,
-- radar.
-- Here's the thing. If you had robots
that were perfectly aware of their surroundings at all times.
These movies would be far less interesting.
-- Right.
-- Let's face it.
I'd be ok with that. They'd be shorter.
Right.
So, anyways, ok. So moving along,
so they're transporting,
was that a bunch of those crystals they were transporting?
They were called
kyber crystals apparently,
which are supposed to be the energy source for a lightsaber.
So for those of you don't know,
they're apparently strip mining this old temple of like all these kyber crystals
and loading them up on a big star destroyer,
which which now actually I've heard people complaining because the star destroyer
is hovering above the city and it is not a known fact,
but star destroyers kind of from the beginning
have been
uh uh able to fly an atmosphere that isn't like something they went off
reservation for in this movie,
this is something they can do. They can fly in an atmosphere
shield technology, right? That can block stuff.
So I assume they could just put a shield around it and fly it into.
The problem is obviously gravity because you have a huge massive object and the
amount of energy that must be required to keep it from falling to the earth
is
outrageous to say the least. However, as someone else pointed out
is when you think about episode five, when they're invading
hath with the uh at
Walkers,
like why didn't they just fly down the freaking star destroyers and shoot the bay
right.
Drop a rock on it. Right. Or even land on top of it for that matter.
So, it's a legitimate complaint.
Yeah. So, anyways, um,
so they're transporting this cargo,
it's like on a little sort of hover car type deal
and it's surrounded by a bunch of guys and they're,
you know, so they're clearly expecting trouble
and then
they get ambushed and they basically just all stand around and die.
They have no air cover,
they have no,
they have air cover. There's a giant ship over the whole city.
You
know,
why didn't they just helicopter those stupid crystals out of there
or like an elevator, right? Like the
tethered
space,
right? Yeah.
Again though, this is a, a plot vehicle,
in my opinion and we can all acknowledge that this is a
ridiculous thing no reasonable organization would
do from a security perspective,
right?
So the other thing from a security perspective, you know, ok, here's a question,
what does storm trooper armor actually
-- block or protect them?
-- I suspect it doesn't protect them, but it is a thing they wear
that mercy kills them if they take any damage
because
in episode, well, think of it, episode six, dude, like ewoks,
throw rocks at them and they die like this is clearly not protective armor.
You know, they, they get stabbed through their armor,
they get just blunt force damage through their armor.
They,
and the other thing that drives me nuts. Is,
their armor is never scuffed up. So they have some sort of technology
because
once they die,
they don't have technology if they get, they get hit once and they die.
-- So they're constantly producing new armor.
-- Right. Ok.
That makes sense because I was, like,
thinking about this and I was looking at my snowboard helmet.
It's like my snowboard helmet is just scuff to heck from just, you know,
being dropped on the floor or whatever.
You know, it reminds me of the scene from the island where, um, you know,
the main character, what's his face?
Ewan mcgregory is like, why, why white, why,
why can't it be like gray or black but white?
-- You know, do you have any idea how hard it is to keep these things clean?
-- Right. Right.
Of course. And
I, I agree, I think that the storm troopers are completely ridiculous. And
I don't know, honestly, again, I suspect it's a plot device.
You need to look cool.
You know, the only thing that's cooler than having a bunch of, like,
scary looking soldiers and white is, is having the heroes, like,
mow them down with no regard.
And that's the other thing like the storm troopers. Ok.
I know they have blasters and they shoot stuff that's cool.
They also have hand grenades which they,
like never use except when they throw them at
a robot which catches them and throws them back
again.
Well,
don't,
you know,
-- make hand grenades with a contact
-- fuse. Not them,
they, they also make armor that provides your protection code, I think. Yeah.
Yeah.
Oh God.
So, anyways, here's my favorite. It's, and it's a movie trope, but
to break them out of that, like prison, they shoot the door lock and the prison door,
like, whips open faster than you can say.
I love that. Ok.
So here's the deal in the real world, you always want doors to fail open, right?
Because if something bad happens,
-- you for health
-- and human safety.
However, in a prison, I bet prisons don't fail open or at least, I hope they don't.
It sort of depends. Um,
but basically if you cut the power to them, uh, I'm assuming they don't all just open,
but they can be manually opened,
which is the important part is you need essentially like
the thing to remember about prisons is prisons are built so they don't burn,
they're all concrete and steel, right?
Because you have people in there who will
very happily, you know, create a fire to cause a
problem.
There's also perhaps this wasn't a prison, this guy was in,
maybe it was like a repurposed room closet.
-- And so shooting the door will open,
-- it had like an armored door with bars repurposed,
right? They, they put a nicer door on II, I
don't know, like
it. I, I totally agree with this that if you have a prison
and you can just shoot the door.
That's ridiculous.
Well, the door lock, right, you shoot the door lock and in my experience, like,
when you,
well, I'm, I'm assuming if, for example, I'm not going to shoot it,
but if I took a hammer to a proximity card, swiper thing and smashed it,
you know, I,
somebody's gonna have to call maintenance to replace it and open the door.
Right. I suspect the terrorist organization doesn't have maintenance.
Yeah. Well, because remember in, I remember, I forget which desk are
but they do clearly have it because, remember they try and seal the door and then the,
the storm troopers do manage to open it.
Yes. That's right. It's, again though, I guess this sort of comes back, I guess
the
imperium is more
and later in the movie they, they break the door to keep it shut.
Right. They seal them in the data vault by,
he smashes the control panel. And that's the other thing. I don't understand.
Why do you have this massive control panel to like a door?
Like,
-- I'm
-- sure it
has
a button
-- up and down. Like,
-- yeah, but it does other things. Right.
It's not just to open the door, I'm sure a button to open the door
and then buttons for everything else.
Right.
And then that's acceptable. I buy that. All right. So the door is,
I'm ok with smashing door locks to make them
stay shut.
I'm not ok with them, like you smash the door lock and the door whips open.
Maybe, maybe the blasters have a special setting
for
open. So,
yeah.
Right, exactly.
Set
number 712
turn it on, shoot the lock, the door opens. Right. It's like a ha.
Yeah.
So anyways moving along the movie, so at one point they have, um, the,
the research scientists on that little
base on the planet or whatever. Right. And they sneak up on them
and this is what gets me,
these are obviously high value scientists because they have a ton of guards.
They have anti air defenses.
They have those, um, what do you call the, the,
the fighters with the hexagonal wingy things?
They weren't to
fighters. They were some other one.
These
were,
they have,
not only do they have air defense, they have like an air wing there to guard them
so clearly a high value group of people
and they don't use landmines.
Well, they did shoot them all at the end so they can't be that important.
Right.
But, I mean, you know, my understanding of the imperium is like if you mess up,
you get force choked or shot.
Uh, yeah, that, that, that seems fair. But did they mess up?
I mean, that one guy messed up, the rest of them
just were doing their jobs.
I also wonder if it was actually them,
uh,
was a security thing because these people knew how the
death star was built and what its weaknesses might be.
And so kind of like, you know, the Egyptian pharaohs or the, uh,
the Ming dynasty tombs, you know, shooting all the workers so that,
-- you know, their secrets go to their grave,
-- maybe.
But you'd think at the same time you wouldn't store the complete plans unencrypted
on a massive storage device
on
some
in fairness. That thing had reasonably decent security that
-- we'll get to that in a,
-- compared to like a lot of the other stuff in the movie.
Right?
Any who? So, yeah. So they, they mow down these scientists and just these poor guys.
But
yeah, the, the fact that she could, like, sneak up on this base and that there's,
you know,
there's no sensors, there's no land mines,
like seriously perimeter defense is a thing for a reason.
I would agree with you
-- completely. I suspect you can have
-- a home security alarm.
I'm not answering that question.
Well, then you're probably, I'm guessing you do and you're,
it's probably more effective than what the Imperial.
Ok. I'll agree with that.
A typical home security system is without question,
better than what these guys had.
Now at the same time,
they were clearly on a remote planet
and they were obviously in a very out of the way location.
And so
there is something to be said by an attempted security through obscurity here.
But I think fundamentally when you put it all together. Yeah.
It's completely ridiculous. And their physical security of that installation was
deplorable.
Yeah.
Well, it always is. Right. I mean, it's
the reaction times and everything are always quite terrible
and, and I, if I was one of the people protecting that I'd be like,
I don't want any storm troopers, like, just give me, like, some little kids,
anything but those guys.
Yeah, that's one interesting thing actually. Speaking of, uh, like air defense.
So you see in, um, on the rebel side they always have that little dude sitting in a tr
-- can on a pole.
-- That's
right
on
the, the moon. I forget the name of it.
-- No,
-- but in the other movies he's in a couple of movies too.
I remember that because I was always like, what is he doing out there?
Like, he sometimes has binoculars, sometimes he doesn't have binoculars. Like,
is he just, is he, you know, the backup in case the radar fails?
-- Maybe he is the radar, you know, like, yeah,
-- so I've always wondered about that.
So, like the imperium seems to,
you know, obviously of stuff like radar but they, they don't seem to have any,
you know, basically the,
the rebels fly a bunch of ships and then start shooting the place up and they're like,
all shocked and surprised.
Uh That's basically what happens in episode five though as well where they're on
h
and
the Empire shows up
-- with their,
-- detect them in orbit.
Was
it,
did
they
remember we've detected them in orbit?
So obviously they have some sort of radar or optical or something.
-- Go, they're, they're at least looking.
-- Ok.
So life technology exists, at least in this universe we can't,
we can't pretend it doesn't.
And so yes,
the empire has zero excuse for not enabling this functionality onto their remote
engineering base.
So,
uh anyway, so, and, ok, moving along, so they steal a plane.
Now, this part is actually somewhat believable.
I, I agree
it's spaceship, not, not a plane
in a spaceship. My bad. Yeah.
So, I mean, in general, planes, um, so apparently some small planes do have locks,
they're just not very good.
Um Or you can buy like a metal cover that goes over, say the throttle or the, the,
-- you
-- know, the club for your airplane
essentially. Yeah.
Um
because the reality is right,
like airplanes are kind of hideously expensive things, you know, like
100 million and up for like, you know, a decent sized commercial jet.
And so, and, and when you think about it too,
the thing to remember about a plane is it's not like it has a driver or a pilot, it has,
whichever flight crew gets assigned to it that day.
Right.
And so, you know, it's who has the keys to the damn thing.
You don't want to lose the keys, right?
And you would just end up with people making like 17 million calls the keys.
So, you know,
most planes essentially that's the thing to remember too.
They only live in secured environments or they're flying in the air,
right?
Like, like my local airport, if you want to get on to the airport, tarmac,
you better have a good reason and a pass,
right?
Because the whole thing is surrounded by chain link with
barbed wire and there's armed security and RC MP.
-- So
-- did you know that there are actually like repo men for airplanes?
Which is a crazy story to read about.
-- Yeah,
-- they've had to sneak on to the, the tarmac and take off with these things.
So I'll buy that because realistically, you know, it's like, uh,
you know what
I think because there are
repo men for airplanes and they're obviously fairly successful at what they do.
I don't think it's a matter of airplane security is,
is the security or the secured location.
I think it's a fact that
there's a very limited number of people who are
actually capable of taking off with these things,
but most importantly is once you get it, like, what do you do with it?
You can't hide it.
-- It's very difficult.
-- There's been planes that have been stolen and gone missing
and
there's very few of those. So that is certainly not a typical thing that happens.
And generally speaking, gone missing, they're pretty sure they all crashed.
Right.
Well, that's the thing. Right.
You'd never be able to fly to like a legitimate air airport without like, you know,
changing the tail number and getting a whole bunch of documentation and
which,
which the stolen spaceship now,
they don't change the tail number.
They apparently changed nothing about it and,
and the rebels have it and the empire clearly either nobody reported it missing,
which seems unlikely because I'm fairly certain they didn't kill everybody
at the location.
In fact, we know they didn't because the, the main character,
the guy who wears the white white cape,
he, he escapes.
And so you think he'd be like, uh, somebody should go and make sure that, you know,
like, nobody stole anything that we care about over here because, uh,
everyone sort of died.
Yeah. And, and sort of the main, one of the main crux points of the movie is
apparently the authentication credentials to get
through the shield and into the stuff
is tied to the spaceship.
It's
not
-- guys, you know.
-- Yeah.
It's not like somebody has, like, the password written down in their wallet.
It's actually like,
or maybe there is a sticky note,
right? Maybe there's a sticky note pasted into the radio.
And so they're like,
we're gonna read this code here and hope it works
every time they do that, transmitting the codes, it takes several seconds.
Like, think about that for a second, right?
Like, it's really slow every time they do this,
-- transmitting the code
-- because it's suspenseful.
If it was immediate, it would be far less interesting as the viewer.
-- I need to be emotionally engaged in the scene.
-- Ok.
It, it, again, I'll call that a plot device that I'm willing to overlook.
Well,
what really gets me too is so then they get to this place
where they need to use the access code and the guy's like,
you're not on the manifest and they're like,
they give some excuse about the delay somewhere or something, which
-- actually is kind of believable, but then it's just like, ok, come
-- on in.
Well, not only that, not only that, I love that
they land them right next to the giant data store warehouse thing that,
that huge spire instead of being like
there's a ship showing up we don't know about.
They have a reasonable excuse, you know, let,
let's have them park over by the farm on the other side of the planet.
You know, not by the sensitive industrial complex that we're worried about.
And the whole reason we have a shield around this planet.
Yeah,
that's what always gets me about all these movies is they
have this like big grandiose security measure that's essentially ineffective,
kind of like, you know,
um, airport security, right?
You have, uh, the,
the line of metal detectors with people
pawing through your luggage and everything and,
you know, when it really, what we,
what we really needed was like reinforced cockpit doors,
you know,
they, they had a door and it was closed.
Yeah. Well, sort of, but not really because apparently anybody can open it.
Uh, which, wait, which store are you talking about?
I was talking about the shield, all of them.
Well, the shield door was closed and they,
the only way they open that was by crashing two star destroyers into it,
which I would say is
reasonable. Door security.
Yeah.
I mean, I, I would,
I would imagine that their threat model didn't
include star destroyers running into the gate.
Well, but again, the, you know, the rebels have some reasonably big ships.
-- Uh, that's true. They do. There's no reason they couldn't just kind of crash it
-- into
an old freighter.
You don't even need to take a warship, like,
because they have freighters in this thing, right?
They have like, or like literal or freighters hauling around rocks in later films,
right?
I don't remember.
-- Probably we'll assume there's some way to move raw material
-- and, and somebody like,
uh, what's his face?
-- Um,
-- you're gonna need more description than that.
-- The Millennium
-- Falcon
Han Solo.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean,
forget Han
Solo.
I hate these films.
I really hate these films.
Um,
so like if a private individual and a Wookie
-- or sorry, what is Chewbacca? He's a Wookie. He's a
-- Wookie Ewok.
-- Ok. And Wookies and Ewoks are related but not the same.
-- I don't think they are.
I think the idea was, but from my understanding of reading things and,
and I could be mistaken here but
uh George Lucas wanted
and, or the, the,
or the, the Ewok moon right in episode six to be wookies,
but they were too expensive. So they made ewoks instead because obviously
an ewok is half the price to build a Woogie suit.
So anyways, I mean, obviously if a private in,
if two private individuals can own something as big as the Millennium Falcon,
-- technically
-- he stole it. He won a card game and he cheated from Lando
Krizan.
-- They were playing a card game and he used the stack deck so
-- Lando can own this thing.
You know,
-- Lando
-- owns a freaking city man, like he's clearly a good businessman.
Well, exactly, Lando owns a city. Right.
Well, when there's people who basically own cities, I mean.
Right. True. But my point being is that, you know,
it's not then unreasonable.
I mean, think about it, they're protecting an entire planet, obviously something,
you know, valuable on it
to me.
You know,
that says that you should actually take into account somebody
like ram raiding you with like an or freighter.
I, which is basically what they did,
we'll say, ok. And I, I don't think that is
because you can steal these things or, you know, not even that, not even stealing it.
If you have a entire planet
that is protected essentially by one door that people can go through,
that means obviously,
you're gonna have a lot of ships in
orbit because they're gonna be bringing materials and,
and of course, if it's a data storage warehouse, there's no doubt,
regular deliveries of massive quantities of data.
Right.
And so
I think logically you have to expect at some point a spaceship
is going to break down in orbit and crash into your shield.
And so it's safe to say
that they screwed that one up. All right.
Ok. Well, I'll let that one go.
I think that's acceptable that, that even if a star destroyer hit the shield,
it should not have broken generator
or
no, the,
the generator, I assume is down on the planet.
Well, the ring thing had a generator because that was the,
it was closing like the little
ring thing.
It was,
I
don't, I don't know how that door works and I'm sure some Star Star Wars nerd
has, has put together some ridiculous explanation. But,
ok, and that's fair.
If the, if the door is generating its own shield, it is conceivable.
A ship crashing into it
would
disable that portion of it.
-- But I think
-- what doesn't make sense to me is if it is,
even if it's generating the door shield, once you destroy that
part,
shouldn't the thing generating the shield, like
on the
planet
just
fill in that little hole.
So it's
closed, which,
which would be the correct way to plan this.
But I'm not a movie writer and this is all made up crap.
So, we'll just go with it for now. Right.
Well, and interestingly, I find it also bizarre that
you can't transmit out of the shield
unless you're apparently using the imperial radio frequencies.
Well, I'm assuming the shield has to block
-- it,
-- but
here's the thing, if it's blocking radio signals, why is it
visible light because you can see the planet? So,
yeah, you could at least optically signal out of there.
Although that would not be enough bandwidth.
We don't know that. I mean, it's,
well, and the thing is too,
they were listening to the radio when they were in hyperspace.
Correct.
I
remember he had the headset.
I think they looked like a pair of um beats that were spray painted silver.
In fact, this is one of those things that I always,
always annoy me is if you are traveling faster than the speed of light,
it should be impossible to send or receive any sort of communication.
And in fact,
-- if you read the book,
-- but you can see the stars outside, remember the light streaks.
-- So that obviously you can, you could
-- receive,
you would not see light streaks either.
But we'll ignore that.
Actually, this is a plot point in the Enders game trilogy or four books,
whatever it is
where they, they, they have, they don't travel faster than the speed of light.
They travel at very close to the speed of light.
And so they have various you know, time dilation, other issues come into play. A
communication is a huge issue when these ships
are traveling near the speed of light.
And that's actually a, a huge plot point in
the third book. I forget which one now it's been, it's been a while.
But anyway, anyway,
uh again, we can ignore that as a plot device in this instance. Ok.
So,
so we got the good guys, they make it down next to
the giant data warehouse,
which again is insane.
And then the, the empire sends inspectors on board.
And like so, and, and this like, don't be,
and some of them were wearing stormtrooper armor and I think
there was one guy just in a regular fabric uniform,
correct?
Like their lieutenant or captain or whatever.
And what gets me is like, none of them have time to be like
when they get shot or choked out or, or whatever or there's no buyers,
biosensors in their thing to say like, hey, you know,
the guy in the suit of armor is dead
might want to check him out. Yo, because
I know the US military has like been working
on smart fabrics and stuff for a long time.
So they can see like where did the bullet hole go?
You know?
Well, I, I think it's safe to say that stormtrooper armor.
I mean, if these guys bump their head on, on the cabinet, they're gonna die.
So
you, you, you the amount of data you'd be generated would be phenomenal.
So we can kind of ignore that. And, and they also do this in episode four where the,
they land the ship, the storm troopers come on, they knock them out
and then
they pretend radio
malfunction by tapping his,
-- well, at least
-- they do that in episode four.
This rogue one doesn't even have that where they just walk out and they're like,
oh look, it's me.
And then everyone in that part I get because you
can social engineer your way through a situation like that,
especially
if
you're wearing the uniform.
Right.
Well, not only that if you're,
how many people are on that base and they certainly don't know each other.
It's comparable to,
if you work for a moderately sized company and you go to an office, you don't know,
95% of the people you see.
Right.
And you just assume if they're in the building, they probably belong here
as
long as they don't look homeless.
It depends who you work for. Kurt.
So we'll let that, we'll let that go even. And so they, they march themselves
into the giant data storage warehouse
and they basically just get in.
Right. It's
minimal security in that
which you think you need like at least a badge system where you're coming in.
You say there's minimal security and yet we see
like storm troopers and robots and stuff constantly stomping around
useful security. They clearly have plenty of security theater.
Yeah, because, like, later on when they,
they, they decide that they're being attacked and they, you know,
there's storm troopers running everywhere.
So they have, like, quick reaction forces that are
the
walkers show up. Right. They have
come out, it's like, where the heck were those things?
I mean, they have like, a garage full of them behind the tree or like?
Right.
Yeah, because those elevators from the, the,
the surface elevator things were not that they were only like, what, 1020 ft high.
Yeah. Right.
Well, and I guess that also suggests that given the,
their ability to respond in force is they, they expected
some level of attack on this facility because if you assumed it was secured
you wouldn't have all of these armaments just kind of waiting.
You know, it's kind of like always in, what is it episode one when they're like,
we're peaceful people and at the end they, like, pull guns out of the chair.
It's like, no peaceful people don't keep guns in their chair. Like, you know,
-- that's not how it works.
-- I remember that. Yeah. Yeah, in the throne room. But
yeah, they have like a little mini armory there and the doors, you know,
those doors emergency seal, like,
you know, and it's like a 20 ft
tall door and it seals in less than a second.
There's
some,
we'll say there's some inconsistencies in, in these movies and maybe it's,
-- you
-- know, back to Theodore Roosevelt, you know, uh,
-- walk softly but carry like a really big stick,
-- carry a giant blaster.
Yeah.
And, and so, ok, let's not get stuck here because
they go
into the vault,
they just go into the vault control room and, like, shoot it up.
Well, they don't shoot it. The robot
hacks the system
-- and then they
-- hit the guy in the head and then
it's later on where some stormtroopers come in and they get shot. Right.
You're right.
And, well,
the robot does knock some people out again just by hitting them in the head.
-- So
-- that's gotta be like at a minimum of concussion.
You know,
I assume they're dead
because they got hit in the head.
I mean, that's, it's safe to say the ST tropper gets hit in the head. They, they die.
And I, again, that's the one thing they're consistent through.
Well, all the Star, all the Star Wars movies,
like the one consistent point is stormtroopers get hit by something and they die,
right?
All the things they have. Inconsistency.
That's not one of them.
So, ok, so the robot hacks a computer they get.
Now,
now this is the thing that rogue one came
out around Christmas time and I saw it very recently
and I, I waited along, I'm not a huge movie person,
so I'm not one of those people who has to run out and see it, but I remember
there were all these comments on Twitter when it came out talking about,
you know, essentially like data exfiltration and proper authentication and,
and some of this stuff.
And I would say
that
ignoring the crap security to enter the facility,
like
the security they seem to have there,
I would say is acceptable where you have all of these tapes in their instance,
which whatever will we, we will ignore that as, as a poor storage medium.
But they have all these tapes and they have clearly
some sort of control room that's designed to work the table
well, and, and you had to manually control the tape retrieval.
Like you literally had to like drive the little robot over to the tape you wanted,
which
is done. And
well, and what's weird is they had like, no, they had like an index of code names,
which is good because, you know, like what's, what's purple monkey?
I don't know, maybe it's a destroyer, maybe it's tomorrow's lunch menu.
-- Like, I don't know,
-- that's
just good planning because when you're working on a project,
you should never call it what it's supposed to be because it could be renamed
or a, another one that'll happen is,
you know,
I if you have your code name for something and you
end up with like three or four revisions of it,
it can make it very difficult to, to decide like this is something, version two,
this is something,
version three where you just had different code names for them all.
And it simplifies things substantially. So I get that, that makes sense.
Well, and I know the military too when they generate code names,
they also make sure it doesn't have something to do with it because in World War
two there was a couple of incidents where they generated code names and it was like,
whoops, that actually describes what this does,
right? Like giant sphere of death would be a bad code name for the death star. Right.
Yeah. And they let the guy pick the code name, you know, Stardust.
So the, the daughter's like,
oh, I know that's, that's me.
And it's like if they just picked a random code word,
they would have never found the damn tape.
Uh Yes, that, that part is correct.
However, the movie would be much less interesting
if they had no idea how to find the tape. And that was a unique way. I think to kind of tie
the beginning of the movie with her interaction with her father into the end.
So I think from its storytelling perspective, that is quite fine
and I think from a security perspective it's uh whatever, right.
Then they go, they end up having to go into the data vault,
right.
Which is silly.
You, you'd think they, what they, they shoot the glass right to, to break it.
And you'd think like if, if, if the weapon of choice in your universe is a blaster.
You would assume there's something like blaster proof glass,
-- right?
-- Or at least blaster resistance.
-- Right.
-- Yeah. Like more than one shot we'll say it should take
or like, you know?
Yeah,
because blasters shoot stuff like walls and it's
not like they punch big holes in them.
-- They rarely do. Actually, they usually hit a wall and leave a black mark.
-- Right.
So that's a good point is why is it breaking the glass?
Well, again, storytelling, story, plot, whatever.
But regardless if,
if you're building a facility that's meant to hold secure data
and it has a window that you can see the data.
-- Uh make sure you, like buy the nice glass. Right?
-- Don't
you
on
it
and see
bars
up. This is leading up, I think to, I think I've figured out the problem. So, but
anyway,
go into the data fault and there's a lot of wind and air noise and stuff going on.
Right.
And at the top there's these like,
I'm assuming air vents that are opening and closing like every one or two seconds.
Right.
And I'm not at
all like everything. I, I know, I, I'll admit, I don't know a lot about HVAC
heating, ventilation, air conditioning.
But yeah, no, that would just mess up the airflow immensely. Right.
-- You just would not do that.
-- But you know what this reminds me of.
Have you ever seen the movie Galaxy Quest
and the aliens?
Build the ship,
like the speck of the movie and there's obviously like
the ridiculous Hammer Room that it serves no reasonable purpose,
but the aliens built it because it's in the movie.
And like, that's totally what I think of when I see stuff like that.
This has happened, you know, World War Two, the, um, America Land, what was it?
A B 24 or a Liberator? Anyways.
And the Russians essentially impounded it and
copied it exactly as much as they could
even to the point where there was like an extra r hole that was never used.
It was like a manufacturing mistake,
but they were like, you know, so terrified of Stalin and all that, that they like,
exactly, you know, we'll put it in the show notes but like literally the,
the Russian, whatever this,
you know, bomber had like an extra, like tiny little hole in the wing because,
well, that's what the spec says. So you better do it.
That's brilliant.
So, anyways, I think I'm beginning to think part of the problem with the imperium
is
they,
you know,
people die so often, right?
Like, I can only imagine what happens when a storm trooper falls downstairs.
They die, right?
They don't even fall
down the stairs.
I mean,
if they, if they scratch their head too hard, I'm pretty sure they're gonna die
and,
and these facilities quite often seem to catch fire
and blow up and you never see sprinkler systems.
I can't say I've ever seen a sprinkler system in a star war.
And so maybe
they have a really aggressive fire code.
How though everything lights on fire all the time.
Well, a really aggressive fire code in the sense of evacuation routes.
But if the stormtroopers
falls,
they're gonna die and then you'll have like this massive pile
of dead storm
and then you can't get out
-- like
-- all those nightclub fires and casino fires.
So maybe that's why none of these windows and doors, you know, they all fail open.
They don't have bars. You can shoot them out easily with your blaster.
It is poor security.
Let's say that, let's say that their physical security is unacceptably bad.
And al although maybe they have a bunch of rogue engineers
who hate the empire and so they purposely designed everything terribly
-- and you think at some point they notice this,
-- maybe they have and maybe they're like,
what do we do?
We don't know what to do because the engineers all hate us because we're,
we're terrible people
and
at
-- the end of their
-- contract, well, as they should,
if you design something that's purposely broken.
Right.
I mean, when you're working for an evil empire and like, you screw it up on purpose.
The shooting you is pretty much the expected outcome there. Right,
I suppose. Yeah.
Right. Like, I mean, seriously, if I was working for a guy like Darth Vader
and, and I purposely, like, ruined his giant death sphere.
I would expect to die. I, I don't see how there's like, any other option there.
Yeah.
-- I mean,
-- no, I must say too.
That's one other thing,
one other nit pick just because I can is that Darth Vader lived on a lava planet.
I would expect Darth Vader to, like,
fall into some sort of ptsd like syndrome as soon as he sees lava.
I mean, like, like, seriously,
right. Darth Vader and lava, I suspect are not friends.
Why would you live on a lava plants?
Like Captain Hook and the, uh, the crocodile,
-- it
-- would be like him living with the crocodile.
Right? Like, it would be some sort of sitcom. And so anyway, anyway, that's my, like,
I, I know again, I've ignored many plot holes, but that's one that I'm like,
this is ridiculous.
You, you know, anyway, anyway, so back to the facility sucks.
They get the tape, they bring it to the top, which again,
there's apparently some sort of wireless transmitter at the top.
There's
a, at the top of it and I'm ok with that.
That makes sort of sense and you might want to put it high up because, you know,
so you can get it as high over the horizon as possible.
Get a little bit more view.
What I don't understand is the controls
to manipulate it and change the orientation are
-- on like a walkway that sticks out like 100 ft into the air,
-- right?
And this can only be explained by the, like,
idiot aliens watching movies and designing the, the interactions.
Yeah,
because why would you need to see this thing to orient it?
It's not like you're manually pointing this thing at a,
this is something where you basically have a, you, you tell a computer,
I want you to point it at this thing over here.
There's a bunch of orbital
information.
Let's face
it again.
If you have ships
in orbit directly above you, like, you don't need to point it at the ship.
It, that ship is gonna pick up a massive dish, like blasting a signal out into space,
right?
You could point that thing at the ground and that ship is probably gonna pick it up.
Well, and,
and here's one of the few areas where Star Wars
is consistent in that they don't have targeting computers.
I think you're right.
E every single scene where you see shooting like on the Millennium Falcon
or the tie fighters or the X wing fighters, they're always,
you know, they, they have their little
BB, you know, thing kind of moving around, you know,
and like target lock and then they shoot, but,
you know, realistically if you have like targeting technology,
you're gonna strap, put it in a missile and like be like missile,
go kill that thing over there.
I don't care where it goes, just kill it.
But it's weird that they can have robots that are, like, self aware,
they can see their environment and interact with their environment and, like,
not like you never see a robot walking into a wall or into somebody.
-- They
-- clearly don't have radar.
That's the only explanation for them.
But I'm kind of wondering if they have like, this weird,
you know, they have this weird missing gap of technology of like, target, like,
target computers,
right? Like, here's a, I'm here something over there.
I wanna kill that thing over there.
Like, what do I, you know, how do I point my gun over there?
You know, this is something that the navy solved back in the, uh, like,
you know, this was, um, solved with mechanical computers back in World War One.
Which funny enough is where the,
the name computer came from because it was a device that computed
and it was
physical.
-- We should
-- probably put a link because there's just amazing us
Navy films online from like World War Two where they,
they actually show how these devices work and like, it's just an insane
mechanical contraption. I
-- think
-- I have some pictures actually where I was at a museum
and it was, it was showing up the computer from World War Two and I'm like,
that's awesome.
The fire director and all that stuff. So,
you know, I mean, the,
the reality is people have been building mechanical computers so that
you can shoot from a moving ship to another moving ship.
Your ship is not only moving, but it's like rolling around in the, we, you know,
in the, in the water
and,
you know, they're reliably hitting these things, you know,
a couple of miles away with, you know, guns,
the shoot in an arc. And, um,
yeah, so I, I just wonder like if that's, maybe there's
that, it's just like gravity. It's just one of the rules of that universe.
They
-- along with their aggressive, you know, evacuation fire code.
-- They have a I though.
And
so this is one thing actually that I, I love Star Trek.
I'm a huge Star Trek nerd.
And I find that in Star Trek they try really hard to get the science like this right
where they try not to have too many inconsistencies
and it's clear in Star Wars they don't care
because none of it makes sense
and, and rightly so rightly. So it's not my,
it's not my universe. I've made zero movies. So we'll, we'll let it go for now.
But so anyway, all right.
So, so back on task, they, they get the data, they get it into the transmitter,
they transmit it up into space.
-- It's picked up,
-- they have to
-- knock the shield down first,
-- they knocked the shield down by, by
ruining two giant spaceships that crash into the.
Here's the thing, I don't get, one of the spaceships was disabled by some sort of
cannons can take up. Basically, they disable something for a period of time.
According to the X wing video game, I was
talking
the um so the star destroyer, big ship dead in the water, so to speak,
floating around and the guys floating next to them aren't like, oh,
that could be a problem.
Maybe we should give them a bit of room
or maybe we should like, push them out of the way or, I don't know, but like something,
you know, and then the, the,
the rebels use a little corvette to push it into the other ship and it's
reasonable. And
-- that's what I totally
-- believe it's a big
flying hunk of mass.
But the point is that the other ship didn't do something about this, like,
maybe push back.
-- I don't know. I'm gonna let that one. They have tractor
-- beams,
they have tractor beams,
they do have tractor beams
because they use them in episode four. But do they use them anywhere else?
Well, if episode four is only a few hours afterwards,
-- but the tractor beam is on the death star also. I
-- don't. True.
-- Maybe it requires a ton of power and only works on small things.
-- Right.
-- Ok. You know what?
Let's ignore
that.
Let's ignore this.
They, they get the data, they put it in the transmitter,
it's transmitted up to a ship in orbit.
Right.
Then they put it on some sort of data storage,
uh,
card
it it looked like a card and that's fine.
Whatever, it doesn't matter what it is, it's kind of kind of a moot point,
-- robust
-- military grade storage.
Now, this is a thing though that they,
they put it on that and then they try to get that the plans,
they try to get them carried away as quickly as possible, like physically removed.
And this is where you would think you'd want to transmit them
like
everywhere.
Maybe they don't want the, the imperial
people to know that they have the plans they
have
at that point because they've attacked the planet, they've blown the place up.
They've
obviously somebody's been monkeying with your
data store and there's a physical tape
missing and you know which one it is plans for the death star.
So it stands to reason that, you know,
they should be able to figure out something happening
in
the very beginning of episode four.
Darth Vader is looking for the plans like they know what has happened here, right?
And I must say at the end when Darth Vader
is like beating people up trying to get those plans,
that's,
that's a pretty solid scene for what it's worth it.
-- It was, it was entertaining
-- to watch the
movie.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah,
which is very similar to the beginning of episode four.
Then where Darth Vader kind of comes through the door and
just everybody dies.
You know what it is?
No character with a cape ever dies from blasters.
The dude with the white cape, doesn't he fall to his death?
Does he
fall? He does fall. And I guess if that didn't kill him, the, the giant
death ray certainly did.
Yeah.
So
that's why,
because there are those high level storm troopers
that have capes and they seem to do,
ok, if I remember correctly,
the red ones or whatever.
Well, there's the emperor's guards which I think
are
storm
troopers.
Maybe they have blaster proof capes
have capes.
But much like, say the Incredibles, they've realized that capes, you know, that,
that's an expert level thing.
Like, you know, that thing gets sucked into a, uh,
-- a turbo engine or something and you're done for
-- capes are dangerous.
Yeah.
Well, it's just doors, man. God, how annoying would that be? Right?
You know, you're trying to make a grand entrance and like, blink, you know,
your cape stuck in the door.
I've never worn a cape in my daily life. So I, I can't say
-- I've
-- done ballroom, uh, dancing and, you know,
with partners who had to wear ballroom gowns and like,
there's a reason you have a little girl carrying the train of the dress
and there's a reason you, like,
push the chair for the ladies because the dress is so massive.
They have to like, spend all their time controlling it.
They, they can't open a door for themselves physically.
It's, it's like impossible. It would get stuck in the door.
So maybe that's why nobody escapes in the, uh,
but all their doors are like convenience store doors, you know,
like they slide open and then they slide closed.
So,
uh,
this makes no sense.
Well, and,
and this is actually something someone has pointed out at
some point is that in the Star Wars movies,
there's never been a door that just opens. They're all crazy doors.
Yeah, that's true.
Yep. All right. So
what, and the, the, the data also, here's the thing
as, as I understand it, everybody
encrypts their data when they write it to tape because tapes go missing all the time.
You know, encrypt the data on the tape.
Obviously not because they beamed it up to orbit and were able to
consume
the transmission device had the ability to decrypt the tape.
But I also feel like their plan was to steal the tape and then leave
whereas the transmission was plan B. So I think it's probably safe to say
they, but again,
why would you necessarily need to encrypt data that's meant to be on a secured planet
in a secure data
vault?
Yeah.
Ok.
-- It
-- also
-- makes swiping media easier, right?
Because you just have to crypto shred the keys.
You don't actually have to, like,
wipe the whole tape because I've had that happen where,
like I've had a hard drive in my file server die enough that I, you know,
can't reasonably wipe it.
But at the same time I can't, you know, use it
so I can't wipe the drive.
So it's like, ok, good thing that, you know,
it's all encrypted anyways because it's,
-- you know. Right.
-- And you just need to wipe the first
one K or something.
Yeah.
You know, the, the, on the route partition.
So, yeah, I mean, and again,
maybe that's just something missing from this universe.
Maybe they just don't have encryption
because they're intercepting each other's transmissions all the time.
You know, sir, we've intercepted a transmission. How often does that phrase occur
in all of these movies?
Because in, in episode five, they talk about a coded signal,
coded but maybe not encrypted.
Like, maybe they're using like a word substitution thing, you know,
like I would like a box of cannolis.
Did the word encrypted exist
back then?
Did the word encrypted exist when they made episode five?
Oh,
yeah.
Well, not in the popular vernacular.
That's true. So it wouldn't have made sense and you would say coded.
So that was kind of my assumption
is the coded message from the spy droid
was just an encrypted message and they couldn't do anything with it.
Well, the other advantage too is, right?
It's like GP G, if you're the only people using GP G, you stick out like a sore thumb,
right?
You know, and that's, I remember reading uh there was a,
um a set of slides and apparently the NSA was
like we love GP G because the only people using it
are either so crazy that we ignore them or legitimately
like we need to go keep an eye on them.
And the beauty is there's all that metadata of who's talking to who,
which is kind of mostly what we want anyway,
this is where signals gotta be a nightmare for these
guys because like tons of people are using it now.
-- And so you can't say anyone using signal is probably up to no good
-- true. But
uh does signal give away metadata like who's talking to who or is it?
We're all just talking to the signal mothership and then God
knows what's happening.
No, no.
If you're spying on the data as it's over the wire,
you could certainly tell who's talking to who,
but they don't store anything like that on the server.
OK.
Well, no, what I mean is, is the, is, for example, if we talk on signal,
am I talking directly to you or am I talking
to the signal server that is talking to you?
My understanding is you're talking to the signal server but they don't log it,
right?
So then in that case,
it would be you'd have a harder time matching up those connection pairs,
right? Because you have a whole bunch of people talking at the same time,
you know,
but I mean,
there's statistical analysis you can do with that and they've done in the past to um,
identify command and control servers and, you know, other
Tor
users where they, like, shut down parts of the Tor network.
Oh, he's still talking, ok, he's not on that part, you know,
to narrow down kind of who's talking to who.
So,
yeah, so maybe, ok, I'll buy it, you know,
this is a universe with A I and self aware robots
that don't bump into doors but they don't have targeting computers
and they don't have like good data encryption.
Sure, why not?
That seems plausible at best.
-- And, and I will say that
-- because they also have spinny computer interfaces.
Like you physically, this is what it never made sense.
You plug a thing in
and then spin it back and forth.
Well, it makes perfect sense because when you're telling the story, you know,
if the thing is spinning around something's happening.
Whereas
imagine if like Archie D two rolled up, he took out his USB plug,
plugged in and just sat there for five minutes and be like,
what's going on like this sucks, you know.
Yeah.
So it's, it's, they have this weird mix of sort of electro
mechanical computing going on, right?
Like they have tapes instead of you would assume
they have some sort of solid state memory,
you know, diamond crystal storage type deal going on with no, because let's face it.
-- Right. Computers with moving parts
-- suck
computers with moving parts on a saltwater planet, right?
-- With
-- humidity.
Yeah, with humidity.
Yeah. It's got to be ridiculous
without
a,
I can't imagine the failure rate
and, like, and all of their stuff is outside,
like the master switch for the communications thing.
It's like that outdoor terminal. So
it must rain there because there's like trees and, you know,
lots of lush vegetation,
-- but
-- they're surrounded by water. Maybe it doesn't rain.
Were there any clouds in the sky? I don't, I don't remember
there were,
were there? Ok.
Uh,
yeah. Anyway,
-- so,
-- I mean, all this stuff has got to be regularized and
clearly we come back to the point that the Star
Wars Universe has so many scientific inconsistencies that it's comical,
I guess.
But I,
I guess at the same point at the same time if you're going to make up the universe,
you have to either be Star Trek where you're
consistent to the point of ridiculous
or Star Wars where you're like, eh, whatever.
Yeah, we need, we need to switch and, and some guys need to flip it and, uh,
they're getting shot while they're doing it right.
Like, ok, sure. Put it over there,
you know, it, I kind of get it, you know, and it's like we need, uh,
data and we wanted to steal it and, uh,
let's climb something and maybe they go through a hole
that's opening or closing or something to be dangerous.
And then, uh,
-- you know, the bad guy shoots them. This
-- fundamentally is the reason I hate,
one of the reasons I should say I hate Star Wars is there is so much forced, like,
du
du du, you know, there's so much forced
fake risk and danger where, like, clearly
-- that character is not going to die because he's Harrison Ford.
-- Now, remember
you can tell Kurt how wrong he is using the Pound Os S podcast hashtag on Twitter.
Hey, if it's any consolation, I also hate Star Trek.
Uh, that's fine.
I, I don't, I have no ill will towards people who like, or dislike Star Trek.
Well, they have replicators and then from there it just goes downhill for me and
transporters.
Replicators are the best and transporters and
replicators are basically the same thing.
Right. It's, it's just how it is
and
I'm, it's ok. You cannot like Star Trek. I have no problem with that.
However, if you want to talk about crap security,
we should talk about Star Trek security someday.
It is.
It's just
keep
going
missing,
like POF he's missing and the computer knows it's like computer. Where's captain
Pard? He is not on the ship,
don't you think that's a problem?
Exactly.
You think the computer would have like some sort of, you know,
maybe alerting mechanism that if the captain disappears,
then it should say something.
Right.
Well, especially since it's a consistent problem.
I know,
-- like, how many times do these people get killed?
-- We're not talking
about this. This is No, not right now. We're nearly done.
We've been complaining about Star Trek for, for nearly an hour now.
Star
Wars. Sorry,
I know, man, I do this all the time. I'm getting confused, but that's ok. That's ok.
So, so I guess here's what it comes down to is people complaining about
the operational security problems of rogue one
and talking about the data X fill and they should have had authentication and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I would say that inside of the facility,
the security was acceptable.
The problem is
they let a ship land next to the facility and they clearly had poor security to
get in because even if they had some sort of key card that the bad guys,
well, they get good guys whoever you, which, whichever side you're on here.
If you, if, if, even if they had key cards,
the rebels stole and they used to get into the facility,
you should still not be able to get into the
data warehouse without some sort of multiple layers of security
that get you in there. So in reality,
rogue one isn't an information security problem.
-- It is a physical security problem.
-- Yeah. Well, an operational security.
Well, these guys are a bunch of idiots. I mean, let's just face it. Right.
Like they don't know how to do this.
Maybe this is an institutional and cultural hangover from when they all the,
all the stormtroopers were clones.
And thus trustworthy
because let's face it. Right. If you're all.
No, no, absolutely not. And
why would you allow a random ship to even land? Then why not?
Just like, seal the whole freaking planet in the shield and be like, nobody comes in,
nobody gets out.
-- What's the point of
-- it
then?
Because you have a bunch of disposable people running the place?
No. But what was the point of the base on the planet then
I assume their data, that's their backup facility, right?
Like you've got all this data you need backed up, let's put it somewhere safe.
Ok?
Because I wasn't really clear on that. Like it wasn't an engineering base.
-- It wasn't, I was
-- just my assumption is it, it's a data warehouse, right?
You, you have, it's, it's like Amazon Glacier, right?
-- So
-- it's their off site data backup facility.
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And that way when you need data,
you can get it and again having it even offline and needing humans.
So let's say you need the death star plans, Darth Vader.
Like, hey, I, I need the plans for the giant, you know, sphere of death I built.
Uh Could you send them to me, please?
And you would need,
like a person would have to acquire the tape and then transmit them
to their evil overlord. Like that is a great idea.
-- That's wonderful security from that perspective.
-- It's
an
air gap.
Exactly.
That's perfect. That's exactly what you want.
Yep. I agree, man,
-- they just should have put some bars in the doors and maybe put a lock or two on.
-- Right.
Right. That would have made a huge difference. And
maybe,
maybe if you have a giant transmitter, you don't put a tape reader,
like at the base of it make them, you know, bring it to the transmitter room
at the bottom
-- or, or something.
-- Right. Because one thing
we talk about two fa but if, if they're all clones,
you can't have
you.
No, not biometrics, but you could have a token and a password. Right.
-- You certainly can't
-- use
-- all the time.
-- Of course, they lose that stuff. And that's why you have
the, the two factor. So you still have a unique password in your brain.
And additionally, if it gets lost you,
-- I would assume they're trained to tell people
-- brain control
slugs because you'd mentioned that early in the film.
Like, that's such a weird scene. It's not control.
Apparently the big giant slug monster thing was supposed to extract
the information from the pilot to determine if he's a lot,
uh, telling the truth or not.
Yeah.
And so maybe that's why they don't rely
on passwords because if you have like brain sucking
-- devices or animals then
-- maybe, and that's fair.
That's fair.
Well, well, is true.
Right. What's the difference?
Yes, that's correct.
Oh, my goodness. All right. This is
all right. So Empire security, terrible rebel security. Just as bad.
And I guess fundamentally at the end of the day,
if you have a secret in the Star Wars Universe, uh don't write it down or tell anyone.
That's, that's the lesson, right? That's the lesson.
All right, sweet problem solved.
Ok. Gang, thanks for listening.
I, I appreciate putting up with our insane ramblings for the last uh nearly hour.
And if you want to get a hold of us,
there's the open source security podcast.com website which will
have the show notes and things such as that.
There is the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag you can use on Twitter to get a hold
of Kurt or myself with any sort of complaints.
Remember we, uh, if you like Star Wars and, and Kurt clearly does not let him know.
I'm sure he'd love to hear all about it.
Uh, direct your hate in his direction, please. Uh, ignore me.
I think Star Wars is fine
and I have nothing else. Thank you everyone for listening.
You have a fantastic day, Kurt and until next time
everybody stay safe.