Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 111 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
111 seems more exciting than 100 and 11.
But whatever,
I can't remotely understand
why you would call this episode.
What
R PC? 111?
Right. Oh, I see. I see.
Anyway. 111.
Right. So, how are you doing, man? Uh,
good, good. The smoke is gone.
We had our
summer forest
choir in
BC.
No, no, no BC had them.
We just get the smoke.
Right. Right. Actually, where I live way over in the middle ish
easty part of the United States.
We have haze from the California wildfires which are 2000 miles away.
Yeah. Well,
it's, it's crazy. I, I didn't think that would be a thing in effect.
It was funny because when I was leaving Vegas,
I,
I left before the sun came up and the sun
was rising over the mountains and the cab driver says,
look at all that smoke. And I said, what? The fog,
there's no fog in the desert.
Yeah, I was gonna say, I don't think Nevada is known for its foggy
weather.
Well, where I live we would call it fog.
However, in this case, it was smoke from fires and I thought, wow, that's crazy.
Like,
I hadn't been outside because it was 100 and 10 degrees. So,
yeah. Yeah.
And,
and it turned out when I got home and they had on
the news that there was haze here as well from California wildfire.
So, that's pretty wild.
Yeah. No, last week we managed to, uh, I think we, we had the worst air quality index
like
in the world.
No, I, I'm
for a major cities.
I don't know, man.
Anyway, whatever. Right. So,
what, what are we talking about today?
Well, you know, I think the big news right now would be TLS,
1.3 is finally going to be a thing.
Seriously. I'm super excited. You can, you can tell from the sound of my voice.
Right.
-- Well, it's one of those
-- things where
it,
you know, it's like having, it's like, it's like hydraulic concrete
in the, you know, most people don't really care but the,
the things you can build with it
are pretty cool
and some of the problems it solves are, are,
I think the biggest thing, you know, because I was reading this one,
I remember this one cloud flare blog where they talked about something a while back,
how they,
they basically tidied up something and I think it was Engine X to
make it a little bit faster and save something like 54 man years,
people years or whatever we call it now
of like waiting time for web pages to load.
And that's one of the things TLS does is TLS,
not only is better from a security perspective than TLS. 1011 and 12,
but it's faster.
And honestly,
when you think about how many TLS connections happen and how many people,
like let's face it, it, it, it's not a lot like maybe a couple 100 milliseconds,
but a couple 100 milliseconds times a few billion times a day.
Yeah, it's huge man.
And, and we should also clarify for people who don't know. Hydraulic concrete
is magic because generally when you, when you have say concrete, you,
you obviously mix everything up in the water and then you pour it
out and it dries and it shrinks a little bit because the water leaves
hydraulic concrete gets bigger. When it dries, you can
pour it in the water
-- and it does work underwater. Yes, that's the thing.
-- Right.
Normally when you pump concrete into water, you get,
well, not just got concrete, spread out water.
Exactly.
Pretty much sand and aggregate
and yeah, hydraulic concrete.
You can pour it in like you,
the Romans would literally build a form that would be full of water.
Like they would basically build a wooden box around a piece of water
and fill it with hydraulic concrete and then they'd have a pier a week later.
-- It's crazy stuff
-- anyway. Magic
man.
All right. So, now people know and, and you're absolutely right though.
TLS 13 is something that
most people have no idea. It's even a thing.
Most people will ever really see the benefits of it. Technically speaking.
But, but their lives will get better and they won't even know it.
Which is awesome.
Yeah.
Well, and what I also love is not only is TLS 1.3 better in speed and performance and um
security,
but it really paves the road to make some really good future advances that,
you know, really will help people with their privacy.
Uh So like here's a dirty secret,
Josh, when you go to a TLS website,
do I know which website you're going to?
You can't prove anything.
Yes, I can. The server name indicator part isn't encrypted yet.
It is not. That's true. Right.
So either you're going to a website that only
hosts one website or it hosts multiple websites.
And so you use a thing called server name indicator because the problem is
you have typically in the modern world, a web server hosting more than one website
because scale issues.
And um,
well, when you want to talk an encrypted connection,
you first of all need to know which one you want to talk to, right?
Because if you go to a server and say
I want to talk encrypted and it hands you
a certificate for cre.org and you typed in cnn.com.
It's kind of like your browser is going to freak out.
So first your browser is like, I want to talk to cnn.com and then the server goes. Ok?
Cool. Yeah, I have a certificate for that and I know how to do that. Let's do that.
So for example, with TLS, you know,
1.2 and earlier with server name indicator support,
you're still leaking
the, the, the host you're wanting
to talk to.
Right? And, and that
it can be a big deal.
Like when you go to cloud flare, you know, they host a gazillion websites,
some of them are fine and some of them, your government might not be so happy about.
Right. Right.
There's, there's many reasons to do this and, and the thing is,
I know there's always the, if you have nothing to hide,
you have nothing to fear crowd.
But I mean, fundamentally
this is one of those things, right?
They, they totally do and, and people who say that are,
are they either knowingly evil or they don't understand the problem?
It's one of those things that
everyone has to hide equally
because there are people who have legitimate needs for this
and of course there are some bad guys but whatever,
you know,
-- and
-- there are people that will punish you for doing something that's normal
and make your life a misery and, you know.
Yeah, I think online privacy is a, is a big deal because like
our lives are online now
end of story,
you know.
So yeah, so t that's one point through um
the, and one of the other things I love about the safety, they made some,
well,
they made a combination of safety and security
decisions in TLS 1.3 that really help things.
So for example, with Diffie
Hellman,
you've got
a bunch of parameters you can set,
not all of them are safe. So
what happens when you give a bunch of software developers
the ability to shoot themselves in the foot?
They totally do and, and on that note as well. So there are two sides to that though.
There have been honest mistakes
where people accidentally picked bad DH parameters
and there've been, well, yeah, that it's always, they don't know better. Right.
It's mistakes
and then there's been malicious attacks that go after, you know,
purposely causing that DH parameters to occur.
And so that's obviously,
I mean, that's a problem. Right. You, you
and how did they fix it? Let's, let's start there.
Uh Well, so they basically picked a safe set of parameters and that's what we use,
which is awesome. Right. Like,
yeah,
-- seriously,
-- like
we all drive on the,
I'm going to say correct side of the road for whatever your country is.
There's only one proper side.
People drive on the right side of the road and then there's what,
-- like two countries that drive
-- on
the left side.
Sweden, Japan, Britain, uh, New Zealand. Um,
couple others.
It's a rounding error of cars. That's what it is.
And if you don't like that
two B
this is, this is what happens when you let people decide they choose wrong.
Well, and there's something to be said for, even if it's wrong for consistency
because at least with consistency you can, you can clean it up.
Definitely.
It's better to be consistently wrong
than, than occasionally. Right?
Yeah.
Um So yeah.
No, they've, they've done a lot of good work and um well, I mean,
I just love what I really love is looking at sort of the original.
So, uh this guy, Eric
Rescorla,
I apologize for saying your name wrong. I'm
99% certain. I said his last name wrong
anyways, this is back in 2013, you know, and it's this,
he had this beautiful slide deck called the TLS 1.3 wish list,
right? Who doesn't have a wish list? We all have one, right?
I want a pony
he talks about. So here we go.
Basically, they want to reduce handshake latency, right?
Because well, speed is good,
right?
They want to encrypt more of the handshake, you know, again,
things like server name extensions, the extensions, the,
you know,
so here's what I love uh current
handshake leaks essentially all the negotiated information.
Yep, that's true.
Both sides identities. Yep. All extensions. Yep, the target,
they want to protect both sides identities from passive Attackers.
So that's your sort of man in the middle machines
that are either nation states or your helpful corporate network,
right?
Uh protect at least one side's identity from active Attackers, which
again with these men in the middle boxes there, you know,
there's a lot of active shenanigans going on
and then ideally also protect as many
extensions and other information as possible.
Um
The other thing is, you know, improve uh
cross protocol attack resistance, right? So
the signature in the server key exchange doesn't cover the entire handshake,
right?
See,
um
one challenge is traditionally, you know, the the server key, you,
you kind of pop that
and now you could play, you could, if you hadn't passed recorded traffic,
you can now decrypt it.
All
right.
And that
can
-- deal with that. I mean, there is perfect forward secrecy. Yeah.
-- Have you tried?
I double dog dare you to set it up.
I've never set it up and I'm not going to
unless it's like something, you know, where you can just
click a check box. No.
And so that's a great example because for example, yeah,
there aren't attacks to decrypt this stuff right now, but
there are certainly agencies hoovering up large amounts of
data and storing it because let's face it.
Data storage is pretty cheap nowadays, you know,
you burn that stuff to CD or DVD or whatever the heck, those optical discs,
whatever the technology is now,
you know, and you just keep it in a vault forever until it may be useful in 20 years.
You know,
another thing I
really love is that they essentially,
when it comes like AES advanced encryption standard is
a good encryption standard, right?
Like it had some teething issues when it first came out way back in the day.
But fundamentally, it is a good solid encryption standard
having said that
like any tool you can also smash your thumb with it,
right? AES has different modes.
There's like cipher block, chaining mode, CBC mode, there's, you know,
stream mode there or not stream mode, but whatever, there's different modes,
you can use it in
some of them are wrong
in the context of like TLS 1.3 right?
And so they've essentially as much as they can,
they've taken away the ability for people to do it wrong,
you know, again, going back to
like we know better now.
And if we know better now, why would we give you the option of doing it wrong?
Like we know these things are wrong now.
That's it. Like it's just why would we let you do that?
You know, it's like my car dings at me if I don't put my seatbelt on
because I'm doing it wrong. Like I should put my seatbelt on
and, and I think
this is one of those things that impresses me immensely with
TLS 13 because I remember in the TLS 12 time frame,
there was a, a
huge hesitation to deprecate anything.
And it's, I mean, it's been one of the biggest problems with TLS 12 is it,
it supports the
kitchen
sink
network protocol.
They always keep backwards compatibility
and especially with something like TLS that is like a death sentence because
attacks evolve.
And now you have all this old garbage and you have to figure out what do we do with this?
And, and in the case of TLS 12,
they've,
they've let a lot of it hobble along much longer than it should
have just because there isn't a good way to get rid of it.
Well,
and I get the counter argument is that you
have a lot of devices that simply can't be upgraded
and it really sucks to be those people and all
of a sudden your phone or your whatever stops working
and I get it because a lot of people can't simply,
well, I mean, the,
the Fukushima power plant just came out in the news
that they have not only do they use Windows XP,
but guess how many machines they have running?
Windows XP.
Probably all of them.
Well, I think the number was 48,000.
I know. I'm like, I get that nuclear power plants are complicated but
like 48,000 machines. Running Windows XP is a lot
-- of machines, running windows XP. Yeah,
-- that's pretty bonkers. I won't disagree.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah, like I, yeah, anyways
just
gamp them, it'll be fine
except you can't because, you know, they want their online reporting.
But, so going to that, I, I get both sides there.
I mean, like, on the one hand I don't want to break, like, every cheap cell phone,
you know, in developing countries because that kind of sucks for those people.
But at the same time, it's like, I'm, you know,
we sometimes we have to move on and like, you know, we picked 100 and 20 volt power. Um,
you know, in most of North America, most of the world and, and that's,
that's what it is and
most of the world is 240 volt, isn't it?
I, I think one
don't
know,
-- technically
-- we have 240 here. It's just, we use 120 high
amperage and
their hoses burned down. But, you know, it's fine. We have
it in truck breakers now.
It's,
but fundamentally with like network protocols, right?
Like you look at some of them like email or like,
well, http, I mean,
some of the backwards craft we've kept that has been an unending series of pain. Like
that's one thing I really respect about the Open SSH people is that they like
have done releases where it's like we as of this release,
we no longer support Open SSH or sorry SSH protocol version,
like one point X basically
like,
and they can do that because they're open source and I'm gonna,
I'm gonna stand up on my soapbox here for a minute because I've, I've dealt with this
more than once is where
we want. I've been dealing with some open source projects where
you want to upgrade something and people say, oh, but it doesn't run on like, so
os version two from 1984
and, and the answer is ok. So here's the deal. Number one, if you want that,
uh you can fix it,
right? And number two
just run the old version and fork it and maintain it.
You don't have to run this new one because we want to support, you know,
operating systems only from after 1999.
Right?
And,
and I think that's the difference is when
you're dealing with something like open source,
you can, you can tell people no, we're not going to do it.
And if you want it, it's up to you.
And,
and I think this is kind of kind of falls into that space
just because everybody's using open source now for all of this stuff.
And so we can say
let's kill old TLS.
Yeah.
Well, and,
and related to this though is if you have a device
that can't talk past TLS 1.2 pretty much by definition,
then it has an old software stack that's full of holes and problems
unquestionably,
you know, that, that is a that, that's a factual statement.
Yeah. And, and there's still gonna be plenty of them.
I mean, I look at, like, I've got,
I've got a cell phone in the drawer that's running like Android
version four and it's never going to support TL SS 13.
And, and really, I should just throw it away.
I kind of wonder about my bathroom scale.
You know, I have a, uh,
one of those intelligent bathroom scales so I can see a nice little chart of my,
my weight.
Yeah.
Well, it,
so let me,
let me
ask this,
-- do you connect to the scale or does the scale phone home to something else?
-- The scale
connects
home for sure. But,
and then you also connect to the scale to set it up.
Ok. Which I did once,
did you connect over TLS?
-- I have no idea. It was an app.
-- I'm
assuming it was
me.
I would be shocked
and,
and like this is one of those instances where it's
going to be up to the scale manufacturer to say
either
we're going to fix a scale or the scale is going to stop working
or we're just going to support TLS 12 until the end of time.
Right.
And,
and I feel like any of those situations are probably acceptable
and they're not your problem unless your skill stops working.
Right.
Yeah.
Yeah. And then I would get grouchy.
No, you wouldn't.
Well, you might get grouchy but you're probably still gonna keep using it.
You just won't have magic internet scale data.
Uh That's the main reason I have it is for that
graph because I find the day to day weight is useless.
It's looking at the trend over a week or a month.
-- That actually is what is useful.
-- Sure. Sure.
Then you should just build your own with a raspberry pie and,
and on a network cable to it.
So it's not using
-- and just make it waterproof because it's in a bathroom.
-- That's fine. It's fine.
It's easy. No big deal.
Uh,
no, I'd rather not. I really, really
like buying things that work.
Yeah. So, Ts has, and,
and the thing I really like about Ts 1.32 is that
sorry,
the thing I like about Ts 1.3 as well. Just so I confuse people.
Sorry is that
they support perfect forward secrecy.
Part of that basically means breaking man in the middle boxes.
Yes.
And, and that,
I don't know, we're going to see how that one plays out.
Well, so the, the argument there is that, you know,
all you're on the corporate network are we have this mandate to, you know,
inspect all encrypted traffic because of what is it socks or
not
H A but is it socks or
-- one
-- of
-- those
financial
all crazy like that?
Yeah.
So anyways, because that's a,
that is a lot easier to deploy than to actually like go
on to end points and deploy something on the end points to
II, I don't know,
decrypt the traffic and send a clear text encrypted version to some central server,
whatever, whatever right point is.
Um
I think that's a poorly thought out security mandate because essentially
it's a security mechanism that requires you to behave like an attacker. Really?
Right. Having a man in the middle box.
Um, so breaking it is something most of us technical people are kind of like, yeah,
too bad,
right? Like you need to live with that.
Well, and there's still some things they can do. If I recall correctly, you can
in
the
certificate,
-- you need a root.
-- It's just a lot harder.
-- It doesn't work as magically as before, which
-- is good.
I think, I think a magic man in the middle is dangerous
-- in almost every situation.
-- Well, there's been multiple situations where
people have been found, you know, with certificates that, oh, look at that,
you know,
we just saw a Google dot Was it google.com,
I think or something like it was one of the Google properties,
you know, where somebody reported like, hey,
I found this certificate of yours floating around and
it's from a man in the middle box.
Like what gives,
you know, and that's when Google really went after I think it was,
I wanna say Symantec.
Remember?
Uh
Yes,
I know, maybe,
-- uh
-- it's one of them like that. Yeah,
I think it was a digit order
-- one
-- could have been.
There's, there was a couple of them caught with their hand in the cookie jar,
you know,
doing these men in the middle certificates that were
unrestricted,
you know, could just sign whatever they wanted.
So,
no, it's TLS. 1.3 is, is objectively, it's, it's a better standard.
And the thing to remember too is a lot of this TLS stuff. You know, we built
it ages ago and
to put it bluntly like the engineers did their best and
then we deployed it in the real world and,
and we learned a lot and the good news is we learned a lot
and it appears that most of those lessons have been taken to heart
and
TLS 1.3 is the result of that,
which is awesome. I mean, so like, let's, let me ask you this TLS, 12
is from August of 2008.
We are in
August of 2018. Now, how long is TLS? 13 going to last?
Do you think it'll make it 10 years?
Well, when you say last, I mean, it'll be around for at least 10 or 20 years.
But how long until TLS, 1.4 comes out,
I think would be the better question. And I suspect TLS 1.4 might be about five years.
Yeah, I think so.
I, I don't know. I think it'll take a while.
Iii I think five years might be optimistic. I'm thinking, I think it might be longer
because
the,
the way I see it is the real reason that TLS 13 became
a thing was because it became obvious that there were failings of TLS 12
and 13, I feel like gets enough. Right. It might last a very, very long time.
Well, I suspect that is true, but with the proviso that
sooner rather than later,
we're gonna probably want to look at
some quantum resistant algorithms and some other future
proofing. And I suspect that's why it'll come
out sooner because we've learned that
we, we can't just, oh it's probably good enough. We'll fix this again in 10 years.
No, we, we probably should get ahead of it this time around.
We keep talking about that for quantum and I'm not seeing a
lot of positive movement. I see a lot of talk
but I feel like if, if quantum is going to be as bad as people say it is,
it, it might be too late,
right?
I, I feel like this,
this compares to global warming where everyone's like the
experts are saying how terrible it's going to be.
But the reality is nobody's really doing anything about it.
They just,
they posted round one of their comments on the post.
Uh What is it?
N posted round one of comments on
the post quantum cryptography standardization process.
69 submissions.
That's quite a lot of stuff
our candidates for quantum resistant cryptographic algorithms
blah blah blah blah blah and that was back in December of 2017.
So and this is moving ahead with this,
they're doing some stuff but I feel like they're moving too slow
and it's too late
because if quantum crypto or
rather if quantum computers can break RS A like we think it is
we're talking 5 to 10 years just to get these algorithms like in use correctly,
right?
Not counting optimizations as well as just real word practicality of it.
So
I,
I don't know, man. I mean, I,
I feel like we're too slow
assuming this is true. Which of course, we don't even know for sure if it is because
nobody felt one yet.
But uh no, there's, there's some definite contenders.
I, I suspect it will happen a bit faster. Hopefully.
Uh I'm, I'm not quite as doom and gloom as you. I mean, part of me definitely is, but
I would like to think that
now that we've been through how many major crypto
messes in the last decade?
Half a dozen, a dozen,
-- a lot,
-- you know.
Yeah,
-- more than I can count, you
-- know.
Uh Here we go, sloth curve
swap. We DH Logjam Freak. Sweet 32 Poodle robot.
I know there's more but um that's the, the list in this one blog entry, right?
No, it's, I think it's good. And the, the thing I really love too is, is
people are also starting to leverage TLS more,
you know,
I mean, it's great that we have this encrypted standard.
But for example, now, you know, when you go to an HTTP website, now in chrome,
it says insecure,
right, like it straight up tells you,
uh,
you probably should be going to that http S one basically
DNS
TLS.
Exactly.
And that's what drives me nuts about DNS EC.
I mean, don't get me wrong, DNS Sec. It's a good idea. I'm not sure.
It's, no, I'm gonna, I'm gonna call it out and say DNS Sec was a terrible idea
and, and we should not use it
and I know that's not a popular opinion but
I despise it because it's overly complex and ridiculous.
Well, yes, I will give you that.
But the problem with DNS
E
-- is, is it,
-- it's all you need.
-- Yeah.
-- But the thing is you use somebody like cloud,
you just click a box because somebody smart did the hard work.
No, but the thing with DNS E
is, I think that the thing,
at least my impression of it is DNS
EC is less about protecting traditional DNS traffic.
Like who is, you know, or not, who is, but who is the IP address for, you know,
cnn.com or whatever?
And it's more about some of these new DNS record types. I'd like to talk about where,
you know, we're, we're starting to realize we have a single,
actually globally unique name space that's enforced and that's DNS.
Right. There's no other globally unique name space
apart from maybe phone numbers,
um,
you know, that's enforced.
And secondly, we can actually publish all sorts of neat stuff to, to DNS,
you know, that can then be used and leveraged by other systems. So, things like
who do I allow to be my certificate authorities?
You know. So when you are, I think, uh,
Google uses it, you know,
and they list the two certificate authorities they're allowed to use.
So in theory,
you know, even if I get a valid certificate from some shady place that's
legitimate, but shady,
your browser should ideally be smart enough to be like, no wait, that's not.
Uh you know,
somebody that Google said is allowed to assign a certificate on their behalf.
OK. So here's my complaint about this though is
when you say something like you, you have to just click a box in Google or Cloud flare,
you've just delegated all the trust to them.
So there's a million other words, you could represent this information.
We've already done that with root DNS. You've already delegated.
-- I agree
-- completely. Which is why DNS SC
is, isn't really solving a problem here.
I think it's more,
I think it's more enabling stuff in the future because then we can
put records into DNS and say
I will serve this record
and you can request this record for me
and you will provably know that you got the correct record for me.
And that's going to matter because we're going to use
the contents of this record to help then create a
financial transaction for the
email.
You could just as easily host all this stuff over HTTP S because that
is just as trusted
for real. But,
but we don't have
what we have infrastructure existing in the form
of DNS DNS servers and DNS record types
that are easy to define the thing with HTTP S.
You would not only have to define like a record type, you'd have to define a location.
-- You'd essentially be reinventing DNS over. Well, http
-- S space
DNS
TLS, what a great idea.
Yeah.
Um but no, I mean, I, I like the idea. I like the idea of DNS record types too because
DNS auto updates, right?
A client comes online and says, hey, I've grabbed this IP address and, you know,
Josh just logged into me.
So,
you know, I'm going to register as part of my IP address that, you know,
Josh is provably logged in at this IP address and now you, you can trust, you know,
Josh is coming from me.
Um
going to fix that.
Well, no, but DNS E means that we can do that.
We can't do that without the records being provably correct.
I'm, I'm not going to convince you of this, but I'm gonna, I'm gonna tow the line.
-- DNS EC is overly complex and dumb and doesn't actually solve it.
-- The
other thing to remember
is
using DNS is a lot more efficient than using HTTP S.
Right. Because you have to make a DNS.
Basically, whenever you talk to the network, you have to make AD N SS call
regardless.
Right. Other things exist like DNS has timeouts,
http S or H web documents, technically sort of have the high
-- notes, but it's not, they
-- can,
well,
again, it's not DNS has some standards around this stuff and I'll agree with that.
But once you start ending in DNS SEC, the complexity goes to an 11
and, and people are just going to screw it up and let's say clown.
It totally is.
Ok. We're not in TLS 13. We just took away all your options.
Yeah. Yeah.
No, but still buying a certificate, getting the certificate deployed correctly.
That's
-- trivial
-- thing.
That's encrypt. Made it trivial
for
real.
I,
anyway, anyway, I feel like
TLS 13 is a great first step and,
and some of these things people aren't talking about with DNS SE C are,
maybe they'll turn into something, maybe they won't.
But I think
we need a, let's encrypt of DNS Sec that makes it insanely trivial to use. Right.
It, it's, that, here's the thing.
Let's encrypt is less about the certificate and more
about the tools that automate away all the,
all the silliness.
Right.
Yeah. Well, and part of it too is, uh, it's not just,
it's the automation piece.
Yeah. Like, like you pointed out anything that requires a human
to do it more like setting out my bathroom scale once. Cool. I'll do that once
-- and I better never have to do it again until
-- TLS 12
breaks
because that means it's broken.
You know, and that's, that's the thing, right?
Like if DNS Sec is essentially turning,
like you install bind or you install windows server or whatever.
And you literally,
well, the case of windows is a good example, right? Because you've got a gooey
and you, I'm looking at this blog entry and you literally
step one, open server manager, click tools and open DNS manager.
Step two in the DNS manager browse to your domain name, then, right?
Click domain name, click DNS sec and then click sign zone
and then it walks you through a wizard to set it up neat
bind
and
no, sadly bind does not. But
somebody could produce a shell script that would do it,
shell script is never the answer
anyway,
-- you know what
-- I'm saying? Right? Like you could build a nice little pipe.
I
can
argue with you and I will, I will maintain
that. The challenge here is the key management,
not setting it up
and
well doing key management properly
-- is a nightmare doing it poorly.
-- It
is very easy to screw up key management. It is, it is much easier to explain
it, right?
Well, it's true. Of most things in life there
anyway.
Yeah, it's something I'm actually looking towards is the whole, you know, how do we,
how do we deal with keys in the cloud?
Right. I mean, the cloud security lines is a great example.
We, we don't have a single physical server.
Never have, never will if it's, I have my way and I do,
but obviously, you know, we have certificates,
we have all sorts of things that require encryption keys.
And
luckily most of them are sort of outsourced in the sense of, you know,
aws data encrypted at rest using their,
you know, I am and
I forget what the key thing is called.
Some three letter acronym.
But as far as if I actually needed to have access to the key directly. Uh
Yeah.
Yeah. What do I do?
I, I,
there's no good solution
that isn't very costly. So, yeah, it's,
I, I think this will happen. It'll get easier.
I mean,
remember how hard setting up a web server used to
be and I don't mean a secure web server,
I mean, just a web server.
-- It was terrible.
-- You know,
-- I remember, man
-- or setting up SSH.
Ssh was never hard.
-- It always did most of the stuff on its own.
-- True.
No, it just works out of the box perfectly.
-- That's the difference.
-- It was, it's always been pretty good. So, anyway, anyway.
All right, man, I think we should call it.
Uh I guess one other interesting point is my, I bought a pixel two which is the latest
phone
and it does,
do they do, like alphabet releases?
What did they? I don't pp,
I don't know.
Oh, was the last one? Yeah, they go in alphabetical order, don't they?
Anyway, anyway, it does DNS over TLS by default.
Well, in Android nine, which it upgraded to right after I got
it. And
it, uh, yeah, it's cool because I can tell it to use cloud flares,
uh DNS server for TLS
instead of Google's, which made me happy because
while I know I really shouldn't trust either of them, it at least makes me feel better
farming some of this out to someone else. So there you go.
Alright, cool. Alright man. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, grab our show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
and Kurt have a fabulous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Bye bye.