Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
How you doing? Uh,
better my thumbs mostly.
Well, it's not healed but it's healing and it's not in pain, which is pretty awesome.
And, and now that you're old it'll take seven years.
There's still a mark on my knee from, like, two years ago.
Yeah. Nothing ever heals anymore.
Like I just, I accept that when I get hurt, I'm hurt forever now.
Yeah. Well, kind of like my computer.
I upgraded the boss of my kids' gaming machine last year
and it was a whole process because, like,
to get from version F 12 to F 50 there's like a very specific
set of steps you have to do otherwise you're going to break it.
And so I got to F 50
which is great because that means in theory I can run
like a Ryzen nine something CPU on like the $70 motherboard.
Right. Right.
The fun part was, you know, how you hit delete to get into the bio settings.
I mean, it depends what the computer,
but in general you hit delete or F two or F whatever.
Anyway,
that stopped working.
Which, you know, whatever. Right.
Like, ok, I can get into the bios, whatever the machine still boosts it works. Right.
I can run games. Did they change the key?
No. So, anyways, I'm like,
who cares? Right. Machine boots is fine.
But I wanted to run Docker and can't run darker without hyper or whatever.
Uh, the, the, what is it? Secure virtual machine? SVM.
Last I checked if you want to turn SVM on. You do that? Where the bio?
So I'm kind of like, huh? Well,
luckily there's like a new bios from like a month ago.
So it's been like eight months with no bio
up
and then a new one comes out a month ago.
Upgrade that and boom, it starts the delete key works again. I can
upgrade it
without
being
within
-- windows. So you ran their little tool, right?
-- Yeah, I ran their scary little tool.
That's like, and now I'm upgrading your bios. Don't turn the computer off.
I'm like, nope, not gonna.
So, anyways. Yeah. And it works
-- nice
-- well, and
EFI Bios
is a little more forgiving
than the old,
old, I don't even know what the old bios was called, but
it's
EFI is definitely
-- harder to break.
-- One thing I noticed that was interesting.
I, I just, I literally got a new machine yesterday and in the boot screen it's like
USB Dis
you
boo
disk
drive,
you
drive.
Like,
I, I'll be honest, I've been a Mac user for about 67 years now.
With the exception of one gaming PC
never really paid attention. Apparently this u
is
all over the place now.
Yes.
And
it works a lot different than we're used to, which is kind of cool.
And, and I would view it as more of a, an operating system than a bio.
It's got a graphical user interface.
-- Yeah, I, I have a mouse, like
-- my new motherboard
has a bios
where you go in
and it's got a motherboard explorer and I'm like, what's that?
And you click on it and it shows you a
graphical image of your motherboard and it tells you which slots
-- and connectors are in use.
-- Mine has little spinning fans
with like for the fans that spin, it's, it's completely used
this but I chuckle every time I look at it.
-- Well, like
-- I was like, wait,
you know what's in this fan is plugged into this fan header.
Why wouldn't it?
Well, but, or like, for example,
it knows that the USB ports on the front are hooked up again.
-- Why wouldn't it know that?
-- Well, I know.
But dude, like I'm old and like, I'm used to computers where it's like you plug,
you put it together and it's like it
doesn't work and then you start shuffling stuff around
and like by the seventh or eighth attempt you
get some good boots and then you're just,
like, never touch it again.
-- Yeah,
-- it's a little different than it used to be for
sure.
I mean, clearly there's an operating system in there because it also,
this new computer has a, a
USB port on the back labeled flash update and so apparent, like I,
I stuck a USB drive in there with the flash, uh, the image of the bios update on there
and from within the bios it's like, oh, look,
there's a USB drive with the new thing on.
That's neat.
Well, but there's also a switch on the back that says bios
update. And I'm like, do I just plug this thing in and hold that switch down?
Like that scares me because I'm like,
bios updates. Scary computer. Brick computer go away. No, no work anymore. Yeah.
It's, it's nothing like it used to be, man. Yeah,
I paid for the product replacement plan on the
monitor in case I drop it or something stupid.
But I didn't on the computer because I'm like, ah, computers, whatever. Right.
-- They never break.
-- Are they going to cover the bio
-- if you, if you
-- break it, if I break it? I don't know.
I don't want to find out the main thing. I get the IP P on the monitors.
Like, if there's a dead pixel, otherwise it's the manufacturer's warranty,
which is like, unless it's on fire
too bad.
Well, and this has become my
kind of strategy. I have for televisions in my house is
-- Costco has a warranty program.
-- Remember when you refuse to shop at Costco?
And I was like, you should shop there because they're awesome.
Yeah. But you're still a bit more zealous about it than I prefer.
But the point is
they have a five year warranty program and I realized that all of the TV si bought,
I'm on probably my third or flat screen now and they all last three years.
So Costco has a five year warranty where for like,
I think 30 bucks because I always buy the cheap tvs for like, 30 bucks.
I get a five year warranty.
And I'm like, well, this is a no freaking brainer right here. Right.
Like, I'm going to get a free TV in three years.
Well, when you, when you think about a TV,
if you pay a dollar a day advertised over three years, that's $1000 TV.
They're basically disposable at this point.
-- Yeah,
-- I pay way less than that.
I'm a cheap skate and I don't care.
-- And
-- so even 50 cents a day.
But the point is like, when I was a kid, my parents bought some Sony TV.
-- And it was a big deal.
-- I remember the TV repair man coming to our house,
like a person
opened the TV
-- and worked on it with tools. Like,
-- at
this point I'm like, uh, monitors, acting, sketchy.
-- Yeah. Buy a new one.
-- Well, let's face it I have a warranty on this TV. If it breaks.
Do you think anyone's going to ask for anything?
-- No, they're just going to give me a new TV.
-- Well, and that's what I love.
Like, the place I buy from has a product replacement plan where they're like,
essentially, it also guarantees if your thing breaks and they can't replace, like,
say the motherboard with the comparable thing.
They're just like, ah, whatever,
we'll give you a newer motherboard with a newer CPU and like
newer RA M and like all that stuff because quite frankly,
I mean, you know, you do the math on these things.
Like, how often do computers
actually physically feel short of pouring pop in there?
Right. It's pretty rare. Anyway,
we're at Holy, we're going to talk about boot hole today.
What's that?
It's a hole in my boot actually. See, you know what's funny?
Yeah, it's like five CV S or something.
So, I,
I did some Google searching on the term boot hole
and,
uh,
-- did you use Google Safe Search?
-- I
do not ever have that turned on, but I did not get any non
safeer work results, at least in what I looked at, but like, in all seriousness,
fixing actual footwear,
what made up a surprising number of the search results.
So, I would say
in
terms of what were you thinking of? I don't want to know,
but
in terms of,
in terms of naming things,
this is, I think an exceptionally
poorly chosen name
because if I'm getting footwear, when I search for your security flaw,
I'm getting downtown shoe repair.
Sherwood Park, shoe repair master. Sorry.
Oh, Mr Safety Shoes, which is honestly a great place to buy safety shoes.
You can't go wrong with safety shoes.
II,
I have owned several extremely high quality pairs of
them in my life and they are worth every penny
gumb boots are CS A approved blah, blah, not cloud security lines,
but actually Canadian Standard Association approved and they are like,
they're felt lined.
They're acid proof like they are the nicest gumb boots I've ever owned.
But anyway, anyway,
so I thought it would be worth talking about
boot hole for two important reasons is number one,
I have an enormous amount of knowledge about secure boot
because when secure
boot was making its way into Linux,
I was more involved than I wanted to be in a lot of ways.
And that was, uh, Matthew Garrett did a ton of the work way back in the day
and now what Peter Jones does most of it for like fedora and friends.
So it's, it's definitely a wild ride. But then also
this security flaw
is dumb
and I want to talk about why that is,
I'll be honest. Have we seen many security flaws that are not dumb?
No, like really
like this whole Twitter thing. Everyone was like Twitter Nation State. No.
Turns out a bored 17 year old in Florida.
Good for him.
Let me, ok, let me kind of rephrase this because I think there,
there have been security flaws that
are interesting and could matter.
But this particular security flaw,
I would argue is probably not really a security flaw
in most sense of the word.
And there's some important reasons for that because of how
secure boot has to work and it's hilarious and sad.
So, ok, first, so here's the thing. So like my understanding of bios
in general is
I need to go talk to the hard drive just enough to get some operating system.
Because for example, like I was showing my son, I took a USB drive installed free
Os on it and then put the, the bios flashing utility and bios
image on it.
And I was showing my son this like last year when I was going through
that whole update process on his gaming PC and like it blew his mind because,
well, in fairness, he's nine years old, he's never seen a non gooey computer.
So, you know, it's funny you say that I've been running Linux for so long.
Like my kids think that's normal.
They, they, those poor kids, they have no idea what, what like normal people do.
Oh,
to be normal again
again.
-- Well,
-- when
I
-- was seven, whatever,
-- I refuse to believe that
anyway. Ok, so, so please explain. So first of all, is boot
hole a vulnerability or multiple vulnerable.
So, well, there's
all right.
Let's do this.
-- I want to start with secure boot and how it works.
-- Secure boots. Simple. Right.
Because if I boot the computer securely,
I will never be in an insecure state and I will be always secure
nonsense. All right.
So,
what we'll do is let's explain secure boot
and then we'll steer ourselves into oncoming traffic.
Ok? Because that's, that's what we should do.
So I'm going to start with the disclaimer
of that.
I'm like 90% sure of everything I'm going to talk about,
but I might get some things wrong.
And if I do, you're welcome to shame me publicly and please do
well, in fairness,
the people who apparently wrote all these boot loaders were also wrong.
They're, they're not wrong. They actually so, ok,
this is where I want to start
is secure boot isn't about security is the first thing we have to set down.
So here's how this works. You have obviously your, your UV Bios
has keys embedded in it by the manufacturer. So the idea is we will only boot
things that have been signed by someone we trust, right?
Because I mean, that's,
that's standard. Ok.
So the way this was done though is basically,
it was decided that Microsoft was going to be the keeper of the keys.
And this was the
sort of not nice Microsoft, I would say they were on their,
their recovery plan at this point.
So most of us were like, I don't know about that.
No, I remember those days where it's like, oh, they're gonna kill Linux. Great.
Well, but, and, yeah,
so here's what
I,
I think they did it just so people couldn't say that.
But, and, and here's the thing running AC A is really hard, like, really, really,
really hard.
-- No,
-- no, no. Running AC, a
properly
running AC A is
easy.
And
yes, that's true. I could start AC A tonight
and
it would make us all.
So Microsoft is kind of in charge of this. And so the way it works is there's two
keys,
there's the key for windows
and then there's the key for everything else.
And
you can imagine
why they did this, right? Because obviously, let's say you have a,
a surface pro maybe or I don't even know if surface does this, but
you could have a device that you could only put one key on if you wanted and
then say you could only boot windows and there's no way to boot the other stuff.
My current motherboard basically will only boot windows 10
in theory it can boot other things. But from my quick look at the
docks on that
you can, you can probably just turn it off too where you can shut off.
But anyway, ok.
No, I'm not gonna let you do this to us. You're not, we're not doing it.
We're not doing it. I'm keeping us on
track,
keep
us on track
it.
So, so
what we're going to do now is you've got the second key
and the way it works is you have to submit code to
Microsoft and basically say here is the code I want to boot.
Will you please sign it?
So when you say the code to boot,
-- you mean like the bootloader or the whole
-- thing or the binary?
Basically this is the,
the UV
-- bio starts.
-- OK. So this is like the low level bootloader. Yeah. Right. OK.
-- It's not like the whole Os or anything.
-- No, it's not the Os.
It would be, it'd be like Grub but,
but, but,
but
Microsoft won't sign GP L code
-- and guess what license grub has?
-- That seems like a bit of a challenge.
No, no, because GP L three specifically accounts for this instance
where you have to release the keys.
Yeah. What was that called? The Netflix or something?
Uh
No, the, the tivo
is tivo still a thing.
I don't know.
We'll look it up later.
So anyway, so what are we going to do?
So what we did in the Linux world is we created this, this boot utility called Shim.
And all Shim is designed to do
is get a signature from Microsoft and then load Grub,
right.
-- That's literally,
-- it's
like
a
Exactly.
So,
but it's a little more complicated than that because obviously
you can't just have shim
loading, unsigned, whatever.
I'm guessing Microsoft would be onto that
-- if that was the case.
-- They, they probably wouldn't sign your stuff.
They'd say don't, don't do this. We don't like it.
So, anyway,
so what happens is basically shim is signed by Microsoft and then inside of shim
is another key
that
is everything else is signed with things like the
kernel and grub and even kernel device drivers.
And so what happens is basically
EFI
boots, shim
shim loads the new key
and then it checks Grub.
-- So it's transitive trust.
-- Right. Yeah, basically. Right. Right.
Loads. Grub. Grub
does its magic. Grub makes sure the kernel is correct.
-- Grub boots the kernel and then we're off to the races. Ok?
-- And stupid question.
But just to be clear, this really only matters on actual hardware like
-- or whatever, like who cares?
-- I think they have like fake secure boot on the limbs now.
But it, it, yeah, whatever. I mean, the idea here is the intent was
you couldn't
-- run unsigned
-- code,
you couldn't subvert the boot process
and, and like for example, the bios is signed. So the bios
can't be backdoor in theory, which
there's some stories
don't Google Intel management engine CV,
whatever,
everything's fine.
So, but here's the thing, right? So here's the thing.
So you have this
chain of trust in your boot kind of system, right?
So you end up
going from the kernel to running the Init RD,
which is basically where like a kit lives and all the things that you need to, like,
you know, pull the system up by its bootstraps.
-- As we used to say,
-- this is the one where you went in, it equals B A bash. And then, like, I
remember somebody was like, this computer is secure and I'm like,
in it equals B bash.
That's right. That's right. But make sure you sink before you reboot.
Right. Anyway,
so,
anyway, anyway,
so the thing is though, so you can have a trusted boot chain.
A
IRD
is generally unsigned because the
IRD is generated on the fly.
Like, like it depends on what your system is because the,
the
I don't even, is it when you update grub, I guess, or the kernel or whatever,
whenever you update these things on a lyric system,
what happens is it'll look at your system and be like, all right,
here's the hardware.
I see.
Let's throw some device drivers in here, like, you know,
let's shake it up and then we're gonna turn it into
an RD and that's how we're going to boot the system.
And so that can't be signed because obviously,
if you have the key to sign things on your local system, you basically invalidate
the entire concept of all this.
Here's where
it gets kind of funny, right? Because if I'm an attacker,
all I have to do is mess with in NRD and I'm basically home free. Right.
And IRD is rarely encrypted because a
IRD
is where you would give a password, for example, to decrypt your disk.
And
Ird by definition
has an enormous amount of control. And if I'm an attacker,
that's what I'm going to go after. Right.
Like I get that init
RD is sort of Diam Aly created.
But wouldn't it generally be the same across similar, say,
laptops or servers or systems?
-- I mean, it, it kind of, it could be or is it
-- just that there's enough
weird stuff out there that who cares? Right.
-- Like, well,
-- to keep it small, they only put what they need in it.
So like if you're running an intel CPU,
it's going to look a lot different than if you're running an AMD CPU.
-- The
-- flash storage on my current motherboard for the Bios is 256 megabytes.
And I'm like, that's bigger than my first six computers,
right? No, like really?
That's,
-- I was trying to explain to my son why this blew my mind.
-- Go
take up a lot of space.
So anyway, anyway, OK, here's where we're going to turn ourselves into traffic now.
OK.
So
Moot hole
is fundamentally
a security flaw
in Grub where you can cause a buffer overflow
and then make Grub execute arbitrary code.
You mean Grub or Grub two because everything says Grub, whatever,
they're all the same Grub two
when I say Grub, I mean Grub two. OK. That's true. Of from now until I'm dead.
-- No one says Grub
-- two. That's like me and IP config or if
config on Linux.
That's right. That's right. So anyway,
the idea is
if you have the ability to access a system
and you can modify the grub configuration file,
you could basically introduce a buffer overflow flaw
and then make grub execute whatever code you want.
Oh, so basically it turns from I have roots and I can edit this file to.
Well,
now I've subverted the boot process and I control the vertical and the horizontal.
-- But
-- you already have that with a KRD,
-- right?
-- But,
but it
-- doesn't
-- give you anything
new
-- but you have it on reboot.
-- Yeah, you'll have it on reboot.
If you monkey with a KRD, as soon as you reboot, you're home free again.
And so here's the thing, right? Like this is cool research
and I think there's value in it.
I'm not going to say there isn't,
but I'm saying from the practicality standpoint of an attack,
this has no practical impact that doesn't already exist
to an attacker with local access to the system.
Well, local privileged access like because to be clear, like I'm just reading this,
if you can edit Grub config, that's bad.
If you
edit Grub config
you can, you can insert a new init RD.
-- That's
-- like saying you have access to the bathroom
off of my bedroom. Yeah. No, that's bad. Like yeah, like
you know, here's the thing, right.
You already have access to that because of an nrd my complaint here
is that just given the way the current Linux boot systems are architected,
this doesn't give you anything you didn't already have.
-- Yeah.
-- As I understand it.
That sounds, I mean, it would be one more place you'd have to look and hunt,
but in general.
Yeah. No. Yeah. Like
you've got root level access to the system
-- reproducibly after boot.
-- Yeah.
Right. Right. Right.
And,
and then now the researchers also found like
a crap load of other plausible security flaws
in, in various stages of the boot.
-- And so, like I get that, that's cool. That, that's a great thing.
-- Well, again,
we should have good quality code, not one to a whole pile of energy overflows
because,
and, and, but here's the thing too is the grub
configuration file has historically been treated as a trusted resource.
And so it doesn't get the level of
exactly,
it's your crow
config file. Like,
yeah, I mean, I would agree with that.
-- I feel like this is one of those situations
-- it's owned by route.
Like if your personal file owned only by route
that if you muck up your system stops booting.
-- Yeah,
-- if you're going to attack it,
you've got local access to the system and if someone has local access to your system,
there's so much wrong that can happen at that point that it's, it's not even funny.
And like this is a place actually where things like chromebooks, for example,
do some clever things because chromebooks are,
are heavily protected basically from start to finish
in terms of what they boot and how they work.
So,
and, and like,
look that was always kind of the intent of secure boot
is that you would have a way to go from the fi
buy
all the way
to running, let's say a web browser
and you can, you can trace back the signatures all the way
to the bios, right? And obviously,
that's not how it worked out and,
and this isn't exactly the right kind of technology to do this.
So, so now here's,
here's the rest of the story. OK?
So Microsoft has obviously acknowledged this is a problem.
It's only a problem for the secondary key.
And so what they have to do now
is they have a choice.
They can
basically push out like an update that there's a black list
in the
bios
that says do not boot these things,
right? Is that why I have 256 megabytes of storage on my motherboard?
Well, here's that.
No, no, here's where it gets good.
I don't remember the number,
but it's something like it can hold a couple 100 entries max,
right? And you can imagine
how many versions of Shim and Grub two
have signatures out there in the wild.
I bet the number is in the thousands
so they literally can't blacklist.
-- Everything that actually needs to be blacklisted.
-- Grub two was released in 1995.
Yeah, but it, it just started getting signed maybe five years ago, maybe.
OK. True. But still that's a
lot.
You don't have to invalidate like every single grub you basically
it's only shim remember Shim is all that gets signed.
So you'd have to invalidate every version of sh I ever released
and well every signed version because you have to remember too,
like Red Hat builds and signs, Shim,
the Dora builds and sign Shim
Tu builds and signed Shim, right? So like literally every Linux
distribution has their own variant of Shim
that is different even though it could be the
same version when you run two things through.
You know what I mean?
-- Debian
-- and ubuntu, right? Like
-- they're totally different except they're totally kind
-- of,
-- but it doesn't matter because if you build,
-- oh yeah, you'll be off by one bite, at
-- least with
-- dates and stuff, right? Like it.
Yes,
it will never be the same.
And so so there are my guess Microsoft actually knows because they've signed
all of these and I'm sure they have a very impressive audit trail.
But my suspicion is there are more signed versions of Shim
in the wild. Then there is space in the blacklist table
-- for the
-- bias.
Well, I mean, you know, like with web browsers,
all those revocation protocols worked so well that whenever there's a major
incident, we push out a browser update.
Right.
-- Well, and, and here is my suspicion, totally
-- valid technology.
Is anyone who looks at this, who knows what's going on?
They're going to come to the same conclusion we just discussed where
this functionally doesn't really change the threat profile of a system.
So if I was Microsoft, I wouldn't do squat here.
If, if people really whine and complain,
I would maybe like, symbolically blacklist a couple shin versions.
-- But
-- you could quasi
argue
that like a super sophisticated attacker might use this. But like,
so what?
Don't.
Exactly. Exactly. So who cares? Don't
an
RD? Yeah, exactly. So like it just doesn't matter.
So
I like to be blunt. Like
I remember when I got my first mac and I learned
about the whole open boot firmware thing and it was like,
what was it?
Windows or it's command key R when you boot it and it, like
there's no way to secure it.
But I'm used to like PC Bios where in theory you can attach an A MIN password.
Oh, I see what you're saying.
You h command.
Are you
game over?
Well, OK. So actually funny you say that
we have a bunch of corporate macs
in at
elastic
and there's this management software called Jam
J AM F
that we use and that apples like Apple and Jam
do stuff together. So it's kind of magic.
But basically what happens is So, II,
I have a Mac I use for testing.
And
II,
I had to, I forget what I did. I broke something, I break things all the time. Right.
Like, it's just,
this is what I do. I break computers.
-- So I did the command our thing and
-- we've, they somehow locked it down.
Well, well, ok, so, like, I don't know,
every couple of months I have to wipe this thing.
I do the control arm magic to wipe it
and it basically
auto puts on, like, all the elastic stuff automatically. Like, I can't not do it.
I, I even, I was like, ah, this might get in my way. Can I turn this off?
Like, nope, it's there and there's nothing I can do about it.
Yeah. Yeah. And, like, whatever, I'll live with it. But, yeah. Yeah.
So there's like some magic going on there between Apple and Jam
and, and Alaska
obviously that
well, but that's the thing.
I mean, Apple's Apple, there's all kinds of magic and whatever. Right?
Like, it's not the windows in Linux world. Linux world, you know, it's the wild west.
It's like you walk into the saloon. It's like,
you know, I want
a
-- Sasa a camel and 17 tacos
-- and you might not even get there because
you might open the door and just someone shoots you and you're like,
oh, well, I'm dead now.
-- So that was neat.
-- Or open the door and it's like, it's magic. Oh, man.
I love it so much.
Yeah,
I do enjoy Linux. Like, you know what?
I especially enjoy, I enjoy Linux on the Raspberry Pi stuff
because it's just
physically, it's such a wonderfully small but full featured computer,
you know, and actually the new P
-- fours you can now boot directly off of USB, which is very cool,
-- even better. The new P
fours you can get with eight gigs of ra M.
Yeah,
it blows my mind because you can buy like proper machines that started aching
around.
Right? Actually, I have a pie four in my basement is my file server now
because my old file server was dying. And I'm like, well, this is 100 bucks.
I might as well just get this
well.
And you know what I was like, oh, sometimes I have to interact with my pie four and
I should get a screen for it. You know what?
The cheapest option was a $45 Canadian touch screen that like bolts onto it.
Yeah, I've got some of that. I have
a
couple of those actually in the house and I love it. They're awesome.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. No, it's cool.
Yeah.
So secure boot, like, well, to me,
the whole secure boot thing keeps coming back to like if I control
this like chain of events from like the start of the universe,
the big bang
to now
I will be secure.
Really? That's what secure
boot was kind of, if you want to listen to the security side of it,
that's what it was about.
-- Right. I mean, that's the idea but the reality is,
-- who cares?
Well,
I mean, somebody's gonna pop your PHP out.
Let's reframe this correctly because
that was never the intent.
I think the intent of this was always about like the tablet ecosystem.
-- I thought it was more dod back in the day.
-- No, no, no, no dod uses TP MS.
Dod doesn't use it.
Secure boot is stupid. It doesn't work in that way.
So the thing because and also TPM have clocks built into them.
There's no way to have a clock.
So like one of the challenges could be, let's say you,
let's say you have a binary that's signed and it has a
date that like the key dies just set the system clock back.
The keyboard doesn't know right TPM have clocks. This is why they have clocks.
But anyway, anyway, so the thing was, I don't, it was never really about security.
It was about controlling hardware for things like tablet
and laptops.
That's what this technology has always been about.
And I mean, this was, this is why the open source universe found it so distasteful.
Well, I remember also trying to get it working was like, oh God, I just,
I ended up literally disabling uafl on every computer
I ever had up until these last two windows,
10 gaming machines.
No it did. I turned mine on everything broke.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Oh yeah, I remember.
But ok,
so here's the other half of this now and this
is where we're going to give a little history lesson.
It's kind of the wrap up is
when secure boot came out was also around the Windows eight timeframe.
And this was also when,
if you remember like remember when Steam was
basically creating their own Linux operating system,
this is all together at the same,
same big pot is the fear was Microsoft was gonna finally say, give me my ball,
I'm going home and they were gonna lock everyone
out of everything and everything was going to be signed
and things like Steam were gonna be doomed and
you work to build a boot Linux on your computer
and like, it was,
it's funny to talk about this now,
but like this was a legitimate and serious concern back in that time.
-- But
-- I mean, dude, the Halloween memos from Microsoft 20 years ago were like,
you know, Linux is a cancer blah, blah, blah. And now they're like,
they're like, like literally, I open up the Microsoft store and I type in ssh
and it's like
you should install ubuntu right on your Windows machine.
And, and yeah, they own, they bought github
and,
and the best part is you go to Microsoft
maker code to like write your little arcade game
which my son was doing for part of a summer camp and it's got to push the github
button.
Oh, that's neat. That, that must be new. I didn't see that last time. I ran it.
Yeah, it's got to push this to github button.
So I'm, of course, I clicked it and it's like you don't have a github
account. And I'm like,
so
you're 13 now,
click,
get in on that,
man.
My son has a github
account. So,
how
old are you? Oh,
I got you. I
got you.
It's like steam today. I'm like setting up steam. I'm like Felix. You're 13. Just
go
with it.
That's right. That's right.
-- Anyway, anyway, but yeah,
-- I mean, yeah, no,
like Microsoft clearly understands now that like
there's these infinitely large pies. If we play with open source,
I just bought a New Windows 10 machine yesterday. Like,
and I like it because I've got, I've got a
better Linux experience on this thing so far than I've ever had with Linux.
Oh, whatever. That's a lie. It's, it's better than your Mac. I'll give you that.
But it's
the sound works. It's not better than Linux
and it's better than Linux.
And the like,
no
sound
works better
than
-- the
-- video drivers.
That too. No.
So actually in all seriousness,
I had this discussion with my son the other day she was talking about, oh,
like if I bought a, build a computer, I want to put an nvidia card in.
What would you put in and I said
I'd buy a D's hardware and the reason isn't even
because it's better or cheaper or anything like that,
you get drivers.
Right. It works on Linux
and even if I wasn't going to use Linux with it, like I want to support that.
So I would still give them my money.
Ok. So, anyway, anyway, it is time to end this and I guess
here is what I will say about boot hole and I think
this is what I say about a lot of security issues is,
-- yeah, who cares
-- pretty much? Yeah, that's all.
Well,
more to the point who's actually booting an operating
system on hardware that they then use natively?
I do every day on my laptop.
Ok.
But I'm talking about people who, like, care about boot hole
probably. Right. Like, aren't you using VMWARE or something?
Well, in that, I mean, that's a funny thing. Right.
Because if you actually care about security you're going to run t,
if you don't really care about security, you're stuck with secure boot.
Well, like,
literally the only server I have and have had for
the last five or six years is a Raspberry pi,
everything else is in the cloud.
-- It's not my problem.
-- Right. Yeah. No, I agree.
I think it's a changing environment, but now at the same time, at the same time,
I don't want to bash
the researchers who did this work because this is cool work it's a great find
and I think from a, a purely scientific perspective, this was awesome.
Well done guys. But I think from a practicality standpoint, did it deserve a name?
-- Probably not. I think that's true
-- of pretty much 95% of security flaws now.
Yeah.
Yeah, a lot of them.
Right. So, anyway,
anyway, that's, that's my story.
We're at a time and I guess, uh, yeah, whatever I got wrong.
Let me know because I'm sure I got plenty wrong.
I bet you nobody actually cares.
No, there's a couple of people I have in mind that I'm like terrified.
They're going to listen to this
episode
and,
and they're going to send me an email and be like, dude, you're an idiot.
-- I'm going to reply with, yeah, I know.
-- Please reply on Twitter publicly use hashtag
Os S
-- pod. Yeah.
-- Right.
That's right. That's right. Reply publicly shame me for all to see.
I'm ok with that in all seriousness, I can totally take it.
So don't feel bad if you make fun of me on Twitter.
Well, but in fairness,
like the my understanding of secure boot is the number
of people that actually understand secure boot is like seven.
It's less than 100 I bet.
And like three of them work at Microsoft,
a lot of them are at Microsoft and I think Matthew
Garrett and Peter Jones are probably the only other two.
Like
so anyway. Anyway.
Right. Ok. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to Overs Source Security podcast.com. Head up the show,
not Su
Pound Os Podcast. Hashtag to
shame me
on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too, thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.