Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in doing things far more
complicated than they ever needed to be Josh Presser.
Yeah, that's an understatement for sure. I don't, I don't think you realize
exactly
the Pandora's Box. We are going to open today. Kurt. You really don't.
I remember how bad mine was.
So we're talking about PP keys and of course, us being not normal people, we,
we didn't,
we weren't just satisfied to have a P GP key because one does not simply have
a
PJ
PKI.
I had one,
I had three root keys that then signed it
like an intermediate key that then signed my key.
And for the life of me, I don't remember why it doesn't even make sense.
Well, because they're all stored on the same system
-- that
-- whatever, whatever. All right. So what we're going to do today,
gentle listener
is this is something Kurt and I have talked about for a long time
is
I, we want to explain the insane setups we had for our GP G keys in the past.
And the reason we can do this now is we have both revoked our keys
and we have no intention of generating new keys.
We've
-- given up. And
-- even if I did, I wouldn't do it anything like this anyway.
So I'm comfortable talking about all of the ridiculous things I did
to protect and I'm using air quotes when I say protect to protect my key.
I even have a hardware P GP key thing from,
I bought years ago from that German company like, oh,
-- I've been through
-- several of those are, we'll get to those.
I just, I've straight up, I've given up on P GP.
I, I'm not too proud to admit it.
We have
-- many
-- episodes where we have complained about
P GP in G BT.
So I don't think we need to rehash
the many, many, many
shortcomings
of, of GP G.
I would say it. It's
I, I view it like
Star Wars episodes 12 and three where Anakin was supposed to be the chosen one,
but everything was just terrible.
-- And that was all
-- I think I not, you know,
it's funny because I'm just thinking about it and
I, to be clear, I think end to end encryption is important for some things,
but I think end to end encryption where you make the user
do all the key management is probably not the way to go.
And I think that's one of the challenges with a lot of cryptocurrencies and NFTS is if
the whole, you know, not your keys, not your crypto blah, blah blah. But like,
I don't want normal people having to do key management. That's insane.
And, and this is why I don't think encryption is ever caught on
at scale. Ok. Anyway, before we, and the topic is not
anything about encryption. It is
about the fact that we are lunatics.
So I will let you explain first because I have a strong
suspicion that your story isn't anywhere near as complicated as mine.
My setup was reasonably sane. Originally, I had
ki and then I kind of realized if I lost it or revoked it, that would be a chore.
So
I set up basically three root keys and like they,
I don't remember if I had like an intermediate signing key. I think I did.
And then I had like the key I actually kind of used on the daily.
The idea being if that daily key got compromised, I could very easily revoke it,
set up the new ones and you know,
my root keys were actually pretty well signed because, well,
I went to like there was a key signing party
once at CCC 999 outside Berlin where fun fact,
I actually helped Philip Zimmerman set up
the B GP VPN because it was broken on his laptop.
And like the guy
like any VPN client back in the day especially, they were garbage.
Like they just did not work without black magic.
And I'd actually caught that thing to work at some point
and I could not get it to work on his laptop.
It was just broken. And that's,
yeah. Anyways.
Yeah.
So I basically had three root keys,
maybe an intermediate key of memory serves and then, like, kind of a daily driver key
and I just sort of gave up on that and then I
just basically went to one key and I used to religiously sign
all my emails and I did a lot of email to like,
oh, is that security and stuff?
And like the CV assignments
and like straight up, nobody cared.
I just stopped signing it one day and nobody complained.
And what kind of drove it?
Like, what,
what started to crack for me is I remember
Sousa sent out a security advisory that was signed improperly
and
I replied to, you know, I think it was Mark or Tom
saying, you know, hey, I like,
I don't think you've been spoofed but like this is not signed properly, like,
what's going on?
He's like, oh, we,
we'll reissue it.
We made a mess, whatever, made a boo boo and they reissued it and a week later,
I'm like,
yeah, I'm really curious, like,
how many people complain? He's like, you and one other person,
I'm like, oh, I'm like, did any of the certs or anything complain?
He's like, nope, the
whole point of signing this email is that if it's not signed, it's not me blah, blah,
blah, blah.
And nobody cares.
That's it.
-- That's all you got pretty
-- much. That's, I just, I,
and then I remember and you can find these emails, but I tried,
basically, I manually sort of generated some funky signed email where I was like,
cutting and pasting the footers and the headers and stuff.
And depending on like,
how you did that Thunderbird would show it as
a correctly signed email when it was like,
totally not
like,
like I'm talking like repeating blocks and like the logic to sort out what part of
the message is signed and is not signed is like super broken and still is.
And and that's another thing is just
this,
this stuff doesn't work reliably.
So like ignoring all the security properties of it, it just does not work reliably.
Like as we've seen
every single secure messaging gateway system now is like
here's a link
like we're not sending you the email.
So
it's just,
but you click this link and like log in with user name and password and read the email.
It's like, yeah, cool. Like,
yeah, like I said,
end to end encryption is really hard and especially in
a
Federated system like email,
I'm gonna go with,
it's impossible. And I'm going to say that confidently because
we still don't have it.
-- It's 2022 and we don't have it.
-- We,
we might not need it. It's part of the part of this also.
I mean,
it's, that, that's probably a topic for another day
and if you do it, you lose spam filtering, which I kind of like.
That's true. Anyway. And, and I will put in a
link to the XK CD comic
that talks about P GP, signed
males.
It's top notch anyway. All right. All right. Buckle up, Kurt.
Here we go.
All right. I'd write this down just so everyone knows because
there was a lot to remember
and
I dialed this one up to an 11. All right. All right. So
this is not a made up story. I want to stress that this is literally real
and this is who the person I used to be.
And I'm, I'm, I
like to think I'm far more pragmatic and sensible now.
-- But like this is all real. You know what,
-- realistically,
I,
I think if you know people in the infosec
community there is that niche subset that is just
like over engineers and over complicates things to some absurd degree.
That is, this
is
this? All right. All right. So here's how we start, right?
I have to generate a
P GP key.
And so what I would do and this is the whole,
how are you going to generate a key in a manner that is secure?
I had a laptop
that I literally used for P GP operations. It was an old laptop, like very old laptop
that I took the hard drive out of.
And I would only boot it from a CD, like AC, a CD R, right?
I would burn a Linux distribution to this. I would boot it
and then I would do what I needed to do.
So in the case of the first time I generated my, my P GP key, I used this machine.
No network,
-- no hard drive, booting off a CD R. Stupid
-- question. What was your entropy source?
If there's no hard drive or network activity to see the kernel stuff back in the day,
the keyboard and stuff.
-- I was using X
-- windows.
Oh So you little, I,
I guess this was back in the day where literally P GP would say like mash your,
like roll your face on your keyboard for a bit.
That's right. That's right.
Yep. Yep. Exactly. That. And so,
so we have entropy.
I had my entropy.
I generated my key and of course, when you generate the key,
the hip thing to do is you generated the, what did they call it?
Was it the master key and then the sub keys. I forget the exact terminology.
Now it's been too long,
but basically I generated like the master key
and then I always generated the three sub keys.
Now, mind you, I only generated things a couple of times.
So it's not like I did this a lot.
But because I was a freak, I literally kept this computer like in the closet.
It was a very old laptop whose only job
was P GP. And I'll explain why I actually needed this multiple times
in
a
little bit because I, I did things with this key on, on, we'll say every year or so. Ok.
So I generate my key right
now. When you generate your P GP key,
it asks you for a password, right?
How are you going to protect
your super secret and sensitive P GP key?
No password managers right back then.
Not that not that I would have trusted a password manager.
So what I had to do was find a way to create an extremely long,
extremely complicated password.
Oh God. Were you one of those people that picked a book and typed in a page of it?
Yes. Yes. Actually not
a page. Not a page. Not a page. Ok.
No, no, I thought about the fact that I could take a book and,
and type a paragraph or a sentence or whatever.
And I realized that there are different editions of a book
and so you can't necessarily trust the text
of the book. So in my case, Lord of the Rings was the book I picked.
So you're worried about like your house burning down, get a new copy of the book.
-- You can't access your pass phrase or
-- like the,
the NSA breaking into my house and stealing my
copy of Lord of the Rings so they can feel
them, you know, like, like whatever, whatever Right.
So
I feel like we're, we're getting close to the territory where I should be like
advising you to seek professional help and medication.
I told you this is all like, like that whole XK CD like, oh no,
he's used like quadruple whatever encryption,
like take this wrench and hit him with it.
Like I, yeah, I was, I was the first panel in that comic 100%. And so anyway, what I did
was,
and I spent an enormous amount of time trying to figure out how to do this in the the is
it the index? I don't even know what it's called.
Like the thing at the back of the Lord of the Rings
where they like explain a lot of the lore and stuff.
The Hobbits in the Shire had their own calendar.
And so I used the 12 months of the Shire
calendar which I'll put a link in the show notes,
but I'm going to read them because I can because they're really weird.
There's uh after ye
soul ma
re
rethe
Astrin Thin
Ridge th
image. No Trim Forli
over life after
life. Wed Math
Heath. Winter filth, which is my favorite one.
Black Math and for
you.
So you use just those 12 months written out.
Ah ah Here, here is where it gets interesting.
Yes. And I can't tell you if there was punctuation or spaces
between any of the words.
-- And so every
-- because honestly, that sounds like a classic, you know, like,
what are his hobbies?
Ok. Like use those dictionary lesson. They like, assuming.
Well, yeah, if you just type the words in straight up,
it would obviously brute force.
Not too, too long.
-- They
-- weren't,
there was something wrong.
It wasn't just the words because every time I had to unlock this key,
it took no less than 20 tries because it wasn't
just the words. I had some spaces and some punctuate.
Like
so some of the letters were capital, I don't remember anymore what it was,
but I know it was very, very, very complicated.
And in fact, when I had to at first, Kurt suggested we, we revoke our keys like,
like on the podcast.
And I'm like, no, because I have to type this password in.
And it's literally going to take me an hour to type it in. You get the point, right?
Obviously, when I revoked this key,
it took me like an hour because I had to remember how to type the password in.
Now, I will say
I unlocked the key on a network attached computer which literally
that key had never seen a network before.
But anyway, ok, we're just getting started though. Lucky for us. Ok.
So I've got my offline computer,
I've got my ridiculously long password and then
I have to figure out what am I gonna do with this key?
Now, storing the key on anything
was unacceptable to me. Right?
So the key, what I did was I bought.
So there were you mentioned that the, the hardware, whatever key,
hsm I don't know what to call them.
I went through what, 1234 of these over the life of my key,
I started out with a thing called an E token.
And then I moved to something called the crypto stick and the crypto stick.
I still have the crypto stick. The funny story about that
is a friend sent it to me and crypto stick was like some hardware.
Yeah, some nitro key people.
Yeah.
-- It was that like red little thing.
-- It was red
and I had like one of the early, early, early versions. It might have been in the beta
testing phase.
But anyway,
I still have the crypto stick in my bank vault
because
I can't erase it for whatever reason I couldn't get the key off of it.
-- You
-- know what that I vaguely remember having trouble with mine as well.
And, and because I'm a nut,
I was, I, I didn't feel like just smashing it was acceptable.
I had to actually make sure it was in a safe place.
I could, I could check on it every now and then and make sure it was still there.
So now actually next time I go to the bank I can
take it and just throw it out because the keys revoked.
-- I don't
-- care or just smash it with a hammer
because I'm pretty sure the NSA is not going to run
a, a hardware level
-- chip recovery
-- and, and the best part is
nothing I ever did was particularly exciting. Like this key had no value.
So anyway,
I had a crypto stick and then I went to actually the FSFE,
the free software foundation, Europe.
Uh, the, the, what they call the GP G cards,
-- right where you got a little smart card.
-- Those were awesome.
-- Yeah, they were very nice. And I had one of
-- those with the
Gemalto card reader.
Yep. Yep.
But well,
so what I did is I actually found a keychain like a reader that
used the whatever the mini SIM size was because you could punch out the,
the chip
and I had one I put on my keychain and then I would because part of part of the,
the goal of this was the key also was with me at all times.
Like I didn't do things without my key. If I traveled, the key came with me
when I left the house, the key came with me.
So it had to be on a keychain, right? It had to be with me,
right? You're, it's no one can see this.
But Kurt's looking at me as if there's something wrong with me,
which we know like this bringing it with me is the least weird thing I've done so far.
Like, come on.
-- So anyway, I remember I, I had a couple of those and those.
-- How did you back the ski up?
We'll get to that.
So,
so we put it on that and then I ended actually with the UI
key
because not everyone knows this, but you can use a UI
key.
It has
uh you can, you can upload like different
what they call them applications or something. I forget the exact term they use.
But basically, you can turn your UI
key
into a UI
key slash P GP smart card basically.
And so that's actually where, where my story ended was, that was my final one.
But anyway, this is why
I needed to
get the key
and
unlock it on a, on a regular basis because I went through these different tokens.
And so every time, like for example,
I needed to load my key into the next hardware module.
I had to take my,
my laptop dedicated just to this key.
Put my burn a new CD R because I couldn't use the same CD R twice.
For, for whatever reason, I, I don't know why that was like,
I had to burn a brand new one.
And as soon as I took the old one out,
-- I had to destroy it
-- probably because the old CD RS like bit rot and like,
-- like I literally remember burning C DS
-- and just this was in,
in case an attacker somehow burnt my key onto the CD R
but just put a read only drive in the machine.
-- Uh,
-- I
didn't have a read only CD drive because it was an old laptop. It, it didn't,
actually, it might not, it might not have been able to burn CD. Si, don't remember.
And that laptop is long gone now
because that, that is actually a good reason to boot like a secure system off of a CD R
because if it has a read only drive, then it by definition, like,
I'm not going to say you can't store state on the system at all because there's
like network cards and stuff or bits of ra M in the bios and stuff.
But it's really hard.
Actually, I'll
trying to find the link to it when,
when Gr Glenn Greenwald destroyed the laptop, that specific
notice,
they, they told him, like, you need to drill in these places on your laptop and,
and the assumption is
those were the locations of, of memory.
But,
and like, we don't, we don't exactly know, someone might have done an analysis.
-- It wasn't me.
-- Well, there's a lot of stuff that is flash ram in it for bios
and for firmware now. And like,
like your printer, your, and in your computer,
I mean, in a, well, as we discussed previously, like a computer now has like,
10 computers in it, like the
management engine and your network card and your sound card and your blah, blah.
Yep. Yep. Exactly. Exactly. Ok. Ok. So now
I've got my key on my laptop. I got to get it off. So, what I actually did
is I put the key onto a USB drive
that then went to the bank. So that's not too crazy for backups. Right
-- now. I kept,
-- uh,
that's actually pretty reasonable.
Yeah. II, I thought so. I kept two USB keys.
One
was in the bank and the other one I kept, what did I do to this?
Oh, the other one was an encrypted, like, like I encrypted the file system with a,
another password.
I don't remember exactly what it was,
but it was basically just an encrypted flash drive.
I kept in the house and I assume the two layers of encryption
were probably acceptable
in terms of keeping people.
I don't know, whatever th this one,
this one's a little more dodgy now that I think of it,
but obviously the one in the bank will say was fine.
And in fact, when I revoke my key, I had to go get the freaking thing out of the bank.
Well, you know, one thing I've not to say away too much,
but one thing I've always wondered
is how many
times because it's got to happen at least once a year.
But, you know,
various law enforcement government agents get some sort of like secret warrant
to go into a bank safety deposit box and, you know, like
they pick the lock and like rifle through the
stuff in there because that's got to happen.
I mean, it has to. Right.
-- You'd
-- think so. I mean, and, and you can get warrants that basically tell the people.
Right. Right. Right. Right. That you can't say, which is the whole canary thing,
which I still laugh at because I assume if you have a canary on, like,
-- your website they're gonna be like, you're gonna keep on using the
-- canary,
you can update it, but then you go to Federal
well, or, or you don't update it. Right. That's the point of the,
you're saying, oh, I haven't received a FISA warrant
and then one month I don't put that up and they're like, did you receive,
they would put a writer in the warrant because I feel like they're on to that.
I, I would, I would be shocked if they aren't like,
you're gonna keep updating this or like we're throwing you in federal prison and,
and you're gonna have a bad time.
So, anyway,
anyway, anyway. Ok.
So now I've got my computer,
I've got my single use CD RS.
I've got my key generated. I've got my key on the HSM.
And now it's time to actually try to be a functional citizen
of the internet with my keys.
You
can laugh. It's fine.
-- You know what?
-- Actually, you and I are pretty functional citizens of the internet.
-- We've done some, not terrible things. I do my
-- best. I do my best. Right.
And so now is where
when you generate your, your, your sub keys, you don't have a key, right?
You have a signing key, you have an encrypting key and I had an SSH key.
And so
I literally couldn't anytime I ssh, I had to plug in
this USB device
which would then
use my SSH key on the device and let me go somewhere then.
So why not? Just do what I did, which was have a
SSH keys and just don't put a passphrase on them.
So when you type SSH space host name, it just works
because that's what I've been doing for like 20 years and it's, it's glorious.
All right folks.
So if you, if you break into any of Kurt's accounts,
you know that he has unprotected SSH keys all over the place.
-- This sounds super safe
-- and in fairness, I have like, actually, no,
I just decommissioned one of the systems today.
There's, there's the pie in my basement and two test systems at the CS A.
That's all I can say to anymore.
Well, I guess technically the GSD digital ocean droplets. But
yeah, that's true.
That'll be gone soon. I hope.
Yeah.
-- But anyway, anyway,
-- a
long time ago I gave up on security over convenience.
I, I don't blame you necessarily. Now, I will say the, the thing that really
pushed me over the edge to get rid of these keys
was when I could use my,
my uh uh
but the Fido
tokens. What is it? U two F? I forget exactly
what they're called. But I've got like one of the, the Google Titan keys and I have UT
and you can
use them. So what happens is like, I have an, an SSH
key file thing on disk that has like the key
but SSH sends the encrypted key into the UB key.
I hit the button, it decrypt it and then it lets me ssh.
And so I still technically have an SSH T and a hardware device.
It's just a far more user friendly devices
that
level
-- of friction
-- now. But there's, there's two ways to do this.
You can have like all of the key material on device or you can separate it where like
the key lives on disk and it has to send stuff to the device.
And that's the option I picked because I feel like if it was all on device,
if someone has my device and they know what to look for,
like they could SSH around and I can, I, yeah,
I've got a couple of public machines I can ssh into.
Well, that's how I got like popped, like seared.org got popped ages ago where
uh there was wordpress vulnerability on a Friday and I'm like, oh, I'll fix it,
Monday, whatever.
And then
I didn't
fix it till later.
And there was also a local Linux kernel issue that again, I'll fix it. Monday
somebody got in
and I had, you know,
unrestricted trust between the host so that I
could like r sync stuff back and forth and
they, like, popped all my systems and it was like, yeah, whatever
it was
cre.org, like, yeah,
I'm not a bank.
But anyway, anyway,
and so obviously I had those three keys. I kept them safe. I also,
one of the other annoying parts is to use the,
the SS or to use the GP G keys for things like authentication and,
and signing in and other stuff.
You had to obviously copy around your dot G new PG folder to all my devices, right?
And, and
shockingly, it worked fine across like Linux
and Mac and Windows when I would put it in all the strange places which I mean,
that's really cool, good, good job guys.
That's not easy to always get right.
But then you,
I also had to set up the, the SS,
was it no GP G? There's a GP G agent process you had to run
and enable the SSH agent mode.
It's still completely broke uh pin entry,
it's still completely broken all the time on like ubuntu LTs running on Windows,
subsystem for Linux
version two.
That could be, I've actually never had a problem with pin entry
on any of the systems I used it on, but I was always,
I wasn't ever running in like WSL or anything.
I was always running like native OS X Windows or Linux
and,
and like that always worked.
But the, the agent
was always flaky for me where sometimes it would work.
Sometimes it wouldn't work and I have to kill it and then restart it.
And it was, it was unpleasant, we'll say to keep that going. But,
but basically, yeah,
and then,
and then what I would do, so I had all this set up every couple of years.
I would double check everything right. When I would load my new key into my device,
I still have most of my devices at the bank, I think.
And
yeah, that's pretty much my story of, of how I took care of all this stuff and it was,
it was pretty bananas now that I say it.
Well, yeah, I mean, I, I
this is part of why
I've gotten big into threat modeling and risk modeling is
so that I take an appropriate level of response.
Exactly that, you know, like a great example would be, my car has four wheels,
one of them may go flat.
So I want a spare tire
and so I did a quick bit of research
and the little turkey tire with the kit
is like 200 bucks. And I'm like, whoa, that's kind of the cost of a full size spare.
Might as well just get a full size spare.
So I did
and
most people don't bother buying a full size spare because a it's expensive. In
this case, it's the same cost as the little turkey tire in the kit.
And number two, because where do you keep the damn thing?
And in my case, my car actually has a full size spare tire well
in the trunk, right.
Which, like if I didn't have a spare tire, man, I could, like,
I could keep snacks in there or something.
I don't know, like it's a lot of snacks, so I have like a full size spare tire because I,
well, not so much now, but like I used to do some road trips outside the city and,
you know, having a real tire as a spare tire is
infinitely better than that little 5050 donut.
I feel like the car is gonna tip over whenever
I see somebody driving on it on the highway.
I mean,
so,
well, but basically,
but a great example of this is I don't bother having a
carjack in my car unless I'm going on a road trip.
Because if I get a flat tire in the city, I'll just call Amy
and they'll be there in like 20 minutes.
Well, and, and ok, so it,
it's funny you bring this up because I think you're exactly right where.
But if I go on a road trip, I do pack a car jack,
obviously because I don't want to be stuck out in the middle of nowhere.
-- I literally
-- don't. Well, ok, we'll get to that.
I'll, I'll talk about this in a second. But you're right. Like if you looked at the,
I guess
the, the whole like realistic threat model slash attack surface of what I was doing,
Josh, dropping his laptop in a bathtub.
That's the most likely scenario.
-- If someone
-- stole that key, what could they have really done virtually nothing?
Right. The key had minimal value.
And I mean, obviously in my head it was super important and,
and like the Russians or someone who was going to come get me.
But the reality is
it, it had minimal value. And I obviously,
I, I created an elaborate ridiculous process for myself that granted,
I only did this every other year or so.
-- So it's not like it ate an enormous amount of my time.
-- Well, companies do this too.
Like, you know, we're gonna get attacked by XY and Z.
It's like, no, you're not,
you're gonna get ransomware by somebody who's
like attacking every IP address on the planet
-- right,
-- right now, kind of tying that back to your, your tire model. Right?
So
in the, the little electric car I bought, right.
It has a range of 100 and 50 miles.
There's nowhere I'm going.
Like basically anywhere I go is in civilization with that car,
I drive it around town.
That's what it's for.
So I do not have a jack or a spare tire in that car. It has this like weird
chemical thing you can like inject in it and it'll like,
oh, the foam pump thing. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
It's like a one time use because it'll screw the valve stem and you have to,
-- I assume,
-- I assume the tire is trashed. Like
the rim might even be trashed.
No. No, no. It's actually really clever.
It's basically, it's like spray foam and compressed air
and it air cures. So, basically it'll, like, go into the crack cure and actually,
like, unless you have like a blowout, it'll,
you'll be fine. Like you can go for a while on that.
The problem is that gunk gets into the valve stem and it may
basically re the valve stem in your tire and have you have to replace that.
Oh, I'm sure
you, you replace you, you gotta replace your
stems every time you get your tires anyway. Like
you don't do that.
I have no idea. Like I just, I bought,
I bought new tires, like
I bought new tires like three days ago and they
didn't mention anything about valve stems on my winter tires.
I
don't know.
Look, I, but although you change your tires a lot,
like I get new tires like every five years,
-- like
-- every six months because we have winter and summer
and there are two very distinct states of being here
where I live.
I get new tires like,
every five years I just get the all season because I live in the city and I don't care
that
work
and I get, I just, they, they replace my vel stamps. It's like $40 and I don't care.
And it's fine
anyway. Anyway. Right.
But, but I think this is exactly the point is now when I drove
our minivan
out to Mount Rushmore, which was pretty freaking like I had,
there were many times I didn't have cell service on that trip and there were times
I didn't see another car for hours while
we were driving around in the middle of nowhere
in the, you know, western
part of the United States.
Now,
I wouldn't dream of driving around there without a
spare tire because if you got a flat,
you could literally spend
a day or more.
You know what I mean? Without, without seeing humans. And that would be terrible.
Yeah.
No, when I go on car trips I take up like a full sled jack because I'm like,
I don't want to be
ding around that stupid little like
tints, chintzy,
you know, looks like it's going to collapse and can barely hold up a cat,
let alone my entire
whatever.
It'd probably work. It'd probably be fine.
But
-- also
-- with the sled jack though, it's just so much faster. Right? You're like chunk,
chunk, chunk.
How
often? Ok. How many times have you had to replace a flat tire in a road trip?
Uh Not on a road trip, but I have done it twice in the city.
In the city.
We got some pretty impressive potholes. Fun fact. Um, the Mercedes run flat tires.
My sister and brother-in-law have like a nice Mercedes, you know,
with the run flat tires.
Yeah. No,
there are potholes big enough here in Edmonton that they, like, killed their tire
that
anyway anyway.
-- No,
-- I've been to rim once.
Like, no, seriously. Like, I hit a pothole in the dark and
impressive. I've been to rim,
I've never have I ever been to rim. I don't think I've ever been to rim.
It sucks because it's expensive.
Rims are tires are expensive, man.
Rims are meant to be sold in four packs.
So when you ask for one,
they give you a dirty look and they quote you
some obscene price because also what are you gonna do?
Not buy one?
That's fair. That's fair. You gotta get some gold plated spinners on that sucker.
Yo. Anyway. Anyway. Alright. So yeah, I I guess
I don't know if there's a lesson here.
I know there is, I think the lesson you mentioned about having like realistic risks.
I've got a really good parallel.
There's a guy on Twitter talking about Os N and about not
like basically scrubbing your social media
profiles of yourself and all your workers
talking about like what kind of technologies and stuff they're into so
that the Attackers don't know what kind of technologies use at work.
And my reply was
instead of spending time like not like literally
spending effort to not talk about stuff,
maybe just like patch it and do an inventory.
I look,
my take on that II,
I saw that too and I don't remember if you're the person who sent me that
tweet or if I sent it to you or if we found it on our own.
But I, I do remember that. And
so my first thought was
if, if you're a moderately sized business,
you have all the tools
they have windows,
right?
Don't tell them
they'll never know.
Yeah. And they might have an iphone.
But, but more importantly,
I feel like
this is one of those situations of,
if someone knows the tools you're running and that puts you at a disadvantage, like,
I think you're doing some other things wrong.
This is, this is like security through obscurity. We know it doesn't work.
I'm not saying you should, like,
put a list on your website of all the tools you're running.
There's the thing people forget. It only works if
you can know that it's no longer obscure.
And you, you can't, like, by definition,
you can't know if something that is
confidential is no longer confidential unless someone,
like prints it on the front page of the Times.
And then the second problem is
you have to be able to swap that
secret out.
And so that's kind of why passwords sort of work is because like, oh,
my password's compromised, I will change it
all done. But like, you can't,
like if using Windows
version X
is a, is a, is a problem. Like, you can't just switch it out real fast for, like, limits
and,
and that's,
that's what people get wrong about security through obscurity
is that for security through obscurity to work,
you have to know when it's no longer obscured and,
and that buy in of itself is pretty much the nail in the coffin that kills it.
But then that second factor of being able to swap it out
outside of passwords and certificates.
You can't
like, oh, we'll just use a different web parson library. No, no, you won't.
That will be your web does, will hate you.
Yeah. Yeah. That's right. That's true.
I, I think that makes a lot of sense and I like that and I think,
and I guess that's just you have to deal with that. Like, that's the reality.
Make sure that's not something that's gonna take you down.
It's, that's like even I was,
I read a quote, a quote from someone that was basically something like
if I click a link and it damages our business,
like the problem isn't me clicking the link.
It's the fact that your security team is incompetent
is bad
if one person, like that's what always gets me with these ransomware attack is
so one person clicked one link and now your whole system's down in ransomware,
right?
Ok. That's
what if you had a malicious insider? Like how much worse. Is it gonna be
right?
Or somebody gets paid a bribe or,
or just some random clicks a link
and so, well, maybe put this in the journal notes. But like I literally have a github
repo called CS A Dash It Dash Operations where I'm like brain dumping
what I do for the new people and it's a public repo,
I'm OK with that.
I love putting this kind of stuff in public
because I think for one thing when you know,
people can look at your stuff, I think you do a better job
and, and just the fact is
this is not, this shouldn't be sensitive information.
Like if you're relying on this, you, you, you're doing other things wrong.
Yeah,
like obviously I'm not going to put a list of who uses windows
at the CS A because there's like a handful of us that do.
But, you know, like we just,
I ran one of the people through like how we're gonna handle
finna. Like here's, you know, first you see Glossy, the dog talking about it.
So he's a reputable source.
And then you see, well, MS RC and if MS RC says it's a vulnerability,
it's a vulnerability because
they don't do this for fun,
you know, and Cisa says it's a V and it's a phone because again,
Cisa very boring people, they tend to tell the truth
and, you know,
and here's the workarounds and they're lovely because
it's easy and it works and blah,
blah, blah,
you know, this is like a nice little public document and he's going to walk
up
the other window user at the CS A through fixing the system,
you know,
and yeah, so like there's like three, I,
I want to say four but I know for sure three of us using windows at the CS A.
Yeah. If knowing that leads
to us getting hacked.
Yeah, it's time for me to quit and become a part.
You suck.
You'd probably be a bad plumber just for the record.
I'm actually a reasonably
ok plumber because I use shark bite fittings and I actually read the manual and like
if I hired a plumber and they were using shark bite fittings, I'd be like,
you have a good day.
I'm going to call someone competent who isn't using shark bite fittings in my house.
Dude. I am so over. It's a better technology than slaughtering.
No, it's not, it's not at all. No
inferior
because it's like $20 a joint.
Yeah. But
again, we had this discussion, remember with the, um, with the marts versus the, um,
oh, what's the one from Europe called?
I'm spacing out.
But the thing is if you're paying your plumber hourly,
that shark bite fitting will pay for itself.
I don't know. I don't know about that.
I guarantee it won't.
Pex fittings are, are definite. I'm not getting into this right now.
-- We have to end this show. It's dragging on too long. Shark
-- bite.
-- Works on copper as well as pecs.
-- I know it does, it works on them all.
I've, I've used it to join copper to pecs in the past. Like I've done this.
But I'm still saying if I hire a plumber,
I don't want them using shark bite like I can do shark bite. Right?
-- I'm hiring you because you're not me.
-- We
were talking about, remember Marts versus
Wago connectors. And the thing is a Wago connector saves so much time,
especially commercially. It just makes sense to pay more for the
Wago connectors, snap the wires together
and,
and that's, that's like another topic and I do like
Wago connectors. But anyway, I'm ending this, we have to go this time.
Thank you everyone for listening to this horrifying tale of bizarre
-- GP G key handling.
-- Maybe we could make GP G key revocation parties a thing.
No, I'm not doing that.
No. Like having like
just letting go of the past.
It just, just do it. You don't need a party. Just do it anyway. All right.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security, podcast.com. Head up the show. Not two pound
says podcast. Hashtag hit us up on social media. Kurt have a lovely rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.