Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
So, what's new? I've actually managed to fix the grass on my lawn.
What does that mean? How do you fix grass?
Well, where there's dirt,
you put seed and more dirt and then water it and then you get grass.
Ok. And then you pull all the weeds out and then you
that for like five days and then you just hire somebody
with a giant truck full of chemicals to come by and
spray down your yard.
Which, and it was great though because like the next day,
all the dandelions were like wilting and dropping dead and then it rained.
And then the next two days after that,
there's like this super fresh crop of healthy dandelions.
-- I
-- must say, I love the way Canadians say dandelion.
You say dandelions.
-- It's marvelous. Well,
-- because it's always plural. Have you ever seen just one?
Yeah.
Ok.
Um,
and then, you know,
I also had my ant guy come by and there was only two ant hills
in my yard this year compared to like 10 or 20 the first year.
So
again, you know,
unrestricted chemical warfare is working on the ants because at this point,
like the powder you buy at, like Home Depot, I think it's just food for them.
They, that powder has always killed my aunts.
-- But I don't know, we might have lax laws in the US.
-- Oh,
yeah, we have pretty, like the, the, the stuff that they use on my yard.
I'm not allowed to buy unless I have like, an exterminator's license.
Oh,
that's exciting.
-- Yeah. Well, we're also not allowed to use herbicides. Like,
-- not at all.
-- Yeah, that's pretty much banned in most major Canadian cities.
-- Interesting.
-- But you can hire someone to come and do it for you.
-- Yeah.
And it's kind of a grayish area in that they use herbicides that are
legally compliant and they're definitely not as good as the old timey ones.
But, I mean, like, the old timey ones are, like,
round up and stuff where it's just like scorched earth, you know,
you put that stuff down and everything's dead.
We still have that here.
Yeah. Oh, yeah, you can get that here if you're a farmer.
-- I see. But again, like, in the city you
-- can't,
I mean, that seems fair.
So, I've,
I've given up caring about my lawn because the people on the radio said it's good
for the bees to just let all the weeds grow and don't mow it too often.
So, I feel like as a lazy person.
That is the optimal explanation for the state of my yard.
I'm not going to disagree with you there.
No.
Like if honestly, if we had more beads,
I would probably plant some more wild flowers and stuff because like,
you can get Cheerios will send you a packet of wild flower seeds, the cereal company
because they need,
well, look at their logo. Their mascot.
Oh, that's true. Their mascot is a bee
honey nut Cheerios. Like
no honey, no honey nut Cheerios.
I'm confident they could use old motor oil or something and, and work it out.
Anyway,
what are we talking about today?
Well, this kind of leads into the whole app security thing.
So what triggered this is as you know, like I was updating a wordpress instance,
you know,
I go to the normal page and it gave me
a warning on the update thing about my security checkup.
And I'm like my what now? Yeah, that's pretty cool.
And so I go and look at this web page.
Wordpress is complaining about a couple of things
a couple of which were actually legitimate.
Somehow I managed to not install zip or image magic
PHP libraries.
It was complaining that PHP was out of date and that's because it's on a,
on an ubuntu LTs, right?
So that the actual semantic version of php that it shows is seven point whatever old,
you know, and the newest version is, I don't even know anymore. 07.3.
No, wait, more rows. Oh, no, 7.3 coming
out next year anyways.
And then it looked and what was really cool is it not only told me the problems I had,
but it told me that the checks I passed
somewhere.
I can talk to wordpress.org and make sure that we're up to date or what I
wouldn't have thought of is I can talk to myself on local host and like,
send myself requests to like, tell myself to do stuff.
Right.
And some cool ones too, like it actually complained about my file permissions,
which are a bit wonky because the whole thing is it's actually a G
repo, you know, checked in whatever.
And it was smart enough to know that it was smart
enough to say your wordpress is managed like it's a Git
repo. So it's probably managed wild, like to be aware of that. Right. Because
if I do like a wordpress update, then I also have to, you know,
check those updates to get otherwise.
Well, they're going to disappear someday.
And conversely, the, you know, the get
repo, you could update stuff in the get
repo manually or whatever and then, you know,
do a check out and get an up to date wordpress.
It got me thinking because, you know,
traditionally apps have sort of just passed the buck on
that is the system up to date or not,
who can say nobody cares.
Right. Like, really? And it got me thinking,
is there a way to kind of get like a health score on an Os
in the sense of for an operating system to say to an app?
Look, I'm like 95% up to date or, you know, like a great example.
My Windows 10 gaming machine.
I religiously keep that thing up to date because
the kids use it for school now and I don't
want it stalling out and having to reboot for an
update when the kids need to get on school.
Sure. Right.
So, like every couple of days, I like sit in front of it,
log in type update and it's like last check for updates, you know,
usually a recent time
and I'll manually force updates just to make it stay up to date.
And is there any way for like, because I know, for example,
there's no way for an app to be like, hey, I'm, I'm talking to the network.
-- Is this encrypted
-- since you mentioned this the other day?
I've been, I've been thinking about this topic a lot and I think
in order to have a functional conversation,
we have to set the ground rule of, let's ignore the fact
that today,
an app needs an extraordinary level of access to the
operating system to be able to make this decision.
Let's pretend
there's an API
that can say these are all of my updates or something.
Well, or just general system settings.
Great example, I mean, I think Red Hat just rolled the soda.
You have system wide crypto policy now, right?
Whereas traditionally, it was like, if I have, well, if I have a website
server
running, how's that web server configured?
Well, the web server knows none of the web apps under it.
-- No,
-- or even more importantly is
you could,
there would, there would be no way to tell the web server
we only want to use TLS 1.2 or 1.3.
And then to also tell, let's say the mail server
that we also, you know what I mean,
where you had to configure everything independently and it was a huge headache.
I know with email, for example, there's now headers that so that the data gets
appended to and you know, so for example, when I open up my email and gmail,
I can see that
this email came from a remote system to gmail over a TLS connection. Right? Yes.
Generally speaking,
I don't have a way of really firmly knowing
that with most other apps and types of data,
this database connection was it encrypted?
Ok. Let's, let's start at the beginning and
wordpress
gave you kind of a little check up
that said here's some things you should investigate.
-- It was actually about 40 or 50 items.
-- That's a lot.
Yeah,
I was pretty shocked actually.
-- Like I
-- said, now,
here's where I think wordpress is special is they have been beat up for a long time
over many, many security problems.
And I would say in the vast majority of cases it is
people running outdated versions of wordpress that they haven't updated in years
and it makes wordpress look bad.
So they have an incentive to kind of do the right thing here.
-- Well,
-- and they're also something like 30% of websites by numbers. It's
-- a lot.
-- Yeah.
It's weird to me.
They're like the biggest little app you never heard of,
but everybody uses constantly.
Yeah, because it works
well. I mean, you ended up moving our
web,
like the open security podcast episode.
-- Do you even know what our domain name is?
-- Open
Security podcast?
You ended up moving it from Blogger to wordpress because it was such a, you know.
Yeah, because blogger was broken and the thing I still love is like
I moved it
in a fit of rage
and I just exported all the podcast content and I imported it into wordpress and like
it just worked.
There were, there were a couple of little niggles I had to fix.
But generally speaking, I was shocked.
-- I
-- think that's why wordpress one is somebody like our
parents can manage it and administer it and use it.
I wouldn't go that far.
But
anyway, anyway, let's move away from them.
Maybe because I think wordpress is too easy. Of an example.
They have a lot of incentive to do this and they have a lot of history behind it.
So let's, let's move to something different and say, I, I don't, what,
what should we pick on?
Let's pick on a web server.
Is it the web server's job to look at the system it's running on?
Let's ask that question.
OK, let's say, for example, let's pick on Apache,
you configure Apache to use TLS 1.21 higher and to not use SSL, right?
Which I think is actually the default. Now, I would hope it is.
And let's say you're running on a system that
only has TLS library support up to version 1.1.
-- Should Apache care or should that be your problem or
-- no,
it should bail if you try to do that because it should have the ability.
It's, it's asking for the ability.
It's not requiring it because it can still do TLS 1.1.
But if you explicitly forbid it in the configuration
-- file,
-- I'm saying you explicitly allow TLS say 1.1 and higher.
But the system underlying libraries say only support TLS
1.1 and they don't support TLS 1.2 and higher.
OK? Apache is now limited. It can't do TLS 1.1 and higher. It can only do TLS 1.1.
-- OK? Well,
-- should Apache bail or warn or air out or something?
Does it?
I have no idea.
It should
work because if you specify 1.1 or higher
in that Venn diagram you've met your requirements.
Let's, let's ask this question a little differently.
Maybe that makes more sense is,
should Apache know
that basically you want TLS 12 or 13 and everything else is trash and,
-- and should it look for that and issue a warning if you're say using TLS 1.1
-- I,
I guess part of it
decomposes to where do you sort of look at the system and,
and and apply policy like do you do it at the system level external to Apache,
like editing its config files or you know,
like wordpress does Apache have some built in intelligence
and for example, a Apache now is smart enough to like
query its open SSL library or whatever and say like what do you talk, what can you do?
What are you capable of? And for example,
has a flag that says,
you know, I am required to do TLS 1.1 and higher.
So TLS 1112 and maybe 13,
I think 1.3 is mostly supported now it should be completely supported now.
And so basically, you know, if you can't do
TLS 1112 or 13, I'm going to bail at start up and say TLS 12 and 13 were not available.
So I'm bailing out,
you need to update your OS or change a config setting to allow this.
So
the historical view on this is that it is
the system administrators problem to set this up correctly.
And that's functionally how Apache works today.
-- And I
-- get past the B because it's, it's a solution that works,
-- it does
-- work.
But I, I wonder so in the context of Apache,
I think it is slightly different
because
you are expected to do a lot of configuration just to get to that point.
And so that might be
a less than ideal
situation.
Nobody runs Apache for the sake of running Apache,
you run Apache because you have an application on it.
Whereas wordpress, you run for the sake of running wordpress
-- and,
-- and that's a good point is I think maybe,
maybe part of the trick here is
to identify the difference between infrastructure and
application or, or useful thing, maybe.
Well, the thing that you want versus the thing that no offense, but I can run
well, Wordpress,
I can run wordpress or I don't run wordpress.
There's not a lot of things that are functionally identical to wordpress.
Whereas web servers, there's a lot of things that are functionally identical,
right?
-- It's just infrastructure like
-- engine X versus
Apache literally took me like five minutes
reading the website to be like, oh OK.
Here's the syntax, here's a slightly different view of how the world works.
Like as far as syntax goes. OK. Done, it's working.
OK?
So I would define this as infrastructure versus solution
I think is a nice way to put it.
There are solutions like let's say I need email, right?
Saying I need email is different than saying I need to set up send mail
because no one should ever set up, send mail again.
But
you know what I mean?
And, and this is a case where let's say you have an email solution.
Should your email solution have the ability to say you've configured?
You know, like, like D Mark is a great one.
You can tell everyone about what happened when you set up D Mark in your domain.
Well, I had D Mark set up on my domain but I had a policy of none. So it was just
whatever, like I have dear
policy but don't. So your three options for
dar policy are none
quarantine and reject.
None is none. Like just whatever quarantine is
send this email to quarantine on your like,
so if you receive email from me that is supposedly spoofed or something,
you know, shove it into your quarantine and maybe take a look at it, maybe don't,
I don't know whatever.
And then your third option,
which is the the harsh one is the reject where I'm saying like
if you get email that claims to be from
cre.org
and in my case, I have SPF with a minus all
and I have DKIM set up to put it bluntly.
Cre.org email only comes from my G suite account. Anything else is not right?
Reject.
My male client knows nothing about this.
And maybe that's the problem is that these apps
and these levels have historically never talked to each other.
That is true.
But I think this again comes back to the solution versus infrastructure aspect,
right?
I think when you have a solution,
you expect things to work together in ways that infrastructure might not.
Here's a great example. Let's say I have a solution.
Let's say it's a blog platform and I'm not going to
say wordpress because I don't know how wordpress actually works.
I just pay Wordpress to post wordpress. So I'm lazy and it's way less work.
But let's say, for example, you have a blog platform and you need a database.
There are certain ones that can support a multitude of databases.
So in that context, it's going to reach out,
but it's not the job of the database to say, oh,
you have to connect with TLS necessarily, it's,
it's going to be up to the application to say I'm not using encryption.
-- And
-- conversely, people do do that at the database level sometimes like you,
you can set your database to only accept hes 1.2 and better connections.
And and maybe that's kind of the answer is that we, you know,
we historically a long time ago gave up because these apps don't talk to each other.
So you just keep slapping duct tape down at every layer that
you can like you can't necessarily fix every client connecting to you
and have them all talk to us.
So you do it at the database server level, you know,
and just reject all plain text connections.
I mean, to a degree, this also comes back to the we, we had that episode.
Oh, it's been a couple now where we kind of talked about this,
this concept of back in the day.
It was common to be generous in what you accept.
And I think this is similar where it was historical
that we would accept like any incoming client and whatever,
it's not our problem.
And, and maybe that time has to change.
You know, we've talked about this in the in the space of like app updates or you know,
device updates,
you know, do we want to punish people for having old out of date systems?
Well, maybe, I mean to a degree. Yes.
You know, this is why I'll never buy a smart appliances.
People are all of a sudden discovering that their dishwasher, what was it
not a dishwasher, a clothing washing machine
now just shows
e where it used to show your calendar and weather.
And my first thought was why doesn't everybody
have a smartphone to look at that stuff?
You would think so?
Like I got a new bathroom scale. It's a smart scale.
And the reason I bought a new one is
because this one actually talks to Apple Health Kit.
My old, you know, smart scale didn't talk to Apple Health Kit.
You had to pay like eight bucks for an app to
export the data and put it into your Apple Health kit.
And I'm like, so it's clearly possible.
Just fitbit has chosen not to do it.
So, ok, I'm ditching their ecosystem because it doesn't play well with others.
And so my bathroom scale is configured to show my weight and my BM and stuff.
And it also shows me like the weather and I'm like, why I have a smartphone for that.
And one thing I realize is really with cars, drives home,
I don't want my car to be smart.
I want my car to be an accessory to my smartphone.
I mean, that's a good way to look at it. So funny enough, my parents bought a Ford car
probably like five or six years ago and it came with this terrible in,
in car entertainment thing and it was like Windows
Auto or something. I forget what it was even called. It's made by Microsoft
though and you look at it now and it's a piece of junk and nothing works with it.
And I keep thinking this is the dumbest thing ever.
-- Yeah,
-- I basically want my car to be a Bluetooth speaker, microphone,
maybe a screen to show me the map.
Yeah, I agree with that. It's, it's madness.
But ok, so anyway, I,
I
don't feel like we've come to any conclusions. I I guess
here is,
here is my thought on all of this is, I feel like
we are reaching a point in the world of computing and this
is partially thanks to containers and cloud and everything that's going on.
Where I think historically, people would buy infrastructure,
they would cobble their infrastructure together
and they would create a solution for, to solve the problem they had to solve.
And I think we've reached a point now where you can kind of buy solutions.
And I do think it's up to the solutions to do the right thing.
I think, for example, let's say I have wordpress and I'll pick on them here.
Uh I would expect if I would say getting
wordpress that it would set up TLS correctly and it
would encrypt things correctly and it would use secure
connections to databases and all that kind of stuff.
Versus if I was literally like creating an art
tal blog platform, it would be my problem
supporting that would actually violate a lot of company security policies and that
the web application shouldn't be allowed to like talk to the web server,
config files and change them.
-- I
-- I wouldn't view it like that though. That's, that's a stupid policy.
Then this is a solution I acquired
and
it effects,
it's kind of funny you mentioned that is I see this with all the container scans I get
where historically before people were like, you know,
opening up a container and looking inside you could do anything you wanted
and nobody knew or cared. And now they're saying, oh, why do you do this?
Well, we did the same thing with operating systems for the longest time.
Yeah, that's very true. I mean, it's exactly the same thing.
The way we shipped operating systems 20 years
ago now would possibly result in a lawsuit
that's reasonable. And I feel like you look at operating systems now and
they generally, at least from the consumer perspective, they auto update.
They, it, it's all just kind of magic, right? You can't,
if you download a web browser and you're connecting to a site without,
without a real certificate, it's nearly impossible to get to it.
Now, remember the good old days?
Oh, I had, I had my own self signed certificates on everything because man,
I couldn't afford to pay for those things.
That's right. I did. Now that you say that I remember that I did run on my website. I ran
my own self science certificates because,
-- because certificates were expensive, well,
-- not just expensive, but like,
I actually bought one for seared.org back in the day and
they didn't really know how to sell it to me.
They're like, can we have your business number?
And I'm like, not a business, I'm an individual and they're like, what I'm like,
I am Kurt
Seri. I own
creed.org. I want a certificate for c.org and they're like,
you have to prove that you like own seafood. And I'm like, it's my last name.
Photo ID work and they're like,
and they mold it over for one.
They're like, yeah, a passport, not a driver's license.
And I'm like, ok, and I literally, you know,
sent them a copy of the front page of my passport, which I mean, no offense,
but I'm pretty sure Photoshop could have,
you know, manage that back in the day even. Right. But yeah, I mean,
it just, it was such a chore and such a pain. And now of course, again,
well, there's an actual Apache module or whatever for let's encrypt that just
like literally that me snapping my finger and going poop.
That's about how long it takes to set up.
Oh, it, it's trivial. It's so easy to do.
I think you answered three questions, your domain name,
your email address and whether or not you want updates or warnings or something.
That's it. You're done.
Maybe it's one of those things where the time has finally come.
Not only that this needs to happen,
but that it's possible to happen because software has matured a bit.
Yes, I think that's a big part of it.
And so the example I like to always use here
is in the sixties humanity went to the moon,
then we didn't
ever again.
And so why was it? Right?
It was because we could go to the moon with the current technology.
But it was the equivalent of cobbling everything together
and holding it there with tape and praying,
nobody died.
Whereas today we actually have the technology to actually go to the moon.
We actually have a space truck now.
Elon Musk.
Right. Right.
And that's a huge difference.
Or I love, have you seen the, I'll try to dig this up and I put it in the show
notes, but there was a picture of the
Apollo kind of instruments in the capsule.
There's a picture of the space shuttle
and there was a picture of the dragon capsule
and the dragon capsule is like an ipad like,
I mean,
and you know what else I love is I was watching.
So the, the for anyone maybe listening in the future, maybe about a week ago,
the dragon capsule carried the first humans into space and it was successful.
Thank goodness, nothing went wrong.
And it was fascinating to listen to everyone though because they kept talking about
how much automation there was and how little the astronauts had to like.
Well, no, it, it kind of, but the thing is actually so in the early space program,
the scientists wanted to basically build a tin can for the
astronauts to sit in and they wouldn't have anything to do.
And the astronauts were like, no, we're going to fly this ship,
you're going to put a stick in it.
And in fact, they,
if they didn't do that a bunch of them would have died
because they ended up flying in and saving their own lives.
But
like the point is that it is a very different mindset of,
I want to fly this spaceship to.
-- Oh, no. Please don't let me touch anything. Well, that's
-- the old Airbus joke. Right.
When Airbus came up with fly by wire, when it was new,
the joke was, you know,
that Airbus planes will ship with a dog and the dog's
job is to prevent the pilot from touching the control.
That's great.
You know, and, and I mean, fly by wire, you know. Yeah, I had teething problems and,
-- you know, some unexpected stuff and then, well, we got it mostly working.
-- Right.
Right.
And I even, even cars now are, I, I wouldn't say they're all drive by wire,
but things like the accelerator
is just a switch these days.
It's not like the good old days where when you push the accelerator,
pull a little cord that was attached to the engine
that pulled on something and made more gas go in.
Like, that sounds insane.
Now,
I remember when I first saw one of the first cruise controls and
it literally was like a wire hooked up to a little sensor,
like a little mechanical Doohickey that literally
if it spun too fast, it pulled the wire and if it spun too slow,
it released the wire or vice versa, you know, to, like,
actually give it more and less gas to the engine.
So,
so my dad had this old motorcycle a long time
ago and do you know what the cruise control was?
It was like a little clip that just held the, the throttle in the same place.
I, I do the same thing on my lawn mower. I have a binder clip. Yeah,
because I hate having to hold that thing down for it to run, you know,
if you release it, it turns off.
-- Yeah.
-- But then how do you turn it off?
Well, I take the binder clip off
binder clip.
I
zip
tie.
Ok.
Now, of course, there are safety concerns because if,
for some reason you fall down in front of the lawn mower, it's going to eat you.
But whatever,
I know
it's been like
25 years of mowing the lawn. I'm, I mean, I would never
this on a tree chipper, but
I will do it on my lawn mower.
That's right. That's right. Ok. Ok.
-- I
-- guess the moral of the story is that, you know, certain safety systems are good,
but it is a maturity curve, right?
Like,
like the fact that
I was shocked when wordpress was like,
here we go.
The folder slash blah, blah,
blah was detected as being under version control dot Get.
That's a really cool check. Somebody at wordpress,
you know,
they put some real thought into these checks
and like this was a nontrivial amount of work
and here's part of the benefit though is
now some other web application that wants to do this.
They don't have to start from scratch anymore. Right?
They can just look at this wordpress page and see like, OK, you know, oh, for example,
you check for scheduled events are running, you know,
so I guess Cron Tab or whatever or
whatever wordpress's internal version of Cron Tab is,
you know, things like that, right.
They're not starting from scratch of like what do we have to check? It's ok.
Well, here's some basic your s
servers up to date, things like that.
And so maybe we'll see more of this now
that somebody broke ground and proved it's possible.
I mean, I,
I think it's inevitable and wordpress obviously deserves a
bunch of credit because this is a cool idea,
but I, I do think the world is just generally moving in this direction.
I mean,
I see this even in places where if you try to deploy certain horribly out of date,
ami S for example, in clouds, it's, it's common to get warnings that you've done
something exceptionally stupid.
I mean, I, yeah, I, I think this is where it goes, right.
We're, we're well past the point of artisanal it
and when you have a solution,
I think there's certain expectations and this kind of stuff should
be one of them where a great example is if,
if I go and buy a car built by a car manufacturer.
I expect it to have relatively few problems.
If I built a car myself, I would expect it to be broken all of the time.
-- You
-- know, that's what always gets me when you watch those
where people build like a custom car and it works.
And I'm just like, wow, now, granted they're,
they're using like off the shelf components that are reliable.
Like, they don't build their own engine
still. Like getting,
well, it's like assembling a PC. Right.
I remember the days when you assembled a PC and if it only
took three or four attempts to post it and we wires and,
you know,
stuff you were considered success and now it's like
the last PC I built was kind of like,
-- oh, that was uneventful and not,
-- it's
not even fun anymore. No.
You know, I had one cable, I had one power cable. That was it, everything else.
I've gone to the motherboard.
It's, it's something else. No, I, I totally agree.
It's, it's a very different world to say the least, but I, I think that's ok. Right.
That's what progress looks like.
Where
if you want to be on the bleeding edge of something now it isn't really it anymore.
You got to go find something else.
Well, it's, I mean,
there's still those corner cases where people do crazy bleeding edge stuff,
you know, and, and build bespoke systems.
But a
lot of that too is they're operating at scales or in corner cases where, like,
you'll never have widespread support for that.
-- Yeah.
-- And that's, I mean, look, you have that today. Look at, look at race cars.
Race cars are amazing creations that are
held together with bubble gum and chicken wire
and they wouldn't have it any other way.
And that's great. But I don't, I don't want that. Right. I, I want my boring car.
Ok.
I, I feel like we've come to a logical conclusion here, which is just around,
this is the expectation of solutions.
And I guess
there's,
there's two sides to this is if you're building a solution
and you're not looking into some of these more advanced features,
someone else will obviously.
And I think also if you are still relying on like artisanal infrastructure,
you probably need to take a hard look at what you're doing
because I bet in a lot of cases you shouldn't be.
It's funny that you mentioned that because we're just in
the process of getting rid of all our infrastructure like infrastructure
at the CS A and we're moving to platform as a service.
And it's funny because the Devs are now like, holy crap. This is amazing and great.
And I love it. I'm like, mhm
Right.
They just, I want this version of Ruby,
everything else happening underneath of it is
the responsibility of a large professional organization.
Cool.
It's not curt anymore.
And I'm OK with that.
-- And
-- that's the way it should be because developers should develop.
They shouldn't like, like the whole concept of devops has always been,
you're making one person do two jobs.
It's not making a lot better.
You know what it reminds me of?
It's IKEA,
we save money by making you assemble the furniture.
That's what Dev
Ops is, Dev
Ops is IKEA.
-- It is.
-- And the furniture falls apart in five years and then you have to find you
-- and nobody knows how it was built. Yeah,
-- that too.
That too. I do love IKEA furniture though.
Well,
I love when you see people try to take IKEA furniture apart to
get it back through a door and move it and it's like,
nope.
Yeah. Don't do it.
It doesn't come apart and you're not moving with it, just throw it away,
like,
pretty much. And sometimes that's ok. Right. Sometimes that is acceptable.
But I, I feel like if, if you want furniture for the grandchildren,
-- it's not from
-- IKEA.
That's funny because my parents actually we have some old
IKEA furniture up at the cabin that's done pretty well.
It's like 2030 years old, but
it's that old IKEA stuff that's actually built out of real wood.
It's not like everything is value engineered now to be
like they got rid of metal parts where possible. They use plastic plugs.
Like my kids' beds are like 50% metal parts to hold the frame together
and then plastic plugs to hold like the slats and stuff together. Like it's,
it's comical. But yeah.
No, it's, I, and I think part of it is, it's also,
I think the infrastructure people have a bit of a duty here
to maybe expose the configuration information a
little bit more easily or consumable.
Maybe, I don't know, I got to think about that
but I, I feel like ignoring all of that.
-- If you are building a solution, the bar is continuously
-- going.
I think you're expected to provide a solution.
And the more solution it is like wordpress is now
-- the, the better.
-- Well, and let's face it.
I mean, the world of it is the curve is complete,
right where, where we filled in all the gaps with early adopters.
You've got the, the, I forget what they're all called.
But then there's the laggards at the end like
it's, it's just done.
And
I also, I know we don't have time, but this is,
it always, I get a chuckle when I hear people talk about digital transformation
because it's like at this point, if you're not doing all digital everything,
you're just going to go out of business. So why even bother having this discussion?
Yeah, I mean, it, it's,
well, it's like people that say the web is a fad. It's like
who
says that anymore? Nobody, nobody says that anymore.
-- That that hasn't been said in 20 years.
-- I bet,
I bet you I can anyways
if you find one, send it to me, I'll put it in the show notes.
Otherwise I'm calling this one.
We're
on the precipice of
turning it into a nut house. Anyway. Alright, I am.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, use the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.