Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
-- Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser
-- and back to Normal Crime again.
I'm super excited today.
We've got, we have a guest, Dave Jevans,
who's the CEO of Cipher Trace and the chairman of the anti fishing working group,
Dave.
Why don't you give us a little intro and we'll kind of go from there.
But as listeners are aware, like I love Bitcoin and so you are right up my alley.
Josh Kurt. It's great to talk to you today.
Yeah. So as an intro,
I'm the CEO of Cipher Trace. We are a Cryptocurrency
compliance and investigation capability company.
So we help a lot of people in the banking
area in the Cryptocurrency exchanges and the OTC desks.
But we also work with regulators and others
and we do help victims who've had Cryptocurrency stolen from them.
My background is in computer security and financial services.
So I've started three very successful start ups in
computer security encryption over the last almost 20 years.
And I have a master's degree in Computer
Science from the University of Calgary in Canada.
Oh, man, another Canadian
actually, it's funny for,
just for the listeners who don't know is I had to cut Dave
and Kurt off at the beginning because they wouldn't stop talking about hockey.
So,
anyway. All right. So, I guess the very first question I want to lead off with is
you talk about doing investigations into Cryptocurrency?
The way people understand this is that Cryptocurrency is anonymous.
-- Are you telling me it is not
-- that Cryptocurrency is pseudonymous? Oh,
I
-- like
-- that.
Yeah, it means you can identify
entities, we call them. You know, it could be a company, it could be an individual.
It could be an automated system, a defi system
that control certain kinds of addresses or smart contracts or wallets.
So that can be derived purely through Blockchain analysis,
which means we know that these
addresses are owned by people. So that's pseudonymous. So it's not anonymous.
It means you can cluster addresses together.
Now when you layer it on with other analytics, you can make it more precise.
-- So
-- you're basically talking classic traffic analysis layered with other data.
I mean, that's really cool.
This is one of the things that I think a lot of people don't, don't always grasp is that
even though you're dealing with addresses,
you're leaving a digital footprint all over the place.
I mean, let's, I guess let's take an easy example, right?
Why don't you explain to us like what is
a Bitcoin transaction look like and what are the
things you guys maybe look at there because I
think Bitcoin's probably the leakiest of them all.
Yeah.
And I think that's,
it's a good way to generalize over the entire space is just to talk with the,
the granddaddy of the mall.
So in a Bitcoin transaction,
what you get is effectively a transaction ID and then addresses that are
involved in that and there could be a sender and a receiver,
but that's even too simple.
There's always a sender, a receiver and what we call a change address,
which means let's say I want to send you
Josh half a Bitcoin but I have one Bitcoin.
It's going to send you half a Bitcoin and I'm going
to get the other half Bitcoin back sent to me.
So in general, there's almost always three parties and a Bitcoin transaction,
the sender, the receiver and whoever got the change.
Not always, but generally now you can make it more extensive.
So let's say you're a Cryptocurrency exchange
and you want to reduce transaction fees,
you might throw 50 inputs in
to a Bitcoin transaction. So 50 different addresses
and then you might send it out to
150 addresses
that are receiving transactions. And this is done to reduce transaction fees. So
transactions look like that.
But this gives you an analysis pattern where
you can start to track transactions through the Blockchain
to see where they started from.
And eventually you could go 10 steps 20 steps, 50 steps and see where they are.
That's awesome.
And now do you guys only track Bitcoin
or do you track other cryptocurrencies as well?
Cipher
trace tracks over 800 cryptocurrencies.
I didn't even know there were 800 cryptocurrencies.
There's way more than 800
holy
cow.
There's, there's, there's about 2030 40 that really matter.
But there's, yeah, there's thousands of little ones but we, we,
we put effort into tracking about 800 of them.
But again, like there's really 20 or 30 they're,
they're the top ones and these are based on different chains.
So some of them are based on
the Bitcoin Blockchain.
A lot of them are based on the Ethereum Blockchain,
which is a complete rewrite and adds smart contracts
IV software that can run on the Blockchain.
And then there's a number of independent blockchains that have been developed,
for example, to support what we call stablecoin.
Ok. Ok.
So
I'm, I'm, I feel like a kid in a candy store. There's so many things I want to ask you.
But
so let's start with criminal investigations. Can you, can you talk more on that?
Because I think that's one of the things that captures people's imaginations
is you hear about these crazy Bitcoin heists where people are stealing,
you know, you know, millions of dollars or billions of dollars in some cases.
And,
and I'm curious, like, what does that mean? Like, what, what does that mean?
From your perspective, like what is cipher trace doing in that, that case?
So yeah, so on the high side of things, it, there's two types,
I would say there's um the ones that are targeted at individuals.
So those tend to be fishing related.
So, you know, I'll fish your password to your Cryptocurrency account someplace.
There's more sophisticated versions of it which we can
discuss if we want to get into detail.
But,
you know, I steal your private keys, but typically think of it as, as, as as fishing,
advanced fishing. And then the second one is
um actual attacks against Cryptocurrency exchanges where people
are holding a lot of their cryptocurrencies,
you know, so they can buy, sell trade,
etcetera.
Um Those are obviously much larger.
So those tend to look like any kind of security attack against a,
any kind of online service or company,
which is I want to break into that company through various mechanisms.
Most of, you know,
what we think about as traditional security breaches
are I stole all your customer data,
you know,
I stole your credit card data and I go sell it on the internet or I sell passwords
and user names on the internet. Now,
the thing about crypto which is different is
if you get people's private keys,
um you basically stole their money.
And
so there's way more monetary incentive to attack
Cryptocurrency exchanges because if I like extract,
you know, I don't know,
1000 bytes of information. That's your private key or that's your recovery key.
Then I basically can steal all your money from anywhere in the world.
Yeah,
I've been looking into this because it's
interesting how traditionally to monetize the tax,
you have to get the data and then do something, sell it, whatever, rent it.
But, yeah, with, with Cryptocurrency you, well, it is money.
One thing I'm, I'm finding really, uh, that I don't quite understand.
So for example,
uh there was the exo
hack back in December of 2020 right?
Where they stole something like $10 million worth of Cryptocurrency.
About 6% of the uh exchange's total value from their hot wallets.
And obviously they know the address is that the money was
to and they've published these and said, you know, don't do business with this.
But I'm wondering, you know, kind of like dirty law like dirty money.
Does the criminal underground?
Are they still willing to trade in these, with these addresses?
Like kind of at a reduced rate because they know the money's tainted or is this,
is this Cryptocurrency, you know, burnt forever or, you know,
if they wait long enough, can they spend it?
Like, how does
I'm kind of wondering how does it work with?
We know that this address is bad. They stole a bunch of money,
-- don't do business with it. Like will that work
-- typically not?
Now if you use a product like cipher trace on the receiving side
of things you can do deep chain analysis that would look at,
ok, I'm going to analyze this transaction, this transaction,
this transaction looking
backward down the chain because what these guys do is they try to evade
any kind of simple blacklist.
So what what what people will put out as you know,
a
blacklist of here's the address is where we know the bad guys sent the money.
Well, no bad guys. Well, in these days anyway,
no bad guys stupid enough to try to send
that directly to another exchange to cash out.
They would have been like four or five years ago. Yeah, or three years ago.
But now, no, so now they move it through,
they split it up into lots of private addresses.
So these are addresses that don't exist on any exchange.
They exist on someone's Linux computer
or their phone
and they split it up into 1020 30 40 5100 different pieces
and then
the smarter guys write software to do it.
So they'll, they'll make what we call peeling chains where they'll,
they'll move the money from one to another to another to another and they might
do like 50 to 100 transactions and then bring it back together at the end and
maybe three or four different exchanges where they can cash out.
So that's the state of the art of it is really kind of trying to avoid detection
increasingly using software algorithms to do it.
Are they also mixing it with sort of like clean Cryptocurrency
or is it sort of sitting out on its own?
No?
Yeah, they'll definitely, you know,
they'll have addresses that try to mix it in with clean.
It's not the biggest way they do it, but it, it happens,
you'll also sometimes see crypto moved into commercial money
laundering services which we call mixers or Tumblr or foggers
And that mixes, you know,
50 people's money into one transaction and then splits it out again.
So it's, it becomes harder to track.
That's not the primary way that we see it being done today.
There tend to be more proprietary mechanisms that people use to
split stuff out.
And um I think you also mentioned Kurt an interesting one which is the time delay.
So sometimes you will see people wait
and be very patient on moving it because I think they think maybe
if you wait 18 months,
people will stop watching anymore,
which is,
you know, generally true. Right.
Well, that this thing is something I don't understand because, well,
I guess technically maybe a statute of limitations could be an issue potentially,
but more to the point.
These are computer records and computers are sort of as I
understand it infinitely patient when it comes to this stuff.
Yeah. But let me give you an example.
So let's say a small investment firm buys
$10 million in a Cryptocurrency let's call it Bitcoin
on a Friday. They move it to a hardware wallet. It gets stolen on a Wednesday.
It moves into some address
and then it sits there for 18 months, which is now,
of course worth probably 30 $40 million.
-- That company's probably gone bankrupt.
-- Oh, I see what you're saying.
-- So, there's no one to chase it anymore.
-- Right. Well, a stupid question.
But wouldn't that company maybe sort of sell that debt?
Like,
wouldn't somebody buy that as a debt or as an
asset that they could then recover at a later date?
I've never heard of market. Perhaps that's a market. That's an interesting idea.
But I mean, I would think that the return rates would be,
-- I would imagine people would offer 1% 0.1%
-- because I just,
because like there's been, you know,
on the order of several billion dollars of Cryptocurrency
-- known to be stolen
-- now way more than that.
But yeah, I mean, it's, yeah,
I think at cipher trace we've tracked probably 4 billion.
Yeah, I mean, to quote Congress, that's real money.
Let me ask this. So
I'm a criminal.
I acquire some Cryptocurrency. I let it sit for 18 months and then I start using it.
I presume
that cipher trace has no problem recognizing that
the stolen money is starting to move again.
Yes. Correct. That's true.
No problem because we put an alert and monitoring on it and once we see it move,
then our analysts get alerted in real time.
That's ok. So let me ask that. Then let's say your analyst does get alerted.
-- What does that mean? What do
-- they
-- do?
-- Well, it depends if
so we don't do any work for free. I mean, we do a lot of work for free. That's not
true. We work for,
we do a lot of pro
pro bono work for small investors that, you know, have been ripped off. We also
have a network of
12 different universities that we work with where they have master's
degree students in financial crime that we feed them cases from.
You know, I got ripped off 50,000 bucks, 10,000 bucks. What have you? So,
you know,
we have 12 universities with these master's degrees in financial crimes that,
that can help and they're trained on the cipher trace product and
they will help small, you know, investors
and small holders to try to recover their funds and trace them.
But in general, what we do is, you know,
if we have a customer who's had one of these heist,
let's say it's an exchange or an OTC desk or something like that,
then,
um, we'll get an alert, we'll have our investigation team,
look at it, we'll notify the customer and then
we start tracing where that money goes.
And what we find is in these cases where people hold it for a long period of time.
That's a long time to think about how you're going to monetize
it and move it out quickly and typically it moves really,
really, really quickly.
So they, ok, so they come up with a plan and then
made it.
-- Yep,
-- they come up with a plan, they automate it.
They come up with a syndication program which is ok.
I'm going to split it up, for example, in five different pieces. So I'll say
1 million, 2 million here, 1 million, 2 million there
and then they'll break it out. And so you'll have either them doing it
completely themselves, either by manual operations.
Some of it will be software automated,
but some of it they'll delegate to some third party who will say like, ok, well,
I'll run it through my mixing service and
you'll pay me 20 percent.
So they tend to break it out into kind of the criminal underground network of um,
you know, combination of money mules,
mixing services and then their own software developed.
And then also people who are experts at doing it by hand.
Sorry, that just blows my mind because there's an old science fiction book,
Hardwired where they actually do this.
Like there's an actual scene in the book where they're laundering some money.
And for example, they send it to this
offshore account and then take a loan against 99.9% of the money,
you know, which gets sent somewhere else to, you know,
to try and break that chain of connection of the money.
Right. I, I just, I remember as a child thinking this was wonderful and magical and
I'm kind of, well, I'm not happy to see it happening now, 30 years later.
But part of me is glee internally like a little child. But, you know, this is finally
we're getting, you know, Johnny, demonic style cyber hacking. Right.
Or, uh, you know, Neil Stevenson's Krypton
Noon. I mean, that's real.
Yeah.
Yeah. Oh,
man, that's such a good book. I haven't read that in a while. I need to do that. Now.
It's a big book though.
-- It is, it's a great, it's, it's very large.
-- All his books are big.
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah, they kind of are now that you say that anyway, whatever,
what I find really fascinating is it sounds like
the criminals are trying to be more technologically,
you know,
coherent and, and sophisticated,
but at the same time, it sounds like
for once law enforcement and tech technology is actually keeping up with them and,
or possibly a step ahead of them in some cases.
And I'm wondering kind of what's different this time around,
-- like why I
-- don't believe we're a step ahead of them.
We never will be as, as we talked about in the intro.
One of the other things that I do is I am
chairman of a nonprofit called the Anti Fishing Working Group.
You can find us at anti fishing.org or a
pwg.org.
We've been working on fishing since 2004.
We run a real time fishing feed that most of the browser
companies and all the big security companies use and big brands use.
We also run electronic crime conferences around the world.
So that's been 15 years doing this. We're never ahead.
We're always playing catch up now. We can predict things
and if we predict things, my,
my experience is if we predict some way that someone's going to do it
in, let's say 18 months from now, they usually do it in about 12.
So we might, we might have a prediction of how it is.
But the bad guys are always figuring it out ahead of time.
So it's ii I feel like it's always a combination of
addictive,
what are they going to do but also reactive because there's
always ways they think about that we never thought of.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, by definition, that's just that's the game of cat and mouse, right? The
cat is always chasing the mouse.
There's, it's never the other way around, obviously.
OK. This is,
this is fascinating. So I guess I'm really curious then. So if you're part of the
anti fishing group and you're dealing with tracing Cryptocurrency,
how often do those worlds kind of collide where you are seeing?
Because obviously,
there's tons of Cryptocurrency phishing everything that goes on every day.
So we started the Cryptocurrency working group at a
PWG about three years ago and you can imagine we had two or three companies involved
and now it's blooming. It's the fastest growing part of the
data sharing network, which is, you know, ransomware,
theft frauds and more and more data is flowing through it.
Even my local police department, you know,
has on multiple occasions issued bulletins and news articles about, you know,
essentially if, if revenue Canada calls you up and wants you to pay them in, you know,
Amazon gift cards or Bitcoin don't do it.
Yes. So one is obviously fishing consumers, you know, hey,
it's your Cryptocurrency exchange. You got to update it, et cetera.
But there's another area you have to be thinking about. So,
um, I fish the it
person who runs the DNS
at my Cryptocurrency company and I now get their third party DNS
providers
credentials.
So now what I can do is I can create
AAA basically route all of your customers traffic to my website
and I maybe I couldn't issue a certificate against it.
So some people will get like bad certificate, match and what have you.
But
I'm going to get a lot of your customers
passwords and potentially private keys.
So you have to think about internal phishing
as well on these Cryptocurrency services where,
what if somebody who runs, you know, the DNS
got fished?
Well, I actually just had this experience with one of the exchanges I use where they,
I was logged in and the support window pops up and they're like, hey,
we need to update your P I and I'm like,
I don't really want to because it's up to date and they're like, ok, well,
you can email it to us
and they emailed me from a domain that was totally different.
It was, you know, some generic support website kind of service thing.
And I'm like, has their support system been compromised and of course, you know,
I email them and they're like, no, no, no, this is totally fine.
This is normal. And I'm like, oh my sweet, you know,
you're basically teaching your customers to get fished.
Well, Kurt,
the other thing that I've seen is
Google and other advertising services allowing advertisements for
fishing sites for crypto. So being able to, for example, advertise fake meta mask
website. So meta mask is a great tool for protecting your Cryptocurrency assets.
If you want to manage them on your own computer, rather than a third party site
on an exchange, you can manage them yourselves,
you can put in your keys and then you can look at all your crypto
assets and it's a great product. But for the last couple of months, we've had
criminals basically advertising meta mask, installs, paid ads
on Google
and
you know, you go click on it.
It looks like it,
you install it the update to your browser and then they
just copy all your private keys and steal all your money.
It's, it's,
I've actually been through that with my kids and apps because if
you search the app store for a lot of popular kids terms,
you know, there's
some really dodgy looking fake copies of those popular apps.
Yeah, I'm just, I hadn't even really thought of, you know, as a, as a consumer.
How do I? Yeah.
How do I download software safely and install it and make sure that it's
not going to shut my private keys off to Russia at some later date.
So, I mean, that that problem has yet to be solved too, you know,
which is how do you educate people and
block these things and all that kind of stuff. So
real time block lists are important. Information sharing is important.
If the government would share information back with us rather
than us only sharing one way would be important.
-- Ok.
-- So this is, so you said you share
information with the government
about crypto,
-- I guess crime would, would that be accurate?
-- So what Cypher
Trace does is we, we create publicly available reports that discuss crypto
crime. So that would be theft
and fraud.
And so those are publicly available reports. You can find it on our website at cipher
trace.com
and those are, those are frequently quoted by government agencies as you know,
here's what the state of the world is.
That type of thing.
Right. Right. I got you. I got you. Ok. So that's,
I mean, I mean, that's fascinating to me because
you are, you, obviously you're tracking all of this information.
And I think what's fascinating about it is it's all in the public, right?
It's all on these public ledgers that
anyone with the resources is capable of doing this in
theory because I'll put that in quotes because I actually,
I imported the Bitcoin
chain into Alaska Search once and it's really big.
But it's, it's,
it's nontrivial. I can't, if you guys are tracking 800
blocks or 800 chains, I can't imagine how much storage you must have.
So I guess here's my question then is you've got kind of this,
this public research being done.
But then at the same time, obviously,
I, I assume like if, if someone goes to the, the FBI and it says, you know,
I've been stolen, you know, or not, I've been stolen.
That's not, that's not words.
But, you know, if they say if someone stole my Cryptocurrency,
then
obviously the FBI starts investigating.
I assume they don't have that level of expertise you guys have, right?
Uh Well, that's true.
But the FBI has a,
the United States FBI has a pretty well
trained uh Cryptocurrency team so they can help.
But remember that, you know,
every law enforcement agency has a limited
budget and limited training and limited people.
So, I mean, unless
you had
$5
million stolen, they're not gonna be able to help you.
That's fair.
I mean, I, I get that it's like,
it's like when people go and try to complain to the police that
my wallet got stolen and you're like, oh,
fill out this piece of paper and we're going to throw
it in the garbage when you walk out the door,
you know.
Well, one question because
uh so there,
I think that's part of the problem is this perception
that all the Blockchain data is public and you know,
immutable on the ledger forever.
But
do you guys also monitor the memory pool like the transaction pools of
transactions before they actually become transactions?
OK.
Of course, they do
monitoring Blockchain is tricky but monitoring the memory pool of Blockchain,
-- that is way way
-- trickier,
especially when you have chain reorgs and things like that.
Why don't, why don't you tell the listeners what that means?
Because I have a strong suspicion. There's some who don't quite know.
So that means that so we think about the Blockchain, let's just again,
keep it simple and think about Bitcoin Blockchain
rather than others because they're all different.
But this is probably the granddaddy of them all
is um typically you can think about
the blockchains get
validated every few seconds every few minutes, et cetera. So
Bitcoins around, let's call it 10 minutes. You know, e theorem is faster than that.
Others are faster, some are slower.
But in between that time,
you have an uncertainty period of who owns
what and there's a consensus algorithm runs,
let's say, in Bitcoin,
every around 10 minutes that's derived by minor solving computational program
problems. Right? OK. So
there are reorganizational problems. So let's say
somebody has a big huge mining pool running in.
I don't know Utah with really cheap power off a dam or in China or something like that.
Or in Iceland, thermo, what they, they might do is they might pre compute,
they might compute blockchains for
20 minutes, 30 minutes, 40 minutes
and they get all the votes on it and then they come back and they say, oh,
that thing from like 10 minutes ago, no, we can prove that we had more votes
than that. And that creates a Blockchain reorganization which
reallocates who owns what
now these don't happen all the time
but they do happen.
-- So
-- this is then leads to people saying, you know,
your transaction isn't finalized unless it's at least six or
10 blocks or whatever.
Yeah,
exactly.
This is why people put depth limits on, on Blockchain confirmations
and while you will see other companies who mitigate risk against it, so you'll find,
for example,
Cryptocurrency at T MS might say we'll take a zero block or a one block confirmation,
but they're going to charge you like a credit card,
you know, 1.5% 2% 3% 4% which covers their risk
of a reorg.
Yeah, for a double span. Right. That might affect their settlement.
I'm curious, how often does this actually happen?
-- Is it like a daily, weekly, monthly kind of thing?
-- It happens on Bitcoin.
It's less and less frequent, but there have been a number of them recently
because it requires tremendous computational power.
So they tend to be more organized or somebody screws up or something.
But oftentimes they might be more organized around that on other chains,
it will happen much more frequently if there is less computational power.
I mean, reorgs are a thing you have to architect for.
And then that means that when you do Blockchain analysis,
you can almost never be 100%.
But the longer it hangs out in as far as transaction confirmations goes, you can get,
you can get more and more confirmation around it.
-- Just
-- a side question because I was looking
at some Blockchain hash rate graphs and it's like
in a period of 24 hours or while in a period of basically two days,
it seems to vary between
like 124 million and 174 million, which is like, that's a huge variation is,
do you have any idea why?
-- That is?
-- I only have theories.
I'm not, I'm not, I'm not an expert on mining hash power.
There's other people who are, I think a couple of those things are
based on obviously power. You know, what is the price of electricity where you are?
Some of it? Is when you get new hardware in or you don't.
So you'll see spikes around that.
But I also think some of it is redirection of the hash rate to other chains.
So there is a whole liquid market around this new chains coming.
We're going to focus hash rate over here.
And some of these companies either will do
it themselves or they have consumer products where
you can say I want to focus your hash rate on this compatible chain or not.
And they'll go like, OK, here's a chain that's about to launch.
Let's like hash the craziness out of it for like the
next two weeks and then we can pre mine everything,
we can control the stuff.
So there's a,
there's a liquidity market in hash rates depending on how old your hardware is,
what algorithms it supports.
-- So it could be, it could be related to that as well.
-- That is awesome.
All right, we are nearing the end of our time.
So Dave, I will give you the last word before we.
Thanks Josh. It's been great to talk with you today.
It's been great to talk about how cipher trace works with Cryptocurrency
exchanges with individuals who might have
had stolen currencies with the regulators,
with the banks to grow the Cryptocurrency economy.
We're working across the world with all of these individuals and these companies,
we want to see Cryptocurrency become a dominant player in the financial markets
-- and that's our goal.
-- That's awesome. What a cool goal. All right.
So I will put links to all of this stuff in the show notes.
So anyone listening, don't worry about writing it down,
just head over to the show notes, find it.
And
yeah, I guess. Thank you, Curt and Dave.
This was absolutely fascinating and of course,
lovely off topic at places as always, but it is, it was fun.
So I guess go to open
source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes for anything we talked about today. You can use the
Podos
podcast. Hashtag You hit it, hit us up on social media.
-- Curt and Dave have marvelous rest of your days.
-- Thanks.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.