Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 147
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser,
-- what's new
-- Kurt?
-- Uh,
-- apparently you can pay a dollar to get into somebody else's house. Now,
-- like anyone you want or not,
-- anybody,
-- anybody who signs up for the service where
-- crowbar as a service, right?
Yeah. So lock boxes, right. If you've ever done,
uh, if you've ever had to go buy a house or rent a place, right.
Obviously, you want to like,
go in and look around and make sure it's not full of raccoons or something.
Right.
And traditionally that's been a real pain, you know, I remember the last time,
like not the last time, the last,
last time we were house hunting and you had to coordinate with the other
realtor for them to show up and like unlock the house and stuff,
right?
Ok.
And for example, now,
locally they have these lock boxes that are actually Bluetooth enabled
so that
you go with your realtor and they have an app on their phone that allows them to,
you know, ok, lock box number 217,
I need to unlock now so I can get the keys out of you,
so I can open up this house and like show my clients around,
right?
But obviously, you know,
not everybody wants to spend money on expensive Bluetooth lock boxes.
So most people just get the cheap ones that have like a combination lock,
like and not a proper combination lock, but like
a four digit, you know, like 1234, click it opens.
But at the same time, you kind of want the advantages of,
you know, for example, you're a landlord and you're
in a different country or heck you're at work or whatever,
you don't want to have to drive out to,
who knows where to like let somebody interview the apartment so that
they can decide whether or not they want to rent it.
So you put the green a
lock box and then you basically subscribe to a service that
allows you to kind of publish those and they charge a dollar to get access to it,
right?
So if I want to see somebody's apartment and it's, you know,
subscribing to the service,
I go and I pay a dollar and I
get the code to the lockbox.
Hopefully I'm somewhat honest and I don't, you know, trash the place or whatever.
So I go there
on
the box, get the key, look around, go, ok?
I want to rent it or no, I don't want to rent it or whatever,
go back out, lock the place, hopefully put the key back in the lockbox, lock,
the lock box and
you know,
continue my email conversation with the landlord whether
or not I want to rent this place.
Right.
And my suspicion is the purpose behind the $1 charge
is you're going to use a major credit card,
that way they can use that for verification purposes.
And I think we all know how this story ends now.
Well, it's a little more subtle than that in that.
So I can pay a dollar using a stolen credit card or something.
Right?
So now I have a code for a lock box that I
can use more than once because this is a mechanical lockbox,
right?
It's not sophisticated.
And now I can put up an ad like on Craigslist in the US or maybe Kaji
in Canada
saying I have this place for rent,
you know, contact me if you want to view it, I'm remote.
So I'll have to give you the lock box code to get in and look around.
So somebody replies, they go, I give them the lockbox code, they look around,
they go, yeah, I want to rent it and I go cool.
You know, here's your contract and you need to make a deposit of, you know,
1000 bucks or whatever and they send me that money and you know,
I disappear with the money
and what really was interesting to me is it, got me thinking
if I go to a physical
location in the world, be it a building, an empty lot, a parking lot, whatever,
how do I know that that guy standing over there who claims to own it or to,
claims to be in control of it actually is.
And he's not just some random guy who showed up, like,
you've been to major events where people are selling parking
on their lawn right around the stadium or whatever.
Oh, yeah,
that happens all the time where it's scammers selling parking or something.
How do you know that guy is actually like the
owner of that house and they're not on vacation?
You don't? And
I think even in the instance where they're not, the owner,
generally speaking, I think everyone gets away with it.
-- And so people mostly just don't care.
-- Well, and that's the thing, right.
So what's happened apparently is like this lady paid
money kind of started moving in and then,
you know,
people from the cleaning company actually hired by the
owner of this place showed up and they're like,
get out, right.
You know, you don't like, we don't know who you are, get out or we're calling the cops.
And so this poor lady, her money and
has, uh, let's face it.
You know,
the cops are not going to be able to track whoever
-- did this down most likely and get her money back
-- No,
no, they, they almost certainly don't care.
And even if they did care,
it's almost certainly someone in a foreign country using
stolen credit cards and stolen credentials for email,
whatever.
And you're never going to find them.
Well, and more importantly, you're never going to get the money back.
Right. Yep. Yep.
And I think I read in this story they, they used a Bitcoin ATM to send the money.
-- So, like it's gone. Gone.
-- Right.
Well, and, and it's, again, that's a classic case of like,
yeah,
we could use money mules and we could do all
sorts of fancy things to make the money less traceable.
But yeah, man, like an ATM Bitcoin transaction,
you know that just turns money into Bitcoin, send it to this wallet,
run it through a Bitcoin washer and boom, it's gone. It's easy.
You can do it from anywhere in the world
and you don't need to involve people. That's the big thing, right?
You don't have to have accomplices
when you use
banks and credit cards and things like that.
There are, I'm not going to say all the time, but there are
there there for certain transactions and
certain things you have fraud protection.
So if you do get nailed,
you can fill out a form
and they will, in some cases you can get some or all of your money back.
But I think the other important aspect is
if you do get defrauded from using like proper, you know,
we'll say monetary vehicles,
you can file the,
the bank will probably help you file a police report at the very least.
Whereas if you file a police report because you used a Bitcoin ATM,
they're gonna be like, yeah.
Yeah, we just, no, no. Right on out. Right. We're not, we don't care.
Well, it's not that they don't care.
It's that they know that there's currently nothing they can really do about it.
Yeah, that's probably fair. I'm sure they,
sure they're sad. You got ripped off. But they know they know they can't help.
-- But
-- this really drives home.
Like, I was browsing reddit and this guy was like, oh,
I'm selling a console online and, oh,
somebody accidentally sent me a too large check.
Is it safe to deposit?
No,
if somebody somehow accidentally sends you a check for like,
three times the amount of what they were supposed to pay and is like, oh, that's cool.
Just deposit it and wire me the difference. Number one.
Why didn't they just wire you the money in the first place?
Right. Like
I live in Canada, we can email money to each other for a buck
using, you know, the intact,
essentially it piggybacks on the intact debit card system.
You register your email address.
So, like if you want to send me money, you,
you email curtesy.org a bunch of money and you know, I'll, I'll,
I'm not going to click accept because I'm gonna be like,
I don't know what this money is and I don't
want to get involved in whatever is going on.
-- Did you hear that? Everyone listening? Yeah, please
-- send me money.
-- But don't seriously don't email
-- KT
money,
see what happened,
you know,
and even apparently Craigslist has like a warning all over the place saying, like,
don't, you know, don't take money orders and like,
cashier's checks for stuff and cash it because like, those are all scams, you know,
don't mail this stuff to some foreign country
just because you got what looks like a check because, you know,
checks take a while to clear sometimes like weeks
or more.
That's right.
Well,
and these scammers know how to construct the checks in a manner
that takes the longest amount of time possible for it to clear.
Yeah.
So, and it got me thinking because there's been stories.
Um, so this is a, this is a first hand story from somebody I know directly
that happened quite recently. So
essentially they were out drinking, they wanted to get home. So what do you do?
You call an Uber? Right? Cool. So they're waiting for the Uber basically.
And this guy
comes up to them and he's like, oh, you know, can I use your phone to call a cab?
And they're like being reasonable human beings like, oh, ok.
Yeah, we'll call you a cab. Sure. So they call the guy a cab.
Cool.
Uh their Uber comes up and these guys get into the Uber
and the other random guy gets into the front of the Uber
and the Uber driver, of course, just assumes they all know each other because
and starts driving and of course, the guys are called, the Uber are like, you know,
you got to stop and like,
dude, you, you need to get out like this, this is not a cab, this is an Uber,
this is an hour.
Anyway, there's a bunch of police cars and the Uber driver, of course,
uh apparently his thinking was because there's too many
people in the Uber and not enough seatbelts,
he's going to get in trouble.
So he kind of
just kept going, didn't stop
for the cops.
So more
cops show up. I know that that's what I love. But here's the thing, right?
-- Do Uber drivers get any training?
-- I would be shocked.
I'm sure they have a phone book sized terms of service. They have to sign that
says,
yeah.
So anyways, but what, but as an Uber driver,
when four cop cars surround you and they come at you, you know,
and they draw their weapons and start yelling
apparently, then you do stop. Uh Right.
So they basically hauled everybody out of the Uber.
And the deal was the guy that, you know, had asked to call a cab and got in the Uber was,
was, had just
done something rather improper in the eyes of the law and, you know,
they wanted to get a hold of him, but of course they're like, you know,
what's the story here?
Right? Like, is this your getaway car? Is this your, you know, your accomplices?
And, um, so the majority of the cops apparently were, like,
after talking to these guys, they're like, ok, well,
this one guy has a long history of criminality and did something really,
really horrible
And these other guys, you know, they're like 18,
they're 10 years younger than this guy. They have no criminal history, right?
Like one of these is not like the other, um,
but one cop wanted to hang on to them to just make sure everything.
So these, these guys had to spend, you know,
the night in the cells while all of this got sorted out.
But it just got me thinking, you know, like, I've seen multiple videos where
people, uh what do you call those
influencers? Right.
Those Instagram influencer people that, like, live stream their life or whatever.
So they're like holding their phone up and
like walking around life and talking and whatever.
And there's like several cases now where those people have gotten into a
car that they thought was like the Uber they ordered and it's not.
-- Right. Right. I've, I've heard of that.
-- Yes.
You know, and of course the person's kind of like,
like, get out of my car. Right.
And this is what I'm beginning to really appreciate the fact
that my car doors automatically lock when I start driving now.
Right. Right.
I mean, and I guess this would really apply, you know, anybody driving a Prius.
I guess this is a real problem for them. Right.
Because I think all Ubers by law in the States are like Priuses mostly.
I don't know. That's my impression
I've never seen, I've ridden in countless different kinds of Ubers.
Actually, I had a guy pick me up in a pickup truck once that
is wild. This,
this can't be economical in any way. Like the amount of gas this thing eats.
Well, I was just thinking that would actually be really handy because like,
you know, if you, if you're a millennial and you go to IKEA, yeah,
you need somebody with a pickup truck.
Uh, that's fair. Actually.
Uh, I don't think you can
order an Uber pickup.
You can order, what is it like? Uber? Uber XL and Uber, like fancy
-- Uber black.
-- Uber black. That's the one.
Yes.
But yeah.
So anyways, like, it's just, for example,
this just reminds me of this whole home thing.
Like you and I were kids of the eighties, stranger danger, you know,
don't get into a stranger's car.
Don't go into a stranger's house. Don't, you know, like
all these things now where the opposite of that is the basic business plan.
Like, yeah, go into a stranger's car
and have total strangers come into your car
and, and I've,
I've gotten into strangers cars and they offered me a
little basket of candy and I've eaten their candy.
Yeah. And water. Yeah. Or like a USB charge port for my phone.
-- Yeah,
-- I don't use those. But actually I have a, I have a hilarious story.
So, when, when my daughter was very young, this is many years in the past
we were going over, like, the dewey, good
strangers, cars. Do we like, do we go home with other people?
Like all this kind of stuff?
And at one point we're like, do you get in a stranger's car?
And she goes, no, we say what if he has candy and she goes, well,
what kind of candy is it?
No, the answer
is no,
the answer is not. What kind of candy is it?
But yeah. Anyway, anyway, I, I, that's, that's such a crazy story, man.
I,
I, I guess here's, here's my takeaway from this is
there have been
many situations
where I've seen something happening
or someone has asked me for assistance
and I've opted not to get involved. And this is why, because
there are depending. I mean, it's all very,
of course, but
generally speaking,
it is not uncommon at all to try to help someone
-- and end up in a world of hurt
-- or they grab your phone and run away. Oh,
thank goodness. That's never happened to me.
That's a,
apparently that's a very common way of
stealing cell phones in some places is literally
they ask you to like,
check something on your phone or like,
can you look this up for me or can I make a call and they like,
grab your phone and run and let's face it.
Most people don't do enough cardio that they could chase that person down
and assuming you do do enough cardio to chase the person down.
-- Then
-- what I, I wouldn't because look,
if someone's willing to steal your phone in that manner,
it is not unreasonable to assume they could potentially be armed or they're
just going to beat the crap out of you if you catch them
because like, I'm not even going to pretend like if I get in a fight I'm losing. Right.
I'm,
I am not the kind of person who's going to win a
-- fight and I have enough sense to just not get in
-- them.
Speaking of which II, I have the perfect, we'll, we'll post a
clip to the video of the, uh,
the guy that was setting vehicles on fire along
White Avenue got chased by two by four guy
and Hawaiian shirt guy
locally that happened a few weeks ago.
Yeah.
Like I, and that's something I kind of hate about the modern world is, yeah,
the modern world kind of sucks because nobody wants to help each other.
But I've literally had cases where, you know, I'm,
I'm carrying leftover pizza and somebody asked me, you know, hey, I want some, like,
money for food and I'm like, oh, well, like, I don't have that
or I don't want to give you money for food because I think you might be lying.
But, hey, here's like half a pizza and then they, like, launch into me
and start screaming at me and it's like
-- that worked out well.
-- Uh. Right.
I've, I've had that too where someone says, you know, I need money to buy food.
And I'm like, look, there's a mcdonald's across the street.
You tell me what you want. I will go get it for you.
And yeah, and then I, I got yelled at, it's like, yeah,
you're clearly not getting money for food,
you know, and I don't want to be a jerk. But yeah, at the same time, I also
locally, I mean, in an
extreme case, you know, Panhandler asked some guy for money. The guy said no. So the,
the panhandler stabbed him and it's like
that escalated quickly.
Yeah.
Right.
No, I know. It's,
this is one of the challenges I think of modern society.
Well, it's really been a challenge forever.
It's just obviously law of large numbers. So we just, and global news.
So you hear about it way more often. But
no, it's, it's one of the things I struggle with because I want to be a nice person,
but I also don't want to, you know,
bleed to death in an alley.
So it's, I don't know, it's a tough one man for sure.
And I guess this again kind of comes back to like, like,
what's your personal threat profile?
And for everyone it's very different and
I imagine mine is ratcheted up in weird ways compared to most people.
-- It's always something you got to
-- think about.
Like, not plugging your phone into anything weird.
Ever, like those little charge cabins at the airport or whatever,
just buy a battery.
There's such an easy solution for this. Buy a battery, put it in your backpack.
You never ever, ever have to plug your phone into anything weird ever again.
So,
so speaking of which uh threat profiles,
so Slack has actually publicly stated that they are probably,
I think this was in their, what filing was it?
The S one or something? Because they're going to IP O
they, they basically as one of their, you know,
in your s one you're supposed to list like all
the sort of reasonable existential threats to your company,
right?
You know, like, oh,
somebody invents a new technology that makes us obsolete or like dinosaurs.
And one of the threats they published was that, you know,
they're a target for Nation State
hackers.
And well, so for number one,
everybody's a potential potential target of Nation state hackers.
And number two,
Slack is actually a probable target of Nation State hackers
because I was thinking how many companies now use Slack
to coordinate incident response,
-- most of
-- them
or even more for their just day to day message backbone for all their
-- employees to talk to each other, like all of them, basically.
-- Absolutely.
Well, the even crazier thing about Slack is
I don't think you can get rid of messages.
I think once you have information in the slack,
I guess, universe for your organization, it's pretty much there forever.
-- And I don't think you can get rid
-- of it.
The one thing you can do now is they,
they have a thing where you can have your own private key to encrypt stuff.
-- Oh, my goodness. That is. Don't get me started.
-- I
know
it's a, it's a start, I wouldn't say it's a solution yet. Yeah.
So it got me thinking because we,
we've spent a lot of time talking about software supply chains and how like, oh,
you're pulling in 1000 dependencies or you're pulling in some random open
source project that was handed over to this guy who put,
what was it?
The malware that stole not Bitcoins but some other coin.
-- Oh, yeah. If you had a certain wallet running. Yeah,
-- exactly.
And I was thinking about operational supply chains. Right. So
people just kind of forget that for, you know, for example,
if somebody were to hack one of the big phone companies,
they would have access to a lot of interesting data,
ignoring the fact of actually listening to phone
calls just that to know who's calling,
who when uh could be very interesting
and obviously having access to Slack,
you'd have access to all the internal track of the traffic of that company.
And I'm wondering for example, other companies that discuss, you know,
mergers and acquisition on Slack.
I would be shocked if there aren't,
you know, I mean, we use Slack all the time and we talk about
material information being, you know, material information, like,
like things that could affect the stock price, for example,
constantly.
Well, Morgan
Point, what are you going to use to talk about that stuff?
That's not
telephone,
you know,
unless you go to some solution like signal or
whatsapp or you have end to end encryption.
Basically every email, the phone, Skype,
Google Hangouts, Slack all have this problem.
Um, you know,
it's just hopefully like Google is mature enough to have a
massive security effort to keep all those bad guys out.
Right. And I, I have a suspicion Slack
has. In fact, I know Slack has a fairly mature security team. I, I,
I've met some of them and they're good,
but I think listing Nation State activity is fair
because it doesn't matter how good you are,
they will get you.
And the reason being a Nation State
has essentially unlimited resources and unlimited time.
You don't.
And
the willingness to do things that rational and typical people,
even irrational people
either can't do or won't do like you know,
kidnapping and threatening their Children.
You know, no matter how bad you make your customers angry,
chances are they're not going to kidnap your Children and demand a refund.
-- I'm pretty sure that's not happened on a regular basis.
-- Nation states can do that.
Right. And, and some of them totally would, where they would,
they would go to great lengths to acquire your cooper.
Yeah.
So I, I,
I'm actually really glad that they said this because I think
this is a good sign of maturity to say that.
Yeah, we're,
we're aware of this problem
and a lot of companies I don't think, are aware of this problem or,
or they don't think, you know, the classic thing is, oh, why would anybody attack us?
Well, number one, they may not actually attack you.
It may be part of an automated attack like the, the,
the crypto malware stuff where it's like,
dude, we just let that stuff loose.
Like we just emailed it to 10 million email addresses and
like 1/10 of 1/10 of 1/10 of 1% clicked it.
And of those like 90% had antivirus that caught it and 10% didn't.
And so of that 10% now, you know, hopefully 1% pain.
We get like three bitcoins and that totally made it worth that email campaign
in the context of claiming nation state
activity.
That's not
like a random, let's just email a billion people. That's a very targeted event.
Right. Well, and that's what I'm saying is that, that
no longer applies like that, even that
random stuff quite often works. But, yeah, if you're targeted,
yeah, good luck.
Like,
you need to have a lot of resourcing and a lot of
discipline to build systems so that even if somebody is kidnapped or,
uh, compromised
or bribed
that
they still can't do the bad thing that the bad guy wants them to do. Right.
And I've been looking around and I haven't seen really any good
public resources for how you architect those systems.
You know, for example, like the two man rule, right?
Where you need two people to,
to actually do an activity versus just one person approving it.
Right.
-- Uh
-- Right.
And it, it, there are a few organizations that are probably ever going to do that.
And I think part of the challenge there is
how many, how do I say this?
It is often uneconomical to plan on that level and it is
actually more beneficial to acknowledge the risk and just take the hit
when it may, it may or may not happen.
And I, I don't know what Slack's plans are. In this case.
I, I can't say I have no insight into it, but it is, I mean, it's cool,
they list it as a risk, but at the same time
are how, how do you stop it?
And
I don't think you can to be honest.
Well, there's, there's some technical measures like, you know,
end to end encryption that would help and there would be other measures, like,
for example,
like code reviews just don't let people randomly
check code in and push it to production.
I would be shocked if they don't already have those sort of activities.
And that's the problem is a lot of the stuff is basic hygiene, but let's face it.
Not everybody has. Right.
And I, I'm assuming Slack does because their client doesn't completely
-- crash every other week. Uh
-- That's, I've never had their client crash on me actually.
-- Now that you say that, yeah, like,
-- yeah, it's reasonable quality.
So, but that goes back to that thing.
Like we know in the financial world we have certain
kind of guidelines and rules to help prevent financial
shenanigans like the two man rule or for example,
my favorite is you have to take two weeks off
so that if you have some sort of scam that requires constant feeding and watering,
like
backdating invoices or, you know, monkeying with floats
that
if you're away for two weeks and you can't keep the scam up, it,
it, it comes out, it becomes, you know,
-- it becomes obvious. Right.
-- Interesting.
-- I, I didn't know that.
-- Oh yeah.
No, there's a lot of scams that involve where you have to, you know,
for example,
you steal a bunch of money but then to cover up that the money is missing you know,
you keep
like the account has less money in it, but you keep enough in it.
So that actual transactions work
things like that where, you know,
it needs kind of constant care and watering or
you're shifting money from one account to another account.
So that, that account has the right amount of money when an auditor checks.
But, you know, a minute later it's like gone, things like that. Right.
So by making people take like a two week vacation,
you know, they, they, their scam hopefully falls apart a little bit.
Um, or,
you know, my favorite was they had a two man rule at this large bank,
but the copper trader and the person approving it or whatever were married.
Whoops. And that was, that was over a billion dollars.
Well, that's great.
Actually, here's a really important point is
you can put all the process you want in place
and
a motivated attacker can generally get around it.
And I think it's really important to always recognize that
the purpose behind most of these processes isn't
to stop a motivated and knowledgeable attacker.
It's really to make sure the normal people don't make dumb mistakes.
It's kind of like door locks aren't to keep up criminals.
They're to keep out opportunistic, honest people. Right.
That it's like, oh, I just lost my job and this door is open and look,
there's a pile of money on that table.
I, you know, I'm gonna I'm gonna take it versus the criminals.
Like, yeah, I got a freaking crow bar. Like, who cares if they lock the door?
I'm not even checking, you know,
and, and that's,
I think we lose sight of that a lot where I go
through this on a regular basis where I talk to someone about,
ok, we need to do X
and it, it's, it turns into, well,
we have to build a rocket ship to go to the moon to get some rocks.
It's like, no, we don't need those.
Just, no, we like it just needs a lock on the door like that's fine.
We don't need moon rocks coating the door to keep out, you know, ghosts or whatever.
And, and I think especially in security,
we are so notorious for trying to over engineer everything
and, and it's kind of like the thing I keep saying
it
and if you look at perfect and nothing, they're the same.
And this is why because if you try to build the perfect system,
you end up doing no actual work because you've just spent all of your time and effort
concocting
a ridiculous ru Goler
-- machine that has no possibility of ever working.
-- Yeah.
No, I,
I was thinking about how would you prove that somebody in that
space and location actually owns or controls that space and location.
And the answer is
without a lot of work on a case by case basis,
you really can't so you have to kind of take people
at their word and kind of hope for the best,
which isn't great.
But you know, what else are we going to do? Right.
Have a public registry or something.
I, I don't think
we can.
So I guess here's the way I would frame this and we'll kind of close on this note is,
it seems poetic. We take the story we started with and we end with it. But
it's,
if this becomes a big problem,
then you're going to see some sort of intervention from a regulating body.
And I don't know what that even means and I don't know how it would end.
But as long as these scammers keep it low key enough,
it's always just going to be a couple of people
getting screwed and it's going to be one of those.
I'm sorry, there's nothing we can do.
It's like anything in the world where people don't care
until someone gets killed and the river lights on fire.
And I mean,
it's, it's,
that's where we're at with this is until enough
people get scammed or the right person gets scammed.
Because if like some politician gets nailed by something like this,
then it becomes really important,
right?
And that's like I always say this to people
when we go out for drinks or something like,
oh, we got it.
You know, how are we going to fix privacy and all this and that I'm like, look,
if you want to fix privacy, you just got to, like
a
Senator's Facebook account and it's going to get fixed overnight like that.
That's how you see change here because let's face it. They, they really don't care.
And, and I think it's a similar situation here is
II, I have a suspicion.
We're never going to see it fixed because it's probably not
going to get big enough to necessitate any sort of intervention.
And I guess at the same time,
this is where
if, if you're a person
kind of being put into a situation similar to this is, you know,
be mindful of what's happening.
If they're asking for dodgy payment methods, be careful of that. If,
if something doesn't smell right, trust your gut and,
and most importantly is when possible, make sure you're,
you're paying people with vehicles that are very official and
there's like fraud protection and recovery protection in many instances.
Yeah. Like, as we discussed credit cards, like, uh,
I, I'm now
just after having dealt with this one furniture store,
I'm so glad I use my credit card and I was able
to painlessly get my money back because I never got my couch
and had I paid cash or with a debit card, I would have been,
I would have had to go to the company.
Yep. Yep.
Exactly. You know, they're not getting
my money back
-- so,
-- well, it's not even, it's, it's also common where
I forget I just, I had an incident the other day where
I, I had, I, I paid cash. It was like, it was some delivery.
It was a food delivery thing for an event where we ordered a bunch of food.
The guy showed up, I paid him in cash because usually cash is just easier.
And then I made the mistake of not having him sign my receipt.
And then basically, the company calls me up and this is,
it was literally three months later
and they said, oh, you didn't pay for this.
And I was like, I paid the delivery guy,
how did it take them three months for that to show up?
Like talk about we internal control.
I
have no idea how it took three months. But anyway, I talked to him for a few minutes.
I'm like, look, I paid this guy cash,
you know, I gave him a 10% tip. It's, I, I don't know what to tell you.
And they were actually really cool. They said, ok, fine.
I'll tell you what, you know, you've been good to us in the past.
We've never had a problem. I'm going to trust you here.
And of course, if it had, you know, if it happens again, they're going to be like,
yeah, you're, you're screwing us over, but it won't because from now on,
I'm going to have the delivery guy sign the receipt and, and you know,
specify I paid him.
Well, and it makes me laugh that somehow signing it would be this because,
you know, he could just sign with his left hand and be like, that's not my signature.
And this is honestly,
this is one of the reasons I love my ring doorbell because now I have for one year,
a little video clip of every single delivery to my house.
Yeah. And, and that's fair too.
I mean,
granted that that wouldn't have helped me because it wasn't in a
place that would be recorded even if I had a doorbell.
But
it's,
it's also,
I think the situation of even if the delivery
guy like tries to scam me out or something,
I think I have a stronger case talking to the company if I have a signed receipt
that has what resembles the name of the delivery guy because like, I don't know
his name was right.
I didn't ask him his name and in fact, I'll make him print it as well,
which I think would be beneficial, but whatever, it doesn't matter, it's,
well, you could just put John Smith
and then claim I never saw that or signed it. Right.
That's the thing you're forgetting, right?
He could just claim I have no idea what this is. This is not at all like my signature.
I'm willing to accept
that
the odds of that happened
are going to be drastically lower than what,
what was basically a bookkeeping mistake in this case, right?
Like a signature from the delivery guy will catch a bookkeeping mistake.
It will not stop a malicious delivery guy.
Well,
the most important thing is to remember is that this delivery
guy can only run this scam a handful of times.
Right. Yes, exactly. Hopefully before
somebody calls them out on it
because I, and I don't know what their non payment rates are and more to the point,
why did the delivery driver leave the food with you and leave without getting paid?
Right. Like that's the part of the story that makes no sense.
Well, no, no, that's normal. They, they, it's, it's
so it's this pizza place and they have like these big heated
containers and they drop you off the food in this heated container
and then you just pay them when they pick it up at the end. It's very normal.
Oh, ok. We do this all the time. Yeah.
Yeah, it's fine and,
and obviously I assume part of that story is
they want their containers back because they're very nice.
Ok. That makes sense.
-- Yeah. Yeah,
-- that it's fair. It's cool. Uh, anyway, anyway, any parting thoughts?
Well, just, you know, if it looks too good to be true, it probably is. And
I
mean, ii I don't want to say like, oh, you should, like,
learn all the common scams because
the majority of people aren't going to do that.
But at the same time
I do teach my kids to look both ways when we cross the road,
even when it's at a crosswalk or a red light because
-- not all, you know, not all, all the car drivers may not be paying attention
-- and, and
I will, I will add one more thing to this closing thought is
someday
you're gonna get scammed
and it doesn't mean you're dumb.
-- It doesn't mean you're bad and it doesn't mean you deserve.
-- I've been scammed.
I mean, I bought a couch and they never delivered the damn thing.
And then they were like, they just, they were like, oh, sorry, well,
we'll get it eventually,
you know, delivery dates five months from now and I'm like, cool. I'm gonna call my
credit card company.
Yep. Yep.
And, and it, it happens sometimes and it sucks and you're just gonna,
sometimes you gotta, you gotta live with it, right?
It's just the way it is. So. All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open search security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, easy po
Os podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Yeah, Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your
-- day. You too. Thanks
everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.