Hello and welcome to episode 64 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried
-- and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser
-- 64 is a great number
as, as a monkey with 10 fingers.
I love the number 64. More than 50 or 60
or 70 I guess. So. There we go.
I think my favorite large integer in that neighborhood is 60
because of the signs
they were, right.
Whatever. 64 is a special number for computers. So, it's awesome.
Yeah.
Anyway, actually it's, it's, it's funny,
I remember one time I was talking to somebody, this was,
this was years and years and years ago and
I don't know why we were talking about it but the powers of two
were, were part of the conversation and, like, I know many of them.
Right, just due to computer stuff.
And I, I used to know a lot more than I do now because I, I don't,
I don't deal with a lot of this stuff
and they were flabbergasted that a human being would know,
like two to the power of anything well into the many digits.
And it, yeah, it was it was fun.
I mean, well, but people memorize sports statistics and dresses. I mean,
I have to memorize my new postal code and I'm like, t
five.
Uh,
-- yeah.
-- Anyway,
you
know
that, that's right. But write that stuff down.
Right.
I just plug in my address to Google and it's like
this address, this post code and I'm like, oh, thank you, Google
-- it.
-- I
hope it's right
because my packages are going there,
someone's gonna get a surprise.
Oh man, I know, I know exactly what you mean. Actually, that's one thing I, I remember
when I moved,
I would always freak out that I was sending packages to the wrong address
and it was one of those things I would keep double checking the,
the emails just to make sure even though I checked them 10 times before
you got to love it.
Yeah.
All part of the fun man.
So I guess on a darker notes, uh do you want to say it or do I
say I am sick of
terrorists?
So
locally here in Edmonton,
like, seriously, I live in Edmonton.
Ok,
like you're going to have to Google it unless you're a
sports fan and know who the Edmonton Oilers are or,
or you host a podcast with a dude from Edmonton.
But seriously, so we had a terrorist attack on Saturday,
uh an immigrant, uh essentially, well hit a cop with his car,
then tried to stab him a bit, then ran away,
uh, and then the cops caught him at a checkpoint, he drove off, uh,
he gotten a U haul van somehow, probably, I guess, rented it as well.
And he basically tried to drive over a bunch of people, hurt four people.
Luckily nobody died.
Uh, and then they caught him and of course,
now he's been arrested and he's facing a whole pile of, you know,
terrorist related charges.
Um,
oh, yeah, he had a, an ISIS flake in his car. So they're pretty sure it was
that,
-- um, but that all pales in comparison to, I guess your country's news?
-- Oh,
man, this thing in Vegas.
Some, some crazy person, I think not calling them a terrorist is wrong
but they were in the Mandalay Bay and shot up a crowd of people,
which is, which is, I guess
the thing that freaks me out as well is Mandalay
Bay is where black hat is held every year.
And so, like I was there just a couple of months ago
and, yeah, it's crazy, man.
Yeah. No, it's, uh,
but we're not going to talk about the things because I think
quite frankly probably everybody else just like us has heard more than
-- enough about that. Thank
-- goodness. I know. I know, man. Everyone has an opinion
and there is, uh, anyway, let's, let's talk about security, right?
Yeah.
So one bit of good news, the fiber guys did their little,
uh,
you know, where they put that orange flexible pipe, I guess you call it.
It's like a garden hose basically, you know,
they shove it through the earth and then they'll blow the fiber through it later.
Conduit.
Is it Conduit?
Conduit?
Because Conduit can be flexible pipe is rigid.
I think I'm gonna Google that later.
I'm probably wrong.
Um, but yeah, so it was, it was, uh, quite nice because they're, uh,
doing up the whole neighborhood.
So about every third or fourth house is getting this, you know,
because you basically whoever signed up to, you know, get this
and um you know,
my kids were quite enchanted by the little ditch wich digger machine thing,
you know, that shoves the pipes into the ground.
They're awesome.
Oh, they are lovely because I was kind of wondering, I'm like quite honestly,
if you want to install fiber to my house, I you can dig a 50 ft wide trench.
I don't care.
I just want some of that sweet, sweet fiber.
Um But they dug like a little tiny hole at
the side of the house that they basically then,
you know, ran the conduit to.
And that's that.
Yeah, it's pretty cool the way it works, man.
And my assumption is it's even less about digging trenches
as
I bet when you dig a trench,
you have to be super careful because there's no doubt other utilities in the way
and so
marked all of them.
Yeah.
Um
but uh well, the biggest thing with trenching too is that you got to, like,
well, there's like trees and stuff in the
and rocks, you know, just stuff, yeah, sidewalks, whatever.
So, yeah, it was pretty cool because they basically, uh,
they've been working at it for probably about 23 months now and they started with,
you know, kind of pulling the main fibers in,
um, you know, kind of the backbone. Right.
And for example, there's like a large vault in the ground in my neighbor's yard.
It's about 2 ft by 3 ft, like it's pretty big.
Uh And there's about one of those, every
uh about every block or two, I guess, kind of scattered all over the place. And then
everybody like me kind of has like a little, sort of a little, I don't know,
like
plant pot sized thing in their front lawn, which is where the, you know,
the fiber goes from the little vault to that into
my house or towards the side of my house rather.
Um So yeah, so hopefully soon I'll have 1 50 100 and 50 megabit symmetrical.
Wow, nice man. You could do some pretty serious uploads then.
Well,
I'm actually ditching my file server because I'll be able to upload all my data,
like in a timely manner
you could
run
right now.
I think the fastest upload I can get is if I buy like business class service. So,
and it's like 25
Yeah. Right.
When you think about it, 100 and 50 megabits is, I mean,
I remember running a home network on 100 megabits.
Oh,
I remember 10 megabit, you know,
two
stupid B and C connectors and then you'd accidentally jiggle one loose.
And the thing,
that's
right, if the cap falls off nothing works.
Yeah,
exactly. You
chasing
the cable and,
like, undo every connector, redo it.
Yep. Yep. That stuff is terrible.
Or Token Ring, man. Do you ever use Token Ring before?
No, I couldn't afford that stuff.
I only had to use it. Actually, I never set up a token ring network
on purpose.
I was working in a company.
No, no, no.
So I was, it was my first job out of college and I'm
a, I'm an A IX
ed
to give me an idea of how progressive this company was.
And
so I'm, you know, doing S
Ain stuff
and one day they,
they come to me and said I need you to get the old Token Ring gear out of the closet and,
and set up a network.
I thought they were kidding. Right.
I thought this was like they were, oh, ha, new guy, you know. Right. Exactly.
They're like, no, you don't understand.
We have a meeting with a bank in London and they only have Token Ring.
So for the demo, we have to make everything work with Token Ring. And I was like,
you're kidding?
And yet. No, they were like, totally serious.
And we had to stand up the token ring network in
the server room so we can make sure that everything worked.
It was so crazy and it was so bad.
And I remember I,
I use this stuff and by after a day I thought
this is the worst thing anyone has ever created ever.
It was awful.
It was, it was a very,
what's the word I'm gonna,
I'm gonna use over
engineered
and it solved a lot of problems as it turns out didn't need solving.
That's networking by committee, right? Like that's exactly what Token Ring was.
It was you like a committee of people in a room and they come up
with Token Ring is the only inevitable solution they're going to come up with.
Yeah.
Well, I guess, you know, well, actually when you think about it,
it's the exact dynamic of a meeting, right?
Somebody has the speaking stick. Everybody else has to shut off
-- the table.
-- Not only that in,
in typical group fashion.
Token Ring doesn't have a failure state. Really? Right. Whereas like
Ether
is just,
you
know
what I mean?
Where Ethernet basically, it's like the drunkard on the corner screaming
and, and you know what I mean? Everything works,
but it only works because of, of madness.
Whereas Token Ring is very orderly, right?
It, it feels like something that would come out of a committee. Whereas
Ethernet feels like something like a drunk college kid thought up one night.
Well, the, uh, the, the Metcalf, was it Metcalf?
Anyways, the guy came up with it on the back of
a
good news for you.
There is only
one
token ring listing on ebay.com.
So it's almost dead for real.
That, that's actually very impressive. Yes.
Yeah, it's a print server, uh, for a Lexmark printer. Token ring.
That's it.
There's, but there's literally that one thing on ebay.com that and I mean,
let's face it.
That means the technology is dead.
Like, you know, if there's no secondary market for,
I agree with that.
So that's good.
I like it when things die sometimes. Uh technology wise.
Uh All right. Just, just because I could, I, I typed it in and my United States, ebay
has more than one.
I have 2000,
2910.
Did you
Lord? You're
Token Lord of the Rings.
Uh I, OK.
So like the fifth thing is a ring now that you say that,
but uh the vast majority of this, are you doing Token ring,
one word or token space ring?
Uh a bit of both.
I,
I did token space ring and there are some
rings now that you mentioned Lord of the Rings,
which
we'll say that counts.
-- So
-- anyway,
there is some stuff where it's, they kind of spelt it funky and it's
for
Token
ring.
I'm going to declare it undead, right?
OK.
It's still limping
along.
-- It's
-- still hanging in there.
Get your token ring. Now, folks, you're gonna, it's gonna be rough to get,
just don't lose the token
-- one.
-- Right.
That's what those rings are for. They're selling, it's fine.
Uh, so anyway, anyway,
anyway,
but, yeah, so, I mean, basically, and that's,
that's largely the premise of getting rid of my,
it here is that my internet connection at home
will actually be faster than, like, my home network was up until. Ok. Well,
I guess 1015 years ago now, 100 megabit. Right.
And
so
the biggest thing, yeah, is that, is that initial,
that upload of all my data can actually happen now and not take like three months.
Mine only took two months. So it's
cool. It's
-- fine
-- and more to the point.
I mean, 150 megabit bidirectional, that's fast enough to, you know,
even with somewhat, not great latency, it's going to be, you know,
2030 milliseconds to sort of the internet gateway of my ISP.
That's still very acceptable,
you know, especially for stuff that's just files,
you know. It's, uh, so, yeah, I'm basically, I'm currently in the process of, um,
dumping my file server onto a, a removable hard drive
and then I'm going to wipe both my file servers.
Uh, I've already wiped my firewall, my network switch and a bunch of other stuff.
Uh, I've also moved just a,
uh, I'm 100% wireless network now. There will be no wire.
-- Uh,
-- you could use that new DNS mask issue to wipe your, wipe your router
probably.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that was, yeah. Yeah.
I mean, that's, well, and that's actually,
that's one of the reasons I'm getting rid of all this gear is because
so
part of it is all my stuff's mobile and so
it doesn't spend all its time at home anymore.
So it's going to end up in a coffee shop or whatever.
So it has to be secured against the raw internet period.
And number two is, yeah, I mean,
if I have a bunch of network here that I forget to update or whatever,
-- I'm just
-- making none of this stuff ever gets an update.
It doesn't matter if you forget or not.
Right.
Oh,
it's one of the reasons I went with a PF
Sense based firewall is PF Sense is a full fat distro
that
gets updates.
That's
the downside being is that, you know, it's,
um,
-- it's one more system to administer
-- is that the Intel box you own that, you know,
is going to self destruct
the chip set that's going
to die.
So if anybody wants to buy it cheap,
it's good for apparently at least another, like,
I think it's good for at least 18 months before the chip set might cramp out.
So,
but yeah, to put it bluntly like,
uh you know, I'm also finding like that,
that I bought a rather high end wi fi router that
um
you know, it is pretty quick. Has the
memo, the, the multi,
what is it, multi
input, multi
output or something?
I have no
-- idea.
-- Whatever the magic that makes the internet faster.
I'm not, I'm not hip to all this new technology.
But yeah, so basically I've downsized my network.
It'll be the ISP gear one box each and then
a Wi Fi router and two raspberry pies.
That's really sweet man.
And more to the point, you know, II I was kind of doing back of the envelope
and,
you know, each of these systems does take 1020 hours a year to administer and manage
-- uh
-- maybe,
and I believe that
it adds up, you know,
three or four of those and that's like two or three working weeks.
-- So
-- I,
I have a funny technology story to tell you before we move on to like real security
is
I have a myth TV machine
in my house
and I've had it forever
and
the power supply was making a terrible noise.
And so I assumed it was probably going to die soon
or light on fire and neither of those would be optimal.
So I, I went and bought a new power supply
and it was strange because I went to Best Buy to buy
it because I wanted it like right now in my hands.
And they, they have,
I think they had six of them
and I, I was amazed. I figured they'd have one
and no, no, they, they had a bunch.
Anyway, I, I bought the power supply.
I take up the old one and it was, it was a 400 watt power supply.
And I thought it is a miracle.
This computer is even working with this power supply inside of it because
there's no way I'm not drawing more than 400 watts.
-- And so anyway, I
-- don't have a video card.
Well, the problem is I have two capture cards for,
for,
I have two hard diss in it because one of the, in their spinning diss
and then I, right, like, I'm pulling way more than 400 watts
in any way I put in the new stuff and turn it on and, like,
amazingly the computer is working much, much nicer than it has ever worked.
One reason I always over spec the power supplies
in all my systems is so that they wouldn't,
like the fans would be a little quieter
and hopefully they would last longer because it
was less stressful on the power supply.
Right. Right. And, and that's my assumption.
I, I didn't think the power supply could really have,
have a effect on a system like this.
But yeah, it's like everything is working really well.
-- It must have just
-- been power supplies, commit murder suicide.
Well, all I can figure is it was barely hanging on.
So it had just enough power to mostly work correctly
and now that I've actually given it the proper amount,
everything is happy.
So yeah,
-- it's crazy man because
-- I know I bought one high
end ASIS motherboard and it actually had like built in
voltage monitoring and protection and
it like would war like the one the power supply it was on was dying and it,
it warned me that like it basically said like the power supply is trying to kill me.
Please do something about this.
Um So I, I swapped that out and yeah, I was much happier. But
uh well, yeah, when you, when you think about these things, I mean, again,
these are like
amazing,
you know, these power supplies are like 50 bucks.
They run nonstop for a couple of years
providing pretty clean
power plus or minus, you know.
Ok, there's a lesson here, there's a lesson I'm gonna,
I'm gonna turn on the security knob.
Here is
this is human nature, right? Is we want to buy something and use it forever
and like in the case of a power supply, whatever, there's to my knowledge,
there's no security updates for power supply.
I'm I'm sure there is one, I'm sure one exists and someone will tell me about it and,
and I look forward to it,
but the point being
humans love to turn something on and let it run
and
in the world of internet insecurity,
you cannot do that because as soon as you turn something on,
you've created a risk
and
the longer you let it run,
the greater the risk becomes until it inevitably reaches 100%.
Right.
Yeah. No, I'm just trying to remember there was that one sun
server where the power splice had and I quote, unanticipated thermal events.
I
wonder how many lawyers it took to come up with that
and, but, yeah. No,
I
mean,
and it kind of goes to that whole,
um,
I don't know if you saw that iphone thing where they basically had like a,
they made a malicious iphone screen that was able to, you know,
basically could hijack the phone
electronically.
Right. And, well, when you think about it, right, these components, it's not like
most computer systems don't have, like,
security between the CPU and the motherboard.
Like, if you put in like a malicious
motherboard, like the CPU is not
gonna somehow protect itself from that. Right.
Or, or a great example being like, you know,
network cards with direct memory access.
Right. Right. Well,
that's getting better. I mean, there, there's things like Intel is SGX now and arm
the enclave and,
-- well, and
-- that's,
we're getting there.
Yeah.
But when you think about something like, uh, when you have a subsystem in your phone,
but
the thing to remember too is we, especially as old timers,
we think of a computer as having AC pu,
right. And that's really wrong nowadays
-- because
-- the battery has AC P
my mouse. Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
My laptop battery probably has more CPU power now than, like my first laptop.
I, I have no doubt,
you know.
Um, and so every single subsystem component has something that
kind of looks a lot like a general purpose computer because let's face it,
it's a lot cheaper to make some silicon like that than
it is to make like a really purpose built chip.
Well,
and did you ever see the instructions that
the NSA gave Glenn Greenwald for destroying his gear
where they, they have things like drill here, you know,
knock the break this with a hammer hit this
here and they were obviously targeting specific chips.
And the intention must have been that these chips either
could store data
-- or some sort of process
-- network card now have how much memory and compute power?
-- Oh man,
-- I know
crazy
-- video card are flat out.
-- Video cards are computers. My video card has two gigs of ra M
I mean, what, when did that happen?
Uh Yeah, and you know, same thing with hard drives, right?
You have hard drives, you can change the firmware on them to, you know, uh sniff data,
report it back, whatever.
Right. So,
yeah, anyways, but
I, I have no doubt that, you know, the same thing, um,
could happen to a lesser degree with power supplies.
Um, although I did have one power supply that plugged into,
I think it plugged into the USB or something to report its condition.
I seem to remember that maybe I'm wrong.
Um, but like,
I know I had another Asus motherboard that actually had like
a firewall built into the motherboard that you could interact with.
So, it was like on the chip set on the network chip set, which was kind of neat.
But at the same time, like, uh, how do I trust this?
You don't,
-- you can't.
-- Well, it's not that I don't trust
them because they're malicious. I don't trust them because they're like,
they write bad software like everybody else
like the DNS mask thing, right? Google took a poke at DNS mask
and they found a couple of
-- flaws
-- tell this story because this one
actually has some interesting undertones to it.
Well, I mean, simply put Google.
Uh Well, there's a couple of organizations now, like Google is one of them
that are kind of looking at that. Really?
There's a lot of computer code, uh
especially in the open source world
that is
really security critical in the sense of like a lot of stuff runs it.
And this stuff typically listens to the network and can be talked to by an attacker.
So
samples include
web servers, you know, SSL, like open SSL
and then like, yeah, all this like DNS and sort of network set up bits
-- and,
-- and what is DNS mask?
OK? It's DNS MA SQ. Right.
And that, for those of you who may not know, DNS, MA SQ, not MA SQ.
-- DNS
-- Mass. So it's basically, uh well, it's
called the web page.
Uh DNS Mass provides network infrastructure for small networks.
DNS DH P rotor advertisement and network booth. So to put it bluntly,
it's doing everything
-- uh needed to stand up a computer,
-- to stand up a network, right? This is
to stand up a computer first, but also a network, right?
So it can do network boot, it can discover, you know what I need to, you know,
where do I get my information? Where do I get my boot image, blah, blah, blah.
And yeah, and then stand up the network
and get your local area network running basically.
So basically every router on the planet.
Yeah. Well, I should say every home
router.
-- Right.
-- Right. Right.
And
like my home network is
pretty much existing right now because of DNS mask running on my router.
And I, I know that in fact, it's quite nice because I can,
there's a box in my configuration that I can give it extra options if I want to,
which I don't anymore.
But I used to because I thought it was cool.
And,
and that's actually one of the exact reasons I'm getting rid
of all this network here on my end with the exception of
my ISP routers, which I, I have to have
because,
you know, they're running the NS mask, of
course,
they all are.
So, anyway, that, that's irrelevant though. OK, we know what it is
and now
Google found some crazy issues with it, but here's the kicker I think
is
they released proof of concept exploits for all this stuff after a
very short window of kind of reporting and fixing the issues,
they provided pretty good patches.
That's what I've heard. But, but at the same time they were
patches.
I, I feel like
they did it the way it needs to be done.
I, I think even a year ago, I might have disagreed with them doing it this way.
But I feel like now
we've reached a point and we've seen things that
everybody figures this stuff out about the same time.
And so if Google figured it out, it means someone else did too.
And, and this actually this hit home with me
about two weeks ago
is
with, with, this is dealing with, with some work things.
We had a, someone internally found a security bug
and then a customer reported the same bug,
not a week later
and then a security person that was doing some research for us reports, the same bug
and today it got, got reported again and I'm thinking holy crap and we, it's,
it's fixed now,
-- but like this is crazy,
-- right? Part of it, I think my theory there is,
is the, the ecosystem is maturing and as people kind of get the skills and the,
the looking for things, I mean,
remember when cross site scripting first came out and everybody's like,
whoa knew what,
you know, or, or all sorts of shenanigans like, you know,
return oriented programming,
which is this like clever way of manipulating programs
to, you know,
when you have arbitrary code execution but
have to like work within certain constraints.
And
R
is the big one now. Well, I mean, I double free is my favorite example ever is
I remember for a long time you'd see a double free issue and we'd say, 00, well,
double free.
Nobody cares.
And then solar designer figured out how to exploit it.
And now all of a sudden they were thinking uh we
didn't fix a bunch of these because we
didn't think it mattered.
Segmentation flaws.
I think it segmentation flaws,
-- faults. I think wells
-- are
caused by a variety of things. You think you can stack buffer overflows by chance
-- or
-- no? No, I'm thinking,
yeah. No ses
and the Linux kernel we used to be like, yeah, whatever. That's not good.
Oh, you mean kernel panics? Probably.
But
more to the
point now, we basically treat them all as code execution because they probably are.
-- Yes,
-- exactly. If someone has enough time and intelligence, they can certainly turn
kernel panics into
an exploitable flaw because generally a kernel panic
is caused because something brought something somewhere it shouldn't
in memory.
And I
part of the problem with the DNS mask is it's not that they found one flaw
they found, well, seven flaws. Uh, what was it? Uh, three of them in DH CP,
uh, and four of them in DNS.
Three R ce s. Right.
Yeah. Well, and the problem is they can also be like
they can be used to help each other. Right.
So there's one flaw here in an information leak that can help you then bypass,
you know, address stack.
That's
funny too because info
leaks. I remember we didn't care about them
but now that a SLR is a thing,
info leaks are potentially more valuable than some remote code execution flaws.
Yeah.
So I mean that's, you know, that's the thing is,
you know, if you found just one of these flaws, it would be like, yeah, OK, whatever,
it's bad, we should fix it.
But you know, when you find seven flaws that
are interrelated and can be used to help each other to get
essentially to go from zero to full remote code execution,
that's a problem.
And I mean,
Google also uh I don't know if you read
the fine print but they talked about how they also
um
release some patches to help make it uh sandbox a bit better with the
the
stuff. Yeah,
it would be, I forget, I forget the particular set
rule. But yes,
you're gonna, they're gonna use Setcom
and, and let's face it man.
It doesn't mean Google could spend a million hours fuzzing
this thing to death and I could come around tomorrow
and, and find something they missed.
And so sandbox is the key.
Yeah, I was having a conversation with somebody and I basically said, you know,
if I fixed a million remote code execution flaws in the Linux kernel,
would you bet your life that there's no more?
What about a billion or a trillion? No,
exactly. Not just that
there, how many, how many commits get added per day to the Linux kernel
and, and some percentage of those are security flaws, right?
Yep.
And, and
I
guarantee you that if we had a graph,
the number of security issues going into the Linux
kernel versus number of security issues getting fixed,
they are,
they don't line up very well.
But um
no, it's, I mean, it's
DNS mask is especially problematic because it's one
of those things kind of like um well,
busy box is another good example.
Uh Well, maybe not so much now because you know, ra M is cheap but
um
DNS mask is, yeah, it's widely used on like everything,
especially a big pile of stuff that will never get updates.
-- That's it.
-- It'll never get an update.
And
man, this is like, welcome to the future. I guess
this is just the way everything is going to be. I fear.
Well, like I said, the, the,
the two ways to deal with this are either you buy expensive gear
that is either supported like say apple or has a subscription model,
meaning it's supported
or,
uh, you get rid of it if possible, I guess. II, I don't know.
Like that's, I'll be honest.
Like that's why I have barely any iot stuff in my house because
it could be the most awesome IOT device ever.
But three or four years from now, I can guarantee you,
I'm not gonna get any software updates.
Yes,
I, I think you're half right.
I, I think
there, there is certain gear you can buy that's better than others.
But I think for the most part, a lot of it is terrible.
What do I find
out though?
Because by definition,
the problem doesn't manifest until two years from now when the manufacturers,
like, oh, yeah, we're not making a lot of money off this thing.
Let's stop shipping updates. Right.
Right. Right.
And it, it, it's even more than that though is,
I guarantee there are devices in existence
that were created and contain DNS mask and nobody knows it's there.
Well, there was that article recently about Equifax and their, um,
that they straight up could not patch
all their strut stuff.
That's what I heard. And II, I believe that
I'm familiar with legacy systems. I know how this stuff works.
I'm not saying it's right
-- that I'm familiar with it.
-- Well, it's how the world is.
It's, it's tough, you know,
if you have to make a decision between kind
of shutting down the business and running vulnerable software.
Yeah. Guess what's going to win.
You know, the security guy is not going to shut down the business
and that's the scene, that's what really tears me about.
The whole infrastructure thing is,
you know, I don't,
I don't really want my power company to take down everything weekly for patches,
but, you know, I also don't want some,
like Russian cyberattack taking down my power grid.
So, you know, what do we do?
We? Yeah, I mean, that's, that's actually a really good example.
And that's a great thought experiment because
power is something that's critical for, for nearly everybody and, and
I can survive without electricity for a while, but I, I lost power for,
I think eight hours.
Um I don't know, this was,
I don't remember, it was sometime in the spring
and it, it sucked.
-- I'm not even going to pretend that I did
-- not
like if you or your local area loses power. That's one thing.
But like if your entire country loses power like Puerto Rico
-- and that
-- you have this incredibly devastating for its own reasons.
But, but no, no, let's not
restarting everything, right? Like I know for a fact
because I've worked with people and they're like, well,
this is a cold start plant which literally means you can turn everything off,
unplug it from the grid and start it.
And there's a lot of plants that are not cold stars.
A lot of
-- nuclear reactors are not cold star,
-- no,
a
lot of nuclear reactors. If you shut them down, you will never turn them back on ever.
Like they, they just, things will break and it will be unfixable.
In fact, I, when I was in college I worked in a paper mill in the summers
and I remember
we, we had to shut the mill down because in the summer the,
the mill pays less money for electricity.
And if demand goes too high, they tell the mill, you know,
you have to shut down in an hour.
And that was nontrivial,
but more importantly is it took 24 hours to turn it back on
once it was time to do that. And that's crazy.
I mean, yeah, it's not like my home computer where, oh, the power is back.
Let's go turn everything back on.
It's crazy. But anyway, anyway, so let's think about this though.
Let's say the power company has to take gear
offline every day to do a security update.
Can you imagine what people would do?
You? It'd be like living in India
in a tier two city
straight up.
And that's part of it. If, if these problems happen often enough,
then people get used to them and deal with them.
But it's, it's when the problem happens infrequently
that we don't really deal with it all that. Well, so hurricanes are a great example.
Right? They, they happen,
you know, frequently enough to be a problem.
-- But like, typically a place only gets clobbered every five or 10 or 20 years.
-- Ok.
No, no, you,
you might be on to something here though is because if we look at breaches,
breaches have historically been, we'll say relatively rare events.
But I think we're reaching a point now where this is just normal.
I mean, everyone is getting hacked all the time.
If you do, you read Brian Krebs website at all.
The thing is just horrifying.
I mean, I, I get in my RSS feed and every time it pops up, I just think, oh, what now?
And, and yeah, like every time
it's some new company got hacked
and it's just like it's never going to end. Everything being hacked is normal now.
Right?
And so this is where, what you just said is, is borderline terrifying to me is
we, we're, we're going to learn to adapt to this
and it's just going to be the way it is.
Let's face it.
Everybody's personal information
has been or shortly will be compromised.
It's all been
after
Equifax. It's all compromised.
Uh You know, it's like the um
oh, it's happened so long ago, like last year,
but I can't remember the name, the, the big government hack where they put like,
-- what was it, a Chinese subcontractor in charge of the
-- database, the
breach,
the OPM breach,
that was the office of personnel management where it was like, that was
really sensitive information. Like it's not just personal information
but like all the stuff around your security clearance.
So like interviews about your finances, your like sex life, your friends,
your family, like
lots of juicy stuff for black males.
And yeah, go ahead. The whole thing. Whoops.
And you know, and uh, well, a perfect example of this is, I mean,
that's how I'm architecting my home network.
I'm architecting my home network now with the
idea that everything here will get owned.
So I'm getting rid of everything I can
and
you know, all my end user devices, ipads, laptops,
whatever are gonna be basically
run as if they were straight up on the internet.
Yeah, I mean, I, you know, you're not wrong
-- and
-- same thing with the distributed weakness filing, you know, I, I've
uh the new CV E form to make it really clear
to people that this is not meant for embargoed CV.
You know, it's like this will go to this spreadsheet and this spreadsheet is public.
You
know,
anybody can comment on it. I mean,
well, we had this discussion actually today on the CV automation board where
uh where
the G pilot project has been successful. And so now
we're going to um
proposed to the board. Uh and I can't imagine why it would be rejected,
but we're gonna move from like Miter's G
server to github,
-- which I can't wait for. It's gonna make my life so much easier,
-- everybody's life.
Uh But anyways.
And, you know, because historically, one of the things that's happened is some CV,
numbering authorities will occasionally, uh upload stuff and be like, oops,
we didn't mean to do that.
Uh It's too early, it shouldn't be public yet.
And, you know,
Miter has a sort of a quasi manual publishing cycle so they can catch it, you know,
given a little bit of warning.
Cool. Um, but obviously with automation
that, that goes away, right?
Like when you get push and that gets accepted by the C I system and published,
you know, 17.3 seconds later.
Uh Yeah, too bad.
-- But, but, you know, that's not an excuse, man, I mean, oh, no,
-- no, exactly.
And, and the general consensus was like, you know, well, first of all, you're,
you're publishing to a github.com A URL.
So like
you, you kind of should have the expectation, this is public,
you know,
um
and that more to the point, you know, these companies just have to
grow up and deal with this. Uh DNS Mass is a great example.
We actually almost had a leak.
Um One vendor leaked the CV numbers and titles accidentally.
Uh It didn't and it got shut down uh fast enough that it wasn't in Google or anything.
Um But it was noticed because some of these vendors monitor each other for, you know,
CV, mentions and stuff because, you know, we all kind of run the same software
and you know, so leaks do happen.
Uh Typically in the open source world, I would say ballpark about maybe twice a year.
Uh We have an embargoed issue where there's like a, usually a,
like a sort of a small leak that's not very bad or public enough to be public.
Um Like, for example, one leak was to a
private mailing list that was not publicly archived
anywhere and it was trusted people anyway.
But the fear was, you know, we don't, once you send out an email,
who knows where it went?
Nobody.
Um
But yeah, and that's part of this is that, you know, especially with the miter,
the true CV database is like, yeah, once you,
once you put something in there, like you, you, I mean,
it's supposed to be a public database that's kind of the whole point.
Well,
and so here's the thing I think about a lot too is I've
been thinking about this a lot lately for a variety of reasons,
but
everything is full of open source.
It's, it's literally everywhere.
And so I think that the days of pretending you can hide
is now on the open source foundation. Is that the name of it?
-- Yeah,
-- they're one of the largest contributors to open source.
They might even be the largest now,
I mean,
which is, which
my brain explodes because so actually I'm, I'm giving an IRC chat with uh
uh the D GP L
tomorrow. I think it is which whatever day this comes out it'll be in the past. But,
but the point is,
uh and this is one of the things I, I was, I was just, you know,
writing some historical notes as part of my intro and, and I,
I got to some Microsoft things and I thought,
I remember
when these guys were like the worst enemy ever
and not just that they were actively hostile,
the Halloween memos just Google the Halloween
memo,
Microsoft
-- and
-- now they're, they're super friendly to open source.
And
Microsoft has joined the open source initiative as a premium sponsor
-- that was six days ago, like
-- good for them.
-- And the world has changed open
-- source,
open source. Totally one, which is awesome.
It's,
yeah, I love it there. It, it's so crazy and, and, but anyway, the point is though
that now that everyone's involved and, and it's spread far and wide.
I,
I don't think you can make arguments like I remember
the good old days when we could embargo issues for months
with, with the Linux distribution,
we would embargo everything like it didn't matter how big or small it was.
We embargoed it because we could,
and part
-- of it was, we also didn't have nearly as many issues to deal with.
-- It was less issues.
There was much less usage.
So you just weren't the target you are today and
it was like four groups having to work together,
right?
It's nothing like today
where the concept of embargo anything I think is, is looney.
And the right answer is you just have to be able to move quickly
because that's the
only
-- to be
-- fair. There are sometimes when we really do need embargo.
A great one being the call stack
stuff back in May and June.
And, and that was a really important embargo because quite frankly,
the scope of the problem wasn't understood.
And as it turns out like, oh, we'll just
increase the stack card pages, you know, it turns out no,
that absolutely will not work like it will be trivial to bypass
and it required changes to the kernel to G lipsy and to GCC.
And I mean, we're talking changes to the memory management in
Gypsy,
which is like that is some scary, scary stuff to be touching because if you muck it up,
you just broke the world.
So here's, here's what I wonder about that though is
stack
guard for as bad as it supposedly was.
Has anything come of it? I haven't seen any security.
-- Everybody patched it real fast. Uh And
-- is that why? No, I don't believe you because
uh dirty cow
is being exploited on android devices. I just saw a new story the other day where
-- there's all these old unpatched
-- device
is
not
-- easy to exploit it.
-- It
isn't. And, and right, and so I get that,
but anyway, it makes me wonder that
there.
I'm not going to say we shouldn't have embargoes, but I feel like we're still
too far over the line.
Well, I would say stack
art is a good example of one of the few times,
probably about 10 times a year that we should embargo stuff.
And, and the thing to remember too is that embargo was like, 4.5 weeks long.
Like, it was not a
long embargo by
contemporary standards.
That's the thing to remember too is like, now when we talk about a long embargo,
we're talking like three or four weeks,
you know, it's a more sort of like the standard quick embargo being like 1 to 2 weeks.
Uh The other thing to remember too is it's,
uh especially with holidays.
It's, I, I, you know, especially certain times of year,
like around Christmas and certain bits of summer, especially in the US.
Like, well, right now China has their national,
uh
they have their,
what is it National Day of something which actually as it turns out is a week off.
You know, so,
you know,
uh like right now it is kind of not like this is
not a great week for DNS mask because everybody in China is
doing whatever they do during the holidays in China,
right? Um
You know,
and, and so that's, I mean, so the one in two week embargoes do make a bit of sense,
especially when you have like a long weekend involved or
Christmas and New Year's, you know, that kind of stuff. Um,
plus just giving people a little bit of time to deal
with it and sort of in a calm manner versus,
like,
you know,
I have the register online one and the, you know, the Wall Street Journal online too,
asking for comment.
Right. Right.
Um, you know, because when people are time constrained and panicking,
they tend to make mistakes and,
you know, that totally, if we'd had to compress the stack,
gu
embargo there not mistakes would have been made, but we would have
not had the time to, you know, find the things that we found and do it properly
all at once rather than. Well, a great example being shell shocked where that's
exactly
dribbled out and we ended up with like, I think a total of,
-- I want to say four CV
-- S it was really bad
-- and
-- yeah, it was just this kind of constant. Like, wait, we didn't, we just fix that.
No, we fixed it. OK. I know we fixed this twice.
Why are you talking to me about it again?
We just fixed it twice.
Oh, there's a third one.
-- You know, and it just got very messy and
-- that was a monkey show. I remember that.
Yes.
Oh, man, I'm, I'm glad that one's gone.
So I would say like, like I said, a few times a year, we have very
difficult problems and,
and typically it's like either a code
that's really old and really ubiquitous like bash
or it's the kernel and that's not to pick on the kernel.
But the kernel is just a very complicated piece of software.
And it's again, very ubiquitous because it's the kernel
and DNA mask is a great example of like, well,
we found some really bad flaws but the patches are very straightforward.
Right.
Right. Right. Generally speaking. Right. This is not rocket science. This is not,
oh let's change how memory allocation works on all the systems.
Well, it's going to be rocket science for some people because
there's a lot of devices that will never see these updates.
And I bet there are developers working on some of these devices that,
that legitimately don't know what to do
because they've never had to go through this.
It's not that they don't know what to do.
What they need to do is simple, rebate to the current version
-- and then run your QE Suite and make sure your
-- software
works.
If that's possible, that would be optimal. Yes.
And,
but the problem is that's probably not possible because why would you spend money on
that when you can also have that developer writing new software for a new device?
Maybe, I mean, maybe it's,
yeah, this is, this is tough stuff, man. I don't think there's good answers.
It's fundamentally the economics, right? Like
uh all in theory, all software should be able to, you know,
have whatever it depends on be updated
which will definitely break things because behaviors change or, you know,
assumptions change or, or we fix.
Uh, I mean, how many,
there's been a number of security flaws that have been fixed that changed, you know,
-- default behavior
-- or
sometimes,
and, you know,
um,
the problem though is a lot of people don't have the source code for their software.
They bought a commercial off the shelf application from a company that may
or may not support it or may or may not even exist anymore.
Yeah.
Um,
and you know that again, going back, that's why I won't buy IOT stuff for my house is I,
you know,
if I could somehow legally be guaranteed like three years of support and updates.
Sure.
You know, that's like with the iphone, a great example is generally speaking,
I'll get for sure.
Three years, I've now got some ipads that are old enough that they will not get ios
-- 11,
-- whatever, man.
You said you just re architected your whole network for beyond Corp.
You shouldn't care if you put malicious IOT devices on your network now. Right.
Well, but those malicious IOT devices, for example, are cameras in my house.
Well, don't run cameras. I mean, that's just foolish. Right.
But I'm saying, you know, you can have
a
lock me
out because they stopped working.
Right.
Right. Wasn't it?
I just,
I read an article the other day that it was it a light bulb that when you disabled Wi Fi,
it didn't actually disable anything.
Kept talking.
I'm not at all.
-- I know I'm just flat out. Not surprising.
-- It's a comedy of errors. And so,
and I guess here's the thing I always think of and this is,
we'll kind of head it, we'll take it home on this message.
But this is, this is crazy talk is,
I feel like we're never going to fix the software,
right? It's never going to happen. Even if the government says you have to,
you have to make it up update.
Well, it, it, it's partially a technical problem. I think
the technical problem is the symptom of the underlying economic problem.
It's not just an economic problem though. I'm saying that the point is
how do we build a device that let's say there is a, a broken DNS mask library on it
and, and how do we do things in such a way that nobody cares? And it doesn't matter,
right? I think
uh well, a big part of that is sand boxing
to
minimize.
Maybe.
And,
and the reason I say maybe is I feel like sandboxes
are the best idea we had using the tools we have.
And I feel like we're, we're cave people banging rocks together.
And someone realized, you know, if you, if you tie a rock to a stick,
you can bang harder.
And in reality, it's like still a rock dude. It's just
my my truly ugly, honest answer.
I think the future is kind of because this has come up on the CV board with, you know,
CV S for software.
What about CV S for services?
I think the truly ugly answer is companies will not so much
sell you a device as sell you a thing that does something
and it does that thing, but like you basically don't touch it,
it automatically updates the company configures it, whatever
and those things already exist.
And essentially you have a contract with them that says
this thing will do this function for five years.
You will pay X
and,
you know,
they're basically responsible for making sure it functions
-- and that it's reasonably secure and
-- that's it.
You know, I'm gonna buy light bulbs
with that
light bulbs cost a dollar.
Right?
Or they
don't.
And that's part of the problem. Right? Is exactly.
People won't want to buy that at the low end.
Um,
when can I buy my Apple light bulbs? Right. They'll cost $1000 and, and
have a funny plug that I have to buy a special lamp from Appleton.
Yeah.
So I think the next best thing is you just buy cheap crap.
That was the
thing
that
cheap crap is winning today. And,
and
it might be the way it is.
We might have a world like a dystopian universe filled with just cheap garbage that
everything is part of a botnet and everything
is attacking everything else and it just,
it sounds like a Neil Stevenson novel.
But
that might be the way it is. I don't get me wrong.
Like, the, the optimist in me hopes it doesn't.
But the realist says
that's what it's looking like today. If, if, if I was a betting man,
that's where I'd probably put
my
money.
Uh, what's this guy's name?
I forget this guy's name, but he's a machinist has a youtube channel,
you know, and he's constantly, like, dissing cheap tools and cheap parts.
But the reality is, you know, like he says,
like these things win because they're really cheap.
Like
he did a review of this, like, really crappy digital caliper.
But it cost $10.
Actually, he was like, I'm going to keep coming back to that point.
I was, I complain about this,
but it cost $10.
No, I know exactly what you mean. I, I buy a lot of tools, a lot of tools.
Every time I do a project of nearly any sort.
I, it's an excuse to buy a new tool.
And I've reached a point where I'm buying very silly tools now that like,
no human needs.
But that's cool because that's fun stuff.
And there is a place in the US called Harbor Freight
that sells,
I will never go there. I went there one time
and I bought saw blades for a hacksaw
and I bought this box of probably 50 saw blades and I can literally,
I can use the blade one time and I have to throw it away because it's completely
in
the show
notes to this guy because he's, he's awesome and he uses old timey swear language.
-- It's the
-- best,
darn
the best
this guy. Arduino Vers versus evil.
I, I'm interested now, now I have to go watch this. That's, that's exciting.
It's, uh, it's, it's quite lovely.
Um,
yeah. No, I agree. And I, I don't know what the future will bring.
I, I could because for example, cars, cars were terrible, terrible death traps.
And now quite honestly,
like they're pretty good at not killing you if you crash them.
Yes.
And actually I, I submitted to talk to Rs A about this and if they don't accept it,
I might just kind of put together a series of blog posts where I did some research on
various industries
uh specifically around safety
where like mining and automobiles and, and
environmental and
like industrial things and all this. And
it,
so here's the thing
is these industries
basically got to the point where a river literally lit on fire,
which is about the worst thing you can imagine before people cared.
And
if the if the world of iot and computers, like if, if a river never lights on fire,
it never gets better.
Just period. Right? That is the story.
-- That's crazy to think
-- the beauty there is not only did the river catch fire.
-- But it was the railroad company complaining
-- there
were like 10 rivers caught on fire.
All right.
Pick one.
But the point is
the river catching on fire means something has gone so horribly wrong
that it, it basically can't go any more wrong than it's gone. Right
and
say
that. But,
ok, it's reached the point.
People have to pay attention because now all of a sudden, like,
-- look ma the rivers on fire and they think,
-- well,
I think that might actually help with the information security
now, like,
like an information breach of personal information.
It's kind of abstract and the majority of people honestly,
even if they're affected,
they're not really affected.
I mean, it's not until somebody uses that information to like their
life.
I hate to say this,
but I think we need like more than 100 people to
-- die as a result of a cyber attack before anyone
-- will.
Or we need like all the light bulbs in New York City to turn off at the same time
or like, start blinking out Morris.
That would be really cool just for a different reason. But yes. Yes,
exactly. And you know, even then I bet, even if a bad guy
literally took over every light bulb in the city and made them blink,
I bet that wouldn't be enough.
Probably not.
And I, I can think of nothing better to end the podcast on
that happy thought.
Uh So what do you think Kurt, is it ever gonna get better?
Um,
I don't think it necessarily will get better, but I think it might get less worse.
That's perfect.
That's
worse.
Is ok. I can live with less worse.
I, I love it.
All right. Thank you everyone for listening to the Lessor
open source security
pod
CS.
If, if you want links to any of the crazy things you talked about,
you can hit the show notes on open
source security podcast.com. We have links to the Facebook group.
There's Twitter, you can hit us up on there and let us know what you think.
And yeah, if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic
rest of your day.
You folks and stay safe. All right. Yep. Yep. Stay safe everyone. Bye bye.