Hello and welcome to episode Thursday of
the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime Josh Pressers.
I mean, that's one way to do it.
So dear listener,
we are going to stop saying the episode number
during Kurt's intro because I've been publishing some things
out of order and it's an enormous pain in my butt to open up a bunch of audio files
out the correct episode number, paste it in,
make the audio sound correct because obviously you can
imagine when you record on different days you get different
quality and I'm tired of it and I give up so no more episode numbers in the intro.
Maybe we should just have like,
oh,
what's that like? Text to speech service that Amazon has.
Maybe we should just use that.
No, I'm not doing that.
Those sound terrible. Everyone.
So
no more,
no more episode numbers.
Which is unfortunate because we won't talk about prime numbers,
but we could just talk about a number if we saw Desire.
Thursday is a prime I believe.
Is it why not?
It's a better off ted reference that I tickled.
I've
never
seen that also. I just googled Ted
Space F
Thursday and
the results
are odd. I, I just, to our listeners, you should definitely Google Ted Space Furs.
A Flursdayii. I, yeah,
I'm gonna, I'm going to do this. Like, it's just all over the place.
The first thing I get is a florist.
I'm getting parliamentary debate results followed by
some gardening related content,
followed by some newspapers from the 19 seventies.
I have no idea what's going on here. This is the strangest Google results
I have ever seen. I'm going, I will investigate this and see what I can come up with.
But
my suspicion,
oh, you know what, bad OCR because it's all books dot Google dot C A results.
That's what you're getting. Yes, that would make sense. That's fair.
Yeah,
this is ok. This is Thursday.
Yeah, this is Thursday getting mangled and you spelled it flur.
Yeah.
Ok. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, and you figure Google has the technology to do kind of, you know,
fuzzy matching where it assumes.
Oh, maybe you spelled the word wrong.
I'm going to look up things that are similarly spelled
to this.
Thursday is not a word.
Everything is a word.
If the internet should teach you anything, it's, that everything is a word.
Actually, there was a local radio station one time that did a contest which was,
can you type two English words into Google and only get one result.
And I don't think anyone could do it. Yeah.
The, the, the, what, what are those called Google Lottery or whatever?
Yeah, I remember this is back in the day and because there was a couple I could type in,
uh, that would end up on my documentation.
Right. Ok. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, this is kind of related to today's topic which is speed runs.
Yeah,
we're going to talk about video games again because I'm sick
of all anyone talks about is bad news and screw that.
So we're going to talk about hacking video games, which is also very speed running.
Well.
Ah, but this is what I find interesting is,
is if you look at a lot of the speed runs videos, they're, they're not,
I wouldn't consider it hacking
because it's not like they're,
they're actually like patching the game or modifying the game in any way or even
some of them do. But I'm saying, like, a lot of them are straight up.
You sit down, like, for example,
at a console here's the controller and the guy does stuff.
And what I love is,
and because you were mentioning this too is there's a whole
bunch of youtube videos where it's not just a speed run,
but it's developers of that game watching the speed run going on.
Yeah, we didn't. Wow. Like that's messed up. It's so much fun.
Start at the beginning because I think we love to get
ahead of ourselves every time we talk and that's fine.
So I'm going to assume everyone knows what video games are
and I'm not going to assume everyone knows what speed running is because this is a,
I would say in the last couple of years, it's become much more popular than it was.
It's been around for at least a decade, probably longer.
I've never heard of it in public or I've let me put it this way.
The only people I know that talk about this are like you and TJ,
that's fair. I talk about it a lot.
So if you know me, I've talked to you about speed running, I guarantee it.
So essentially what happens is everyone's familiar with video
games and the idea being you start playing the game
and there's some logical conclusion to the game
in most games, you beat the end boss,
there's games where it could be beating a score or I mean,
like Minecraft is a great example where like the end of Minecraft is squishy.
So what does that mean?
Well, originally it's, you beat the Ender Dragon at the end that there's
Yeah, sure.
But the problem with Minecraft is there's so many,
it's bifurcated and there's so many different versions now, right?
And so what happens in speed running is the idea is
how can I get from the start of the game to the end of the game as fast as possible?
And we should probably mention that
what qualifies the end of the game
in some cases is like,
what you would consider to be classically completing the game.
And in some games it's they consider that getting to
like the final screen that says like well done.
You did it right? Because there's some games you can get to glitch out
well and they even have different categories.
So I will pick on Super Mario World as one of my
favorite examples here where this is a game on the Super Nintendo.
If you've never played it, you're totally missing out. It's an amazing fun game.
It is one of my favorites. It is so good. I love that game so much.
And there are kind of a couple of different ways to beat it.
And so you can just go right to the end boss to Bowser, beat him and that,
that's one way right.
There's beating all of the levels and then beating Bowser,
there's getting to the end credit screen.
And I say that because some people found a bug that
lets you create arbitrary code execution in Super Mario world.
Oh, and it crashes or something?
Well, they, they basically, they, they figured out where the like
the the program is that runs the end credits
and they cause arbitrary code execution to jump to that instruction.
Like there's actually a really, really good explaination video on youtube.
I will link to in the show notes that talks about how they do this,
how they overwrite all the data.
And it's like,
and to be clear, they're doing this like with like the standard controller,
like they're not hooking
up.
And
so basically what happens is they get on Yoshi,
they cause like a glitch state in the game and then they placed all these items around
the level that writes memory in certain locations
that by doing a certain action with Yoshi,
you basically cause the game to jump into the
X and Y coordinates of items you have placed
in the game which then jumps to the end credits. It's completely insane.
So they basically invented return oriented programming in a video game
actually
really
impressive. It's amazing. And so in fact, this has been really topical lately.
If if you, if you read Reddit, you would have noticed this has been a huge topic for
the game legend of Zelda Ocarina of time
because they actually recently achieved arbitrary code execution.
And in a way humans can do it
because historically, it's been one of those, you know,
only a task can do it because you have to push the, you know, a million buttons,
a second type thing.
But they found a way that a human being with a
controller can do these actions and then make ocarina of time,
do anything.
And of course, in their, in the instance of speed runners,
they're just jumping to the end credits.
But it doesn't mean you have to, there's actually there's another video from
uh it was uh one of the games done quick. I forget which one I will try to find it.
But they basically took Mario three. They
started in arbitrary code execution flaw
and then they reprogrammed the game. And
it's absolutely amazing what they did here because, and this was task, right?
This wasn't a human when I say, OK, if I say task,
that's called tool assisted speed run.
And that's where like
you plug a computer into the controller port and
the computer can push the buttons at ridiculous speeds.
But anyway, they like they reprogrammed Mario three to do crazy things. And it's,
it's so wild anyway. But the point is
this is a fascinating topic because it's fun
and it is essentially hacking video games in almost every instance there are,
there are speed runs that do not do
what I would call hacking where you're leveraging bugs
and you're causing, you know, arbitrary code execution or whatever.
But the vast majority of them
do
this exact thing. My favorite was I was watching this one speed run video
and the developer was like, he's just running past the God guys.
He's not shooting them.
It's like, well,
yeah, because
you don't need to
like unless they drop something, some loot item that you need to complete the game.
Yeah.
You know, like,
and so it was interesting is this,
this speed run basically was predicated on getting healed a
lot because you got shot a lot and you just,
like, ran through the game.
I know which one you, I forget the name of the game. It's a fairly new game.
And actually that one they had the developer, I think was at games done
quick when they ran it and it was,
yeah, it's fascinating because the developers just never
imagine someone would do this. And, I mean, but here's the thing, right?
And this is why I love this topic in the security context is,
I mean, what are security bugs?
You're
not
supposed
to
do that?
Right. Exactly. Why would anyone do that? And, and I have a great story I always tell.
So my first job out of college was
for this company that wrote life insurance software.
And I remember they were, we used some ridiculously old database on the back end.
It was one of those like bree
style databases, you know,
key value pairs and they were rewriting the application to use SQL.
And I remember at one point they had any time
a company makes like a fundamental technology switch like that.
I just, you know, I want to go find a bottle of liquor.
That's exactly what happened.
But anyway, so I remember we, we had the login screen
and in, in the old system, there wasn't even logins,
like if you had a computer hooked up to
the system because it ran in like freaking mainframes,
like you were just, your security was physical and it was
because everybody had, and this, I
think part of it too is this a lot of people remember this
back in the day, people had offices and those offices had locked doors. Exactly.
Exactly. So anyway,
we are rewriting this to, to work with the SQL server and they have the log in and I,
I did a sequel injection on the login.
I'm like, look at this and I remember the developer looked at me and said,
why would anyone do that?
I'm like, I just did that. And what's funny is you're making a login screen.
So ostensibly you're making the promise or the contract that
you have to have a valid user name and password.
I'm assuming it's a user name and password to get in.
Yeah. Right. And yeah, and then the developer is like, I don't get it.
Why would that be a problem? You're building something to explicitly handle,
you know, to enforce a condition.
Josh just showed you how to bypass that condition.
It's like every time I, you know,
when you're driving on the road and you see like
mashed up guard rails that haven't been replaced yet,
you know, it makes me kind of nervous because
a that guard rail was put there for probably a good reason and b
clearly was put there for a good reason because now it's all mashed up.
So like we should probably replace that one would think. But, but anyway, right,
the the attitude is you have developers building something
and they assume people are going to act with, with good intent.
And in the case of obviously computer security,
the bad intent often leads to bad consequences.
But in the case of most of these video game speed runs,
the bad intent leads to awesome speed runs
well.
And in fairness too,
there's a lot of games that kind of suck
because they try and force you through a certain,
you know, sequence of events.
And I get that like 20 years ago, like, remember the original, you know,
Doom or the original Half Life where, you know, you had to go do this,
flip this button.
Get the rocket to fire, blah, blah, blah. I kind of get that.
But then there's more modern games where it's like you have to like,
oh,
there's a penny arcade comic, but you have to, like,
you have to go through duct work and actually make a noise to alert a bad guy.
And, you know, it's kind of the joke is, but I'm playing like a ninja character.
Why can't I, like, sneak past it, drop down and cut his throat.
Right. Right. Right.
And I think some of the newer games
are getting more interesting in that regard where they're
way more open and you can do far
more interesting things than you necessarily could before.
And one of my,
so my favorite example of this actually is the legend of Zelda Breath of the Wild,
which is on the Nintendo Switch.
And if you've never played it,
it is an amazing game for a variety of reasons
and I'm not going to Fanboy on it too much.
I've seen some pretty crazy videos coming
of that game.
Like if you, if you want, right, he basically just built this huge physics engine.
And like my favorite example actually is my, my son figured this out.
There's these puzzles where you have to like hold the controller and move it in,
in space because like literally it's got the gyroscope inside of it.
And as you move the controller, it moves a platform
on the screen. OK?
And like you have a ball in a maze sort of game, right where you have to move it.
And he figured out if he just flips the controller upside down,
uh
The bottom of the maze is flat, right?
You could just roll it to the end. I'm like, that's amazing.
I never would have thought of that. And yeah, like there you go, you just choose it.
And all of a sudden pu
what goes for? Actually a really hard puzzle is now a joke
and the game is full of stuff like this where you can just,
you can do crazy things and the speed runners abuse this
where so you're obviously you're supposed to start the game,
you play the game, you get your weapons,
you get your power ups and then you go beat the, em.
Well, it turns out if you can get to the end boss, you can basically defeat him.
So they basically show up naked with the exact weapons they need to defeat it. I'm,
I'm totally serious. These people have like, no armor.
They show up and they, they have
like, they literally, they, if they, if they miss a hit,
they die because they have it exactly choreographed
and they can do it in under half an
hour and it took me like 200 hours to beat this game when I did it.
It is
well, and that also speaks to me as to making the games a bit more open ended.
And, you know,
like one thing I've seen is kind of that style where it's more like a well like magic,
the gathering or pathfinder where, you know,
you have these cards with these traits and these abilities
and you can mix them in new and interesting ways.
Yeah. Right.
And what I like, one thing I love about the game Starcraft,
there's a really good quote at any time.
The game of Starcraft in a specific matchup is unbalanced, but
the game overall is generally quite well balanced because part of it is, you know,
so I remember when battle cruisers came out and then they had the
ability to teleport jump and for a while all these tran players would like
rush two or three battle cruisers out jump them
over to the enemies and just destroy them.
But within like, two weeks,
you know, the opposing, basically the people had to deal with this,
figured out how to deal with this.
Like, you know,
put up some scores to shoot up or get some queens to shoot up or whatever, like,
you know, it, so the game kind of rebalanced because it's like, ok,
there's this strategy that, yeah, if you're not prepared for it absolutely works.
But if you know how to react to it, oh, it's, it's actually really easy to deal with.
It's just that, that novelty and that newness where it's like,
what the heck is going on?
Right. I think that's fair. That's
true of everything. Right.
I mean, attacking, defending our security world, right?
Like, oh, proper overflow,
return oriented programming.
Oh, you know, I remember when XSS came out and everybody's like, what,
why would anybody do that?
I'm like, because they get to control what they show you on the web page. Yeah.
But it,
it took people a while to understand or one of my favorites actually is double freeze
where for the longest time we thought double free issues were only crashes.
And then one day solar designer shows up and says, hey, look what I can do.
And
all of a sudden we're like, oh, crap. And we had a decade of ignoring these bugs.
I remember when, basically I, yeah, I remember
that pretty much that week where I was like, well,
these are all getting CV S now and people are arguing with me and I'm like,
go look at this posting like that's it.
Like, just go read the posting.
I'm giving these CV si understand that you don't like this and you, you,
you whatever, but too bad.
These are all,
you know what ruined it for me was learning it and then thinking,
what about all the crap?
We said not a bug two years ago now, I've got to go look at it all again.
We don't work there anymore. It's not our problem. Not anymore. Well,
that's not true.
I still deal with this stuff all the time, but it's,
it's definitely different for sure.
And,
yeah. Yeah. But this was also what, 20 years
more, probably, probably almost 30 years ago, man, it's been a long time.
I don't even remember anymore. It's been long anyway. Anyway.
The point being that it is one of those fascinating games of cat and mouse and
I mean, in all seriousness as well.
So in the speed running world now where you have the ability to update games where,
for example, the Zelda developers are constantly fixing bugs in the Zelda game.
And so there are bugs
and to be clear they're fixing bugs or they rebalancing it. Like are they actually
saying like this behavior should not have existed? We're going to patch around it?
I don't, I don't think it's rebalancing.
I think it's legitimately fixing bugs where they, because what,
what you'll see in speed running.
And this is even true of the old games like on the Nintendo where they
will run the Japanese version of the game because the Japanese version is like 1.0.
And then the version that came out in the United States would be
like version 1.1 and they fixed some of the bugs that were just
covered from the time each version got released.
And of course, more often than not, the more bugs you have in these games,
the more they can abuse them, which gives them obviously faster times.
And like this is a challenge actually in all
seriousness because so let's say you're a speed runner,
you want to start getting into the Zelda game right now,
you need to find an original version of the cartridge which they don't make anymore.
So you have to acquire one used.
Mhm.
Right.
And so, I mean, this is one of the challenges. Isn't that what the pirate pays for? No.
So in all seriousness, you can hack some of the older switches,
but the newer switches are,
they learned a bunch of lessons and they're pretty un hackable at this point.
When you said car, my brain went to, like, not the old stuff. Yeah. Yeah.
The old stuff, you can get flash ROMs and all that kind of nonsense.
And so they have ways to work around that.
But like when you're playing, say breath of the Wild on the switch,
if you don't have a 1.0 cartridge, you can't do some of the tricks.
And now what happens in the speed
running world is they'll have different categories.
Well, they'll say 1.0 speed runs go over here.
And if you're playing on a fully patched version, you're over here.
So different divisions in weight classes. Right. Right.
And, and people will say like no major bugs.
Like a great example is with Super Mario world,
you can do the arbitrary code execution, you can beat the game in like five minutes,
I think.
Whereas if you play it for real records like 12, I think,
and they just have two categories where there is
all people who want to do arbitrary code execution.
You're competing over here.
People who want to actually like play the game as if you're a human.
You go over here and you compete on in this, you know, Playpen makes sense. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, it totally makes sense. Absolutely. So anyway, anyway, it is,
there's so much, there's so much to talk about.
I'm so excited too because I love this topic so much. So.
So here's one of the other really cool aspects of this that,
that is kind of based upon the developer saying, oh why would anyone do that?
Is
there are also games that don't technically stop you from doing things
and my favorite example here is a game called Super Metroid,
which is also for the Super Nintendo.
And when you speed run it,
there's obviously the way we would play it or the game
kind of guides you gently through it to go over here. Do this, go over here, do this.
And the speed runners found out that you don't actually have to
do anything in the order they tell you to do them in.
And so if you can, for example, get up over a cliff,
you can go there, right? Like there's nothing stopping you.
And so one of the craziest speed runs, if you've ever played Super Metroid,
there's an order you beat the bosses in.
They have something called the reverse boss order where
they go and beat like the hardest boss first.
And
it's amazing because like the whole while they're doing it,
they're losing life because they're in like this lava
filled level that is constantly draining your life.
So they don't have any of the upgrades that keep the lava from draining your life. And
it's so
bizarre watching these guys do it.
But the thing I always think of here is, you know,
we always talk about the fact that when you have
a motivated attacker and you can't defend against them.
Like these were motivated individuals like they have
the will to figure this out. And they did,
when you consider how much time some people spend playing video games.
And I don't mean this, like, derogatorily, but like,
professional Starcraft players,
like these guys are grinding 8 to 10 hours a day for, you know, the last decade.
Right. Exactly. And they can, I couldn't play eight hours of a video game in one day.
If you told me I would get a million dollars for doing it. I just, I can't, I can't do it.
I think your hands would probably fall off at this point.
And that's actually a thing like that's the thing in Starcraft now is like a lot of
these players are aging out in their like thirties
and they're literally the one guy was like,
yeah, my doctor says I have the hands of like a 60 year old man, right? I believe that.
So,
so you say this,
I have my right thumb is really sore right now.
And the reason for that is Animal Crossing just came out on Friday
and I have played a lot of animal crossing and like, I have literally,
I have repetitive stress in my thumb.
I had Nintendo thumb as a kid. You know that weird.
Yeah,
you don't get that anymore because now you've got like the the nice stick to move.
But yeah, for real, I've played actually
I have another funny story. So in my household, we own three switches,
Nintendo switches.
And the reason for this was we got one on launch day and
then it became obvious that we would need a second one to avoid,
we'll say problems with my marriage.
And so we,
we acquired a second.
That's right. That's
right.
So we, we acquire a second one
and then it, at one point, my wife and Children left on a trip and
I was left without a switch and the new Mario maker came out and I just said,
I'm buying another switch.
Right. I'm not going to not play this game. I want to play it right now.
And I had a lot of free time because like the wife and kids were gone.
So anyway, buy a third switch. And then on uh Animal Crossing came out on Friday.
And on Sunday,
I went and bought 1/4 switch to avoid anyone killing anyone else in our house.
Now I own, everyone has a switch and everyone has a copy of Animal Crossing
in Fairness. I remember buying my first ipod and I'm like, I'll buy one ipod. My
people will share it.
And then the next day I was at the apple store getting the second ipod. And then,
and then when I bought their ipads, I was like, I'm not even pretending like I need,
I need a black ipad and I need a white ipad.
So we can tell them apart.
So like literally to this day just I, every 3 to 4 years reup.
I've thought about getting, getting a switch.
But yeah, I don't know, man, those things are like cocaine. Uh,
they're, they're fantastic. I'm not going to you. I love it. It is awesome.
And now I have the little one which I'm loving because I thought the switch is too big.
That's my story. But Animal Crossing is great, by the way.
Yeah. No, it's, and, and, well,
see, that's what gets me about Nintendo, right?
Is they got two things build quality because like
I took my Nintendo wii not the Wii universal,
but like the original Wii and it had been sitting in like a,
a plastic box in my garage for like five or six years and I plugged
it in and then realized I couldn't plug it in because it didn't have HDMIO.
So I had to go on Amazon by like a 20 I think it was like a $23 adapter
and then that showed up like four days later, plug it in and it just works. Yeah. Yeah.
There,
I still have my original Nintendo in the basement
and every now and then I will plug it in
and it is basically flawless to this day.
And the second thing is Nintendo.
I don't know what pact they made with the devil,
but they make some of the most fun games to play
it. I won't disagree with you. I have been like Mario, Zelda,
Mario and Zelda alone. Mario and Zelda are my favorite games ever.
Well, alone, those games Nintendo would make enough money to it.
Would be embarrassing,
right?
Like they literally, if they literally only made those two franchises,
they could stay in business for 100 years.
Probably.
They, there's actually a really cool quote from.
So,
so the guy who created Donkey Kong and Mario and Zelda and
there's Peakman and there's a bunch of basically most of Nintendo's characters,
except for me,
except Metroid were created by this guy named
Shigeru Miyamoto.
And he is,
I
read an
interview with him once that he used to joke,
you was the best video game designer in the world because he was
the only video game designer in the world when he created Donkey Kong.
And like now I don't think anyone would argue with that.
Like he, he, he's the Einstein of video games. Yeah, for real straight up.
But anyway, he has this quote where he basically says
that he will never release a game before it's done because
a game delayed by two weeks is delayed by two weeks,
but a game released bad is bad forever.
And there's been so many of those like,
remember like what was it Red Dead redemption?
Like watching some of those glitchy attempts to play it, like, what was it?
Red Dead Redemption or another one that was just so glitchy. I don't know.
I mean, I don't, I haven't played Red Dead Redemption.
I don't feel like I saw a lot of
like great broken glitches
that
but there are games that had been released that were unplayable, bad.
Absolutely. Who could imagine releasing broken software to people,
you know, as,
as we have like Oracle patch or Oracle
quarterly patch and patch Tuesday for Microsoft.
And I mean, I get at some point it's normal,
you can't fix all the bugs before you release it.
But yeah,
leaving it in a playable state.
And I, I think in general software, you know,
being in a not completely unusable security state would be good.
Well, and you have to think, I mean, video games back in the day,
it's a little different now with all the online everything,
but back in the day you had a cartridge or a CD.
And that was the end, if it, if it was broken
that, that was it,
there was, there was no,
all those, what is it, those, um,
Atari et cartridges is that they dumped out in the middle of
the desert and somebody actually tracked down and dug them back up,
right?
So
horrifically bad. But that was not because I mean, so ET sucked for its own reasons.
However, I will say that game was made in like a month by one person.
So in that context it's surprisingly good,
but
it was, it was terrible and I don't know if this is true.
I, I'll, I'll try to look it up and put a link to it. But I,
I remember I heard once they released more ET cartridges than they had sold Atari,
which obviously you can imagine, just economically speaking,
that is a bad decision.
Yeah, it's in the, it's a popular rumor according to Wikipedia.
Yeah.
You think they would?
And no one's going to admit anything because everything
that happened around that game was a train wreck.
Well, they buried 728,000 cartridges of various games.
The whole,
the whole game industry crashed at that
point because Atari was releasing shovelware.
Although one of the issues actually,
so I just watched a documentary about this not long ago
is Atari, like anyone could release Atari games because they had the
attitude of we'll just sell units,
people can make software and so people were releasing garbage
and then,
and this is one of the things Nintendo actually did
when they released the Nes is they said no,
no,
if you're going to release games, like you have to come to us.
And this is actually where the Nes lockout chip comes from.
Nintendo was famous for being completely fascist about who
they would let develop games for their platform.
Yeah, but on the flip side, yeah, there weren't a lot of terrible ones.
Oh, there were tons of terrible Nes games. Well, I don't remember them.
Yeah. True. Survivor Bias, man. No, I'm thinking of actually I downloaded a RO
pack and I was looking for some of them and like, yeah, I tried playing
two random ones and it was
terrible
and there were,
there were like 200 Change Nes games if I recall correctly or was it 400?
It's, it's 2 to 400 somewhere in there. Right.
And
if you told me to basically like list Nintendo games,
I think I would struggle to list more than 20
because I can list like the 20 that aren't terrible.
715. 0, wow. That many.
Now,
at the same time there's a guy, I will find a link to this.
There's, there's a runner who goes by TMR. He's the Mexican runner
and
like, that's his name.
T MRI just got, I'm like, wow, that's, that's borderline racist.
OK. The Mexican runner that can't be right. I'm like, oh no, that, that's him.
He, he lives in Mexico in his defense. So he is literally a Mexican runner.
But
OK,
so anyway, he beat
Nes game like he made that his goal. What does this guy do for a day job?
That's his day job. He like, he does like Twitch Streaming and
he streams on Facebook now.
He's a, I haven't watched the stream because I like,
I'm not willing to do that on Facebook.
But
yeah, yeah, like he's the real deal.
He's really funny actually when he does speed runs at
like games done quick or any of these events,
he is,
he's a hoot because he's really funny and his
humor is really dry and he's really good.
So it's, it's one of the, you need that, like,
combination where you can be really good and really boring
or you can be really funny and kind of bad
when you're both. It's amazing.
Yeah.
No, it's,
it's funny to watch those professional video game
commentators because some of them are not good.
But I get that there's such a small pool of them that it doesn't really matter.
But the thing is though, some of them are just beyond hilarious. And
it's funny because there's actually a couple that remind me
of myself in that they are terrible on their own.
Just terrible on everyone with the right partner.
Beautiful.
Well, no, some of these commentators are good on their own.
Like um no, no, I, I get this. I, there are very few I will say this.
So actually I will, I will tell the story.
I don't know if I've ever told you this story before or not,
but I tell it to everyone I talk to about us.
The podcast is
when I met you for the first time,
right?
And I remember because Vincent was someone we worked with at
Redhead and he basically will say prepared me for meeting you,
right?
And,
but anyway, I'm like, ok, we'll see like, and,
and you are one of those person that you fill a room, I'll say that, right?
That's the polite way of saying you're just kind of loud and in everyone's face.
But like, you fill the room, right.
And I remember I met you and I thought I want to do a podcast with this guy someday.
Like that is my goal.
And of course, we, we made it there and, and I'm very pleased by that.
That's because the usual reaction is people want to punch me in the throat.
I, I, that mine was, I want to do a podcast with you. So it worked.
But like the point is like, I know if I did a podcast, it would be by myself.
It would be boring.
If I did, if you did a podcast, it would probably also be boring.
But I feel like when you put us together,
we have the right Yang and Yang on most of this that I think it works
and it's, it's awesome anyway. Anyway.
But at the same time, like there's lots of podcasts, like I listen to a lot of podcasts
and
there are very few that are one person I can tolerate
because generally speaking, I think when you're by yourself,
it gets boring eventually.
Whereas when there's other other people, you can work together. It's hard.
Well, how do you present two different viewpoints?
Right. Like you do a funny voice for one. No, seriously, right? Like they don't,
they don't,
the one thing I've consistently not the good one person podcasts are either
somebody who is going over like amazing content.
Like say David Allen's GTD podcasts
come out like four times a year
or they interview people a lot, which is, well, basically a two person podcast.
Yeah, that's not a one person podcast.
Then I don't, I consider I'm ok with, with interview podcast because like,
whiskey Business is a great example where like
that guy is always talking to somebody,
right?
Whereas,
yeah, if it's just a person talking into a microphone,
it always bores me and I never, I never stick with them.
Well, I think this is one of the reasons public speaking is so scary to most people.
Right.
Like getting up in front of everybody having 100% of
their attention for 5 to 30 minutes and speaking,
let's, let's be blunt.
Right?
Like one thing I've noticed with this thing going around
the world is watching some of these politicians speak.
Wow, brutal, terrible.
You know, and then some of these politicians, it's like, ok, wow, I,
I feel slightly less terrible now.
It's, yeah, it's not for everybody and it's, it's hard, it's really hard.
It's hard to hold an audience.
I, I have so many stories. II, I like, I love giving talks to conferences. I really do.
I really enjoy it. And
I have been to
probably more bad security talks than good.
I would say if I was going to count them all.
And I'm,
I'm actually really sad what we'll have to do an episode at some point
here because I have this marvelous star Trek talk I've been working on for,
for years at this point,
but it's all about the security problems on the starship enterprise.
And I call it next generation enterprise security because
I focus on Star Trek the next year.
Like it's,
it's a marvelous talk and I don't know if I'm going
to be giving it for a very long time now.
But anyway, anyway, I'm not talking about this right now.
That's depressing and annoying. And it is time for us to wrap up anyway. So
here's what I will tell anyone interested in this is
there are amazing resources if you want to get
into speed running or just watch speed running.
Because like, for, I, I, I've tried doing some of this.
I can't
rocket
jump
anymore. Well, sort of.
So, I mean, here's,
the challenge is so at one point I was able to
beat the original Super Mario Brothers in about six minutes.
Right.
But I was playing an hour a day probably to get there.
And I realized finally, like, I'm sick of playing this game.
I don't want to play it anymore. And I actually yesterday I picked up my switch.
I started Super Mario Brothers
and I, I suck. Right. Because like, I've lost the skills. I need to beat it that fast.
And it's like, well, that's that
I'm not going to invest the time again to do this.
But, but if you watch people do it, it's, it's amazing and you know what, you know,
what really
is the thing I always tell people is,
I don't understand how, like my father can watch football on a Sunday all day.
Like, it just doesn't hold my attention.
I can watch maybe an hour of it and I'm like, I'm sick of this.
I don't care if you're into a sport
and you watch the professionals do it.
I can now appreciate that because, like,
I watch these people play Super Mario brothers and I appreciate
what they're doing and I know how hard it is.
And so it has given me a appreciation for sport ball that I never had in the past.
Well, it's, it's classic Dunning Kruger.
You need to actually have a reasonable amount of knowledge to
have an appreciation for who is good and bad at this.
Yeah, that's exactly right.
Or like, are they even playing, like, if you showed me 10 football games and said, ok,
which one of these teams is playing good football and bad football?
I'd be like,
yeah. Right. Exactly. I, yeah, I have no idea. One of them won. Ok. That was neat.
I have no idea what happened.
Yeah, exactly.
Anyway, anyway,
all right, sweet. I'm going to call this and for real.
Like, if, if this is something you'd be mildly interesting, go check it out.
I will put a ton of show notes in
this one because this is a topic I love. So, anyway, thank you.
Kurt, thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up our show notes, you see Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag You hit us up on social media and Kurt have a fabulous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.