Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 120 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
Now, 100 and 20 is a number I can get behind as it's a multiple of six
also 12, which is a multiple of six.
Yep.
Those supers.
Right.
That's right.
Oh, man.
So today we are going to talk about the super micro, I would call it a kerfuffle,
but I don't think that's
near, near descriptive
enough. It's like a dumpster fire on top of a tire fire in like a nuclear waste zone
except it's not real
-- and it's full of stinky poo.
-- Right. Right. And that's the beauty of it. Right.
There's, there's so many layers of
it probably is.
It is, but it isn't. And it's just
all right. Let's start at the beginning
to, to unpack this one.
And do you want to do the honors of explaining what Bloomberg did?
Well, I'm not going to lay this on Bloomberg.
Um
They
publish it.
But,
well, that's OK.
This is meta, but I think it used to be a lot of these news organizations used to be a lot
more selective and professional than they are now.
Like, if you look at Bloomberg, you kind of have like a,
they, they provide like a blog platform for random people's opinions as well,
right?
But um anyway, so two reporters, Jo uh Jordan Robertson and Michael Riley, uh
who, and if you look at their uh publishing history of Bloomberg,
these guys have done
quite a bit of legitimate tech and tech security reporting,
like they both have over a dozen articles a year to their name.
And,
you know, and like you said, these aren't like these little sort of cut and paste,
you know, Buzzfeed style things, but these are some proper, you know,
investigative,
uh you know, effort was made and it probably took several weeks, you know, you know,
for some of these articles.
Um So these guys definitely come across as professional journalists.
And so I guess what happened is
they found this story talking about hacked super micro hardware
and they apparently managed to get a whole ton of uh confirmation and uh and,
and supporting evidence from people.
-- So, I mean,
-- look, if you want the evidence, you need to take a picture of a board
and say
that's it,
right?
Because according to this story,
the the layout of the motherboards was modified and extra chips were added.
So,
and see this is one of those classic things where
it's kind of like, uh
it's one of those things where if you show me the proof and describe it properly,
it's relatively easy to validate, especially, you know,
if you're Super Micro or Apple or something
and more to the point, Super Micro and Apple, for them to deny the story,
this is not something you can deny.
And they'd be like, oh, oops, you know, we sort of misunderstood.
No, they've issued a flat out very strong denial.
And if somebody gets a hold of one of those motherboards at a later date and, you know,
takes it apart or uh photographs it or x rays, it or whatever,
you know, that that evidence is very, very strong, right?
This isn't something you can sort of like fake the evidence after the fact easily.
And the way Apple and Super Micro have and Amazon was implicated in this also
and the way they have denied this, it is pretty clear
that that denial made it through lawyers and marketing,
which which leads me to believe this isn't one of those. Oh ha ha.
No, no, no, it's Wink Wink. Right. This is like
-- this is the real deal.
-- Their denials at first were kind of like
reading between the lines. It sort of sounds like they're being very specific like,
no, I did not murder him at 12 o'clock with a pistol,
you know,
but their later denials were very emphatic and no,
this is not real Bloomberg is wrong.
So, so basically the story is, is that, you know, the
supposedly the Chinese got some extra hardware put into super micro motherboards
and, and I love that, you know, on Twitter you were like, oh, you know,
wouldn't the engineers notice?
And then I sent you that video of that guy touring a PC B factory in China. And it's like
they get the design, they tweak the design,
they make sure it works and then they produce this thing and like,
yeah, it would, it looks from judging from that video,
the supply chain security is such that, that if that company were malicious,
they could easily add an extra component or two.
Well, it, it,
yes and, and so actually, I've been thinking about this a lot and,
and I still agree with you that it's totally doable.
I, I guess there's, well,
the trick is would super micro then be validating the
boards when they come back as part of their Q A
in, in. There's the, there's so, so there's a couple of pieces to this.
There's first of all,
uh super micro does the design, they send the design to the, the PC B manufacturer in,
in China in this instance, right.
And
that group definitely could make modifications without issue.
I'm I'm 100% sure of that now.
But then also like,
I'm skeptical the same factory makes the P CBS as assembles things.
So now you have two factories,
you have to essentially subvert management which
which I don't think is unreasonable.
-- What do you mean
-- two factories?
So you have to subvert the PC B manufacturers and then you have
to subvert the second company that's putting the chips onto the P CBS.
-- Right. Those are probably two different companies.
-- Oh,
not necessarily,
maybe. And, and so anyway, but regardless, then, then in theory Super Micro,
-- it's definitely possible to subvert both.
-- Right. Right. It's, it's, I
think it's probably already done
regardless of this story.
Do you think some guy at the PC B manufacturer
won't take $100,000 to tweak the design files slightly?
I would take $100,000 to
be like, I'm not asking questions. I'm taking your money.
Don't even tell me what this is. I'll do what you say
anyway.
And, and,
but then Super Micro gets it back and I would
hope they would notice if there was something different.
However,
the one thing I don't know and this is something
if someone out there listening knows the answer to this.
If, if you are someone manufacturing something like say a motherboard,
would it be expected for it to come back
with alterations and even possibly new chips just depending
upon what sort of supply existed or the people
you were working with and what level of,
I guess ability they have to do this sort of thing.
Like, I don't know the answer to that.
Yeah.
So one interesting thing is, uh I've been watching a lot of Luis Rossman,
he's this guy in New York that does component level repair of like apple and,
you know, other devices.
So, like, he'll, you know, open up your damaged mash
and like, find the burn
out chip or
the thing that, you know,
I didn't spill water on it. And he's like, and look at this water damage, you know,
and in that case, he pulls up these schematics, Uh I don't know where he gets them
and they,
the schematics definitely have a physical mapping to the actual physical board,
right?
Like where the chips are in the schematic, you know, the,
they're not just some random sort of layout.
Um but at the same time that he spends a lot
of time swearing at these things trying to find chips.
You know,
what, what's interesting to me too is like Apple has, you know,
they've relatively well compared to most manufacturers, they have like
seven product lines,
you know, like compared to somebody like, uh, well,
the Android phone ecosystem where there's like 10 million different devices.
And even within that, you know, there's major changes to products,
you know,
that are labeled as being sort of the same product and even almost the same version,
you know, like the boards will change a bit or whatever.
And so
I, my question would be, is, is, you know, is super micro Qing boards that come back,
are they, you know, taking a photo of the board
and comparing that to the chips and saying like, OK,
that chip is that chip on the schematic?
And is that, that says the right number? Ok, check that one off you go.
OK, right below it. You know, we have
a,
is that OK? That's on the thing. Yep. That looks right. I doubt they're doing this
in, in all seriousness. I don't know if I would do that.
I would have sort of functional testing where I like plug the board in
-- and I make sure things happen.
-- Exactly.
Well, and the thing is that the factory, they're supposed to have done this with,
you know, with that again, that video of that PC B factory where
they make these PC DS and then they have that, like, essentially
automated multi meter machine,
-- I guess is what you would call
-- it.
The connections essentially.
Yeah, it pokes all the circuits and, you know,
runs current through them and make sure they're,
you know, not, uh connected to ground and that they're correct and everything
I would assume also that those sort of audit results are sent back to Super micro,
you know, to some degree.
Um, because quite frankly,
the cost of Super micro validating every board would be obscene.
I,
I wouldn't work with that manufacturer if I had
to get them all back and validate them myself.
I mean, just, no, absolutely not.
And more to the point. Yeah, if it plugs in and works well,
-- probably. Ok,
-- everything's fine
if it, if
it builds its chips. Right.
So, anyway, so, yeah, so there's this supposed
chip added to the boards, you know,
and, and this chip could be embedded inside the PC B layers, you know,
at PC B manufacturer.
And, yeah, good luck spotting it and, or,
well, you wouldn't be able to remove it, you know,
without destroying the board basically.
Right. Well, from my understanding, reading the, the report
is, it's, it's literally a chip on board.
It's not like hidden in any way from the way it was
literally just another component stuck on the board,
which seemed to be my understanding and I must say, like,
if you're going to go after the supply chain, that's a really stupid way to do it.
Right?
You want, you want to get inside the silicone, you don't want to be like,
just a chip sitting there.
-- I, I
-- don't know. I think it would work because quite frankly, it, it,
it's one of those attacks where, yeah, once it's noticed you're blown.
But how long is it going to take to notice
forever, you know. Yeah. I mean,
but anyways, let's, let's assume for a moment that
let's just thought experiment and assume that this is actually real for a moment
because let's
before we do that,
we should, we should talk about the fact that this probably is real
because
you have to think how many chips and how many devices are manufactured in China?
Right.
The NSA was running, what was it?
Uh, the NSA upgrade factory, remember where they were
uh hardware chipping
devices, you know, there's,
-- or there's a photographs of this
-- and we should also clarify.
I'm not blaming China for this. Every country does this.
Right. They're not the big bad wolf.
Well, every country I,
my government better be doing this if they're halfway competent.
No, seriously. Right.
This is like having a military nowadays. This is,
you know, this is like in the olden days where you'd have, you know,
coal and steel plants because those are strategic resources
and that's fair.
Silicon and hardware is very much a strategic resource.
That's fair.
I mean,
any weapon system beyond your rifle is going to
probably take a battery and some computer chips.
Not only that there's so many chips in this gear.
Now there's, there's, I would guess that a modern laptop probably has hundreds of,
of microprocessors inside of it.
Right. There's, there's ac
we always think of,
but like the freaking battery has more than one microprocessor in many instances.
-- Now,
-- those hard drives with the built in, you know,
basically equivalent to ac pu thing where
you remember the guy was hacking them and reloading the firmware
and having it hide data on the hard drive and,
and do literally
who knows what
exactly. Exactly. And so I guess from a supply chain perspective
you could probably attack any one of those chips.
And I'd be shocked if it hasn't been done by some
organization
somewhere.
Right.
I,
I think claiming that you have hardware that hasn't been compromised
in some way is probably a fairy tale at this point.
Yeah.
Well, and some manufacturers are directly dealing with this now, you know, apple,
with their,
the security chip in the new max can and it looks like at some point will be enforcing,
you know,
the replacement parts having the correct cryptographic signatures in them.
You know. So when you wanna
add a, a new video card or add a new uh
whatever,
you know, it better be a correct
OEM part that has the approved cryptographic signatures in it.
You know, they're doing this for phones already with you, remember the screens
and they get so much crap for this though because people freak out because they
-- want to like go to the dodgy place at the mall to replace their
-- screen.
Apple will probably tell them too bad.
I think Apple is mostly back down at this point, haven't they?
They keep trying to do this
-- and I feel like they keep backing down
-- the thing
is they keep pushing the line forwards and they keep
gaining an inch or two.
So, you know, it's kind of like we, we, we take two inches, give one back. Oh, ok.
Well, we'll slow down on that
and in fairness, right?
This is, this was tried in the auto industry and they got um, well, the US Congress,
you know the right to repair bill
for cars. But what about the whole John Deere tractor thing going on right now?
Right. John Deere tractors.
Uh,
you need this very specialized software just to diagnose
what's wrong with the tractor and you know,
farmers are pissed about this because,
and rightly so this one guy was like, I,
you expect me to load my tractor up onto a flatbed trailer,
drive it five hours to the nearest dealership
so that they can tell me like this,
you know,
electronic module or component is broken and swap it out for like five grand.
No, I want a guy to show up in my field with a laptop
at a park, right?
And that's reasonable because these tractors
cost hundreds of thousands of dollars.
Oh yeah, they're crazy.
And I read somewhere that these farmers are now
downloading like uh uh pirate firmware from the Ukraine
and
their track,
which that's great.
Yeah.
Well, we had this discussion with the self driving cars and you know,
will people be allowed to modify their self driving car firmware?
And the answer is I hope not because
man, I want to be crazy about it.
Um But back to this. So, so is this
type of attack possible? Absolutely. 100% guaranteed.
Yes, this is possible and it's been done now, this specific instance of it
did it actually happen and it's looking like the answer is no.
And I would say that based on one simple
fact that the evidence that there has been none released
and worst,
the sort of the, the additional claims and the additional sort of backpedaling
has been in some cases really
bad. Um, you know, talking about, uh, like Ethernet
Jacks, like the physical Ethernet Jack that's like in your computer, right?
And how, like people are hiding, you know, evil chips in there. Yeah, absolutely.
Possible.
Again, this is something that is possible, not just in theory,
but in practice has it happened a lot?
No.
And the problem is then they're saying things like, oh,
these Ethernet Jacks had metal,
uh, enclosures, meaning that they were hacked and it's like, what, like,
no, like that's,
well, you know how
Ethernet Jacks can be plastic or metal
and the better ones are metal because it gives a bit of shielding.
Yeah, exactly. And they're like, that shows that it was hacked and it's like,
and then they're like,
exactly.
And then they're like, oh,
but these Ethernet Jacks wouldn't have enough room physically inside of it for it.
Well, and then, so the problem is the other side is like, oh,
an Ethernet Jack wouldn't have enough room inside
of it for a chip that does anything.
It's like,
-- no, it absolutely does. These things are huge and
-- it probably does,
you know,
so that's part of the problem is both sides have, um
the sort of the peanut gallery making a lot of bad and spurious and wrong claims,
you know, like on the one hand, people claim, no, this is impossible.
And it's like, well, wait, no, we have proof that this has happened in the past.
So this specific case though, here's my question.
So these two journalists who appear not to be idiots because
they've done a lot of good work in the past,
you know, they, they both have track records of at least
uh about 100 articles each just on Bloomberg
going back, you know, a decade or so.
Um
Yeah, what the heck happened here?
Like, was this some sort of false? Like, is this something
like getting metaphor?
Is this something the Chinese government did
to discredit future legitimate stories about this?
Yeah, I doubt that. Is this simply like they
somehow Murphy's law fucked it up badly.
I, I don't think that's possible either because these guys seem professional.
So like, how did this story come about and get so screwed up?
I don't know. I've been thinking about that a lot actually. And, and I guess there's,
what is, is it, is it Hanlon's
Razor
says
the most obvious answer is, is generally the right answer.
That's all comes Razor. Hanlon's
Razor is never
maliciousness. What can be explained?
OK.
Both,
both
of them
two
things. Thank you.
Right. I have a feeling that
these guys are,
they, they don't totally understand what they're talking about.
They don't, when they're making comments about Ethernet Jacks,
metal versus plastic.
It's
like
that's fair.
But sorry, that's, I've had both for decades.
Right.
However, II I have a suspicion.
Somebody led them astray somewhere and I don't know if it was on purpose.
They apparently had multiple sources though.
So, is this just a giant troll? Like a bunch of guys? Ha ha.
-- Like
-- I
go,
I'm skeptical. that's even true.
I also wonder how many of the sources were, is this possible?
And like, oh yes, it's totally possible,
right?
Versus this is actually what's happening and here is the chip
that's being used and here it is on the board,
which is what they should have demanded.
Well, so
from what I heard, they had a number of sources that, you know, quote unquote,
confirmed this
-- and my understanding of confirmed is not. Is this possible? Yes. No. You
-- know,
I don't know, does does confirmed have like a legal,
I don't know that it has a legal meaning, but I assume it goes beyond just.
Is this a possibility? Yeah. Ok. Good enough. We're going to run the story.
I don't know. It just, it definitely
is a giant mess regardless if it's true or if it's not true,
doesn't really matter at this point.
And I guess
here's,
here's the real thing I want to talk about today
and it's even less about is this story true?
Is this story not true. There is,
there's the attitude in
insecurity of assume compromise, right?
Where you have to design your infrastructure to
assume you have an attacker on the inside
and, and you can do a lot of things to even if somebody attacks you,
you can protect a lot of your assets.
And so I guess we need to bring it to another level and say,
how do you build your infrastructure when you
assume the hardware running your infrastructure is compromised?
Yeah. And I was reading about this and they were talking about how,
you know, some of these.
Well, so the what is it, what was that router firmware that's been hacked?
And now it's being counter hacked by a guy who's actually fixing it.
-- I want to say microtech,
-- oh, I heard about that.
I don't know what brand it is but yes, I heard that
I think it was microtech anyways.
The point being though for something like a home router you can very easily spot.
Oh, look traffic to China. That's naughty.
But for something, you know, for example, hypothetically speaking,
a server running part of uh you know, Amazon web services infrastructure.
Oh, look that server wants to talk to China. Well,
yeah, maybe there's people running stuff on Aws that does that like,
you know, at a certain scale, you can't
easily
this Chinese company is sending all of its traffic to China.
Like what's up with that?
Yeah, exactly.
You can't you know, it's one thing, um, what was that,
that defense company that got hacked and sent like a terabyte of data to China.
Ok. That, you know, you probably shouldn't have a workstation
on a, you know,
on a secured land, being used to do military work,
sending a, a huge amount of traffic to China. That's probably not good,
but
a server running at AWS sending a couple kilobytes of traffic to China every day.
Hey,
maybe, I mean, it, so the thing I keep thinking of here is
depending upon what you're using the system
for because there's also varying levels of,
well, here's the thing,
Aws isn't necessarily using the system. It's their customers. Same with Apple.
-- Well,
-- and so that's part of it. Right? Is,
is what
Aws, for example, I'm going to pick on, they have something called GOV
cloud where they have a special cloud,
they set up just for the United States Federal government and
there's all these crazy rules before you can even use.
And that makes sense.
Uh, you need, you don't need clearance.
There's, it's crazy but there's a bunch of rules. So anyway,
I
have
to
deal with certain countries, for example.
Right. Right. Right. Right.
So, anyway, anyway, the point is like that cloud
should have different rules to the, just we'll say regular Aws infrastructure.
Well,
the funny thing is you could easily do this with existing
run of the mill Aws and that you could have,
for example, on your VPC, on your virtual,
you have a cloud set up,
you could have egress firewall rules saying,
you know, don't.
Right.
Right. You should have,
I mean, so this is part of the example you can have for example, your VPC set up,
do not send traffic anywhere outside of the VPC except for say one mode
and like that traffic that leaves, you should be paying attention to that traffic.
Right?
You should be logging it in some meaningful way and,
and the days of just like ignoring everything I
think are officially over is what it means.
Like you need to pay attention.
Well, I, I wouldn't say that so far, but for example, I'm,
I'm redoing my VPC so that they can connect out
but only through the elastic load balancer
and to,
you know, essentially get OS updates.
Sure. And then you, but you can also like pay attention to that right.
In, in your case, you may not be dealing with
sensitive enough to really care.
Right. Right. Exactly.
But let's say it is sensitive, you should be paying attention to what's going on.
And if all of a sudden you see traffic at
midnight to some weird obscure IP address in some,
you know, country you don't normally deal with.
Like
that's weird
products that just do this,
right? You can just buy off the shelf products that handle this, right.
There's all the intrusion detection systems and intrusion protection systems.
Most of them have pivoted
to also do that, you know, information in the letter
to do that information egress of.
Yeah, you know, all of a sudden this server is like talking to China a lot,
you might want to look at that
-- or whatever,
-- right?
And, and this is, I mean, this is something we have like with elastic search,
you can obviously log all kinds of stuff and then
you can even do correlations where you can say,
all right, you know,
like this A P address started talking to Russia and it started with she
also it did these things and it logged into these other computers and then,
you know, you can start like following things around your architecture
and and
that's what people need to be doing now.
And if you're not doing that and you have sensitive anything, which let's face it,
we all do because if we didn't like why are people paying us?
-- So
-- the CS A is working with True Star.
And so one of the things True Star does is allows you to correlate stuff but not just
your stuff, it allows you to share your information securely within the system. So
when you say, hey, my machine is talking to this weird IP address, True Star is like,
oh yeah, these other 10 people reported that starting, you know,
yesterday at 2 a.m. as well.
In which case
now, now we have a problem,
right? And and that's kind of my point.
There are a lot of products that do this stuff out there. Right. I mean, uh,
find one and use it
is basically where we're at at this point. Right.
-- Because, I mean, even Aws can do this, can't it?
-- Um, Aws.
Uh, I know, for example, if you do a port scan from an Aws service,
you get a grumpy email from them within five minutes saying please explain
this uh network activity from your host.
Uh or we're giving you the boot, totally respect that, you know,
-- and
-- actually I've seen emails come in like from Aws and Google that are saying, oh,
you know what's up with this?
It's like, oh crap, like
we,
we better fix.
And so, and that's the beauty is, you know,
I was talking with an Aws guy years ago and he
was pointing out that Aws cannot look inside of a client's
machine. CPU and memory. They just can't or what's on the hard drive, right?
Because that would be such a gross breach of trust.
But
uh and, and you also don't want to be like, actually like
maybe doing deep packet inspection of their network traffic. But at the same time,
you don't need to because
just the, the sort of profiles of network activity. And
he was saying even just the CPU and RA M and hard drive activity, not
the content of what's going on, but just sort of the usage patterns
they were finding was enough to generally. So, for example,
you know, openshift.com has this problem where people keep trying to
sign up to openshift.com
to use it to do crypto
mining.
Well,
that's really easy to spot because you have some stupid
little thing that tries to peg the CPU to 100%.
I'm sorry. No, that's not allowed.
Um
So there's a lot of things you can do with even very simplistic rules based systems.
Not even machine learning or not even anywhere close to A I is needed
to spot sort of this anomalous naughtiness
and, you know, 99 times out of 100 it is naughty, anomalous behavior.
And then that one time in 100 the customer will go like, oh, no, no,
we do this weird thing.
Can you please let us do this weird thing? Oh,
-- ok. Sure.
-- Whatever.
Right. And, and you can get permission to do that as well. And, and I guess
here's the other side of this coin also
is we're talking about looking for, say, anomalous behavior in,
in bizarre network things.
But the reality is if like if you have an infrastructure set up and you
have it installed patches and you're not like
logging your things to a centralized location,
you don't, don't do this first.
This is like step seven, right?
And, and that's part of it too is there's,
I see so many organizations that are just like you're talking about logging your
network traffic and you have a computer running like windows 95 serving web pages.
You need to fix this.
Well, realistically, though that might be a business requirement.
-- You know, and I've seen things like it
-- never is.
The number of times it's a legitimate requirement is very, very small.
Most of the time they just haven't updated
the systems because nobody wants to touch it.
But in fairness,
I would say that also some of these larger companies do
do the more exotic things before they do the basic things.
Because quite frankly
with the way their networks and organizations are set up,
sometimes they can't do or force the basic things,
but they can, for example, have the network group tie down the network, you know,
but you can't force people to upgrade.
There may be instances where that's fair and I'm not going to disagree.
And I guess this is one of those cases where everyone has to look at
what they have and what they're doing and figure out what's best for them.
And, and I feel like we, we often get lost in the weeds.
In fact, I just published my blog post about this.
I was talking about general advice versus targeted advice and like
we love assuming China's hacking us when the reality is, you know,
you have a machine with no login credentials set up over there in the corner.
And it's like
you need to figure out like where is the line of
things we should care about and where's the line of things?
Like, just you can talk about this after work at the pub. But
-- no, we're not spending money on this stuff. Right.
-- Yeah. No, I agree.
It's, I think it goes back to the,
the sort of maturity model that
doesn't really seem to exist very strongly in most organizations.
I agree with that.
You know, that's something I'm, I've been working on.
Hopefully we'll make some progress. But
I think by and large
going back to this,
what really gets me weird is both sides have sort of dug in their heels,
you know, with Apple and Amazon saying absolutely no,
this has not happened in Bloomberg saying, yep, this totally is a legit thing.
But back to a tweet, I sent a few days ago, you know,
extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence.
And in this case, we don't even need extraordinary evidence.
We just need a photograph
or
a
single board to which this happened or,
you know,
is there some guy at Apple, you know, who's going to tweet us being like, oh yeah,
you know, last month we uh
they had us pull like 100,000 server boards and set fire to them in the dumpster.
You know, I feel like if something like that happened,
somebody would have spoken up by now.
-- You
-- know, I think you're right. I think
you can't hide the truth like this. Somebody would leak this.
They're claiming tens of thousands of boards were compromised
and not a single one of them has somehow
somebody got a photograph or smuggled one out and, like, showed it.
-- I wonder, I wonder if you can buy super micro boards off ebay.
-- Yeah.
So,
you know, so, yeah, basically I, until I see
some evidence of this, I,
is this type of thing possible. Absolutely. 100%. Yes.
Is this specific instance of it
correct? And did this happen? I,
I have not been shown any credible evidence, right.
I'm I'm leaning towards no at the moment.
However, if I was unscrupulous,
I just saw you can find many super micro computers off ebay,
you could acquire one and, and we'll say, uh
take some pictures
and gain quite a lot of notoriety by making certain claims about
exactly
the other thing, you know,
where would I get the board level specs for this thing to actually
match up, you know, this component. Yeah, this component. Yeah, this component.
-- Yeah, this component.
-- Where did that come from? We probably can't,
but I would hope Amazon and Apple asked Super Micro for the schematics.
Oh, they wouldn't have to ask, they would I,
I assume the conversation would go like send us the board specs.
I'm not even going to say or else.
Yeah, that's probably fair.
I have a suspicion
that Amazon and Apple
uh there was also if you notice before their very strong denial there was a pretty,
there was a couple of weeks there.
So I have a feeling they did some real work in that time span to do some verification.
Well, this again, if this boils down to, if you say no, and it's true
and somebody shows the evidence that it's very easy to validate that truth,
right? This is kind of like a hashing algorithm
generating the evidence is not super easy but
validating The evidence is generally not rocket science.
-- Yep.
That's right.
Anyway, anyway, so I guess how, how do we want to end this one? Uh Stay afraid,
plausible,
not busted. I like it. I like it.
Oh,
oh my goodness. All right, man. I'm going to end it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to
our
security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
You can find us on social media with the Pound Os S podcast.
-- Hashtag and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks. Bye bye.