-- We're going to call it the Christmas special.
-- Whatever you wanna call it.
Christmas special doesn't sound grand enough to me.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
The Christmas spectacular episode with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Santa Claus.
Ho
ho ho
-- wait, wait. No ho ho homeland Security. Yeah.
-- So um sir, did you pack these bags?
What did sir? Did you pack these bags?
No, I'm Santa Claus. I don't pack my own bags. All right, sir.
-- Do you know, do you know the contents of these bags?
-- Presents for good girls and boys?
-- Who? It sounds like you're not on that list? Uh
-- Are, are these presents wrapped?
-- Some are
-- wrapped?
Uh I'm gonna need to unwrap them and examine them before I can let you in.
What?
That's what it says on the Canadian government website,
traveling with gifts.
If you are traveling with gifts, do not wrap them before crossing the border.
If a gift is wrapped. A BS O Border Services officer
may need to unwrap the gift to examine the goods you are bringing into Canada.
Because what if you're trying to bring kinder eggs?
No, wait, we are allowed, we're allowed to have kinder
eggs.
-- You guys are
-- allowed to
have,
what? Can't I bring to Canada?
I mean? 000, you want, you want, you want that list?
Firearms and weapons, food plants, animals and related products, explosives,
fireworks and ammunition vehicles,
vehicles. What?
Oh.
And consumer
products.
The taxes that could pose a danger to the public.
Eg baby walkers and security beans that are often found in art or bead work
are not allowed to be brought into Canada.
What's
I had to look it up? It's like this weird.
It's a bean
like that. They put on jewelry. It's like this.
-- And
-- what, what's wrong with the bean?
Aris precatory, commonly known as J
security bean or Rosary pea is a herbaceous flowering plant in the bean family
facia. And I apologize for my pronunciation.
It is a slender perennial climber with long
pinnate leaf flitted leaves that Twines around trees, shrubs and hedges.
Oh, so it's like an invasive plant?
Oh, yeah. I don't imagine they do well here in winter though.
You never know, man. Some of these invasive plants are amazing. This is what they do.
Equatorial.
-- So
-- OK, that's fair.
I was, I was not expecting that to go there.
Nor could I stay in character for any period
of time given how absurd the questions were.
But
-- so
-- these are, these are actually like things I've been asked.
Uh No, I, I agree. You do get asked them.
But at the same time, luckily,
Santa illegally crosses the border so he doesn't care.
So
I just assumed he was going to be going
under diplomatic immunity with like a diplomatic bag.
I know
that's a good point. But let's before we go on,
we will,
the, the, the topic of this year's Christmas episode,
which is always my favorite episode of the year is the,
the border security implications of Santa Claus,
which I know in the past we've talked about all kinds of crazy
stuff and it's actually getting harder and harder to come up with ideas.
So if anyone has good ideas, always let us know. But
-- the border implications of Santa Claus.
-- Well, and also the, um,
the transborder, you know, monetary movement stuff because
I know for a fact some people do get, you know,
cash or cash equivalents for Christmas, you know, gift cards.
Let's lay that down, right. You've got people get guns for Christmas.
I'm sure people get drugs for Christmas. People get beer for Christmas.
People get money for Christmas. People get fruit for Christmas.
People get plants for Christmas people get
and animals for Christmas.
Basically, every single thing you're asked at crossing a border
someone is getting for Christmas,
not counting the fact that this man drives a flying sleigh pulled by farm animals.
-- Are
-- they
-- farm animals? I thought they were wild reindeer. Are they wild?
I don't know, they're not wild. They're named you don't name wild animals.
-- Yeah, you can name wild animals.
-- No, you don't name what they're pets or farm.
I don't know. Is,
is the north wall a farm? That's one of the questions I would argue.
It's a reindeer farm and a slave encampment.
-- But I'm sure it could go either way.
-- Ah, reindeers are not fully domesticated.
-- Well,
-- not in the wild. This is Santa Claus. He can do whatever he wants.
No, nowhere.
What would you be? Nowhere
-- you're
-- telling me
domesticated, what does that mean?
It means they're part domesticated.
No.
Look, man, according to this ridiculous narrative,
Santa Claus has domesticated reindeer.
They are named, they can fly
-- and they pull a sled.
-- Well, and one of them has an atomic glowing nose to lead the way.
Right?
And that one you could maybe argue is,
or isn't canon depending upon what you want to do and copyright law and whatever.
But,
right. Anyway,
no, I, seriously, they're, they're easily domesticated and I have no doubt
if you had a cart being pulled by reindeer and you tried to cross any border,
-- they would not let them in.
-- Uh, I don't know. I'd, I'd wanna
maybe between Finland and Russia or vice versa.
Any border with people paying attention to those crossing.
No, I'm just wondering, this guy's customs declaration would be a mess.
There's obvious it doesn't have a custom declaration because Santa Claus
is illegally crossing borders.
You figure when he's on the border between, say America or United States and Canada.
He's not just only staying in the United States and then going back to Canada. Right.
He's got to do some up and down action here.
See,
I've never understood that because everything I've seen generally
says that he goes in some sort of alphabetical order
-- or like door to door.
-- What,
what do you mean? Well, I door to door, chimney to chimney,
chimney, chimney.
And if you don't have a chimney, then whatever, too bad. Right.
But I've also seen movies where he's going in alphabetical order.
Well, I've never seen the delivery in alphabetical order. His list is clearly in
alphabetical order
given every movie ever seen.
Just the fact that you have to organize people in some meaningful
way and alphabetizing their names seems the most reasonable thing to do.
Maybe Santa has quantum computers.
I didn't
-- this last
-- year.
That
one way to anneal the traveling salesman problem
maybe. Or
use
magic, which is the easier
for every problem of, oh, magic does it. It's fine magic.
Maybe he's responsible for global warming. Right.
Because if he's traveling through the night at like mach 1000 or whatever,
infinity, million
MPH,
no,
global warming is the cause of humans
releasing carbon dioxide into the atmosphere.
And
while you're joking,
I don't want that to catch out.
Sadly. True. Yeah, I guess we do.
Yeah, that and, and vaccinations are good for you in general.
So I
probably go with your flu shot folks. Even if it hurts for a day.
-- It does.
-- Good day, man. I was sick for like, three days but whatever. Got it anyway.
-- They're good to get.
-- I think that's just our immune system.
Like, like, I remember being sick as a kid and it wasn't a big deal.
Now, I get like this, like, I've had this head cold for a week.
I hear you. It's getting old sucks. It's dumb. Don't get old kids
don't do right. Anyway,
Santa Claus Crossing borders.
So,
no, I, I was, I was thinking about that
when any of us cross borders,
we get asked all these crazy questions and it occurred to
me that literally Santa Claus violates every single one of them.
-- Absolutely.
-- And that's,
it's kind of wild if you think about it.
I'm still not clear like why prohibited consumer products, baby walkers,
infant self feeding devices, which again,
I had to look up what that was because I've never heard.
What does that count?
As, is that like one of those cups they can hold or is it something else?
Um,
like a fork, fork is a self feeding device.
It's uh it doesn't,
I,
I'm actually not able to find a good definition of what an infant's
self feeding device is and I was googling it for a while.
They all mention it,
but it's like banned.
But yeah, like I, I can't actually like if you, like, if I search Amazon for it,
obviously I'm going to get like a whole bunch of random
stuff that I don't know if that's correct or not.
It wouldn't shock me if it doesn't have like a real definition
just because
there's, there's so much that happens on border control.
It's like airport security where
you don't even know what's going on half the time and
the rules are not clear and I have a feeling they're,
they're ambiguous on purpose
because it gives
that agent
kind of more discretion and power over the people they're having to deal
with which and I'm not going to say it's right or wrong.
It just is what it is.
Well,
if you go down the aisle of like trying to actually define every single illegal act,
you know, to quote Charles Strauss, you end up with laws like, you know,
operating a segue aggressively in a residential neighborhood after 8 p.m.
You're right.
Yes. And I mean, that's the intent behind a lot of the
just law
in the western world is there's that kind of interpretation aspect of it, but
whatever, we're not going to talk about law today because that's boring.
We're talking about Santa Claus illegally crossing borders.
Well, so I'm going to assume he's going to go through like, you know,
those uh portable like truck, X ray scanners, you know,
they have like the big truck with the boom that comes out.
-- No,
-- he's not going to go through anything.
He legally crosses the border, Kurt. He can fly. He doesn't care.
So, I mean, seriously, let's break this down. Ok.
You've got, now, where is the North Pole?
Does the North Pole have a jurisdiction by country?
I don't think any country owns a North Pole, right.
Uh, so magnetic North Pole is in Canada.
Actual geographical North Pole is, it's a block of ice.
-- Yeah,
-- it's over the ocean, right?
For now. It's a block of ice.
Give it a, give it another decade. And
-- that's
-- right.
That's right.
So, ok, so we all know that Santa Claus lives on the geographical North Pole,
not the magnetic North pole.
So he is
in a region that has no allegiance to a country. So obviously Santa is a rogue nation
that violates countless laws every single Christmas.
Well, probably outside of Christmas as well because I, I imagine he travels
outside of that.
Maybe.
Well, no labor laws don't apply when you're a rogue nation cart,
you can do whatever you want.
So, enslaving those elves is probably technically not illegal. Although
I have a suspicion once you bring your goods into another country,
there are certain laws and regulations you have
to follow many of which he's no doubt.
-- Breaking.
-- Wait, is any of his stuff ul tested or listed?
It has stickers on it.
What does that mean? Well, no, no, no.
Like if it's underwriter, like is all,
all the electronic stuff he makes and all the batteries
he makes are those actually safety certified and tested or is
he just some random guy making millions and billions of batteries
every year that hopefully don't catch your house on fire?
Well, that's the question. Right.
Is there also massive IP theft occurring here
where Santa and his band of enslaved elves
are copying something,
someone else made and duplicating it to the point that the forgery has
the UL stickers and prints on all the products in the boxes.
I don't know.
Let's assume for the moment we will ignore that particular
facet of this because I think the intellectual property theft.
Yeah, I, well, the IP theft, it's
uh
at
least he's not making money doing this.
-- So there is that sort of moral side of it like he's doing this as a charity,
-- right?
Is it? I don't know what's the purpose behind it? I don't know what the angle is here.
-- Do
-- I
-- have to cut Santa check? Now? Is that something I've been missing out on?
That? Sounds like a heck of a deal.
But I don't know. We'll, we'll ignore that.
Although, no,
I believe the historical purpose of Santa was
a benevolent person who would reward the good
and in, in some, some cultures,
there was a partner who had punished the bad where obviously you've
got uh Krampus who is the best bad guy at Christmas ever.
-- So,
-- yeah, for those of you wondering about Santa's sidekick.
We've discussed him on previous podcast.
But needless to say there's a lot of these old cultural tales were not
terribly sensitive. Shall we say?
Krampus?
Krampus is a wholesome character. All he just what eats the Children?
It's fine that I'm, I'm comfortable with that.
I can get behind that.
I know a lot of kids that I wouldn't complain if a monster ate them. So I'm fine.
It's fine. It's fine. Krampus. We can live it anyway. Anyway.
Yeah, exactly. Some days I wish he'd eat my kids, but some days
-- we've all been there.
-- Does he? Politicians?
-- Uh
-- oh, man, that'd be so nice. That would be so nice.
Send Krampus to Washington DC and it would fix all of our problems,
you
-- know,
-- when you left,
right,
you probably have a bad case of politician indigestion like poor krampus.
It was a good effort anyway. Anyway. Ok.
So we're going to assume Santa has no
claim to any one nation,
which also means Santa Claus can't have a passport.
Right?
If he's, well, he could be a stateless individual. Yes.
And, but if you're a stateless individual, how does that work?
I, I don't understand that.
So if you're a stateless individual,
you can get like an emergency passport from a variety of countries.
It's, I forget what color is. I want to say yellow. I know diplomatic is white.
Regular is blue. I think it's, oh, gray, sorry. I think gray.
Is the kind of the emergency one. Anyways you can get,
if you are a stateless individual,
you can get travel documents because this actually happens more than it.
Well, should, I mean,
some of it is people get their citizenship revoked and they only have membership,
you know, citizenship of a single state or in some cases.
Well, I mean, uh uh, what's his face?
-- Uh, Tom Hanks the movie where he lives in the airport for a while,
-- the terminal.
I think
I never saw it but I'm familiar with it.
There have been cases where, like, I'm a, you know, I'm a citizen of a country that,
whoops, it stopped existing
and I didn't get any new paperwork.
Ok. That's fair. Well, actually I didn't know this, I looked this up a while back but
I,
I don't know if other countries have this but I could denounce
my US citizenship and become not a citizen of the United States,
-- but you can't do it for tax purposes.
-- No. Right. There's,
-- yes,
-- they figure that one out.
Yeah. Good for them.
I know.
And funny enough that's not why I looked it up but now that you say it,
I chuckle at that because I,
I was talking to some friends about such things where
there's obviously countries with the tax rate is really high.
And I was like, well, can't you just, like, pretend to move to some other country?
And they said, oh, no, they they have that figured out like you can't,
and there's all these protections they have around
not pretending to move somewhere else and become a different citizen.
-- Just so you don't have to pay high tax,
-- how many days of residency and so on.
That's right. That's right. Exactly.
Anyway, ok, so let's even if he has a travel document,
well, in fairness,
he doesn't necessarily need a travel document because for example,
the Queen of England does not have a passport.
No, Kurt, he doesn't need it because he's illegally entering all of these countries
like that.
But let's let's pretend for a minute
that Santa Claus
is going to try to legally enter a country from where he is, right?
So first of all,
you have to enter at a, a port,
you can't just go in wherever you want, right?
And there's obviously certain places you can enter in certain places you can't.
So if he's coming from the North Pole into basically any country,
you're going to have to fly out over international waters first
and then
enter the country
at some port
and I don't know the rules, but I have a suspicion,
an unknown aircraft can't just enter the airspace of any country they want to go to.
They generally frown upon that. Like I know
there's a lot of internal flights within Canada that go to Toronto,
obviously being the heart of Canada.
And you know, Toronto is pretty much to the South and sort of surrounded by the US on,
well, 2.5 ish, it's
kind of like dips down
the
leg.
And so
those flights that go through, they go through American airspace,
they have to send the passenger manifest, you know, to America.
So there's people that have been refused
boarding on a flight because they're on the US, no fly list.
Even though they're flying from
a Canadian city to another Canadian city.
I didn't know that was a thing actually because when I,
I fly from Detroit a lot to different places and like, when I fly Detroit to Boston,
we're totally going over Canadian airspace
-- most of the time
-- we
relaxed about these things.
Interesting.
I didn't realize that that's why I, I suppose that sort of makes sense because
you figure if you're flying from,
say Detroit to Boston and you have a problem over the top of Toronto,
you're landing there.
Right.
Well, more to the point
they've quasi
entered America.
It's, it's one of those things where, you know, it's like a legal fiction of like, ok,
you're entering America.
So we're going to have, you know, some interest in it.
But we also acknowledge from like a rational sane perspective,
we're obviously not going to enforce border
controls because you fly through our airspace because
to fly around our airspace would add, you know, 1015,
20 minutes to the journey and just generally be a pain in the butt.
Right.
So,
yeah, I mean,
I, I get it, you know, it's, it's,
the world is complicated, you know, not all
everything's
-- squiggly lines.
-- So,
so,
problem number one
is Santa Flies. He's going to have to find a way to not fly
to a port of entry in the country.
Well, he's also violating airspace rules, all sorts of, I mean,
what, what's this craft classified as? Anyways,
a sled? Like, is it a small engine or is it a multi engine?
-- Like there's what, how many Reindeer
-- Reindeer multi engine? Eight plus one? Yeah.
So,
yeah, it's a nine engine craft and I'm pretty sure that, you know,
-- like does he fly under visual flight rules
-- is a reindeer an engine?
Well, I don't know, I mean,
what if I want to take my, my horse drawn carriage to Canada?
What, what does that count as a vehicle? Can I?
Well, if your horse and carriage fly, I feel like, you know,
now
is going to want to have words with you?
I mean, that's fair too.
You can't write like I'm gonna just wheel my airplane across the border, right?
-- They're gonna be like, no, you're, you're not doing it.
-- I don't
-- think
-- you can
put a land crossing in a Cessna 172, like put, putting along.
I wonder, that's a good question. I bet it's,
I bet it's never been done before.
I feel like they're gonna have a lot of pointed questions for you.
I would hope so, but that's the least,
that would be the least weird question just for the record.
Ok.
So, ok, so let's assume Santa Claus can somehow get to
the customs on a port of entry coming from international,
something right out of waters, airspace, whatever.
-- Yeah. Well, you could just land at an airport
-- and
can you though, can you just radio? Does he have a radio? I don't know.
I will assume he does.
Well, he's got,
he's got radios as gifts. Right. I mean, people get radios as gifts, you know,
aircraft radio.
I'm sure,
I'm sure somebody does.
Somebody does. That's right.
And his right, his intellectual property thieving factory could just make one.
So we'll assume he has a radio.
Why not?
So, I wonder how that works.
Can you just, like,
-- be an aircraft and show up and say I need to land at your airport
-- in an emergency?
That happens all the time, right.
Like you divert to an airport and it's like we're landing here now,
except this wouldn't be an emergency. All right.
So we're, we're, we're rat holing ourselves.
Oh, maybe what if the, one of the reindeer has to go to the bathroom?
We're 20 minutes in and we haven't even entered a country.
This is a nightmare.
So, well, I mean, the thing is he's going to land at an airport
and, you know, like they're going to send out a customs agent to
have
a
-- chat with him. Great.
-- Let's say he lands at an airport.
That's just easiest then you have, right?
Customs people are going to show up and be like, what's the deal?
Yo, fat man with a bunch of reindeer.
And so the way I see it,
imagine filling out that customs form.
When we fill out a customs form,
you're supposed to list like every individual thing.
I mean, what does Santa write? Like Christmas gifts, like,
you know, estimated value infinity. Pretty much
it's
more money than you have. I,
I
mean, in all seriousness,
I bet the worldwide share of Christmas gifts
share in a value equal to most countries.
GDP.
-- Si suspect that's safe to say
-- probably,
I bet if you move down probably to number 8 to 10 on the list of GDP,
that's probably the amount of money we're talking about, which is,
which is kind of nuts if you think about it worldwide. Of course, for Christmas. Ok.
So Santa gets at an airport,
customs people come out,
they're going to, I guess first of all, what you're going to
potentially need a visa because I assume
if you're traveling on country list documents,
even if you're just transiting, right?
Like uh for example, you know,
Americans will fly to Vancouver to get on in on a cruise ship.
Well, you,
you know, from my,
from my binge watching of, you know, Canada border controls
if you're inadmissible to Canada.
Because for example, you have like a criminal history or something.
Yeah, tough. We're not letting you get on that cruise ship.
You're, you know, getting bounced back.
Well, yeah, I mean, I would totally expect that even if you're getting on a boat,
it still counts as entering the country,
regardless of whether he's staying or just transiting.
He's, yeah, they're, they're going to want to see a visa or something,
you know, I, I imagine a piece of paper with, I am Santa.
It is allowed, is not going to cut it for them.
I have a note for Mrs Claus.
Right. Right. Exactly. So, now you've got nine deer.
Oh, they're going to need to be quarantined for, uh,
I think horses are quarantined for a week or two.
Yeah. Right. You can't just bring animals into a country for fun. I know my,
my brother used to live in Europe and he had some cats and he looked into
what it would take to bring them back to the United States and it was,
it was bonkers what it took to.
I mean, it was honestly,
it was cruel and unusual because they basically were
locked up in a cage for like a month.
Yeah.
It's funny because my, my sister's cat is American and actually he,
he's been across the border probably at least 50 or 60 times because she used to
work in the US, but, you know,
travel back to Canada a lot and so she'd take her cat back and forth with her.
And honestly,
she would bring all the paperwork for this guy with all his shots and everything and
they really didn't mind that much.
It's a cat in Canada, like these are nine deer
that can fly.
That's true. Reindeer are not just deer.
Oh,
we might have to put some of them down and examine
their brains to make sure they don't have that wasting disease.
Chronic wasting disease,
chronic wasting disease is a huge problem actually where I live
in
it's becoming really bad. And, yeah, I mean, that's completely fair.
I would not be shocked at all if you can't even transport deer
across a border right now. Just because of all the disease.
I imagine it takes a lot of paperwork,
uh, maybe. And, but, but the thing is you said you might have to put some of them down.
You could have 30 deer
and you could kill half of them and test them.
And that says nothing about the other half
because that's just how that disease works.
It's spread in bizarre ways.
Ok.
So
this is harder than I thought this is really hard.
All right.
So
we'll assume he can land. We'll assume you could fill out the right paperwork.
We'll,
we'll say that the customs officials might be willing to turn a blind eye
to the fact that it is Santa Claus and they're familiar with his deer
and they aren't going to stay
ok.
Or I guess if Santa was smart, he would build animatronic reindeer.
We could have the cyber deer. We'll call them
-- cyber
-- deer. I can work with that.
Yeah,
that way you don't have to worry about getting them into the country.
But even then
you have to think
there are countless things you can bring into one country and not another.
Like you said, Canada,
obviously you can't have firearms like we have in the United States.
Well, no, you can import firearms and ammunition. It's just you're going to need
a paper.
So
there are firearms you can't own in Canada, I can.
-- Oh,
-- well, yeah, there are, well, there's, there's nonrestricted, restricted,
prohibited.
And then, yeah, then there's a bunch that are just straight up, completely illegal,
right? And, and Europe is another example, there are tons of places in Europe.
You can't own handguns,
right?
And,
and you figure so, so Santa is going to have to put some, it's, it's,
I guarantee
you can't plan a delivery route that would drop off certain goods
in certain countries because like, obviously you could say, oh, well,
just go to America first and unload the guns.
But then you can't have things like your giant bag of dope you're giving to your
friend for Christmas or which in Canada that he even in parts of the US,
that's legal, right?
-- Just some places it's
-- not at
the state level.
Well, and as we're calling constantly reminded, in Canada, you know,
even if you're flying to a US state where it's legal,
it's not legal at the federal border.
And the same thing for Canada, right? Uh,
marijuana is legal federally
in Canada.
But you, you, uh for example,
as an American driving to Canada still can't bring pot with you.
So actually funny you say that is, I was recently in Toronto for a meeting
and the, the Canadian customs people asked me if I had any marijuana,
the American Customs people did not.
So I was coming from the place where it was
illegal being asked by the people where it's legal if I
have any and then going from the place where it's
legal to the place where it's illegal and they're like,
whatever, don't care
anyway, which I did not smuggle dope across the border.
-- That's exactly what a smuggler would say. Or
-- Santa.
That's right. That's exactly what a smuggler. Yeah, man. You know,
the
potential cost of doing that is sky high. It would be,
it would be foolish
anyway. Anyway. Ok, because you think about it.
So, uh, kinder eggs are my favorite example.
Kinder eggs are legal in the United States,
which I think is the dumbest law in the world
because kinder eggs are like my favorite thing ever.
The, the law is back to 1920 it's, you can't have
a
food object covered.
Don't care.
I want kinder eggs then they should, they should amend the law to say,
except for kinder eggs.
I have some bad news for you. Kinder eggs.
I mean, I've bought them over the last few years and the toys in them are terrible.
Now,
they're getting worse. But I don't care because I don't have them.
So they're like, they're, they're the, they're the chalice.
I can not quite reach, I want them. Right.
And if I had them I'd be like, yeah, they're not that good and I'd probably
buy them,
but because I can't have them, I want them more than anything.
That's fair.
I know. Hey,
that's like me with certain things that in America you can buy at the
corner store and here are very hard to find or whatever wheat grits.
I cannot buy wheat grits in Canada. Reasonably corn grits. Yeah. Absolutely.
But like, just like a box of an
Mima wheat grits.
Seriously,
dude, you can't find him.
And it's so funny once I remember there was a
Toronto Raptor from the US and they were interviewing his mom
about, you know, what do you think about life in Canada because she moved up with him.
Right.
Because he's like a young kid or whatever. And she's like, can't find wheat grits.
Like we have to buy them in Detroit and bring them back with us.
And I'm like, are you kidding me? Like,
yeah.
And, and it's not like Canada doesn't, you know,
grow and export a ridiculous amount of wheat No, we just don't have wheat grits.
It's the weirdest damn thing ever because I love them.
I'll mail you a box of wheat grits. Like,
yeah, just make sure you declare what they are.
Can't you buy them off Amazon or something?
Well, yeah, but, you know, they won't, uh,
typically they don't ship food stuff to Canada without
it costing a freaking arm and a leg.
Oh,
really? Oh. So, like
-- Amazon? Canada doesn't even sell them
-- wheat grits. $15 for a box of, yeah.
-- No, I'm not paying 15 bucks for a box of
-- grits. I bet I can buy that for like a buck.
And then my next choice.
My next choice is Palmetto farms.
Yellowstone ground grits, two pounds, non GMO, $67.
Holy crap.
-- So it can be.
-- This is like, this is my future calling.
Kurt is smuggling wheat grits into Canada.
That's already a thing with Trader Joe's.
There's a bunch of Canadians that drive down to the US,
buy a whole pile of stuff at Trader Joe's.
Bring it back up to Canada.
You know, they declare it, pay tax on it, whatever and then mail it around because
there's a whole pile of products you just cannot get in Canada. That
nutter butters.
I dare you to try and find a nutter butter in Canada.
Seriously. They're not even that good.
No,
I need
to get your
from Nutter Butter fan. All right. Anyway, anyway, we're,
this is a hard topic because it's so easy to rat hole here. All right. So,
I guess
we're, we're,
we're running ourselves out of time and I don't want to
spend two hours talking about the bizarre nature of border control.
But I think fundamentally
so it's safe to say
if, if Santa can get himself legally landed,
he's gonna struggle. There's no way he can get all of his items
through a country's
border, border control. And
he, he's going to have to stay within certain regions.
Let's say he makes multiple trips back home to refill with, with illicit materials,
given where you're at, you'd have to make multiple trips basically for, well,
I should say multiple trips, but you have to make like one trip per country,
right? Because every country is going to have different enough laws.
Well, but also by state and by, well, once you get into the Schengen Zone, you're OK.
That's true by state
actually by states even crazier because you think
if you are, if Santa Claus, let's say, has to enter the United States
and he's got a huge bag of weed that he's got to deliver,
then you've got, you can't get in obviously with that because no,
no customs official is going to let you in.
But then even if you were in, there's states like Colorado, for example,
which is marijuana is legal, but all the surrounding states are illegal.
So there's like there, there's physically no way
that Santa Claus could get to Colorado with his giant bag of Christmas weed
and get that delivered without breaking federal law.
Well, and state laws
-- and
-- state laws. Yes. Exactly.
Yeah.
I'm pretty sure the state trooper is going to want to pull somebody over with,
you know, 11,000 pounds of weed or whatever.
-- He's
-- flying. You can't, you can't pull him over. He's flying. It's fine.
So, ok, so fundamentally, we've, you know what,
I think we've proved that there is no way for
Santa to legally operate within the jurisdiction of a country.
He has to be like a rogue smuggler that only operates under the cover of darkness,
which explains everything.
Yep. Pretty much.
There we go.
Also by, by GDP,
just alone in the US. So the US spending on, on Christmas is just a bit over 700 billion
and that alone would put it at the number
-- for GDP
-- globally. And I, I bet the worldwide
-- Christmas spending is probably double. That is my guess.
-- Yeah.
And that would put you around number 10 or 11
for GDP.
Like, basically that would put you ahead of Russia.
Yeah, that's,
that's crazy. And he's got that in his sleigh which flies once a year. That's right.
Once a year. That's, wow, that's madness. I didn't realize it was that high now.
Although, although at the same time,
Santa isn't delivering all of the presents because
obviously there's certain gift exchanges and whatnot So
I bet we could probably assume at least half of that is not Santa gifts,
maybe more, maybe less. But I bet half of it.
So, yeah, that puts us at what 18 in GDP is what Santa is delivering.
So there we have it. All right. So things we have decided on this podcast,
Santa can't possibly enter a country.
It was
Santa is, is clearly a criminal
and that is all right.
Yep.
There's literally no legal framework under which there's literally nothing
you could do under any framework to pull this off.
There's, there's no way he could be compliant.
We should all write
our government representatives and demand
that they, they pass a law legalizing
Santa's Christmas time
illegal border crossing night of Terror.
-- That is what we should do. Like
-- a 24 hour window where he gets off scot free.
Right. It could be like that Star Trek episode.
Remember the Arcon where there's like the one, once a year they have their festival
and everyone goes crazy for 12 hours.
I forget the name of their festival. It might just be called Festival.
But with Landrieu the computer, which is one of the, and that's some,
someday we'll talk about that.
But I love the old star Treks where Captain Kirk outsmarts computers
a lot
just as no one knows.
Yes.
That's right.
And it always explodes, which is marvelous. I love that. But anyway, anyway. Ok.
All right, man. I,
I don't even know what to say. I feel like this started
-- harder than I expected.
-- I feel bad that we killed Santa.
We didn't kill him.
We just proved he's a criminal,
which I think we all suspected deep in our hearts anyway.
So
I'm comfortable with this. Right. Like it's, there's obviously something wrong,
at the very least the amount of IP theft going on is astronomical.
Not counting the fact that he clearly has slave labor doing all of this work.
And he's,
I don't know if his reindeer are trapped or not, but whatever,
-- whatever
-- doesn't matter.
-- Well, they are animals. That's tough. That's being a cart horse.
-- Right.
Well, you didn't, you just say you can't domesticate a reindeer.
-- No,
-- I said they're semi domesticated. I don't even know
-- what that
-- means.
So, for example, zebras are so fundamentally ill tempered,
even with selective breeding, they cannot be domesticated.
-- They are just such utter and complete nasty animals.
-- Oh, I see. So, like
I,
-- a semi domesticated could be like they live in a fenced area.
-- Yeah.
And you can get them to, like, pull a cart.
But, you know, I feel like it's not like a horse where you can have, you know, uh,
we went to the, the, what is it, the nights table thing in Vegas.
And I mean, they had a couple of horses there that,
wow, like the tricks those horses were doing, you know, they made dressage
horses look like drunks
-- and
-- I don't know a lot about horses, but I know, like,
when you get them to walk sideways and stuff like that, that's a big deal.
But
when you get them to prance sideways
in time to the music.
Yeah. Right. Right. Well, it probably just looked like it.
Maybe they adjust the music to match the horse. I don't know. Anyway. Anyway.
All right, I'm gonna,
we have to end this because we're terrible people. And
-- that's the moral of the story we fit in well, in the security industry
-- and Children.
We didn't actually Santa's real. This is all just been a terrible dream.
-- Go back to sleep. We,
-- we've said nothing that
would ruin
the Christmas Magic Cart.
I'm, I'm comfortable with this episode.
This, this does not need a spoiler tag at the beginning for small Children.
Anyway.
Yes, kids. But go ask your parents where babies come from. So,
thank you.
I did not, I do not endorse this man's views.
I'm comfortable with this.
All right, cool.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you ever for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com. I don't even think we have shown nuts for this.
We'll figure something out. You can use the Found Os S podcast hashtag
to hit us up on social media. You are welcome to let us know we are terrible people.
We are well aware of this.
So I guess Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too, everybody. I'm sorry.
Thanks, everyone. Have a great Christmas. Bye bye.