Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers
-- every now and then.
I'm extremely grateful
that nobody but me has access to the free roll before we start the show.
And today is one of those days.
-- Anyway.
-- I honestly,
I suspect a lot of people's heads would explode.
Like, I always remember 20 some years ago,
I, I'd written the Linux
Administrative Security Guide and I would be talking with
people and they kind of ask me like,
what do you think about windows?
And I'm like, oh, I really like NT four,
whatever. You know, I've got an M CS C in it and I really, I really quite like NT four.
-- It works really well and they'd be like, what?
-- NT sucks. I disown you
-- anyway.
-- Yeah. Well, it sucked way less than the Windows 3.11.
Well,
-- that's not a valid comparison in any universe. It
-- was back in 1999
sorry Windows 95. But I like in fairness,
I had a Linux desktop and a Windows NT desktop. It was a good world.
I,
I won't lie back in the early days I
kept a Windows machine handy to play games because there
just weren't any games on Linux.
We had X
Lander,
-- man.
-- I love that game. I forgot all about X Lander.
I should, I should fire that sucker up.
They have a really, they used to or they still have it,
I think at the local kids science museum, like they have X Lander,
but they have like a nice chunky throttle and like,
you know what I mean? Like, they have nice kind of controls for it,
you know, and of course everybody just destroys themselves,
which is,
uh, like software signing.
It's just,
you know, I love watching.
That was a good Twitter thread.
It, it's, it's probably not done yet, but it is. So
I'll give some background, an old friend, Mark Borstein
who is the CTO at Tremolo I think is what he's doing. He, he has
a, he's part of a company called Tremolo. They do,
they kind of did single sign on before a single sign on existed.
It was,
I remember way back in the early days. Oh, that's right.
Yeah. Right. Right.
The big claim to fame was you could
ssh into a machine without having an account on the machine. Basically. Andreola
did the magic on the back end, which was unheard of back in those days these days.
It's like, oh, whatever everyone could do that. But it was a huge deal. Anyway,
Mark sent a message on Twitter to us basically saying something.
It, it was a public message right now like ad
and I don't even remember. We should probably look this up.
-- So I don't,
-- we'll link to it.
Well, we got to explain what it is.
We should probably read what we're talking
-- about
-- and that's never stopped us before.
Like
yeah, what, what can copyright do for you?
Uh That one will never die.
-- It pleases me so good
-- one.
It appears we actually learned a lesson from our mistake, which is, I think that's,
that's the part where most people they don't get there.
That's fair. That, that's another topic I think. But
so Mark asked us to do an episode on artifacts signing and its impact.
Has it helped in the past?
What will it protect in the future? Lots of hype any data
and this enormous threat ensued.
And my assumption was we wouldn't talk about this for a long time. And then
Kurt convinced me we should,
-- which is fair.
-- Here's one simple thing, one very specific part of
any data. And the answer is no.
So
it's not like waiting is gonna, we're gonna magic up some data.
Well, that's exactly what we do.
I mean, I'm working on N PM data right now, which is fascinating by the way.
But like it, it, it can be done. It is hard though, I will say like it's, it's
the N PM work I'm doing is probably going to be three months. So like
signing data is if we're talking most likely
something in the neighborhood of a year,
if I can even figure out what to look for.
Well,
I was about to say the problem with signing data is you need to
look for incidences where it either saved people or it didn't save people.
So, I mean, like that's, that's exactly the point,
right is
you
bring up, I think that the crux of it all is
like, what, what is the point of signing data?
And I don't think if you read this enormous Twitter thread,
it's clear that that's not even particularly understood and it
feels like that should be a really easy answer,
-- but it's actually not when you think
-- about
it. There's a good answer. I'm going to read.
I'm actually going to quote myself from October 23rd of 2000.
-- Want that meme
-- of Obama giving Obama a medal like
Kurt says this is the best answer from Kurt,
but the thing is, here's the thing,
KTS
Free Security Advisory number two KSS A 002 History of Advisory October
23rd 2001 while downloading Red Hat 7.2 not Red Hat Enterprise Linux,
but like Red Hat 7.2.
Curtsy free noticed various packages were not Gnupg signed.
Wait, is this a real advisory
that that you, you name yourself in the third person in this advisory?
Yes, I do.
Anyways, Terry loves yogurt.
So basically, here we go. And this is why it matters.
Red Hat 7.2 distribution files on popular FTP sites such as ftp.ibo.org
and Mirrors dot HPC F dot U Pr dot Eu are not signed
then blah, blah, blah. Oh, yeah.
And here it is unlikely that this is an attack as the
number of sites involved make it likely someone would have to,
would have noticed and notified the community.
Either Red Hat did not sign these packages or someone subverted
the distribution process before the files got to various sites.
For Red Hat 7.1 please note that all files were correctly
signed with the Red Hat G and UPG security key.
And then basically they went, oh yeah,
what's somehow didn't sign these and they went and signed them.
And then my understanding is, you know,
that's one of the reasons when I worked at Red Hat.
Remember we had all those gates for a package going out and one of those gates was,
is this thing signed, signed,
-- this establishes two important things.
-- There's something
way more important we have to touch on here first.
So
you have
security advisories on your website, which I did not know.
I've known you a long time and this is the first time finding out,
but I see 12345 and 10, what happened to six through nine?
-- Uh That's a good question. I don't know
-- like this is bothering
-- me five,
-- last updated
January 21st of 2002, but the copyright is Kurt siefried 2001 on the website.
This is intriguing to me. Um Anyway, ok, sorry, I'm not going to dwell on this.
This will be a topic for another day.
But I want to say that this establishes two very important things around signing and
basically number one that we've been doing software signing for over 20 years,
right. So
it's kind of one of those.
It's been, we've been doing it for so long. Why do we do it? We do it because we do it.
And number two, in this specific case, there was a good reason for software signing,
which is simply put Red Hat could not afford to
run a content distribution network back in the day.
Nobody could. Right? And literally
the majority of open source software distributed
around the world was done through.
Uh Well, one of the biggest ones was, you know,
a university with like a sun site or an FTP server that somebody
managed to convince the admin to like dedicate a couple of gigs of space
for mirrors of stuff or they mirrored it themselves
for their own stuff and just made it public.
Yeah. Right.
Like when I worked at Progeny Linux systems, we ran archive.progeny.com,
which was a modest sized machine. You didn't need huge machines to do all this.
And we had,
I think back then it might have been a couple 100 megabits.
-- Everybody's internet was so slow.
-- Yeah. Right. Right.
And it was like, modem speeds.
And I remember we got, I don't remember the internet provider,
but they basically said
if you drop a machine,
we'll give you the cable.
And then we obviously hosted Progeny Linux,
which was the Linux distribution as well as we mirrored,
like Debian and the kernel and some other stuff.
And,
yeah. Yeah, that was perfectly normal back then.
Like everyone, I shouldn't say everyone, but lots of, lots of organizations,
lots of companies ran mirrors and, and that was like the poor man CD N, right?
The intent was
you would just run all the, these mirrors
and then all the software would be distributed like in the case of, for example,
things like
Debbie and Apt or Red hats back then. It was um,
Yum
Yum Yum was the first one.
-- It just kind of like randomly picks a
-- mirror.
-- The yellow dog update manager.
-- Yeah.
-- But now it's called DNF which stands for, I don't know
-- what
Yum Yum stands for yellow dog update manager. Yellow dog Linux invented. Yum.
-- Yeah, I know. But
-- what is now they, it's called DNF. What does that stand for?
I don't even know.
I don't know. It doesn't matter anyway.
Right? Ok.
So now there's also another piece to what you just described,
which is bug 998 and Fedora's Bugzilla.
This is emblazoned into my mind. It's closed now.
But fundamentally, it was the same sort of thing of how do you kind of provide trust
in the things that are being distributed from
years and functionally back in the day,
you couldn't, it got closed kind of accidentally?
-- Well,
-- and to remember too,
back in 2001, a GP G signature with a detached signature file.
So like you had file and then file dot sig with the GP G signature in it,
that was considered very sophisticated.
Like that was,
you know, like open BS D did that, you know, you had like blah, blah, blah dot T
dot GZ and blah, blah blah dot Well,
the check sums or whatever and then the GP G
signature of the check sums or whatever it was,
I forget, but that was considered like, whoa you're doing real security here,
you know. And of course, no, it's, it's that, that's ridiculous
because you had to hand check signatures, you had to hand, get the keys, you had to,
it was really a lot of this was in your face.
There was no magic of it just worked, although it was starting to just work.
And the funny thing is like every false positive as far as I know was always, I,
I don't ever remember any
real attacks on signed software apart from like maybe two
that got spotted pretty quickly because
either it wasn't signed or
it was signed improperly or something.
The other thing that would always happen is a mirror would get hacked.
Someone would just replace stuff on the mirror
and
people would download it and the signature would fail and half the time you like, oh,
whatever, just force install anyway.
Or in the case of downloading like a tar ball,
no one ever checks those signatures even though they're.
And so now, now all of this. Ok.
So there's all this weird history that I don't want to spend
a ton of time on because I don't think it's as interesting.
-- But the question kind of becomes,
-- here's my supposition.
This is why we still do software signing.
-- It's we haven't moved on, we haven't solved any new problems.
-- Well, OK.
This is the set up to that, right?
Like why we do a thing because we do a thing, I think in this instance. And
so one of the questions in that thread
is so now that we have things like HTTP S virtually everywhere, right?
We have the ability to do cer certain verification.
If I have a system that reaches out to say a server on HTTP S downloads,
just a sha checksum for a thing
and checks the thing, the artifact versus the sha checksum that's been downloaded.
Is that any different,
-- then? Say signing an R PM?
-- Yes, there is a slightly different attack path which is
if I'm going to attack a signed file,
I need and assuming people don't just like YOLO and like, oh, whatever,
it's a different key or their keys.
Not, right. And they ignore it right.
But assuming that they have a copy of the public key
and actually use that public key correctly to verify it,
then I have to attack the private key. Whereas with the file and check some, I
by getting access to, you know, ftp.pressers.org or whatever,
I can replace both those files.
Can, you,
here's the thing if I gain access to
ftp.pressers.org and you're just doing check sums,
I can replace the file and the check sum.
If I break into ftp.pressers.org and you're doing software signing,
I still have to go get the private key.
My domain is actually breast.net.
Oh, sorry
breasts.org might be owned by someone else. I don't think I own that.
Sorry,
I
feel bad for there to be a server.
-- I
-- don't want to spam someone. So
yeah,
so, but that's the thing, right? So software signing in theory adds the
step of you have to get at the private key.
And then again, in a perfect circle cow world,
that private key is very strongly secured, like, you know,
your SSH key and its bank vault or whatever
you're talking about a very specific type of attack.
I just mean, generally speaking,
assuming
nothing is being attacked, the infrastructure is acceptable
is downloading a check sum
over http S
as trustworthy as having
a signed artifact that I also need a public key for.
And then you also have to obviously verify the public key and do all that stuff.
It is not as trustworthy. It's, uh, it's a different form of trust, right?
Because is it
in the, in the check some scenario?
There's no, there's no private key to be protected? There's just the,
-- some file and the file, but
-- it's coming over HTTP S which is a trusted,
right?
But they have the same, it's like having
two passwords instead of one password.
They have the same failure scenario, they have the same attack path.
Whereas if I have a password and a one time authenticator,
that's a different attack path.
That makes it, that's the theory behind this right is
if I have to replace
one file, well, replacing two files isn't any harder than replacing one file.
But if I have to replace a file and get it a private key, that's a different attack.
That that's more work for the attacker right now.
Having said that there's actually a really good example of where this matters is,
remember there's that software that will do interception
of like binary downloads and like staple on a
software and stuff,
right?
So, yeah,
we definitely need stuff secured in transit
because there's I SPS that will literally,
oh, you're downloading exc let me help you with that.
A check sum solves that problem.
Yes.
Well,
it, but no, it does not because
they could also intercept the check sum and rewrite the check sum.
If, basically, if they can rewrite the software, they can rewrite the check sum,
-- which
-- I don't think, but I don't think that's a practical attack anymore.
I think you're, you're, you're movie plotting this whole discussion at this point.
I think, I think
-- everything is hetps now.
-- Right.
But what I'm pointing out is I don't care about the transit so much
as I care about the, the, the server
delivering it because people get that wrong all the time.
Like people break into S3 buckets and servers like that's not a movie plot threat.
People break into that stuff.
And so the idea with a private key is, yeah, you broke into my FTP server man.
That's kind of a bummer.
But hey, you can't sign my stuff because I have my key secured now.
-- But that doesn't matter because most people don't secure their keys.
-- Right. Right.
So
I, I look,
I don't disagree with you, but I don't think your argument is,
is as strong as it sounds like it really is.
Oh, no, no, no. To be clear, I'm not arguing for or against signing.
I'm just trying to point out what the different attack paths are and why it,
why the perception is that it's harder or in theory,
it's harder because you have to attack the file and attack a key.
But I would say in fairness, most keys are not very well secured
-- or
-- a lot of signatures never get checked either.
Yes.
And I've had that happen where I remember, um,
Sousa sent out an advisory that was mis signed
and I replied to them and they said it's
basically like two or three people asked what's up,
out of, you know, thousands.
Yeah. Nobody checked that stuff. Well, or they check it and they ignore it because
it's,
let me put it this way.
How many times does a person walk through a metal detector at airport security?
And it's actually like a bad person with a bad thing.
It's pretty rare versus sir, you have to take your belt off,
right?
And that's the thing like 99.9% of these signature fass
are
like a cosmic ray hit it or
like red hat forgot to sign packages or whatever.
Well, let me, let me ask you another question. How many instances
do you know of
where a successful attack
evaded
properly? Signed artifacts? Generally speaking,
most attacks are
-- solar winds would be won but
-- solar winds that got signed.
Oh,
-- you mean sorry, you're saying evaded properly signed,
-- right?
Like here's the thing,
the vast majority of attacks we see are happening prior to the signature stage.
And I think the number of times an attack happens after a signature
-- is very rare. Like, I don't know, I can't think of any.
-- Well, and see,
I think the reason for that is because attacking the thing post signature.
Well,
you just replace the file and kind of hope the person
ignores the bad signature and just jams it in with,
you know.
Yeah, really force it.
Like, because hey, like literally solar winds told people that they're like, hey,
this file is not properly signed.
Yeah, just like smash that like button and make it work.
But also I would point out for the for the Attackers that are very sophisticated,
they just go after the signing certificates and keys, right?
Like if you Google stolen driver signatures, there's
actually way more than I expected. Like I know it happens every once in a while.
No, that that's very common actually.
But I mean, so this is a great example because what usually happens is, for example,
in the Windows world,
you have
some sort of, you have like obviously Microsoft owns like the root C A
and then they work with
certificate authorities be it like literally the same people doing
SSL certs generally where if you want your binary signed,
you go to them,
you get your key signed by their key, right? Typical C A universe stuff.
And then you can sign drivers and that key that gets
signed or you see instances where bad guys just get their
keys signed by AC A because the checking isn't that impressive
and then they can sign things using that infrastructure and then
basically implant malware and windows using completely official channels.
Well, it's, it's, it's more like
it's not even that so much as for example, I have a web camera here
and literally the documentation says go to this IP address and download the CXE.
Yeah, we know you, you talk about it a lot
and like,
and you know what I did because I want my web camera to work and it does,
you know, I'll never buy this brand again.
And you know,
I chucked it through virus total and nothing bad seems
to have happened and I'll never update that software and whatever
this actually led to the thing I brought up and nobody could really answer is
does signing software in some ways actually make it worse.
Because if the software is properly signed,
people just assume everything's perfectly fine and going well.
Well,
and we know for a fact that people are
stealing driver signing certificates in the windows world.
Ok.
I'm glad you asked that question because that was the
end state I was going to lead us down to is
what does a signed artifact prove. And I think we often confuse trust
signatures, it proves it was signed by someone who has the key.
And you're exactly right. That's literally all it does.
And I think sometimes we confuse that signature
with trust or safety in some way
of saying, oh, this is signed,
I'm ok to use it.
And the reality is it really just means that
the thing that came from this place over here
is the same thing you have now,
it doesn't mean it's safe. It doesn't mean it went through any sort of vetting.
It just means because in a world without
hetps,
that is a concern.
So, people get this conflated in the web a lot.
Like,
just because you have wall with like three
Ls mart.com doesn't mean you're Walmart or a
-- misspelling of Walmart or like Walmart dot C A doesn't mean you're Walmart dot C
-- A.
No, you are walmart.com. You definitely are.
Yeah,
it means you just have control over that domain and
there is no way for me to determine how secure
is the development life cycle of this software company.
How secure is their key storage.
Like I know at Red Hat, you know, we had some pretty good controls like they had an HSM
doing the signing
and it logged everything so that, you know,
even if like if an attacker somehow broke into like whoever's
account to get something signed there be like a log.
So Red Hat would say
you'll be able to say very easily like, oh,
Bob's count got broken into three packages got signed.
Ok. We're revoking those done. Boom.
-- Well, ok,
-- we couldn't revoke
that literally happened.
-- You can't
-- revoke but
you know what I'm saying?
You would at least know about it or whatever
-- and
-- open SSH got, I mean, there,
there's an advisory for this and someone broke in signed a copy of open SSH.
-- Sorry,
-- I forgot you can't revoke.
That's right.
But we know the R PM world but, but here,
but here's the beauty of it because we had the logs, we knew the version
of the signed package.
So we just released a new version that was higher enough
that no one would ever accidentally automatically install the old one.
And more importantly, you know, which package
you, you were able to say it's just this one, not like these 17 or 1000 or whatever.
Now, here's something though,
that's the other part of that story and this is all public, by the way,
like I'm not leaking secrets here, by any means,
the Fedora keys actually got stolen.
So Fedora had to rev all the keys because in that case, when,
when the attacker has the actual key,
you have no idea what they can do with it.
And you, the only option is to basically invalidate the old key and create new keys.
And you can imagine in the world of a Linux distribution,
-- that's a huge deal.
-- Well, those keys used to come on CD.
Like when you bought a copy of Red Hat Linux or whatever, that's,
that's how you got the keys basically.
Or you downloaded them from their website and hope for the best.
Yes, I know. I know. Well, there was no http either because it was all http.
So, but anyway, anyway.
Right. Right. And, and so the, the point of all of it though, I think
the when we talk about package signing and we talk about artifact signing,
I think in general
and, and really the root of all of this was also s
store because I think SIG
Store does some really cool stuff
in the way they, they have like their public transaction log or their,
what do they call it?
Public not registry? Um I don't remember. Anyway,
transparency. Thank you.
And like that, that's the stuff you need
in a
massively signed world.
And like,
let's encrypt does the same thing where they have all these transparency
blogs that show like what's getting signed by who and how,
and that's really the key.
And I think that's where when you look at like the old
C A model,
uh IC A certificate, authorities, right?
Where they were signing and they were, what was the, what was the super expensive?
Like I verified this is the real company C
domain validated Os V and
um
it was the
green,
I don't remember the name and it doesn't really matter.
But the point is we tried to build like
explicit trust into these systems.
-- Oh Eove,
-- Vev,
certs
and extended validation and extended validation is that one where I like not.
This is actually like TD the bank. What's interesting though
is that most companies shied away from ev because essentially
one nobody cared
and two,
they found
it basically was kind of training people to make things worse.
And there's a reason like you,
like, if you can actually find an OV or the EV certificate,
-- like, I haven't seen one in probably a decade.
-- Oh, they're gone now.
They, they ended all that,
none of it exists anymore.
The browsers took away all of the special treatment and, and whatever.
But the point of all of it is that
that universe was, I guess, secretive, I would say
and there wasn't a lot of transparency and
I think projects like Sigs Store are making
it obvious that the way we did signatures
and signing of literally everything in the past,
it didn't really work.
And I don't think anyone would disagree with that.
It's funny you say this, there is one
project that has done software signing correctly
for over a decade now
and that everybody uses and that's it.
And it's interesting to me that I,
I don't think Linus Torvalds sort of meant to make it like super secure,
but he did.
And one of the ways he made get super secure is number one,
there's like all the shaw signatures which helps.
Right?
And that's again, he doesn't care about security so much as like just, you know,
bit rotten stuff.
-- Like I don't want my source code getting all mangled, they're
-- not signatures,
they're just checks.
Yeah, Troy checksum
is not signatures. It's a Blockchain
like
-- it is a Blockchain.
-- It is, it literally is,
it also has the Blockchain property of everybody basically has
a copy of it of the source of truth,
that's not cryptographic signatures, that's just good engineering.
But the point is it's that transparency log piece.
And I think that's the key to all of this is you need
not just a transparency log, but you need that transparency log
either in a Blockchain format.
So that basically given the genesis record and a current record,
I can do validation of everything in between, right and number two.
But it's easy to get a copy of all that data, right?
-- It's not like gated through some API well,
-- I mean, the
-- SAR data is in an API it's another whatever it doesn't matter,
-- right?
-- But you can download all of it relatively easily.
-- You're right.
It, it needs to be public.
And I think we are now at a point where Sig Store has created this technology
and process that we're still applying the old ways to using Sig Store today.
We're not using it in a novel new way yet. However,
I think
this is kind of that chicken and egg problem of.
You can't have progress until you have new tools to give you the the progress, right?
It's, it's how do we do this. But now SIG store exists.
I think it takes a lot of the right boxes. It's got really smart people working on it.
And so now I think we're reaching a point where we, we, I'm,
I'm completely confident we're going to start
seeing some novel uses of cryptographic signatures
that we haven't in the past and it's not going to look anything like it does
-- today because everything we do today is old and dumb and doesn't really work
-- well.
Actually, there's,
there's one thing that's missing in all of our current software signing processes
which is
there's no feedback loop other than oh like perfect example, right?
I downloaded Corda node explorer version 0.12 or 12 or whatever it is from github
and like chrome through a bit of a 10
like chrome literally went, I don't want to give you access to this executable file.
And I'm kind of like, I've never seen this error before and I didn't screenshot it,
which annoys me greatly
because I tried it on another computer and it didn't work like anyways,
but like chrome straight up,
threw a warning saying I don't want to give you
access to this and it grayed out and wouldn't like,
let me click on it and I had to go, you know, show and folder and go to the folder.
I threw it through virus total and it's, you know,
nobody had ever virus totalled it before.
So I'm like, it's a little weird but whatever it stands clean
and I'm not running it, I'm going to go run the old version that I have
instead of a VM man and,
and I, you know, I filed an issue in github
and it's kind of like something maybe weird or bad has happened. I have no idea.
And like, here's the best information I can give you and like, OK, thanks. Bye.
And that's the thing, right? Like
when there's
files missing signatures, literally, I had to email Red Hat and be like, hey,
there's files missing signatures.
There's, there was no,
there was nothing built the tooling.
Like the tooling didn't go back to the server and say, hey guy,
like you just gave me a server that or a file that doesn't have a signature.
Like what's up man, like in the certificate world where you know, we're,
we're creating this by having like CAA records.
So, you know, you can say in your CAA records for like c.org
that, you know,
lets encrypt is allowed to assign certificates for it and
like cloud floor is allowed to assign certificates for it,
you know, using commode or whatever they use.
And anything else
if you assign a certificate for seafood.org and it's not one of these cas,
please email, you know, court at sea.org. And like,
so I know that somebody just grabbed a certificate in my name, right?
And we're finally starting to build these sort of automated feedback loops.
But as far as I know with the software signatures, like Windows,
as far as I know, like does Windows if it encounters a bad software signature,
does it like send a telemetry
-- back to Microsoft for their security people?
-- I don't know. That's a good question.
-- So
-- that, for example, they can then see,
maybe someone listening knows, like,
let us know if you know the answer because that, that's a great question.
II, I don't know anything about how windows really works.
-- Yeah,
-- that's the kind of stuff we need.
It's like, or conversely, I downloaded a software. The signature was correct.
Can I maybe add that to, like some sort of public log that, you know,
this file has been here for like six
months and it's consistently correctly signed and good and
-- people are using it and you know, it seems legit,
-- right.
That's what, that's what recor does in, in s
store land is, you can basically have that kind of information sitting out there
for people to see like that's its job,
right.
That's it. That's what it's supposed to do.
And, and, but I still think
the things you're talking about are rooted in the old way.
I don't think those are the progress we're going to see,
but we need these utility grade systems to build higher order behaviors on.
And
it's really hard to build a complex system when you don't have feedback loops,
right?
Any complex system, be it,
restaurant order flow or your human body or a nuclear power plant,
you need feedback loops, you need back, pressure
need to know like this is working or not working or this
is too much or too little or I'm starving or I'm too full
and I think that's one of the big things missing
from all this is there's none of these feedback loops.
And so, like, for example, if you issue a signed file, wouldn't it be nice to know
that like,
1% of people downloading your signed file are getting an incorrect signature.
Like it seems to me like that matters, but you'll never know unless they,
unless they email you
well. Right. Right.
And that's kind of a hard problem too in a different way.
I, oh man, this is bringing back some weird memories but it doesn't matter.
-- So,
-- anyway, anyway, what I'm saying is I think like, yes, I'm,
I'm kind of rooted in the old ways because, well, I am like, that's all I know.
We're old like,
yeah, but I firmly believe we need, we need
these utility grade behaviors,
especially with feedback loops because that's one thing
I'm seeing with like the global Security Database.
There's no feedback loops for a lot of these vulnerability identifiers.
Like you basically email the company or email the, the vendor and kind of like,
hope that they reply.
There's no way to like publicly register a,
like a Yelp review of this identifier saying like, I like,
I think they misspelled this word or it's wrong or it's
whatever.
There's a ton of stuff on Twitter about this.
-- Well, that's, that's not a feedback loop. That's
-- Twitter doesn't count.
Twitter is just like the garbage heap of information.
So, OK, we need to wrap this one up now.
But I, I think honestly at the end of the day,
my view of all of this is that the historical use of cryptographic signatures
I think has been oversold and under understood is under understood a word.
-- It is
-- now under understood is a phrase,
whatever. I don't care. I'm going to hyphenate it. So it's a word.
-- So
-- here you go.
Just
do whatever
I want. This is English. Nothing matters.
But
I,
you know, it's true.
Oh, it makes me sad that that's too much truth in that sense.
Anyway,
I,
I feel like we are on the precipice of amazing change and
I'm very excited to see where it goes because I have been
overinvested in
just the old way of doing signing and,
and like P GP and signing RP MS and signing data and emails and whatever.
And
it makes me sad that my knowledge from 20
plus years ago is basically still completely valid today.
I
know.
Right. And that's, that's not ok.
So, I mean, I'm,
I'm ecstatic that sig store is
going to invalidate decades of cryptographic knowledge
as it should.
Yes. Exactly.
All right. Any last words?
Um No,
great. All right.
That was fun. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not at Susy
Podos Podcast. Hashtag do hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a lovely rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.