Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Resor. So,
-- what's new and exciting?
-- Well,
-- what time is it Josh
Showtime or
do you? Well, it's, if you're using good old
-- NTP, it's whatever time I say it is
-- maybe, I mean, not exactly
NTP can only have a skew of a certain amount before the results get thrown away.
That's assuming an attacker doesn't, you know, maliciously intercept it and,
and manipulate it.
We fixed that we now have NTS network time security for NTP.
-- It's finally became an RFC last week.
-- Was it last
week,
two weeks ago?
-- Well, where
-- it was officially approved, but this has been in the works for
as long as I can remember at this point,
-- it's
-- literally
-- been something I remember looking for this in 2000 where I was like,
oh, I want to get time and TV.
Sure. Cool. But I want to make sure it's like
secure because this is going over the, like,
it basically has to go over the internet because I'm not buying
a PS time unit to sit in my server rack because they're expensive.
They're really cheap now though.
-- Well, yeah, but not in 2000, back in 2000 they were not really cheap.
-- That is true.
Also having to run an aerial to outside the building.
-- Yeah,
-- you probably need that in a lot of cases.
Generally speaking, server farms are not conducive to, you know,
receiving low level GPS signals.
-- I bet
-- you could use the cell phone network these days.
You know what?
I used to think that too, until I noticed both
cell phones were like two minutes off,
they were on different networks. Seriously. That's embarrassing.
This is back in the day, right?
That could be. But anyways point is also, you know, NTP UDP, it's over the internet.
It's easy to spoof it's a anyways
we finally 20 years later have network time
security with a bit of hashing and signing.
-- Hallelujah. It finally happened. Is it
-- Hallelujah?
I mean,
I feel like this is one of those movie
threat plots that probably isn't real smart contracts.
Ok. In that context,
I
-- with it,
-- a big problem in Blockchain is where do you get a time signal?
And well, the answer, of course you go
NTP.
But the problem is you have a whole pile of malicious actors potentially because,
well, literally smart contracts are money.
No, you shouldn't be using
NTP. There are signed time sources you can use on the internet that can't be spoofed.
-- Yeah. How do I put this
-- nicely? You don't have to
be nice.
Have you seen what smart contract authors are doing? It needs to be the default.
It needs to be
simple. It's a great example, members, certificate, host name checks.
Like how many languages didn't do it by default,
like Python and how many developers got it wrong.
A lot of people still screw it up. Yeah.
And that's with it enabled by default.
-- I think the only reason people are turning it on now is because of let's
-- encrypt.
Well, it's more that it's as a client side thing.
-- It's because it's becoming the default
-- because of let's encrypt.
Yeah.
I mean,
if you look at host name check, there's literally 500 change CVS,
I'm sure there's, there's tons of problems like this.
-- What
-- Jenkins codefresh integration plug in 1.8 and earlier disables SS LT
LS and host name verification globally for the Jenkins master JVM.
-- That does not surprise me at all.
-- That's from last year. Like what
I, I just got one for a third party library.
I found the other day it's actually got a 2016 CD ID because
someone opened the issue in this project's github in 2016 pointing this out.
And then I was like, hold on. This should get a CV E ID.
So people start caring because it came up due to some other discussions.
But I'm like, this is bananas here.
Well, the fact is, you know,
by now we should know that if you're going to do
SSL or TLS and nowadays you should not be doing SSL.
-- It's broken use that
-- just don't even say the word SSL. SSL is dead.
-- Stop SSL is dead TLS. Yeah, the
-- problem is, there's a perfect example.
I'm just reading Adam
Schott's Threat modeling book from 2000. And
was it 14 or 16? And it only mentions SSL.
Well, yeah, because he wrote it 150 years ago,
-- six years ago. It's
-- older than that. Are you sure? Which? No, it's
a reprint.
-- This is the
-- print date. Ok. It could be a reprint, but he obviously didn't update it.
And now at the same time I know a lot of people who say SSL and they mean TLS.
Oh, absolutely. Yeah.
And the whole point of that is, was what wasn't a trademark thing or something.
It was some stupid trademark thing.
And in my brain when I hear anyone say SSL,
now I just automatically turn it into TLS and assume
nobody is running SSL three because if you are,
you're just inexcusably stupid at this point.
Well, or you've got old stuff that you're stuck with and no inexcusably stupid.
Well, and I was about to say, and you've got far bigger problems.
But yeah, so, I mean, let me ask you a question.
Is there any reason network traffic should
not at a minimum be signed and authenticated
-- and more ideally be encrypted by default now, I
-- think there is no good reason
that all traffic shouldn't be encrypted. And I think the zero trust model is why
there is a good reason,
things like NTP and DNS that have to
super fast and ideally lightweight
and do have a lot of valid scenarios where
I care more about the integrity and availability than
I do about the confidentiality of this data.
I don't care that people know I'm looking at cnn.com.
I am fine with that being public. I just want it to work reliably.
Now, granted there are other, you know,
DNS systems that people are looking up where
they would care about the confidentiality of it.
Look DNS over HTTPS,
-- solves
-- that DNS over HTTP also solves a whole pile of performance problems and,
and I've come to the conclusion that
solving security is nice but it should never be the reason for doing something.
It should be,
it should be a hopefully a good side effect of doing something.
So for example, DNS or HTTP gives us a bunch more privacy
which yes, is a form of security, but
it's privacy I believe is actually something that is
very tangible and important DNS over H TV.
Also gives us a whole pile of performance improvements, you know,
for certain websites,
but do very much matter.
And the fact that it, you know, solves a whole pile of DNS related security issues is,
is great.
Plus while DNS we have a ton
of providers actively intercepting and modifying responses
to send you to a servers in case you get like an nex domain,
like
does exist query or whatever. Right.
I think the reality is with NTP, we want NTP to be lightweight.
-- It has to be fast, fast matters.
-- It has to be fast and have low jitter. Right.
It can't have like different latencies in the responses because, well,
then you're not getting an accurate time signal.
And in general it's hard to mask.
Like, if you encrypt NTP,
it wouldn't really matter because I still know
fundamentally you're talking to an NTP server,
right?
And, and that could be a legitimate security problem for,
all right. Maybe you have a job that kicks off once in a while to talk to NTP
and that gives the attacker some piece of information about your server.
But at this point we're talking about like movie plot threats, you know,
where they're hacking the Gibson.
-- But ntps doesn't solve that problem.
-- No, it doesn't.
And I'm saying it doesn't need to because it's,
that's a problem that's essentially so difficult to solve that.
You just can't.
And if you really do want to, like,
anonymously somehow or secretly get a secure time signal,
you know, go and buy a GPS time receiver.
Yeah, exactly. 100%. So this is interesting.
I mean, kind of on a related note is so there's obviously the CIA Triad, right,
where you've got confidentiality, integrity and availability.
And in the case of
a service like NTP or classic DNS confidentiality
is non existent in that
in that instance, right? You need integrity.
Obviously you want to get good results
and you need availability but confidentiality,
throw that one out the window.
-- Well,
-- you can have confidentiality by VPN
it. Well, now more to the point, it's
-- generally not worth it, especially for something like time. Is
-- it though?
I mean, we, we,
we didn't design it that way from the start and
I can't think of a reason it should matter.
But is that because I've just been brainwashed by
the world into thinking no one should care.
I could see an attacker, for example,
determining what operating systems you have behind a firewall based on their NTP
time signature traffic,
you know, pack of time to live, stuff like that.
Sure, maybe so there could be information.
But again, I mean, we're talking movie threat level
of plots, you know, whereas most Attackers are like,
go take this exploit that's been around for three months and like go use that,
you know, one thing that occurs to me at this point which is,
it's comically overdue is so what is NTPS?
-- What does that mean? What does
-- it
do?
NTP is network time protocol and very simply put your
system and a server ping pong packets back and forth to
figure out how far the network is away in milliseconds
and then the time server sends you a packet saying,
you know, the time is now 417 at the beep, beep and your server goes cool.
It's now 417. And generally speaking, without trying too hard,
you can get your server clock. So, within a few milliseconds
of whatever the correct time is, it's,
-- it works really shockingly well and has been working for over 20 years and
-- 20 years.
Way more than that. INTP is 30 or 40 years, at least.
Well, I remember when Nist ran a dial in modem service to get a time signal,
like they had a public
uh public number where you dialed in at like 2400 bod
and got your time signal. That's pretty awesome, man.
Well, again, networks weren't as reliable or, you know,
latency wasn't as guaranteed like there was a lot more P jitter,
things like that anyways and NTP S simply put is just the time signal is signed,
which gives us what, which means I can't easily spoof the time,
not easily. Don't weasel this one?
Oh
-- UDP is trivial to spoof in certain situations.
-- Hang on.
Let's talk about NTP attacks first and then we'll kind of explain that.
So the thinking is yes,
P can be spoofed cause you could just like
crap
P packets onto the internet and they go where you told them to go,
which obviously you can't do a TCP.
Well, we'll
ask
anymore. I'm not going to let you do this
you can't do it with TCP. We'll see.
Well,
the thing with NDP is you can generally predict
when the system will want to get its time
and you could just spoof, you could blindly spoof time packets to a system.
Well, it's even,
it's even kind of more complicated than that
because let's say I spoofed the packets.
The
NTP demons are smart enough to be like, whoa, the time isn't 12 hours off,
Something's going on here.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I used to have that problem constantly where the time was too far out of sync where
NTP would basically, like, be like, no, I'm not going to fix this.
It's broken and I'd manually run
-- NTP date, get it within a few seconds and then,
-- yeah, exactly.
-- Start the NTP
-- servers.
So anyway, the idea is if you're trying to attack
NTP,
you would have,
it's like the long con where you'd actually have to
run the attack probably over the course of several weeks
to actually change the clock on the machine you're dealing with, which is, again,
we're talking about movies.
-- There
-- were some more subtle attacks where,
especially from a denial of service point of view.
If you could get a KOR
server
-- to be off by two or three minutes, bam, nobody can log
-- in.
-- It's usually like five or 10 or whatever.
-- But
you know what I'm saying?
Like,
-- and
-- then Kurt a two minute skew is going to take you probably days
or weeks cause most of these servers only check in once a day.
I forget what the algorithms do but all the clients are different.
They are. I understand that.
But I'm saying practically speaking because obviously you
don't want to overwhelm the NTP network.
-- So you're not checking in constantly.
-- Like that time.
-- Lysis bombed that university. Yeah,
-- that was great.
I'll put a link in the show
notes to that story. I know we talked about it before. It's hilarious.
There's a reason we use like DNS redirect to handle NTP servers.
So it's hard code in this NTP server.
And then
they couldn't undo it because it break all the routers.
It's not that they couldn't undo it. It's that
Lysis wasn't willing to fix it
-- anyway.
-- Well, I think they also just sent a bucket of money to the school.
It was like, please keep it up
anyway. So.
Right.
So there is the theoretical possibility to send forged NTP
packets over UDP to anyone in the world you want.
So the idea is let's sign them
and then you can't spoof this stuff. But now here's kind of why it has taken so long.
And this is,
I think the most interesting part is when you're dealing with something like
-- NTP, milliseconds matter less
-- than milliseconds
matter. Well, OK. Right.
But the point is like signing and verifying signatures takes
milliseconds to do.
So, now you're talking about, well, how do you decide what the time
-- actually is.
-- Here's a, here's the trick though.
That wouldn't matter if, for example,
the application could know exactly when that packet came in off the network.
And then, oh, ok.
That packet came in off the network at time X
and then I spent like a minute processing it.
Cool. The time at the beep when the packet came in was this time. Right.
-- And I can just figure it out. But the problem is that's really hard to do.
-- Yeah, it is.
And you most of these encryption app, well, OK, I shouldn't say this in the past
signature and verification operations were nondeterministic.
Meaning you didn't know how long it would take these days.
A lot of this stuff is happening in silicon.
So I think it is easier to understand.
OK, this operation is probably going to take this long.
It's not a guarantee,
but I think it's far more predictable now than it ever was in the past.
And here's something wild. So I just wanted
this is from a cloud flare blog entry two years
ago during the period in which error reports were,
they're collecting error reports for time on systems during
the period in which error reports were collected.
6.7 of client reported times were behind by more than 24 hours.
0.05% were ahead by more than 24 hours.
This sku is a causal factor for at least 33.5% of the sampled reports from win users.
8.71% from Mac Os, eight
46 from Android 1.72 from Chromo S.
These errors are usually presented to users as warnings that the users can click.
Basically, they're talking about certificate time
related issues, right? Where
if you're, you know that, well,
the certificate is now expired because the clock on your system is so wonky,
it's a problem.
But yeah, it was,
I was shocked at how wrong these systems were by and large because like,
my understanding was that, is that pretty much every
operating system in the last, I don't know, 10 or 20 years has like an NTP client.
I would agree with that.
Although if so an easy example is if, if your machine is off by a year,
NTP is never going to fix that because it's going to be like, I'm under attack.
-- I don't know what's going on.
-- True.
But in general then nothing on the web is going to work anymore.
Nothing will work at all. That happened to me.
I forget what somehow
the clock on my computer was off by like, 12 hours. And I don't remember exactly.
I think it was
a Linux kept turning the clock to UTC and the system
and windows expected local time zone or something like that.
And anyway,
they kept fighting with each other and at one point I remember it had gotten so bad.
I was unable to literally do anything on the machine. And it was, it drove me insane.
It was so, it was so annoying.
And the thing is though, I knew I knew it was wrong right away
where it's yelling about certificate times and signatures and stuff.
And I'm like, oh, the clock is wrong.
A normal person would probably freak out if they,
no, they would just start ignoring the errors and click through them.
-- You can't click through them anymore though. Well, not
-- anymore. But
-- ok. So anyway, anyway, we have signed time.
-- Yeah, we have signed time. It's, it's
not only do we have signed time, but Crony and NTPC
both support it. And Crony is, I think pretty much across most Linux distributions.
-- The default.
-- Now I want to specify, Crony is C hr Ony like chronograph,
sorry, not, not Crony Cronie, which is like all of the politicians now.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
So, yeah, I mean,
hopefully we'll see because the other thing is time often matters quite a bit for IO
-- devices.
-- Does it?
-- Well,
-- if you want things to happen at the right time
-- in sync,
-- look my lights on my house. I have actually, they're on my garage.
I have the lights outside,
set up to turn on at dusk and turn off in the morning
because I have literally no lighting in the back of the house.
And so this is kind of my
yay everyone,
there's some light here that clock could be off by 30 minutes and I wouldn't care.
Right.
But what if you start, you know,
actually tying stuff together and having sequences like first this,
then that maybe having an, well, let me put it this way.
What are people like, who are
a few minutes off? They're annoying as hell. Let's be real.
All of us have a person we know
who runs like, half an hour or 20 minutes or even 10 minutes late.
And it's just incredibly annoying if you are a punctual person.
-- Right.
-- And I try to be very punctual.
You do you, because I could, I could list some instances. We'll see.
-- I'm not saying
-- I'm perfect, but I try and I care.
So, here's the thing though, Kurt,
we're not talking about 10 minutes or two minutes or one minute.
We're going to be talking about probably 10 seconds or less.
-- Generally speaking does 10 seconds matter in io
-- from the looks of it,
the systems that fail are not going to fail by five or 10 seconds.
They're not get a time signal at all or it's just going to be completely messed up.
And that's probably fair.
And, but at the same time, how is signing time going to solve that problem?
Well, signing time doesn't explicitly solve that problem,
but it in general makes it easier to get an accurate,
-- known, accurate time signal out to things.
-- I mean,
sure, that's probably fair. And at the same time how many of this IO
gear is going to
verify, signed time stamps?
-- Uh Well, if it's the default in the DEV kit, they will.
-- That's true. That's true.
Like that, that,
that's literally where you're going to get all your
IOT security is whatever the default Dev kit does
-- in
-- 35 years.
Singapore has an interesting,
has an interesting thing that they just
released essentially a security label for IOT stuff
and they have like three classes of essentially security and class one is like,
this thing is not a
flaming train wreck all the way to class three,
which is like this thing is like securely designed.
I saw that
honestly, if statistically
class 12 and three won't really be much different,
there will be like absolute piles of fire in,
in class one.
But in general,
people who try to spend a lot of time and money
designing secure software usually don't do that great of a job,
especially when they're on a time constraint and
a budget constraint like IOT stuff is,
well,
we just talked to Larry who told the story about how he
screwed up his web server or even he wrote a web server,
which is a dubious,
you know, thing to do to begin with.
But the point is so actually,
I want to talk about this for a minute because I actually
forgot about this story and I'm glad you brought it up.
So here is my take on this and this is a signal. I think people give.
So you've got these classifications,
Singapore's trying to do and I give them tons of credit
and now I'm going to start out with just saying,
yes, we're going to screw it up.
Yes. It's going to be a train wreck.
But that's ok because this is how we learn, we learn by making mistakes.
They're going to make tons of them. Good job. Singapore.
-- Well, the thing is once you have a framework, you can start to fix it.
-- That's right.
Exactly. Exactly. And you never start, you can't start it. Perfect.
You have to start it terrible and work your way towards. Perfect.
Which is an unattainable goal, but you can never start it. Perfect.
I want to know how well, if at all will this device function
when a there is no network or a degraded network and b when the
mothership servers and the company servers or whatever don't work or go away.
I don't know if they're tracking that though.
-- No,
-- no. But I'm saying like as a, as a, as a nutritional label type thing,
for example,
there are light like, oh, perfect example, security cameras,
I looked into a bunch of security cameras.
I ended up going with Ring.
Yes, I have to pay a subscription fee. Yes.
If Ring goes away, my cameras are basically garbage,
I could have gone with something like ubiquity.
-- They're more expensive cameras. Yeah.
-- If you can find one.
Well,
they're sold out.
Yeah.
-- But
-- anyways ubiquity cameras, for example,
can log to local storage and like the company ubiquity could
basically go away tomorrow and my stuff would have still worked.
But due to cost availability and a couple of other factors,
I went with the simple ring stuff made this as a knowing informed decision.
This is for example,
why I will not go with nest cameras because Google has this habit of killing stuff
they just kill. Was it Google music?
And my favorite or Google Play or whatever it's called?
And my favorite is all these people that bought lifetime subscriptions
and were told basically transfer all your crap to youtube.
Good luck with that.
And then from what I can tell outside of the US that's not supported.
So I would like to see things like that as part of
-- this whole security label thing because that's availability
-- and that's fair.
I don't think they will. But here's, here's the point though, right?
I don't think the details matter at this point.
I think the fact is if you are a company making
stuff and you're willing to participate in this program at all,
I think that while it doesn't say that you are or aren't secure in any useful manner,
I think it says
you are willing to learn and that's huge because there are so many companies and so
many organizations and so many projects I've dealt
with that are just like f you nerd,
get out of here with your stupid security.
And it's like,
all right.
And now I will say also back when I was younger
and maybe had a little more fire in my belly,
which is just a nice way of saying I was a massive a hole, but
I had my fire in my belly.
I would, I would go to, I'd go toe to toe with some of these people and,
and try to explain to them why they were wrong.
Of course, I never did.
But now that I'm a little older, I understand like
there's some people, no,
if they don't want to work with you don't waste your resources on them.
Find people who want to work with you and work with them.
And that's where I think a program like this is huge because
it is self selecting the people who actually want to work with
security folks and do the right thing.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
-- And I, as a consumer then can make a much more informed choice
-- like these are signals.
-- Yeah. Right. Your security might suck.
But I know you care and you're going to get better versus someone who's like,
screw you nerd.
-- Get out of here.
-- Well, I mean, uh
yeah,
where to even begin with these companies.
Like my whole printer buying experience where it's
like now I realize basically I have to,
I have to be very gentle to my toner cartridge.
So that I can save the chip in it so that I can buy the chip less toner cartridges
and rip the chip, like,
physically rip the chip out of my toner cartridge once
it's empty and put it into the new chip,
less toner cartridge.
Because the chip less toner cartridges cost about one third of what the chipped,
-- proper HP ones cost. So
-- I can't speak for HP.
I have a cannon printer and I bought the cheap toner
and it didn't last very long at all.
And the quality was garbage and I ended up actually taking it all out,
throwing it away and just paying the stupid cannon tax and it's flawless now.
So I did a bunch of research and yes,
there is bad toner that's cheap and there's also ok, toner that's cheap.
And that could be,
I obviously didn't do enough research and I bought garbage toner and
my,
I atoned for my sins by buying the real stuff and
paying more for the toner than I paid for the printer.
Yeah, that sounds about right.
Which is, it's going to last me probably five or 10 years so I can live with it. But
no, I just, I'm sad that I needed a new printer because my old printer, the, the,
the processor and it was so slow as it started choking on fillable PDF S,
it would just spit out the, uh, exclamation mark error and stare at me.
That's pretty awesome.
Well, it's got a 366 megahertz processor in it and, like,
all the modern stuff is multicore gigahertz.
-- Yeah,
-- because like a freaking raspberry pi cost
five bucks.
-- Well, but, I mean, should not a printer last 10 or 20 years.
-- It should. I, mine will.
I think that I have now, I've got,
it's probably three or four years old and it's still doing great.
-- But,
-- and again,
like this iot stuff like I just replaced all my s my old IOT light bulbs with newer,
but generally they, they do better color, temperature, different colors,
their Wi Fi so they don't need their own base station.
And so that's a good example of something where it's like, ok, I've removed,
you know, like a failure scenario from the chain of,
whereas my old light bulbs required a 700 megahertz space station.
But, you know, if it dies, well, all my stuff's dead.
Right. Whereas I can always buy new Wi Fi gear.
You know,
I go back and forth on this a lot because I have Phillips hue light bulbs right now,
which are very nice and
the Phillips software seems pretty secure as far as I can tell it doesn't use. I know
-- people laughing. It's ok. You can laugh at me. No, it's
-- just, it's all crap.
-- Like I, of course,
-- this is how I sleep at night. I lie to myself so I can sleep
at night cart. It's fine.
-- I just stopped
-- caring. That's fair. That's one way to do it too.
So, what I did,
I only buy my it stuff if I can now at Costco because they've won your money back.
That's true. They do. They do. But the point is I go back and forth thinking.
Do I want like 1000 Wi Fi devices on my network or do I want a Phillips Hugh Bridge?
That then is doing some sort of like back channel.
-- Who cares
-- if you have 1000 devices on your Wi Fi? I don't know.
Do I?
Well, if you have a crappy single
Wi Fi router? Yes. Yeah, that would be bad.
I have, well, I have a Google Wi Fi system which has been strained,
we'll say under the pandemic situation of school from
home and work from home and everyone from home
all the time and everything and like a million
devices on my network in effect just this weekend.
I started hard wiring my access points because they were just all meshed up before.
I didn't.
-- It was, it was terrible, man.
-- That's the problem with the Google Wi Fi, right?
I love my Google Wi Fi, but they only have one channel.
So like the, the higher end mesh stuff has two channels, one for the clients, one for
all mesh. So that's the problem with the Google mesh. You're basically,
well,
especially if you're like if you have like ABC and it
goes like from C to B to A to the internet.
Well, you're, you're, now,
each router has to receive the signal and send the
signal on the same channel as all the other clients.
-- And so you have to wire those suckers in and,
-- and I did, they're,
they're wired now and it seems better
than it was. I'm still, I,
the people I work with people who have ubiquity
gear and they keep singing the praises of it.
My next purchase will be ubiquity gear.
I don't know if I want to drop a grand on networking gear though.
It's a bit more than a grand.
But the thing is like you, some of the features you get are so nice.
Yeah, that's what I, that's what I hear, man.
The other thing I personally not to show for them, but, you know,
I'm waiting until they come up with their Wi Fi six stuff
and then I plan to get rid of my Google Wi Fi.
-- Yeah,
-- that's
true. I should wait for Wi Fi six. I can tolerate this for the time being.
Yeah, exactly.
And as long as you wire in, you're like, you know,
like all my desktops are wired in and they're the main data consumers, you know.
-- So,
-- you know what's killing me actually is I have PLEX internally
and I've got a couple, I have two TV S,
both of them can talk to flex and when you stream 1080 P video
off of because I'm using Flex for live TV over the air.
That shouldn't be because like even a couple of gigabyte
video file streamed over an hour or two is not that much data.
-- 1000
-- and 80 P is oh,
wait, because the PLEX is doing the upscaling and then shoving.
It's not upscaling at all.
It's literally taking the 1080 P off the air and it's,
it's shoveling an MPEG two stream over the Wi Fi then
and it is enough that the Wi Fi doesn't become unusable.
But you know that something big is going down
-- when it's
-- streaming. Well, and again, if it's,
well, no, 1080 P is only a couple of like single digit megabits per second.
-- Is
-- it?
Yeah, but the problem is like I said, if you're using Google with the mesh, it's,
it's all over the same channels.
Like it doesn't have two channels. Once you get that wired in, it should be better.
They were all hopping through the mesh. Oh, yeah.
-- Well, then you're, it
-- was consuming. It was, it was noticeable.
-- I don't actually know what 1080 P depending
-- on exactly what it is. 1080 P video. It's
frames per second. The bit rate is between 4500 and nine
megabits.
You know, that's
honestly like that's fine.
I regularly run speed test on my Wi Fi devices and get 2250.
No, I mean ubiquity is a good example of this too, of, you know,
they have like this cloud control software that you
can run it on pretty much anything you want,
you know, a workstation, a server or they'll sell you that little cloud key.
It's like a Raspberry Pi in a USB dongle.
And it's a perfect example that stuff will
keep working even if like ubiquity disappears tomorrow.
Now, you won't get software updates, obviously,
but at least everything just doesn't fail.
Right. And this is the reason I won't buy a smart door lock is
from what I've seen all these smart door locks.
If your internet goes down or the head office or whatever goes down,
your door won't lock and unlock remotely,
which cool until it's minus 40 degrees outside and you want to get in your house,
the obvious answers just live somewhere warm.
-- Yeah. Well, I, that's not an option in Canada. I
-- know. Ok. Ok.
So, I guess let's end it on time because that's where we started.
It is. Oh, that seemed funny. I didn't even mean for that to be funny.
Oh, I just totally assumed you just, you were going for a dad joke there.
That's an accidental pun, like
I approve. I approve completely.
So, anyway, anyway, I guess signed time, it's exciting.
I look forward to it.
I don't think it's going to really
change anyone's lives drastically but it's progress.
It makes it easier to know that you're doing the right thing.
-- And
-- yeah, I do agree with that. And not only that, it's one less thing to worry about.
It's one of those situations where
if I was constructing,
let's say some sort of security sensitive data center environment
time would be on my mind.
But if I can get signed time from NIST,
I will not be concerning myself from anyone.
Well, no,
not from anywhere because obviously certain places are
going to be more trustworthy than others.
And Nist is a place I can get time from and not feel bad.
I would get time from, let's say like someone like Microsoft and be OK, you know,
but when you start going to just random time servers, then it turns into like a,
I don't know about this as much, but that's OK.
Thing is honestly if you're getting random time
from random time servers but different time servers,
-- it's you're going to notice if one of them is out of whack,
-- maybe,
-- maybe not
-- unless they're specifically targeting you which hint they aren't.
-- Probably
-- not. And if you, well, and it's one of those situations, right?
-- If you are being targeted in this way.
-- Yeah, that's Nation State mossad.
-- Spoofing
-- time is not going to make the list of things they're going to do.
You know, like
I still love, I'll put the link that XK CD comic where it's oh,
the encryption is too strong.
We can't, we can't crack his laptop. It's
like,
yeah, take this wrench and a
really tell you the F
word.
Yeah,
-- pretty much.
-- That's exactly how it works.
I just like the idea of something.
Now being, I don't have to think about whether or not this is secure and being done.
Right? It
is.
That's right. And like, look, is it going to change our lives? No. Is it progress?
Yes. Is progress good.
It depends who you ask, but I would say yes. All right, I'm calling it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
social
security podcast.com. Head up the show note, Jy
poo.
It says podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.