Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 157 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
-- Well,
-- we're back. How are you doing?
Good. And uh I just noticed 157 is a quasi prime number.
Oh,
my goodness.
-- Yeah. Is it, is it like what it rhymes or something? I forget it's
-- not divisible by 24
as I believe the first step
and then you make a table of roots and squares
and start deleting the ones that are divisible by nine
and then you take a square root or something.
But see, but the thing is because it uses nano time.
Remember it uses nano time to create the encryption algorithm using these
quasi prime numbers and based on music theory that never repeats.
All right. So for those of you who think Kurt has lost his mind, which he probably has.
There was, there was a black hat presentation that was,
I don't even think calling it Snake oil. Does it justice, right? It was
-- AAA
-- sponsored presentation.
That's the best. It wasn't, it was a sponsored vendor sponsored presentation.
It, it's beautiful.
We will put a link in the show notes to a recorded talk by the company in question.
But it is,
it is beautiful to say the least the crap they make up and the claims they make are
I couldn't come up with this in my wildest dreams. It is beautiful. It's like poetry.
The thing I loved about it was, it was such a dense mishmash of crypto
buzzwords and like they were using legitimate
words like all the words and grammatically,
it, it
is grammatic.
Like if you put it through a grammar checker, it would, it's actually sentences, but
the actual content is so bizarrely insane.
Like talking about music theory and nano time and
you know,
uh giving up something about how it would specifically take,
they gave an actual specific number of
like 31,279 years or something specific to like
-- to, to crack or repeat this thing or something. Like it
-- was just
the Jabberwocky poem applied to crypto.
That is what it is.
It's beautiful.
It's utter beauty but also nonsense. Yeah.
And, but the problem is
-- they've got investors
-- well, with words like that.
So, so some people, so, so some people believe this and, and my,
my thought was I looked at this and I tweeted about this is like,
how do we tell this apart from?
Well, for example, like a project I'm working on where it's like, oh,
we have like provably,
you know random noise data in our Blockchain
that you can use to validate your records.
But like, we totally don't have your data because blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
right.
Words hashes
you know,
nonsense that are randomly generated on your side and we don't know what they are.
Uh Right.
How do you, how do you,
they both like honestly when I give the dense version of what I'm talking about,
it's like it kind of sounds the same, just a lot shorter and less music theory.
You tweeted that and I replied to you, but I
this is a good opportunity to, to kind of expand on it a little bit.
This one
a problem in things like medicine
a couple 100 years ago
and
it, it kind of still is in medicine in some ways.
I mean, I would lump some of like the anti vaccination arguments in this.
Oh, you want to see something horrifying,
go look up cures for autism and what some of these people are doing to their kids.
I will not because that sounds terrible. Nor will I link to such a thing either?
-- And that's
-- no, it's beyond terrible.
That's a good comparison. And so
one of the challenges we have in security and this is something
I know we've been talking about forever is this isn't like a scientific field,
right?
There's medicine where you go to school,
you study the science of medicine,
there's reproducible tests,
right?
What happens every time you and I ask for somebody
with a strong opinion that they present as fact.
And we're like, cool,
like, what is that opinion based on as far as data goes? And
-- it
-- never stops him either.
Like, literally the only people I've seen doing actual data are,
you know, like Google and like Miter attack and a few very like, literally,
I can count them on one hand,
the number of people who've made decisions,
like the nist guy is great.
Like back in the day, passwords should be complex, we should rotate them.
Yeah, we, we honestly thought that was true.
And then they basically gathered a bunch of data that is password
failure in the industry for the last 20 years or so.
And they're like,
whoops,
we were wrong,
you know, and the data is that
clearly, you know,
based on password breaches and the people choosing like password password,
123123456789, whatever, this doesn't work, you know,
there's some actual data out there, like, have I been
pwned kind
of good data set?
And
literally those are like everything else, you know,
I'm fine with people having opinions.
I have opinions, but
when people present them as fact, with no
-- evidence, it's like, hm,
-- well, this is beyond the realm of opinion, even
this is somebody with
just lies, let's face it. They're lies, let's call them what they are.
They have a collection of lies
and they're presenting it as actual information and
we have no structure or mechanism in our industry
to disprove any of this in a scientific manner.
Well,
you could sort of disprove it but who's going to take it
on themselves to spend a couple 100 grand to disprove this?
Right. What's the benefit to them of disproving this?
I don't think you could though Kurt,
I think these are the sort of people that even if you
say took all of their arguments and you laid them down mathematically and
you showed why our current understanding of crypto in prime numbers and
just math in general doesn't line up with any of these claims.
They're gonna come back with counterclaims that are hogwash.
Well, they've,
they've already done that where they basically claim
that this is new crypto like this is,
you know, this always happens with new stuff.
Right. Exactly. That. Exactly that.
And what's the, who has someone has a quote that like
the energy needed to refute bullshit is, you know, magnitudes higher
and energy needs to
create
it. And that's exactly what this is.
-- Well,
-- we're still dealing with anti vaxxers despite Andrew, what is it?
Andrew Wakefield being,
you know, convicted struck from the register, all this evidence,
you know,
it's just
sorry, this is something very personal to me.
But anyways, it's, it's very frustrating and it's,
yeah, like
there's still
like measles is back. That's how bad anti vaccine is that measles is back. Like
there's news reports, like somebody traveled through my local airport,
went to a Walmart, did some stuff traveled on
and like shed measles for like four hours around the place.
And so they, you know,
there's a public news story about this saying if you were
at the airport of this Walmart or whatever at this time,
like, and you have a compromised immune system, like, man, it sucks to be you,
you probably should go see your doctor right away.
And it's like I thought we fixed that,
-- didn't we?
-- Well, we we did, but then things happened.
I mean, this is kind of the same story is how do you refute this
when
you have the people who are delivering the message
are emotionally invested in this and then the people listening
don't actually understand the science behind it.
Well, the other thing too is, is not just you have to refute it,
you have to get people to believe it,
right?
And I'm not sure I, I think I might put myself in this category. I'm not even sure.
For example, what, what clearly defines evidence like seriously when,
when you present me with so called evidence to refute something,
how do I know that evidence is correct?
Well, you said, so it was peer reviewed,
you know, like people still argue with the whole climate change thing.
And what is that like 98 or 99% of scientists are now saying it's,
it's a legit thing and people are like, yeah, but that 1% that says it's
so let's let's not go into that space because that's a different problem, I think.
But let's look at kind of the context of medicine is there are
professional medical associations
and
if you make false claims, they kick you out
and we could look at something like the world of crypto,
there's no professional crypto associations, right?
We have something like nest where they would
say here are the crypto algorithms that are good
and here are the crypto algorithms that are banned.
-- But that's kind of another level up.
-- Yeah. Well, I agree because the
black,
there's a lot of encryption vendors that have their own encryption and they're,
you know, they,
some of it sounds a bit wonky, some of it sounds pretty legit.
But, you know, I was looking at some stuff where it's like this,
this thing to do one time pad key streams for certificates
in the cloud, blah, blah, blah, some other stuff.
And it seemed mostly legit like the most of the primitives they were using
were primitives. I know the names of and like, recognize.
So they're not like at least they're not making their own primitives, right?
Like that.
Like when people start inventing new math for crypto, that's when I'm just like,
yeah.
No,
you know that you can do that, but it takes about 10 to 20 years
they did it over Christmas break. Yes. Yeah.
That,
that was my favorite part of the claim is that he invented this over Christmas break.
And it's like,
was it,
is there some country where Christmas break is, like, 10 years long?
Because two weeks, I don't think it's gonna cut it.
-- I
-- want to live in that country because I could use a 10 year long Christmas break.
But that's the problem even.
I, you know, I've been doing crypto, I've,
I've actually read Bruce Schneier's applied cryptography, you know,
so I probably know a little bit more than the average payer.
But
even listening to these vendors at blackout, I'm like, it sounds legit, the,
the pictures look reasonably correct with the way the arrows point around.
But like for all, I know there could be a huge gaping hole in the thing.
And even if the math is solid, the implementation likely is not
because those are two different problems.
-- Also, you can have good math and bad implementation
-- because humans wrote it.
Exactly.
I would actually argue it's having a good
implementation is damn near impossible because I mean,
everybody look, look at how many security flaws we've had in open SSL open SSH,
-- you name it, it, it is
-- completely impossible.
And this, in fact,
I just wrote a blog post kind of about this where I don't
remember if you were in the Twitter conversation that brought this up.
But basically I asked the question. All right.
So we expect to train people to not write security flaws in their code.
But do, do we talk about training people and then not write bugs in their code?
And of course we don't because that's the most ridiculous thing anyone said,
but it's the same problem.
Security flaws are bugs.
We can't teach people to not write bugs.
Therefore, we can't teach people to not write security flaws just full stop and,
-- and
-- actually security flaws are worse in the sense of many of them are not obvious.
Like if, if the site is the wrong color or the font,
like we had an issue where the font had like an underscore under the font in the title.
And we're like, ok, you know, that's visually obvious like that. What's wonky?
What the heck? Oh, you know, the, the font file was something like Magic Web.
I don't know, man.
Web's complicated now, the whole CS S thing just blows my mind.
It's like, true and complete.
It's true and complete. So,
yeah.
And, uh,
I mean,
I, I think the good news though is
in some ways we're making progress because
at least we're having these discussions,
like, like this guy actually got called out
on being probably a snake oil salesman,
you know, on Twitter and there's a lot of press about it. So that's good.
And I mean, well, with a, here's a rather ugly, brutal segue but
to, you know, the Attorney General Barn Encryption
Schneier
talks about it and he points out that at least now
the conversation is moving from, hey, you guys, I love this quote.
You just need to nerd harder and like make a bunch of backdoors and
stuff that are like magically secure and safe for the government to use.
But the bad guys can't use
and we're, we're moving away from that argument which is obviously like,
ain't gonna work too security versus security.
Like, let's talk about tradeoffs, right? We want,
ok, you guys want secure communications.
Well, actually most people want that and so do we cool.
But we also want maybe law enforcement to be able to do their job,
which means law enforcement wants to be able to listen into things in real time.
So let's talk security tradeoffs.
Let's back this up a minute and explain what's going on here.
So the attorney general of the United States
has brought out the old boogeyman again of,
we need to backdoor crypto except this time, like you just said,
he's not saying we can actually technically do this.
He's saying, yeah, we know it's insecure, but we don't care, do it anyway.
And that's a different conversation
than we've ever had before.
And it's even more interesting in that he's saying
we need to do this for consumer technologies.
We won't attack what big business uses
which shows a fundamental flaw in understanding.
-- That's all the same stuff, man.
-- It it is. Look, let's face it.
They want to backdoor the chat apps,
there's encrypted chat apps and they want backdoors in them.
And then that's fundamentally what we're talking about here.
The thing is though, as far as I know those are the same things most companies use.
-- Of
-- course, they do.
What I find interesting is
I feel like it's a thin end of the wedge. OK?
We tried this brute force approach of everything. No, that won't work.
OK. Let's try the thin end of the wedge because, you know,
here's the, here's a frustrating point is when you attack a company,
if they're not that big,
not that savvy, you can probably get away with it.
And by attack, I mean,
like legally attack and force them into legislation and stuff or, you know,
a company like Google or Facebook,
like they have full time lobbyists living and working in DC,
but I'm guessing signal probably doesn't have a huge team of lobbyists
and that guy that released an open source project on github,
pretty much for sure.
Exactly.
I mean, that's one of the difficulties but,
but even in the context of Facebook,
I know I read an article shortly after
this all started coming out where even Facebook was
starting to investigate how they can do client site analysis of messages.
So they aren't necessarily
doing any shenanigans on the wire.
It's a matter of let's put something in the app to look for keywords, let's say,
and then we can forward those messages somewhere else.
Well, and that's actually a somewhat valid use case because people ask me, you know,
Kurt, what about end to end encryption for email?
And I'm like, it's terrible. You don't want it. And they're like, no, I want it.
I want end to end encryption. I'm like, you really don't
because
you will get all the spam and viruses. Right? Because it's end to end encrypted.
You, you can't
scan it for spam and viruses on the server
and they go, oh, well, you know, whitelisting centers and stuff.
And I'm like, yeah, that, that's fantastic for some people,
but for most of us we do like
to be reachable by,
you know, other people,
not just the people we know
and all the spam I get now comes from gmail accounts,
they're either hacked or just
accounts.
And so the other challenge then is you want to do, end to end encryption. Cool.
Now you get to do key management and if you lose that key you'll lose all your email.
Oh, well, I didn't need that email anyway.
And again they go, what do you mean? And I'm like, well, number one. Ok.
So the, all your email can be backed up that, that part's easy. You know, the servers,
you know, all that stuff's back up, that's relatively sane.
But if it's end to end encrypted then
and you really want to,
that means only you get to have and control the keys. Oh, cool. That's what I want.
Yeah. So that means you have to have
and control the keys.
You know,
because you Josh have that insane system with
your ssh keys and safety deposit boxes and
I believe physical tokens. And
uh yeah.
Yeah.
I don't, I don't really care anymore,
but I did create a monstrosity of a process for myself.
-- It's terrible. I agree.
-- Yes. And you never use it because it's such a pain. Right.
And this is,
this is just, uh, this conversation, man. It, it depresses me
every time we talk about this just because
I'm, I'm going to, I,
I wanna clarify something really important that always comes up and
these people will always make the argument of law enforcement needs to do their job
and here law enforcement does do their job and they
don't necessarily need this ability to do their job.
You could make the argument that certain things they do would be easier.
-- Well, it certainly makes it easier
-- and that could be,
it would also be easier if,
but it would also be easier if we had warrantless searches for everything.
Yes. Exactly. Or it would be easier if we all just were tracking devices 24 7.
-- Um,
-- well, we kind of do, don't, let's not go there. Yeah.
Sorry, I have some bad news for you.
We kind of do. We kind of do. But, I mean,
law enforcement's job
is to investigate
crime.
Let's, let's, I mean,
I'm sure there's tons of edge cases and someone's yelling at the computer right now,
but that's fine.
But, I mean, fundamentally right, their job is to investigate.
Well, actually it's a bit more, I think, I think the subtle part there is
there's investigating the crime sort of before something significant
happens and investigating the crime after something significant happens.
And obviously my understanding of most law enforcement people,
because they are by and large, generally decent human beings,
they prefer to investigate the major crimes
before they happen so that they don't end up happening.
Which, yeah, I want that too to be clear. I also want this,
but at the same time, I don't
necessarily want to live in a police state. So it's that trade off.
I want to be secure and safe.
But I don't necessarily want, you know, to have a
government approved surveillance camera put in my house
to make sure I'm not cooking meth.
Right. Exactly. That. And so
law enforcement's inability to see encrypted messages
doesn't prevent them from doing their job.
And I think
that gets lost sometimes because I feel
like this is a dishonest argument always where
the attorney general
is.
I think being more honest than they've ever been in the past,
but his arguments are still not completely honest.
And unfortunately, the people
talking about this, like, I'll use us for an example.
Uh, we want to have a completely honest argument.
Our intent is not to deceive.
Whereas the attorney general there, there's kind of two places he's at.
He either doesn't understand the problem which is bad
or he understands it and he's purposely lying to us, which is even worse.
II, I wouldn't say that he's purposely lying to us.
I fundamentally, he's a lawyer arguing a case.
And you know, what's that expression?
When, when you don't have the law, you argue the facts, when you don't have the facts,
you argue the law.
And so he's arguing the law because the facts are complicated in this case,
I would say,
right? It, it's like these are very complicated tradeoffs because for one thing,
we don't have any data
to really base it on like, like if we literally say
we back like let's take, I'll pick on signal because I like it and I use it a lot.
So let's let's assume signal for a moment actually puts in a like a call,
a wiretap style backdoor.
But you know, the FBI can come to them and say like uh you know,
this phone number because signals based on phone numbers.
So
yeah, like we want to tap this phone number every incoming outgoing
call as it were, you know, text
blah, blah, blah,
we want to get that stuff in real time just like we would with a phone switch, right?
Seems reasonable.
How open to abuse would that actually be,
you know, for example,
do they just have anybody who says I'm from the FBI and they call 1
800 number to request a wiretap or do they have some really onerous secure process
or something in the middle
or? You know what I mean? The problem is
-- the devil's in the details
-- or what about other countries? What about a country
that says we want to spy on these dissidents and you say, well, I don't,
I don't think that's ok and they're like, but it, it's illegal here.
Let's pick on Kazakhstan.
The Kazakhstani government comes to you and says, uh yeah,
we want to wiretap everybody in Kazakhstan
actually.
Did you hear that they're undoing that they're not gonna roll out certificates?
Well, probably because they also realized it doesn't
really accomplish what they wanted to, but back to that. So, so
you could make a case that a government can say we want to wiretap all our people,
right? Because at least they have the legal
authority over them. I'm not going to say they have the legal authority to do so.
But
you know, at least those people live in that country and blah, blah, blah.
But what happens when Kazakhstan says, oh,
we suspect Kurtis committing some crime in Kazakhstan from Canada.
We want to wiretap his number does signal, say yes or no.
What about when Kazakhstan says,
uh we just want to wiretap everybody in Canada
to signal,
right? It's a lawful request. It's gone through the Kazakhstan,
you know, legal process for the sake of argument.
The Supreme Court has said yes to it.
What does signal do? It's a lawful request
from a country, a legitimate government like, and when I say legitimate, I mean,
that's the government that's in power,
you know how they got there. That's another question.
Well, in the internet is an amorphous place. The internet isn't
-- kind of a physical location.
-- One could say it's the fifth domain,
the fifth domain.
That's right.
And when we look at the context of
wiretapping a telephone network,
you go to a building
in your jurisdiction
and the person on the other end of
the building is almost certainly in your jurisdiction.
And you can say this is the data I want
from this person who is here
where
you just traveled to the United States and use signal from there.
What is your jurisdiction?
Right?
Does Canada have any say over what you do while
you're in the United States using a encrypted messenger?
Well, funnily enough, actually, uh US law,
now there's cases where essentially people breaking us law while they're
not in the US have been found guilty of breaking.
So they're,
they're breaking what is against the law in the US
but not against the law in the country they're in.
Well, the, the US did that against a bunch of Russian hackers.
And now if these people ever enter the United States, they will be arrested.
Yeah. Like so like the Russian hackers.
Yeah, the Russian hackers did something that is,
well, at least you could say there they did something
you can argue where it happened but it's sort of quasi happened in the US.
But I'm talking in the case where you do something.
Like, for example, you Jaywalk in Germany,
I don't know if it's legal or not, but let's assume it's legal in Germany to Jaywalk
and then you come back to America and you get charged with Jaywalking in Germany.
-- You know, because they have security footage of it.
-- That sounds ridiculous.
There are some laws being enforced like that in the US and other countries now where,
you know,
you do something that's not illegal in a
foreign country but it's illegal in the US like
that whole, uh, what is it? The foreign corruption, bribery practices act thing.
Um,
-- what's it called in the
-- US? Uh, yeah, I know what you mean,
where it's illegal to bribe foreign officials when you're in their country,
if you're a company doing business in the United States.
Yeah.
And my understanding is even if, uh, because, you know,
I've had to take training on this.
It's a US company and even if I'm not
in the US, I'm not a US citizen, I don't work directly for the US company
as a subsidiary or whatever of it.
Yeah. They, they, they don't care. Right. Right.
Well, or a great example.
I remember when we were getting the, the stock, the insider stock trading, uh,
lecture.
And I was like, I'm a Canadian. They're like, it applies to you. Right.
Like, that's it. Right. Like, tough, you know, it's the SEC.
They don't care that I'm in Canada.
Right. Right.
And, I mean,
you're kind of a bad example because you traveled to the US on a regular basis.
Whereas it's when, when you and
all right, so let's, let's reel ourselves back in and get back to the topic at hand of
encryption, backdoors for use by law enforcement.
Well,
I guess the question is how do we make security trade offs when we don't have data
to assess the risk?
Like, what is the actual, uh, remember from back in the day?
What is it, the annualized loss expectancy? Right. It was that old formula of like,
you know,
a cyber attack cost a million dollars and it's like a one in a million chance a year.
So the A le for that is a dollar to be clear.
That kind of math doesn't really work in the real world very well.
Um, but it's simple. So people like it, that's the thing.
What is the A le like of signal, having a back door?
It, it's enormous.
I mean, in the, in, in the context of signal, it would destroy them. And
the thing that always eats me about all this though is, let's say
that the US government passes some laws and
they force Facebook and Google and whoever else to
put these encryption backdoors into the products.
Only the dumbest criminals are going to use these and in reality,
you're going to catch those people anyway because they
would be making so many other ridiculous mistakes.
I mean, that's the honest truth of it.
Well, and the really brutal truth is, you know,
-- honestly I care more about the metadata and that's
-- fair to them.
-- There's so much in
-- metadata, right?
The metadata who's talking to who and how are they talking to each other?
-- Well, that's also a heck of a lot easier to parse
-- it is. And they already have that.
Yeah.
Well, you have to have that if you want to write your calls. Right. Right.
You know, and that's, and that's another brutal truth of end to end encryption,
right?
Everybody's like, oh, end to end encryption all privacy. And I'm like,
not so much.
Right. I mean,
let's face it.
If, if I call you every day for a month and then I commit some heinous crime,
they're going to come talk to you even though they
have no idea what I was talking to you about.
And they're going to say, what were you talking to Josh about?
And then
you'll probably cave briefly and tell them, you know, we,
we were discussing cookie recipes.
-- Oh,
-- I
-- will
-- sell you out for a
sandwich sandwich. You buy is higher than mine.
I
mean, yeah, it's, uh,
so I, I guess,
and see the problem is lawyers, generally speaking,
are good at making arguments because that, that is literally their job.
Uh, yes, it is.
And I mean,
as much as you may like or dislike the current attorney general,
the fact is he's at least reasonably competent as a lawyer,
probably.
I believe he's a lawyer actually.
I, do you have to be a lawyer to be the attorney general.
I don't know the answer to that actually. No,
-- no, I think
-- they are all lawyers
but
I, I can't imagine one who is, well, here's the thing.
The reality is having a non lawyer in that position
seems like it would be a bit of a problem.
It would be ridiculous. Yes.
They would have to have the training to understand all that stuff and
the training to understand all that stuff is called being a lawyer.
Exactly.
I always,
I always love talking to the lawyers because it's like here's how
you don't sound like an idiot and get us in trouble.
And then when, when someone tells you it sounds really obvious,
but at the same time there's that kind of basic
knowledge you need to get there in the first place.
No, it's, it's wild man. Definitely.
So, I,
I feel like we haven't answered any of the questions around encrypted backdoors and
I guess
I
-- don't think we ever will.
-- We probably won't
even with data, we still have the tradeoffs. Like
even with data, different people have
different values on that data. So for example, dissidents versus companies versus
-- anti-government protesters,
-- I want to back up for a minute and,
and you're talking about trade offs and I think,
I don't think the tradeoffs are ever going to be worth it
in the context of encrypted
anything
on the internet because
without encryption,
the internet could not function the way it does today.
And if we don't trust that encryption,
we have a problem. And I think as soon as you give any sort of government
a little bit of a foothold in this space,
they're going to take a mile, they're not going to be happy with one little thing.
What I really don't understand is that something like email, for example,
is generally not end to end encrypted.
And it's not my understanding is if anybody serves Google
with a subpoena or a warrant for my email data,
they can just hand it over.
I would expect them to.
-- Right.
-- Technically speaking. Yeah.
And so like it's encrypted in transit, it's encrypted at rest,
but it's encrypted at rest by Google.
And so my understanding, like as far as I know, they don't like
use my password to as part of the encryption key or something, you know,
like say um like, what was it?
Uh Mega did you know with Mega,
the idea was they stored your files and the
encryption keys to store your files with your password.
So if you lost your password, too bad, so sad, your files are gone.
And on the flip side mega is like,
officially we don't know what's in there.
Exactly. And so
what I find so weird is that things like email and phone calls
all have that they're all accessible with a warrant or a subpoena.
And so what I really worry about is, is part of the push for this is
a push
to get around warrants and subpoenas and, and due process because,
you know, from what I've read
-- due process is good. I like it.
-- It, it is the cornerstone of our society.
-- Yeah. Yeah,
-- exactly.
I don't think they're trying to circumvent due process, but at the same time,
there have been a lot of sort of creeping
changes where certain parts of due process are have,
well, there was a case here in Canada where, you know,
these parking companies were given access to the license plate database.
The argument being that if we don't have access to that license plate database,
we can't give them a tip,
we have to tow their car and that's expensive and it's people hate us
and blah, blah, blah.
And part of it is the,
you know, the privacy commissioner. My understanding is the privacy commissioner
and everything kind of went well, yeah, too bad.
Like you don't get to just have access to these police databases because
it's convenient to you. Like we have privacy laws.
I bet that would not happen like that in the United States.
Ok. So,
I guess let's,
let's call this one where we're basically out of time and I guess fundamentally
the thing to do for everyone listening is
make sure you pay attention to these issues,
make sure you're writing letters to the people who you can write letters to,
to affect some of this change.
And this is one of those fights that I don't think will ever go away.
I think we will all be dead long before this fight is.
And it's up to all of us to make sure that these people don't win.
And it's not that I think they're like, I'm not going to argue they're bad people,
but I do think they're misguided and I
don't think they completely understand what's happening.
And so it's up to us
to basically be like the watchman of the internet and make sure this never happens.
My thought would be,
even if we don't have data on the tradeoffs,
we can at least identify what the tradeoffs and potential consequences are.
And I think we should do that and make them aware of it because like you said, II,
I honestly think some of it might not be
because it's really subtle when you start talking about,
you know, back door,
something like there's a world of difference
between backdoor signal and how you would
do that and back door slack and how you do that and back door
Irc servers and how you would do that. And,
and these are some really complicated, subtle technical differences.
It is and I'm not sure I even understand them fully.
So I'm pretty sure elected officials don't
see, I think one of the biggest problems was,
-- I, I suspect these two sides aren't arguing about the same thing and
-- I,
I don't think they are and that's probably
conversation for another day.
So, all right, man, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes,
you can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up
on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the