Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
Oh, back to Crime. I'm so excited today. You have no idea.
So we're joined today. We have a guest,
Adam
Shostack who told me to introduce him as the leading
expert in threat modeling in Black Hat review board member.
But we all know he's a true legend of the industry who has contributed
an enormous amount of security. So, Adam, thank you so much for being here.
-- It is truly an honor and a pleasure.
-- Well, well, thank you. Thanks for having me and
yeah,
I'm excited to be here and we've been having
fun and I'm really excited to dive in today.
-- Fantastic.
-- All right. So the, the, the real reason you're here
is
you told me you're writing a book and it is a topic I am extremely interested in.
-- So why don't you tell us a little bit?
-- So,
so let's start with the title.
It is Threats.
What every engineer should learn from Star Wars?
Awesome.
You know,
II I have to giggle a little bit when
I say it because I'm just really excited about this
and it comes out of, I'm so excited to be able to talk about this. Finally,
the last three years I've been working on this because when I train,
when, when we'll talk about what, three years of working on a book is like, it's not.
Wow, it's, I'm sorry,
this is actually why I never wrote a book. I, I was, yeah. Right.
I did the lasg and then that was enough.
But, but when I train people in threat modeling,
the number one question I get is where do I go to learn more about the threats?
And this,
the reason that this has been a multiyear project
is this is
in one sense, it's a lot of fun and I'm really excited about it.
And in another sense, it's
an organizational process to take all of this information
that the three of us and many of your listeners get by
osmosis over the course of becoming an expert
and
put it in one word after another and you don't get hyperlinks because it's on paper.
So it has to start at one point and go to another.
That's something I've noticed the way my Children consume media
is very nonlinear because that's a possibility for them.
Whereas we all grew up in a linear world.
And I, I think there's still a lot of value in
trying to figure out what is important and not important to tell people. Because
one thing I've noticed is when,
when people are learning something they don't know what is,
and is not important and they have a tendency to skip the
things that are actually important because they're also the things that,
you know, tend to be tricky.
Hm.
Well, I mean, look, if they knew it was important
they wouldn't need to read the book.
Well, exactly. Yeah.
Yeah.
I mean,
awesome. All right.
So, now I, I just, I need to pick on you for a moment, Adam,
because you've written books before you knew how much work this was going to be.
Yes,
that, that, that's it. You're, you're just pointing that out to
just that, that's fine.
The point about it being
what's important and what isn't
when
I've given myself a really high bar for this one
because when I say what every engineer should know about security,
that's really my target.
And so
in a sense, everything there
is important and everything is, needs to be made accessible.
Y you know, just the other day
I decided I had to take out the three pages I had on how to store password as well.
You know why?
Because the framework, it's 2022
the framework ought to be doing that for you.
So you don't need to know about salts.
You don't need to know about Rainbow tables and they're so much fun to talk about.
You can learn so much
by going through
the work that people have done
analyzing how to store a password safely.
It's a great topic
for a cybersecurity expert or for someone
who wants to be a cybersecurity expert, but it's not a great topic.
Yeah.
So, well, question then. So, uh I'm of two minds because yes, I agree.
It should be done by the framework and not the engineer just like crypto.
But then the question becomes,
is how do you give them enough information so they can make an
intelligent choice about which framework they pick or is that out of scope?
It's not out of scope.
And the way that I'm taking that on
is by focusing in, on the threats.
So
here, here's sort of the hypothesis that underlies the book
over the last years,
engineers have become responsible for more and more
things we used when I got started,
quality assurance was a separate discipline.
No, we had Q A engineers.
No, I remember those days and now it's just like whatever man, Dev
ops YOLO,
Dev
ops YOLO
-- test,
-- just write tests, it's fine,
but also yes, but also write tests
and make sure you have things like smoke tests in your build.
We've got, we've got ideas like test driven development.
And so my belief is that if we teach people about the threats,
the threats motivate the defenses.
And so if they know about threats of spoofing
and they know about threats like
password theft, leading to spoofing and fishing, leading to spoofing,
then they can ask the question. Does this package I'm picking up,
help me deal with this problem or not?
That seems fair. I mean, I, I like that. Ok. So if you pull the pages on passwords,
I don't feel bad asking you to spill some beans here so that this,
this book fundamentally is using Star Wars as the lens we're going to learn through.
-- So I'm curious what the Star Wars lessons were around passwords.
-- Did they?
I'm sorry, just did they even I don't, now that I think about it,
I don't think I ever saw a password in Star Wars.
There is a scene in Jedi
where as the shuttle is flying toward the stolen
imperial shuttle is flying towards the new death star.
They,
it's an older code, sir, but it checks out.
So
is that an authentication code? Is that like they're using an expired certificate?
But you don't want to fire on your own ships?
And so that scene, let's stick with this scene for just a second, right? You can learn
about,
ok, we need flexibility
in these systems. We've detected a problem. What decision are we going to make?
Because the downside of this going wrong
is that the star destroyer that's there blows a shuttle craft
out of existence and a bunch of people are dead.
-- Well,
-- I
mean, what always got me is, couldn't they just tell him to park out signs?
-- Send someone to look? Yes.
-- Your movie sucks. Kurt,
I watch a lot of cinema sins in my defense.
A recurring theme of this book
is Star Wars would be a much sadder movie if
I love that.
I mean,
ok. Ok. So
I'm, I'm II, I want to keep on this because I think it's funny.
So
they, they have a code,
it's old but it checks out.
But then
the,
I guess we'll say maybe the guy in charge of security in the cape and the helmet
knows that it is Fred Actors on board the shuttle and he still lets them go.
It's true.
It's true. And this is not something I'm going to chase in this book.
But if you want a Star Wars geek here for a little bit,
Darth Vader is clearly an insider threat
at this point who is manipulating the system
so he can reconnect with his estranged son.
-- Ah, that's
-- true.
That's true. That's a good point.
Where do we sit on Jar Binks then?
Um,
because, like, I personally ascribe to that, he is a Sith Lord. I, I mean,
it basically makes everything make sense.
I,
I try and minimize my opinions about George Rinks to the extent possible,
-- but he's
-- such a beloved character.
Oh, ok. So let's, let's talk about, let's talk about this part of it.
I am very focused on using the three core movies,
ah,
the real ones
for this book.
So, the three good movies we'll say, right.
So. Ok. So I think Rogue 1 may be the best Star Wars movie.
It, it was pretty good and in fact, uh, I don't know if you know this,
Kurt and I actually did a whole episode on Rogue
One because it has so many information security parallels,
like everywhere in that movie,
I did not know that.
But, but you, you need to, you need to send me a pointer to that after this if you,
if you will.
Yeah. Yeah, totally.
But for teaching purposes,
I don't want to get into
right. Here's
this episode of the Clone Wars in which something happened or in this book,
something happened
because
it's a logarithmic fall off, right?
That the number of people who have seen all nine movies
is way way lower than the number of people who have seen the core three.
Yeah. Yeah.
And you know, look, I,
I am envious of like Tim's on
his worst book sells more than any of mine ever will.
But
the overlap in the readership, I don't want my read. I don't want to take a dependency
on these other things.
I wanna make sure that these are accessible,
fun examples of that people can learn from.
So that when I give them the thing
just like you did with the, it's an older code but it checks out,
it clicks in their head and they can use that to cubby hole, the information
and chunk it and attach it to something they're familiar with.
I mean, I mean, for what it's worth, Adam,
I think this is a brilliant way to convey information.
I think
just from the, like the human wet wear experience,
we are a storytelling creature
and
I mean, it, it Star Wars is the, the, the three good movies
is unquestionably one of the most told stories, I think, you know,
probably in the modern age by far.
And so I, I absolutely adore this, this idea
and I, I'm not going to ask you to like, give away the farm here.
But I'm, I'm curious about like some of the, the themes and concepts and ideas that,
that are just sprinkled all over the book.
-- So
-- I think one of the fun things about this book is I can spend time and energy at work.
Star Wars. Gee.
And
yes,
and one of the things that,
that I've learned about is George Lucas's obsession with Kurasawa as a director,
which I knew about a little bit.
But,
and, and this ties to your question, I swear, just give me a second.
The,
there's a movie,
The Hidden Fortress,
which is told from the perspective of
the two least significant servant characters.
And Lucas has acknowledged that those characters are R two and C three po.
And
so
the, the theme that, that recurs is I am trying to use
more R two and C three po
and less of the other characters
which also has this advantage
that they're droids and droids are sort of like computers.
Oh,
nice.
And so
I can follow and, and, and by the way, I,
I just want to be clear
listeners. You do not have to be a Star Wars geek like this to enjoy the book.
But as I delve into some of these things, it helps me think about as an author.
What structures do I want to use? Which examples do I want to use?
And for some of them, they're really,
I, I go way deep in sure.
The question that opens the book
is how does R two D
two know who Ben Kenobi is?
And, and that one question, by the way,
I spend pages on
because there's so much there that relates
to how computers identify people
ranging from biometric I DS to passwords.
And from there, we can get to what, you know, what you have, what you are.
And now we're into some pretty significant computer security concepts,
but we're having fun with them.
Yeah, I actually, I just had that discussion on Twitter with, you know,
there's that whole thing about the incident
response where apparently the Attackers have figured
out if they get into your incident response loop when you do incident response.
Well,
it's not going to go real well for you if the Attackers are inside your decision loop.
Um
And you know, and so, so what's kind of the alternative? Right?
Because everybody's like, you know, and I'm like, well,
basically we use a signal group, worst case scenario.
We can just like text or phone each other because we have the phone numbers and
well, we know each other well enough we can use like personal stories or, you know,
like, hey, remember that time, that thing where Kurt, you know,
almost fell asleep in the front row.
Remember that? Yeah. What,
you know, how much money do we spend on beer the night before? What's the number?
Right?
You know, there's, there's people I work with that know that number and it would be,
even though I haven't seen these people in five or 10 years.
Yeah. How, how do I know that, that person at the end of that line?
Because as we've established, I don't know if you've seen but the,
the whole voice faking thing, that's a thing now, like there's services for it where
I, well,
they could just feed in the podcast recordings and they'd be done in a minute and
same thing with video. And, you know, this is
mildly terrifying to me because Josh is what, like,
300 hours of recordings of us online,
you know, I, I have enough.
We'll call it enough.
Yeah.
So like, yeah, how do you actually know I'm me without, you know, being face to face.
-- Although
-- I'm not sure when I last saw you face to face.
But yes, you're right. This is an emergent problem and it's a dangerous one.
That's a hard question. Let's talk about Star Wars instead.
No. But so, so nobody ever fakes
voice
or a
hologram in Star Wars,
right. They dress up in costume.
Leah
when she goes into Jabba's
palace is dressed as a bounty hunter.
That's true.
-- Well, they are constantly knocking out storm troopers
-- and,
and what they're storm troopers on the death star.
So, like those, those uniforms are one size fits all. Hey,
you know,
um, Spandex is amazing stuff.
That's like my favorite thing from die hard where the shoes don't fit
because it's like, that's what would happen in real life.
But,
but they, they never fake a message
in Star Wars. They jam messages, they intercept messages,
but they don't go there.
And,
and I think that the challenge and one of the things I
love about Star Wars is that the technology feels like technology,
not magic in support of the story.
You know,
there's other science fiction shows and I'm not going to r Josh over the coals here.
Oh, no, that's fine. I was, I was, no, no. Ok. So I want to set this up. So
I actually, so we're talking to Adam on a Wednesday evening
and in two days I'm giving a talk called Next Generation Enterprise Security where I
watched a lot of Star Trek and embarrassing amount.
And I basically wrote a talk where I just pick out a bunch of like,
why is security terrible on Star Trek.
And,
and when Adam and I were chatting on Twitter, he mentioned that, oh,
he thinks Star Wars is a better vehicle for conveying security lessons than,
than Star Trek is.
And I'm like,
it's on like, II I wanna know. And so anyway, this is it. I'm excited for this answer.
So please, please, please I explain. I'm I'm very excited.
So
like the older code that authenticates
or like the tape being stolen.
It's not.
And I say this with love for Star Trek just to be clear.
I think most Star Trek is tremendously well written. We're, we are re-watching next
gem
right now.
But
most of the tech
in Star Trek is something like
the
Tachyon emitter has gone mis polarized.
Huh?
They, they call that techno babble in the like writing spheres of Star Trek.
Well, that's what they literally put in the scripts.
Exactly. Exactly. And so
it,
it's just something went wrong and we need our people to have some
human conflict over the thing that's going wrong and then to collaborate,
which
OK, fine. You know, you, it works as drama.
But in Star Trek there's a data tape that's been stolen from an
off site backup facility and they're chasing people to get it back.
It's, it's just
a
different,
I can't believe I just did that. All of my.
That's OK. I won't edit that out. At least
now if this was actually Star Trek,
you would malfunction in your head would explode.
No, I mean, no, OK. No, no. I think this is
a completely valid explanation. In fact, because you are a, now that you say this,
I, I totally see it because technology in Star Trek is fundamentally magic
and I think they put almost an overemphasis on a lot of it. And in fact,
there is most of my talk. I'm just laughing at how
completely idiotic everyone on the ship is like they,
they make the same mistake over and over again.
They have no passwords.
The, the the robot mimics the captain and takes over the ship and it's just this,
it it's insane event after insane event. And II, I will agree with you that I think the
stories and
backing material of Star Wars is probably a little more grounded
and you can focus more on the core concepts of what's going
on versus the just hilarious stupidity of everyone on this ship.
-- I think
-- more simply just the, the technology and stuff
Star Wars or Star Trek is, you know, it's uh whatchamacallit deus
ex
machina,
-- right?
-- It's just like we reverse the polarity of the tractor beam and push them away.
-- Boop. Done.
-- So,
so you know, it's the most unbelievable tech in Star Trek
transporters.
Nope,
I'm,
I'm gonna go, I'm gonna go with the fact that they can just hail an alien species
and magically talk to them without any your mic isn't working. I mean,
is this on,
at the beginning of this recording we were getting echo.
Why do they never have an echo?
And this is, this is with species who have never met before.
That's,
that's freaking magic.
Yeah. The universal translator is pretty amazing.
-- Now.
-- I mean, in, in defense of that though,
there is a fair bit of long range communication happening in the Star Wars
Universe and we also don't see any of the holograms asking if it's working.
Yeah, but you have one standard like you have the imperial standard,
right?
-- I would assume now
-- that you bring it up.
I think what you have is the old Republic standards which are still in use
and the Standards Committee is no longer available to make updates to it.
So if someone found that vulnerability, it would be impossible to get it patched.
I mean, you know, so that's actually funny you say that because
I think history has shown that generally speaking,
when you have a totalitarian regime in charge,
they don't do the little stuff and it's
like boring and annoying as like communication protocols are
they're the functional basis of modern society, right?
If we didn't have TCP/IP, like nothing would work
well, just logistics and pallets,
it matters a lot.
I'm not letting you rat hole us into pallets. Kurt, we're talking about Star Wars.
But no, I think you're right where it's, there's,
there's to make things run efficiently.
In a modern technology based economy which, you know, both Star Wars and Star
are clearly technology based economies.
Yeah, you, you need somebody to write an iso standard on like
screw threads
or, well,
the fact that R two D two can just keep
jacking into all those computers with that spiky thing,
like whoever designed that was a bit of a maniac, but like,
apparently it was successful
and it works,
you know, I love your point about
authoritarian regimes not doing the little things well,
because heck, I
can't even keep a USB device with the same cable for five years. Never mind 20.
It's actually, it's funny that came up today.
My son wanted a universal standard like cable. I'm like, yeah, USB,
that's, that's, that was the plan but
-- didn't work
-- out someday someday.
-- There's,
-- there's that XK CD about standards.
That's right. Now, there are 15 standards.
Exactly.
Oh, don't give me, I, uh, I'm in the middle of something like that right now.
I, I won't go to detail anyway.
Ok. So
this is, I don't even know where to start.
I, I feel like we just got going and, and we're, we're running ourselves to the end.
But, ok, I'm curious and Kirk brings up R two D two little spiky thing is, is like,
like, tell us about that.
How is that
-- used as a learning tool in this book?
-- Ok. So
R two uses that little spiky thing to plug into the Death Star.
Ok. I, I want to ask you're a Star. Star Wars nerd. Does that have a name?
-- The plug
-- that AR two has? I don't know that it has a name.
Ok.
It
is. Someone's typing in the background so maybe we'll get an answer in a minute.
Oh, it's an S
comp link. SCO MP.
Ok.
-- I love it. A computer coupler.
-- Well, there we have it.
The magic of the internet. So ar you plugs in
and starts running quarries,
right? He, he discovers that
there are, there are these power couplers that will cause the tractor beam to go off
and then moments later discovers where Princess Leia is being held.
-- What user ID to those quarries run under?
-- It's easy.
Just use root for everything, you know.
No. Well, there we go.
Just saying,
you know, why is there no authentication step that happens?
So one of the questions you can ask is this so
thing
like HDM I
where you plug in and the thing on the other side just gets data
or is it like USB when you're plugging in your phone?
And so we can use that to start thinking about concepts like trust boundaries
right? Here's, here's this plugging that happens.
What is the designer expect is plugging in and what can we learn from that?
Sure.
So,
so that's how that little spike thing he plays into the book.
I mean that that's a fair point because he not only finds out all the information,
but then he also uses it to shut down the,
the what? The garbage, the trash compactor at some point as well.
Right. So, yeah, it's like reading and writing. Obviously
the trash compactor is the thing that screws
up my utterly geeky theory about what's happening.
Oh, you gotta tell us.
Here's my utterly geeky theory. It's a little bit like that.
That other character is a sith Lord. I'm not even gonna say the name.
I
thought
everything
makes sense if you believe
that Archie plugs into a honey pot
because
the goal of the plan is to allow the princess to escape
and follow her to the rebel base. Ah,
in order to do that, they put the tracking device on the falcon.
They tell R two where she is
and they allow
ob one to disable the power coupling but falling into a trash compactor.
Your honey pot doesn't connect to the trash compactor.
Well, what if the trash compactor due to health and safety had to have, you know,
an E stop that could not be disabled or
access to that esop
could not be removed?
Oh
Right. Because like let me put it this way.
What happens in a data center if you cover the esop?
Like put like it has, it can be behind breakable glass but you can't like wall it off.
Like because you're gonna,
like the fire marshal is going to have harsh words for you.
You have harsh words for Darth Vader.
Go for it.
But I mean, if it,
if you look at it from that health and human safety overriding kind of everything,
then,
then I think it kind of makes sense.
That's true. So, our R two D two did not disable the trash compactor.
It just conveniently didn't kill anyone because that's its job.
-- I
-- think you overestimate the, the impact of the Imperial OSHA division
and protected lives of work.
Well, in fairness, they weren't real big on safety railings. Huh?
-- They were not big on safety rail
-- legs
like that. That one always got me like, just
like,
I mean, they're not cheap but they're not that expensive.
-- I'm
-- pretty sure they're less expensive than having
your staff accidentally fall to their death,
especially at crucial moments on a battle station.
If, if you've ever been on like a modern naval warship,
the amount of safety gear in place is actually quite large
because when you're gonna go do dangerous things,
you want your people to be safe
when they're doing things under
emotional pressure,
when things might be literally blowing up around them
when they might have to be moving quite quickly.
Well,
the one counter argument maybe would be is
because they originally started with the clones,
right?
And the clones, if memory serves,
they had their emotions damped down a bit and they were just quasi
functional robots in a way. So, maybe
their safety culture comes from that where, you know,
they weren't so concerned about the, the cost of human life.
I think their safety culture comes from the s
who enjoy killing people for sport.
I,
I think the sith just think this is funny.
Right. It's, well, and, and look, uh, the movie you two are making is gonna suck.
I'm just saying so
fundamentally like, like that's what it comes down to.
All right. So
my goodness, I love this.
I, I feel like we've talked about nothing. We've talked about everything,
I guess, Adam,
I'll give you the last couple of minutes to just dump some knowledge on us all and,
and then we'll take it home.
Ok.
So
one of the things
that I that's been fun for me
is thinking about
how do I organize all of this
and the place that I've ended up is
surprising to some people because we don't have a lot of things in computer security
that last a very long time that really show
that really age well.
And a lot of people ask me isn't Stride old and creaky
and Stride was created by Lauren Kon
Felder and Preet
Garg in 1999.
Uh You're gonna have to tell the audience what Stride
is because I suspect a bunch of them don't know.
Oh, thank you. Stride is a
mic
that helps us remember, key threats of spoofing, tampering, repudiation,
information, disclosure, denial of service and elevation of privilege.
And
so when R two is plugging in, maybe he's spoofing someone.
Ben Kenobi tampers with the power converter that supports the tractor beam.
I think Stride has stood the test of time
and I'm adding to it a couple of additional threats.
There's a threat of predictability.
This covers randomness, randomness in cryptography, randomness in memory,
randomness in sequence numbers as things are going across the internet,
predictability
is in and of itself something of a threat.
And I think that's something people need to know.
Another big thing that I cover is parsing
any time
parsing happens at trust boundaries.
And so
we have to think about why is parsing hard.
And there's a lot of good knowledge from the LST
community
that I think is in the category of what every developer needs to know.
And then the thing that brings it together at the end of the book is Kill Chains
and Kill Chains are at the end because until you understand the component steps,
Kill Chains are hard to understand.
And so sure,
I feel that this is a good organization.
And as I'm announcing the book,
I'm also doing
some beta reading. And so if your listeners are interested
and wanna go to Threats book.com,
we're taking sign ups for people to be beta readers.
You'll get a chapter or two over the summer.
If you've got great feedback, I'll acknowledge it.
If you've got really great feedback, I'll send you an inscribed copy of the book.
And
so
that's the organization that's there.
And
yeah, I this has been so much fun
and I'm hopeful that
this response
extends beyond the three of us
to
every engineer
that even if you're not a Star wars geek,
you have the
basic story, you've run into spoofs,
you've run into an homage.
You've, you've,
you've seen the movie once
and that this will make
the security concepts accessible to you
so that you can actually deliver
more secure systems.
I love that.
And, and I will just for, for anyone listening,
I will put the link to Adam's site in the show notes.
So you don't have to
remember what it is because I've already forgotten it.
But
fantastic. This has been an absolute treat.
Adam, I want to thank you so very much for coming and talking to us about your book.
Thank you for having me. I, you know,
I, I apologize but I had no idea that you had done an entire episode
on rogue one.
-- It's been a while.
-- It was five or six years ago. It was episode 29.
This is like 300 something. Was it that long? Holy cow.
I
know
when I saw that I was like, oh,
my kids were like, not really talking back then.
Wow.
Yeah, it's been a while.
-- These classic stories stick with people. I
-- agree.
I agree. All right. All right. I'm gonna, I'm gonna end this one.
Thank you so much, Adam. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, a Podos
podcast hashtag hit us up on social media curtain,
Adam have fantastic rest of your days.
Thank you so much. This, this has been an absolute blast.
-- Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the