-- Notepad has no color though. That's weird
-- because it's Notepad.
Like,
hello and welcome to the Open Social Security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried my partner in dishwashing. Josh Bressler,
dishwashing. Oh. Right. Because I,
right. I had to delay recording the podcast because I was finishing up the dishes.
Did you actually wash them by hand?
-- Only the pots and pans?
-- Oh,
ok.
Yeah. Yeah, I filled the dishwasher
and then I have a,
so I have two Teflon pans. I generally don't like Teflon,
but it has its purpose and obviously I care.
I take very good care of them and they're,
they're cared for meticulously because I don't want to consume Teflon.
So those get washed by hand very gently and then put away.
Yeah,
I just had to throw one of my smaller Teflon pans away because
I noticed a chip in it and it's kind of like yummy.
Yep. Yep. That's right. We don't, we need to know eating Teflon here. No.
Yep. Yep. Exactly. Now, now I will say for anyone listening.
Yes, I have a bunch of very nice cast iron pans.
I have a bunch of steel pans. I do not use a teflon very often.
But there are times when it is accepted like
eggs are a great example of teflon is lovely.
I was about to say breakfast,
Teflon
and breakfast.
That's a match made in heaven.
Uh It generally is. Yes. This particular meal this evening had noodles and gravy.
Fried with schnitzel and
the noodles and gravy create a mess that you cannot clean.
Wait. Did you make
Schmetz
Spetz?
Oh,
the Spetz
noodles? Yes. Yes.
They were Spetz
noodles literally from Germany
because
my wife orders there's some,
she found some German company that will mail like
a box of German stuff to the United States
and like an online store and stuff and
about two, twice a year ish give or take. We order
just German candy and German foods and whatever. And
then we always throw some noodles in.
-- And so, yes, the noodles were literally German noodles
-- tonight. Awesome.
Because I, I personally am ok. I'll be blunt. I am po pooing you on the inside because
I've only ever had my mom's homemade
-- peel.
-- She's from Germany. That's valid.
Well, but, like, and the thing is like my mother, myself and my sister,
we all own a Schmetz
Press.
That's fair.
It's kind of like a ricer but thicker.
Ok. Anyway, let's talk about unicode. That's way more exciting than my dishes.
-- Ah,
-- yeah, it's, well, it's interesting because
so, ok, so there was actually some really good work done recently like this.
Week called. Uh,
I love their website too because it's, it's Trojan source do codes.
I didn't know dot Code is a New TLD but
-- of course there's a TLD dot
-- Everything is TLD
now.
Ok. Off topic. But what I've noticed
more and more ads are inserting www dot whatever
because it used to be clear food.com.
That's, that's like a web address. Right.
But now there's so many just random two letter combinations
And I'm like, is that a web address or not? I don't know. But so
www dot blah, blah, blah.
-- So anyways off
-- topic, so it amuses me.
You said off topic before you said that as if we ever stay on topic.
So,
Trojan Source dot Codes is an awesome website
because it's got like a nice chunk of image
with a floaty cloudy thing and then a big red paper button and a link to github.
-- Oh,
-- the clouds do move. I didn't even notice that now that you say it, I see it.
Well, I don't think it's so much clouds as missed on the water,
whatever.
Anyways and you click repap
and it's, it's, I love that.
-- The paper is this classically formatted latex
-- blog people who do two column
white papers. You are a bad person and you should feel bad.
-- They're like full stop. That's
-- it. I'm tired, man.
It's been like, ok, 20 years ago, we didn't know any better.
-- But now
-- if
-- it's,
-- if it's printed out on paper.
I think the, the narrow columns are easier to, like, take notes and things like that.
But when I'm reading it on a computer now I have to scroll your
PDF down and then scroll your PDF up and then scroll your PDF down.
And, like, by the time I hit page three I want to, like, I get all,
I want to stab someone.
-- It's terrible.
-- So this is one of the reasons I own a giant
monitor.
I mean,
-- mine is very wide. I need to flip it 90 degrees.
-- There you go. Anyway.
So the premise is essentially,
well, basically what it boils down to in the beginning we had
Asy and Asy was good and simple.
There was 256 I'm gonna say character codes I think is the right time. I
don't know
what to
call
it.
Well,
because there's not actually 256 characters because there's
control characters like line return and stuff.
I
mean, it was seven bits are basically the stuff we can look at
and then the other,
the next half is like all the,
the, well, essentially the
Asy Art.
Yeah,
for the
weird
-- stuff, the control
-- codes. Yeah.
The little smiley faces and stuff like what do for uh Door Fortress uses.
So
in the beginning we ask you and ask you is great and awesome unless of course
you want to speak any language other than English or maybe a bit of French.
-- It's almost like a bunch of tech dudes in California thought all this up.
-- Right.
So, we have unicode and actually I do quite like unicode, but the problem is
we,
we still live in a world that generally assumes everything's going to be asking.
-- And so
-- that's not the problem isn't.
Well, it's, it's not just that it's the people and the technology
essentially are still living in an ask you world, but we've moved on to unicode,
but they haven't mentally,
maybe I'm, I'm waiting to see where you go at this and I have to decide if I'm going to.
So basically, almost everything supports unicode by default now, right?
But most people are quite shocked when you cut and paste a smiley into the text film.
They're like, what? Well, what, what just happened.
So like a great example of this is cut and paste a smiley unicode into a password field
and like half the time it'll just work. No problem.
The other half of the time it'll, it'll cause a horrific problem.
Ok? Because essentially a lot of people haven't really moved past
Asy, like in their brain. We live in a nasty
world. I mean, I'm not saying it's ok, but I'm just saying this is how it is.
There's a lot of tooling that now supports
Asi or a unicode rather.
But for example, it doesn't explicitly tell you like,
are you looking at an ask you letter a or
-- one of those weird Cyrillic version letter A
-- si mean,
should it tell you that there is a difference?
-- What
-- if it's an address bar maybe, am I at Walmart or am IW Mart?
Doesn't the address bar denote
when you have,
-- I guess that the maybe fishing characters
-- they do and they don't.
So for example, with the, with the Chinese characters that will show the actual,
like the X and blah, blah, blah, blah blah, with some of them,
it'll show essentially, I brought this up with the Homo Glyph attacks.
And the biggest thing is
if you can indicate, am I showing you
Asy or am I showing you unicode?
Because if I'm showing you unicode, that might not be a letter A that you think it is,
right.
Anyway, I think we, we're at
look, here's what basically happened.
Some,
some group of people made a fancy website, they got AC B ID
and they created some demo source code files that use the kind of the,
the right to left character set.
-- Oh,
-- this is my favorite part. There's left to right,
right, to left
or sorry, there's left to right, embedding, right, to left, embedding,
left to right over, right, right, to left over, right,
to write isolation,
everyone. It
so the point is they basically built these files
that when you look at them in certain editors,
it'll for example, look like there's a comment.
But then when it's interpreted as unicode like
the return statement isn't in the comment,
the return statement is outside the comment.
Right?
Well, and a more a better example would be like you're writing a smart contract
and it looks like the number 100
-- but it's actually a one or vice versa.
-- Sure. Sure. And you get the idea, right?
They're abusing
the properties of unicode to try to trick people
and I guess here's my take on this, I'm going to just,
I'm going to get it out of the way now.
This is freaking dumb.
I mean, just for real. Like
so if you look at these files
in various editors, I everything I've looked at
it is obvious something weird is going on in every instance
if you accept this as a pull request, like
you what I mean, come on from a security perspective at the same time,
like if I'm gonna attack your application with, with a malicious pull request,
this isn't how I'm doing it.
You know, this is, this is obvious
and it is silly and I think giving this a CV E ID, just
it fills out our narrative of like CV E is broken. That's all this does.
So I disagree
in that this is definitely something that needs
to be fixed because this for example,
would be great for an insider attacker,
right?
That this would allow you to hide something
in a way that most people wouldn't expect.
And I think as proof is how annoyed and angry a lot of people are.
They're like, oh, it's not really an issue except, well, wait, I can make the editor,
like I can make the code editor show ABC def.
But it actually turns out like
-- some other ordering of like BCE
-- D. Not exactly though. That's not true
when you look at these files in. So I've tried a bunch of editors. Funny enough.
Windows notepad actually renders them correctly which like
kind of blew my mind a little bit.
Like Vim does the right thing, emacs does the right thing VS code displays them
in the wrong order, but the the syntax highlighting gets it correct.
So it's still when you look at it,
you can tell something is broken in the file you're looking at like I,
I think you can make the argument like sure Lyter should catch this.
I'm OK with that.
But fundamentally saying this is some sort of novel new attack I think is a stretch.
The challenge is there's no really good way to tell somebody.
Well, the first problem is, is this
-- ASI or unicode?
-- Everything should be unicode?
I should assume everything is unicode from now on, from the straight forward.
I'm putting a stick in the ground.
-- It's unicode.
-- I agree.
But then the second problem is I'm looking at this character,
what is this character?
Is it a or is it Cyrillic A?
Is there a left to right or right to left?
Embedded control character lurking somewhere.
And now I would say, especially for source code
tools, if you're going to show source code to somebody,
you should probably strongly highlight weird stuff like
left to right and right to left and all those weird
encoding signals, right?
Like just like if you have some sort of well control, like the, the, the, the carrot m,
you know,
when you open up a AD OS file in emacs and it's like
you got the D OS line returns instead of the UNIX line returns,
right?
And it's like, so it's covered in control MS and you know
that, well, there's different line returns, right?
They're not hidden, they're not,
you know, acting weird, right?
But the the challenge becomes is if you highlight every bit of unicode
for the people that legitimately need unicode, which is
basically everybody
outside of North America,
you know, their, their experience goes all to hell in a handbasket.
People in North America need unicode. Kurt.
I mean, there's loads of people with um lots and their names we'll use for example,
who live in North America.
I mean
there was a, there was a thread, yeah,
about like these name fields where most name fields
uh default, what is it? 12 characters max. So people with like
names of Christiansen or whatever
are just
out of luck or this one guy, you know, his name is Joe
with the, with the
accent and it's like, yeah, I
can't use that.
Right. That's ridiculous. I don't, that's not. OK.
So,
all right. So here's
something for us to consider.
So first of all,
there are legitimate
reasons to use right to left comments, for example. Right.
-- I mean that, that's just, that's how it works.
-- It's
people in the Middle East.
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
OK.
So I think there's validity, validity to that.
And now you make the comment about how do I know if this is a,
an English A or a Cyrillic A?
And the,
the thing I always think about here is does it really matter?
I mean, if we're talking about like a comment,
then no, because who cares? Right.
It's, it's a comment. It doesn't matter.
Now if we're talking about, say a URL bar,
obviously, there is an argument to be made that fishing can be used
in those instances.
And I think that's a separate problem that we should
not discuss today because that's a very different thing.
But now in the code itself, for example,
you could have one variable named a one variable named Cyrillic A
and those would II, I, I've not tried this,
but I assume they would be treated differently by the compiler.
Well, as a simple example, right?
Instead of you think you have one variable called the letter A,
it's actually two separate variables and it gets set
differently and it doesn't get reset properly at some point
-- leading to a security vulnerability
-- Right.
So here's where I think that argument kind of starts to
fall apart is that is not going to happen on accident.
Ok. I
think that's just, that's the reality of that
situation. Now, let's say someone wants to create nefarious code.
You can easily make the argument that yes,
you could use Unicode as your vehicle for creating dangerous code.
But as actually on the OS S security mailing list, a
discussion started and David Wheeler rightly pointed
out that like there are literally contests
to create underhanded code that is designed to trick people.
And the thing is if you have an attacker who can submit like a pull request,
they can get past you.
Be it a a minor bug you don't notice be it literally underhanded code,
you know what I mean?
Be it multiple commits that when put together do something scary.
-- Well, I
-- mean, the University of Minnesota,
yeah, we talked about them what, like 10 or 12 episodes ago I think
or my favorite is all of the
and I don't mean off by one in the sense of like off by one
buffer but off by one and that like somebody forgot a character or made a typo
and boom security flaw, right?
Because at some point, your,
your eyes sort of glaze over and you don't notice these things.
-- So
-- I, I think using this
as an excuse for the source code is a stretch to say the least.
I feel like
you can easily make the argument. Like this is weird. We should have consistent,
I guess just behaviors in our editors.
Like I think VS code should display this correctly.
I don't think VS code should be displaying it the way it is.
You can make that argument and whatever.
But
I think calling this a security vulnerability is just, I, I don't, I don't buy it,
I would say across a trust boundary.
Well, it's like a homoglyphy attack, right?
My brain says it's a letter A but it's not a letter A, it's a Cyrillic letter A and
the thing is there's I, I'm just not sure of how do we solve this
because like I said, if we flake every character is unicode, that's unicode.
That's gonna look like garbage for everybody
outside of the English speaking world.
I mean, yeah. Yeah. Unicode,
unicode one,
right? We, you cannot pretend
going to going back to
Asy is a solution.
It's just, it's completely out of the question suggesting it is ridiculous.
-- Some
-- people never left Asy, right? That's kind of the problem.
That's a different problem as well.
We're not, we'll, we'll set that over there with the URL with attacks, right?
Those two can play together
in the sandbox. Now, here's a great example. Actually, I have a great example of,
of a way to deal with this.
I'm going to send you a link,
I'm
not
putting a signal
and I will also put this thing in the short,
it is a link to get up, open that up.
-- Uh
-- OK. Right.
The early return, this file contains bidirectional unicode. Yeah. And,
and that's
except uh hang on a sec. I'm in Adam right now. Which one is that?
The early return, early return,
early return?
Yeah, Adam is just like her
di
so OK. So for anyone, OK, this is a podcast. No one knows what we're doing.
So what I did is I just sent Kurt a URL to one of the test files.
It's a Python file on github
and github
pops up a little warning that says this file contains bidirectional unicode
text that may be interpreted or compiled differently than what appears below
to review open the file in an editor that reveals hidden unicode characters.
-- Which one is that
-- which editor?
-- Because like Adam is not
-- it
Windows notepad
like
like, but here's the thing. OK. So here's the deal. So
I'm comfortable with a warning like this.
I'm comfortable with the winter giving a warning.
I'm comfortable with the compiler giving a warning,
right? I think hard failing on a compiler. That's probably another topic.
And I think that gets into weird territory of,
of like
you're, you're giving a lot more credence to the
Asy tech bros
than, than not, but whatever. I'm not gonna argue right now.
But the point is like warnings like this are valid where, where someone can say,
oh yes, I'm doing that on purpose.
Go away warning everything's fine.
But if I, if you sent me a file, I opened it and I see this warning, I'm gonna be like,
holy crap.
Kurt's trying to p me, you know what I mean?
Well, and it's great that github
does this,
but I'm guessing a lot of things don't,
not yet
so well.
And that's why we need a CV for this and that's why
we need a public identifier and we need some discussion about this.
See,
I think part of it is not all security identifiers need to be, you know, like the
like basically not all security identifiers need to be,
this is exploitable and it fits in a tweet and I
-- can take over your system entirely but all
-- CV ES
do.
Yeah.
But in this case, I think this is an interesting security
problem
but
like text editors,
you know, just like address bars and browsers now should tell me.
Nope because like this is cool, everything's asking or, you know, hang on, whoa,
like this is not asking something, you know,
and maybe that's fine because you're going to,
you know,
Nber
Leb
Kuchen with the accent or whatever.
So here's my problem with what,
what you just said though is we exist in a world where there are CBS
for things you should just pay attention to cve equals vulnerability,
which is a broken system.
-- And we've discussed this in
-- the
-- past
-- and that's why
we're moving on and doing the project we're doing.
Right. Right. The UV.
And,
-- but the point being here though that this has a CVE,
-- sorry when I said CVE,
I meant security identifiers in general.
But, but no, my point is literally,
I'm literally complaining about a CVE because here's what's going to happen.
This,
this gets a CV E, this is going to go into the vulnerability databases,
this is going to start getting flagged all over the freaking place.
And this is not a vulnerability in the context of this
is like a problem you have to fix in your code.
This is the sort of thing like
we just need to be aware,
this is an issue and we need to deal
with it elsewhere as part of policy and compliance.
It's like Python Pickle in that it is a very sharp edge but on its own
is not an issue. But
-- if improperly done somewhere can result in an issue, I
-- don't buy that.
I think pickle is legitimately dangerous.
This is not legitimately dangerous by itself.
It fundamentally changes what you're seeing unless you handle it correctly,
which a lot of things don't by default based on the number of people patching.
This. The other thing that really annoys me is this breaks the CV rules, right?
CV is supposed to be
vulnerability intersection with code base and this is one CV E for
like
the
whole
giant pile of stuff.
So
I would prefer for this to be somewhat legitimate. It needs to be split up more. So
I agree. I agree
because I think, but, but I, I guess here's, oh man,
my brain,
here's how I would break this down.
You, you said just a minute ago, something about like,
things don't display this properly.
But I would argue, uh,
virtually everything I've looked at
it. It, this is not like it looks weird everywhere you look at it.
There, it is obvious something strange is going on.
-- I'm
-- in Adam and it's not super obvious.
So for example, if I'm in Adam and I look at the uh where did the
Python one go? Because that was somewhat clearish.
For example, if I go to the Python one, that's uh homoglyphy function,
the say hello and the say hello,
the,
the one say hello is all blue and the other say
hello is like four gray characters followed by four blue characters.
OK. So, but that is
that should trip something in your brain that says
-- what is going on
-- unless you're color blind.
OK. That's a fair argument. I will, I will accept that as an argument.
But actually, so in all seriousness, if you are a listener and you are color blind,
I would really love to know like, do you use like a syntax highlighting?
Is there colorblind friendly highlighting?
-- I legitimately don't know
-- because I'm looking at this
and it's like it's purple gray blue and green.
And I know for a fact I'm not red, green, color blind because my dad is
and I'm not because I've been tested because, you know,
it's a concern if you're driving a car, red green and close enough.
Right.
Yeah. Whatever. They're the same, it's fine.
So
I'm looking at this and
now that you mention that I'm thinking about the colors used in this
default atom highlighter thing and it's like
I'm not a fan of them anymore.
-- OK?
-- But now now we come back to the like there's one CV E which is wrong.
Like if Adam is doing the wrong thing, I would be comfortable saying, OK, Adam,
people,
we would appreciate it if you would
maybe do something more than you're doing today in handling a situation like this
like pop up that
-- github warning saying this file is weird looking with,
-- right?
-- I mean, I'm perfectly comfortable with
-- that.
Going back to what I was saying about ask you,
I'm expecting
characters in my file that I can see
and I am expecting
one or more forms of whitespace in the form of whitespace or tabs.
And I'm expecting some form, ideally the same of line return.
I think that would be safe to say that those three things can
-- pretty commonly be expected in a text file.
-- I'm comfortable with that.
Yes.
OK. So if there's more than that, please tell me because I'm guessing for myself.
-- I'm trying to think,
-- yeah, I mean, you could put, what are the, the zero with spaces?
You could have a 700 megabyte text file that looks like it's four lines long.
Exactly.
So I'm thinking basically outside of,
well, outside of displayable characters,
especially
Asy versus
Unho,
I, I want to interrupt you though for a minute
if I'm in Israel and I'm writing comments in Hebrew.
Those are all displayable character. You know what I mean?
That's not weird.
No, but you have a preference.
But for example, having control characters that are not like having left to right,
right to left control characters
for a lot of us would be weird.
And for the people that it's not weird for cool, they can,
they can like ignore that warning the first time it pops.
I guess that's fair.
You could look at the locale because obviously in the
unicode universe you set a locale for your session.
And if you have a locale of essentially like us English, for example,
then having right to left characters is worth giving me a warning.
You know what this really reminds me of is all the stupid foreign language spam.
I get in my gmail account in Japanese and I'm like,
I, I don't, I don't speak nor read and never will
Japanese.
Like you can't say never will.
-- You don't know that
-- it's,
it's a hard language to learn and I am old
-- and dumb
-- and willing to say it's unlikely but,
but, but you know what I'm saying, like it's,
I get this spam in foreign languages that I've never sent or received emails in
like how, how like,
because I run it through Google translate and it's very obviously spam and I'm like,
can I just set a setting where it's like
just English email only cause if it's not in English, I can't read it
and,
and that's kind of what I'm reminded of. Like in Adam,
I don't,
I,
I can't think of any legitimate case where I would need
or use all these weird kind of left to right,
right to left, whatever, blah, blah, blah, control character things.
I mean,
and if I do end up having to go through some Israeli code base, cool.
I'll,
I'll deal with the warnings then and either
ignore them or turn them off or something.
I mean, and,
and I think you could even make the argument the other way that
if I have a code base that's full of right to left comments.
I could obviously use left to right comments to, to, you know what I mean?
Like it's the, it's the same attack in reverse in that instance. So
I think we have this obsession with like
the English language aspect of it, but there's a lot more going on here.
Well, have you not seen all the A I training data that doesn't see people of color?
Right. Right. Yeah. Yeah. Stuff like that.
The other thing is you just mean these code editors
are generally quite smart with their code syntax highlighting.
And
for example,
I would like to like, like looking at this Python example with the whole, you know,
it's got like, what is it four characters in gray,
four characters in blue or all characters in blue, like some sort of
more of a, like a red s
like a red squiggly line under it, like a spelling error squiggle.
You know what I mean? Maybe
because
this is
like, I've never seen this before.
This is the first time I've ever seen this.
Right.
And I feel like it's weird enough that it's something that should get a red squiggle.
I mean, but, and, and
I think it's ok, it doesn't today because this is not,
I mean, we all, like, secretly we all knew this was a problem,
but none of us really talked about it and now someone
got a bunch of attention which is kind of not needed.
But now I think a lot of editors and other things
will give this a little more attention more than it deserves.
And like, that's ok. I guess it's, I, I don't have a problem with it.
I don't think it's going to make
world the worst place necessarily.
I mean, it's interesting because actually it's uh so cwecwe to be clear,
1007 is insufficient.
Visual distinction of homoglyphy presented to users. So that's more the
when I was proposing that I was thinking more of the address bar use case, right?
-- And
-- I think the address bar is
kind of special in
some ways.
But I, I also had mentioned
as part of that just,
just telling me
is this pure
Asy or unicode is, is very helpful
but I
he's dead. Nothing should ever be pure
ask again.
Exactly.
So back when I said that I,
I think I was reasonably correct but it
no longer is because everything should be unicode
-- full stop. That's it. Everything should be unicode.
-- Unicode one. It's over.
And then the question is how do we start to display Unicord? Sorry. Unicode in a
way that
helps us people that know Hablo Espanol so good.
But doesn't annoy the other 90% of the world that bilingual.
I mean, do we, is this a problem we need to solve?
Well, I mean, look, man,
nearly every programming language is functionally English.
When you look at it,
we're already torturing all these people who don't
live in North America for the most part.
Seriously. Oh, no, I know.
II, I have some German relatives that program and they all speak English fluently.
Well, because they're German.
Well, you know what's even worse is every,
every European I know who programs they own an American keyboard
because you have to, the German keyboards are silly.
-- Right?
-- Well,
look, it's not silly. It's, our keyboards are silly to them.
Yeah, I I think this just generally because on a related,
very tangentially but related topic is augmented reality and virtual reality
in the sense of this goes to
the human vision system is amazing,
right?
Like the, the,
the fact that we have a blind spot that our brain just straight up tunes out.
Like,
yeah, that it just, wow.
And so as senses go, we heavily rely on vision, especially with computers, right?
Because basically everybody who's blind and uses a screen reader
from what I've read.
It's, it's a pretty horrifying experience compared to, you know, like,
just all the problems they have to deal with.
Right. With all these stupid websites. That's what I hear.
And I feel like how do we give those sort of visual cues
to people
that are not
annoying and messy
or, and like lead to alarm fatigue.
So your brain literally just like, ok, you had your, your old truck, right?
The check engine light was always on
and your brain just was like, cool. That's, that's great.
I'm going to ignore it for the next five years.
Um, we're like 10. Yeah,
but that's the thing, right? Our brains tune stuff out like that because,
oh, I don't need to worry about that.
That's not something that's going to cause me trouble or eat me great.
It's visually gone,
you know, like
close your eyes right now and tell me how many things are on your desk,
right? Nobody can do that
I can because it's three.
I'm in my studio and I have my phone,
my computer and my coffee cup full of water
because it's too late to be drinking coffee.
But
so I guess part of me wonders,
especially with respect to augmented reality and virtual reality.
How do we signal?
But this is like a special thing in some way.
Be it a homo glyph or a control character or, you know what I'm saying?
I think in some cases that's important and I think in other cases it's not.
And I don't know, I don't know if we know the answer. And I guess here is
how I will take us out with this because we're, we're basically out of time anyway, is
we are discussing a problem that doesn't really affect us all that much.
There are countless people in this world who have to deal with
these sort of things every day where they have to deal with
their, their unicode language, their native language and the unicode characters,
they have to deal with their terrible English programming
environments.
They have to deal with
a different language from a person who lives across the street from them.
And
yet somehow societies
in the rest of the world function.
And I think
the real answer here is that
it's not our problem to fix.
There are people far more capable and qualified than us to solve
this problem and they're the ones who we should be working with
to get it done.
You know, I can't help but wonder.
So Apple really paid attention to the human interface design
guidelines from way back in the seventies or whatever.
If I had to guess and put money on this,
do you think they said something
intelligent about this problem we're experiencing?
-- I'd be shocked if they've said anything at all.
-- Well, no, no, no.
But I mean, in general terms of like,
how do we display text characters to people and give
them hints and clues as to what is going on?
I mean, honestly, if Steve Jobs did this, he'd be like, this is the character set,
the whole world will use.
-- I designed it on a piece of paper, use it or die like that is pretty much how
-- that
works.
-- And if it doesn't work for you hold it differently.
-- That's right. It's your fault.
If it doesn't work, it's not mine.
I did it correctly,
I guess. Well, I guess the good news is pretty much everybody has learned English.
So, thanks.
Whatever. No, that's
-- ridiculous. No, that
-- is not a good solution.
But that's the worst that if I had to pick all the solutions,
that's literally the worst one
literally.
And yet it is the solution. Many people
that's pretty
much
come
on. Let's be real. That's what Silicon Valley.
No, I agree. I agree.
I mean, one of my favorite examples like you and I live in cold places. Like
the early self driving cars had never
seen snow.
You know, as soon as there was snow, they, like,
just completely shut down because they literally didn't know what to do.
So, I lived near a couple of major roads in some spots.
They go from 3 to 4 to 5 to even six lanes wide on each side
and straight up when it snows heavily before it gets plowed properly.
Essentially, it's like, ok, we've decided there's five tracks in the snow today.
Ok. It's now a five lane road. That's right.
That's how it works, you know? And just if we all move at the same speed,
it's probably gonna be ok.
Yeah. I mean, yeah.
Yeah, I'm,
I'm completely Fali with this where I've been on
the highway in the snow before and it's like,
well, I'm just gonna drive in these tire tracks because
I don't know what else I'm gonna,
I know I'm in a turn lane but I'm not getting out of the tracks.
-- It doesn't matter.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
-- All right. That, ah, man, snow is coming and I don't want it to.
-- We've been lucky.
It's been, actually, it was plus five today. It was warm.
Uh, yeah, you live way farther north than me. It's
so
far. I think, I think it might have been zero C when I woke up this morning.
-- Which is,
-- we have,
we've been consistently below freezing overnight for a while now.
-- Yeah,
-- we haven't gotten there yet. I haven't seen Ice yet. It's coming though.
I know it is.
And, and I'm actually, I'm excited for my, my electric vehicle
experience to see if, by spring I'm like, this is the worst purchase I have ever made.
-- I don't know.
-- Yeah.
I've actually learned a lot about trampoline maintenance and
ice over the last week and a half.
-- Did you
-- say trampoline maintenance?
Yeah.
My two trampolines are out in the backyard.
-- My kids are still using because what else are we going to do?
-- Oh, I suppose.
Yeah, that's fair.
And you had ice on your trampoline.
-- Are you
-- saying it rained and then it froze and so I had to learn how to not get the,
all this ice off the trampoline.
-- And also you just
-- like, tell the kids to go jump on it
like, well,
-- but then they get wet socks and they get annoyed and cold feet
-- so
that, it sounds like fun. I want to jump on an ice covered trampoline.
That sounds great.
I whacked it off.
II, I like, hit it with the pool scraper and then used the, uh,
I bought a leaf floor actually to get stuff off the trampolines, which works great.
By the way.
-- There you go, folks.
-- No, seriously. All that's the thing. I love.
All the new battery powered handheld tools are just so good nowadays.
Yeah. Yeah,
they are. But I'm not, we're not talking about that. I'm cutting us off.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for putting up with us.
You can go to over Atar Security
podcast.com. Head up the show notes, Su Pound
O
Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.