Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode number
37 with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
How you doing, Kurt?
I am doing actually surprisingly awesome.
Fantastic, man.
So this week, yeah, nothing exciting has happened so far, right?
Not really. I mean, there were those two kernel vulnerabilities, but honestly,
-- you know, who cares?
-- No one will ever know because
because of vault seven,
which is way cooler than vault one through six. Right.
True. Yeah. Sadly, I've never played fallout.
It's been
actually I, I just II, I know a fall out boy,
which I appreciate because do you know why he holds
his thumb up in the strange way he does?
So
I, I didn't know this. I, I think I learned this from Reddit one day. But
so the, the, the thinking is if you hold your arm out and you hold your thumb up
and if your thumb can cover the mushroom cloud,
you're far enough away from the nuclear blast that you won't die
if
it doesn't cover it, like you better get moving.
But what if you have like those weird flat paddle thumbs?
You know, some people have those, like, weirdly flat thumbs.
I, this is an estimate, I imagine.
Right.
And like, yes, if your thumb is the size of a dinner plate,
I'm sure the least of your problems is going to be the fallout from a nuclear blast.
Yeah.
Well, it reminds me of, um, what was it called? I think it was, uh,
it was a,
it was a short range nuclear weapon but the launcher couldn't launch
-- the weapon far enough for the crew to kind of survive
-- whoops,
uh
you know, minor detail. Right. Yeah.
Well, I mean, I, I assume by the time you're using those kind of weapons,
that's the least of your concerns.
Yeah, that's probably fair. I
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah,
you're right.
Yeah. So, yeah, so the big news this week Vault Seven.
Oh man,
it's so,
so here's what I wanna do is I don't wanna dwell on
too many of the crazy details of this because there have been
numerous write ups that are much better than anything we could possibly do.
And
what I want to talk about is the fact that Vault Seven
convinces me beyond a reasonable doubt that
we now live in the Neuromancer universe.
I would agree and I would go one further than that cause
there's a really awesome comment here on hacker news I wanna read
but puts Vault Seven
in a, in a sort of it frames it in a way I would have never thought. Um But basically,
so this is from uh
this is on hacker news uh item 13810015.
from a po
here we go in what is surely one of
the most astounding intelligence own goals in living memory?
The CIA structured its classification regime
regime such that for most market valuable part of
vault seven
unquote the
CIA'S weaponized malware
implants and zeros listening posts LP and command and control systems.
The agency has little legal recourse.
The CIA made these systems unclassified.
Why the CIA chose to make its cyber
arsenal unclassified reveals how concepts developed for military
use do not easily cross over to the battlefield of Cyber war
to attack its targets.
The CIA usually requires that its implants communicate
with their control programs over the internet.
If the CIA implants,
command and control and listening post software were classified,
then CIA officers could be prosecuted or dismissed for violating
rules that prohibit placing classified information onto the internet.
Consequently,
the CIA has secretly made most of its cyber spying and war code unclassified.
The US government is not able to assert copyright
either due to restrictions in the US constitution.
This means that the cyber arms manufacturers and computer hackers can freely,
you know, basically, quote
unquote pirate these weapons if
they are obtained.
The CIA has primarily had to rely on obfuscation to protect its malware secrets.
That's fascinating to me that's from the vault seven stuff.
Uh,
you know,
that sounds like a lot of legalistic. Mumbo jumbo. I mean, let's face it.
I
don't think it matters that much to be honest,
-- but it isn't,
-- but it puts an interesting light on this in that,
you know, for example, if you have a classified Zero Day,
well,
how do you use it online?
If it's classified, you would have to, it would have to, by definition
be able to be used on a non classified network,
the internet
and it might fall into the wrong hands
-- if they have an idea.
-- That's overly legalistic to me though because I mean,
-- let's face it.
-- Have you worked for the government
ever?
No, I never worked for the government.
There, there's,
they have their classified rules and they have all
these rules and all this stuff that happens,
but
there's still the realm of reality they exist in.
And I mean, I,
I'm sure this is very similar
to the transport of classified intelligence documents
which let's face it.
You know,
you see in the movies where you got like the guy with
the briefcase and the handcuffs and all that stuff because in reality,
you bet you a significant number of these documents are
literally transferred by like a dude with an envelope.
Most diplomatic pouches are just like literally a pouch
with a seal on it and like fedex,
right?
And, and I'm sure that that technically violates some obscure law, but in reality,
these guys have work to get done and they're gonna get it done.
I, whatever that,
ignoring the legal side of it. I've always wondered about this because,
you know, when I use some intrusion technique, like I break into a safe or something,
the actual technique is not necessarily, you know, exposed
as
-- easily.
-- I'm
gonna call this up. How many safes have you actually broken into
zero?
But basically what I'm saying is like there's a, I mean,
the reality is most people don't have good cyber defense,
they don't have
cyber
defense.
But the reality is if you know, by their nature, these digital things can easily,
you know, be cloned and copied.
Yeah, I mean, that's the nature of digital.
I mean, heck man, that's the nature of physical documents.
Once you write something down on a piece of paper, I mean, all,
all you need is another piece of paper and a pen
and you can copy the document. I mean, that's the reality of it.
Yeah. No, I'm curious about this because it's
the whole vault seven thing and, and apparently, uh, I mean,
you mentioned this earlier,
but apparently the majority of the stuff is not actually zero days or that,
-- you know, fancy schmancy.
-- That's my understanding is it's not zero days.
And, and the first thing I thought of when this all came out was, was Neuromancer.
And
if, if any of you out there listening, have not read the book Neuromancer.
I suggest you, uh, press pause right now
and go read the book
because
I, I'll probably, I,
-- I guarantee the first
-- chapter and then come back and finish the podcast,
-- be gone for a week.
-- You won't regret it. Just read the whole book and
I'm, I'm certain we're going to spoil it
and that's
whatever it doesn't matter. It's an old book. It was written in 1984.
If you haven't read it by now, you certainly should.
And,
but here's the thing I remember reading this way back in the day
and
one of the things that always stuck out to me is
they, they basically,
the main character is
case. I, I think it's,
and he, he buys like a, an exploit
from
the icebreaker. Exactly from, and I think he even said it was from China
and this thing, like, it builds itself up and it, it, it, you know,
he keeps watching it in cyberspace and, and it's turning into this huge thing and the
virus. Right. Right.
It goes to like it, it doesn't attack and, and you know, it, it,
what it breaks through the turning rules or whatever it is to let neuro.
So
turing was the agency in charge of uh
licensing and controlling a is and making
sure they didn't, like, wipe out humanity.
Well, I'm glad you remember this better than I do. But, but here's the point.
-- Here's the point. Right.
-- It's not always good. That I remember these things,
whatever, man. It's awesome.
So, but here's the deal, right? Is
I, I think about Neuromancer. I remember being like, that's not how exploits work.
You don't just buy an exploit from China
and then it,
it builds itself up into some giant
monstrous creature and then attacks the internet.
And now I'm like,
that's exactly the way it works.
You know, it's funny
because, I mean, nowadays we take, we take,
do you remember when Satan came out security analysis tool for networks?
-- And
-- it was 95 maybe? Yeah.
And it was like, literally the end of the world as we knew it like that.
I almost got sued. It was in, you know, it was
a, it was like
huge, it was a huge deal.
And of course, it's funny now because things like
mises and Metas
are just like, whatever, they're commercial products, who cares,
you know,
and even things like metas plait.
I remember when, you know, HD Moore came out with Meta,
it was like, oh my God, you know,
we're doomed because the bad guys are gonna
have this like tool that they're gonna like
rape and pillage the internet with and all that.
And it's like, and now it's just kind of like, yeah, whatever,
you know,
and, you know, I, I even uh
one of the 1st 1st commercial ones was uh core impact
and I actually went, you know,
um
down to Argentina and like wrote the documentation for it. And I was like, holy cow.
This is the best thing. And here's the funniest thing is like
their test servers keep, kept getting screwed up because they would, like,
they had the,
they had several different exploits and one of the
exploits was they could inject the exploit into the running
code of the process.
So there was like nothing that would show up anywhere
basically,
right?
Like it would,
it would compromise whatever service you compromised and like inject a bit of
shell code into it and then just happily like listen on port,
whatever it was and like take commands and stuff
and they had to reboot that machine every once in a while
because it just got kept getting so infested by the testers,
you know, and they couldn't get these things to die.
They just wouldn't, the shell code just wouldn't die.
There was no nice way to clean it out.
So they would just have to reboot this thing every day or two,
right?
And that's what really gets me is when you look at
some of these root kits and some of these other,
you know, tools,
how do you get rid of them?
Like how do you get them off of a running system nicely or even detect them?
But if you look at the requirements of these tools, like turning it off
isn't on the list, right?
I mean, once you get in, let's face it,
it runs till it's found and then turning it off isn't your problem.
And that leads to the second thing which is on something like, say a smart TV.
-- How the hell do I examine the system?
-- Right.
-- So,
-- actually the TV,
one is super interesting because I wanted to pick on
this and especially pick on you because you're very anti
smart TV. And I'm lazy and I connected my smart TV to the, it's
-- not that I'm
-- anti
-- smart TV, it's that they suck,
-- whatever it runs out.
No,
not even security wise, I've seen the apps on these things. They're garbage.
They don't,
youtube takes like a minute to turn on
my smart TV. Runs Road.
And so it's awesome,
but here's the deal, here's the deal.
The TV
-- actually has a Roku built into it,
-- like it's built into it,
which is why I bought this particular TV.
Yeah. Yeah, I think it's the only one and, and that was
when I saw that I said
I'm buying this and it's not even like one of the
fancy brands by any means. It's, uh, I think insignia is the name of it.
It's like, it's like one of best buys off brands, but
that Roku
built into it was that totally sealed the deal for me.
And I'm, I'm quite pleased with it actually all in all. Um, anyway, this,
if I could buy one honestly with an apple TV, built into it, I would buy that.
Yeah. Right. Right. Exactly. Same deal. Right. Anyway, anyway, so here's the deal
is the various things I read talking about smart
tvs and this Vault seven thing says that apparently
the,
the malware that targeted smart tvs didn't care
if it was connected to the internet or not
because it would just use the Wi Fi on the TV
to connect to something to X, fill the data later.
And so, like, even if
you don't have your TV connected to the internet,
it doesn't mean you're safe because there, it, it, it can connect to a Wi Fi
and it could be like, literally, you know, the,
the plumbing truck parked on the street
and, and it happens to be,
you know, an open access point
and full of not plumbing supplies.
It's getting better because honestly, by default, all the routers issued by, well,
the local IP S at least here in Canada by and large have, you know,
a password enabled on them.
Yeah.
-- Well,
-- you know, if you buy a router kind of in general now it comes with a password,
but it doesn't even matter if it has an open access point.
The fact is you could have the malware.
-- You have
-- a
drone.
-- Right.
-- Exactly.
You
have a drone with the Wi
-- Fi, the gums stick thing.
-- I mean,
let's face it if you have a piece of hardware and it has a Wi Fi radio in it
or
Bluetooth. Right. Any sort of radio, right?
Who basically have a means of XL now built into that device.
Where was that on? Um, remember that, um,
uh, phone radio hack?
There was, remember the be,
oh, hey, here we go was from two years ago. Wow.
Um,
so I was looking for at the Chaos computer conference in Germany,
they had a guy who basically managed to get like a, a normal IP speaker phone
to become a radio transmitter. Remember?
Um,
but here's the thing,
-- he
-- just bit
banged, uh, like an unused pin
to get it to listen.
Um,
but apparently also because here's a dirty little secret. Right.
All cell phones have an FM,
uh, chip set built into them. Remember, for the FCC emergency stuff or whatever?
Yes. Cell phones have amazingly versatile
S pr radios and
apparently you can maybe sort of get them to listen outside the frequency
-- range of what they're supposed to.
-- I believe it.
Well, it's kind of like, have you ever, uh, there's these radios,
RT L something or other?
I have one at home.
I have a software to find
one of those. I have one of those
new
-- hicky. It's like a little USB key.
-- Right. Right.
-- Yeah,
-- I think I paid like 13 for mine from China.
Yeah, they're super cheap.
But here's the deal is there. They were, they're meant to be
essentially a television receiver for high def television.
And someone figured out one day that Hey, this is,
this is a radio that we can tune to this huge frequency range,
not just this narrow band that's used for television
and they're, they're super awesome.
Well, that's what gets me right.
It is just this classic thing of, like, well,
we could implement a control in hardware but that would cost money.
So let's just do it in software. Yeah. Right. Exactly. You know.
And so, yeah, all these,
all these quote unquote hardware radios are actually just like
a completely generic radio that can do pretty much anything.
And they just,
you know, well, that's, I mean, that's always been the classic problem in Linux.
Right.
All these Wi Fi drivers are binary blobs because they don't want people, like,
blasting out their transmitters at like, six watts or some, you know,
absurd amount of power or, you know, across wonky frequencies or,
you know, like in North America. Right. We have 11 Wi Fi channels.
Right. France. Yeah, France and Japan have like, what is it? 13 or something?
There's like two wars,
you know?
So, you know.
Yeah, I mean, you don't want people interfering with, like, the radios used by,
I don't know,
-- the police or whatever,
-- whatever, man. I,
yes,
anyway,
so we won't get into this.
-- But,
-- yeah. No, it's, it's, it is,
it is fascinating because
I think what it really boils down to is
ok.
If you have internet access there's, you can't, like,
data will be ex filtrated end of story.
And even without internet, it's still,
it's,
I mean, there was that article about, you know, using hard drive lights to flash
Morse code out.
Right. That's the thing, you know, you don't need
-- internet. I think the fact is that just
-- have the smart TV, show QR codes
and look
through the
-- windows
-- so
many ways to exel
data. I think
we've reached a point that if you're up to no good
and you have any sort of
electronic device in your possession,
you're in trouble.
I mean, that's just the reality of it.
Well, and I mean, this would be why, you know, the US and, well,
Western agencies in general have historically invested
a lot of money in tempest shielding
and, you know, things like skiffs, you know, what is it,
secure compartmentalized information,
uh,
whatever things which are basically to put it bluntly shielded
rooms where you can control what goes in and out
physically and electronically.
Um, but it's hugely expensive because I actually looked at doing it for my house
to keep my kids off the internet when they get older.
No, it's just, it's too expensive.
Excessive.
Well, it's just, you know, because the reality is four or five years.
Well, already today you could go to a pawn shop and buy a new smartphone for 10 bucks.
You can go to the store and buy a new smartphone for 10 bucks.
I think you need a credit card.
Can you use a prepaid credit card?
Uh, good point.
Yeah.
Anyways, but point being
is, it was more like, because, you know,
when you and I were kids we would read under the bed with like a flashlight.
Right.
That was our Wi Fi stealing. Yeah, exactly.
And our kids are going to be, like,
hiding under the bed with like an ipod or an ipad
or a whatever Samsung Galaxy seven that hopefully doesn't catch fire.
This is where I'll just hook up the directional SDR
their bedroom.
So I'll know if they're, they're using Wi Fi in the middle of the night.
But I mean, that's the thing like tempest shielding is incredibly expensive
and almost impossible to do correctly because even a
pinhole gap is enough to like leak radio signals.
-- Yeah,
-- it's complicated. It's not that
easy. So here's what we want to look at it. So
you have a microwave, right?
And you can see inside of your microwave, right
when it's on
and it cooks things
and what is protecting you from
boiling your eyeballs when you look inside your microwave,
-- the shield with the little perforated
-- holes and the small holes.
And so what it really comes down to is the, if,
if the whole size is smaller than the wavelength of the radio signal,
which let's face it, microwaves operate at like five gigahertz,
then
you won't die.
So it's
pinhole, it's more complicated than
-- fundamentally
-- when you talk about doors and windows and stuff.
Yes. Exactly. It's, it's hard to do. I'll agree with that.
Well, it's hard to do correctly and, I mean, I, like,
you know, you need window coverings, you need door gaskets,
you need all sorts of crazy stuff.
So, the reality is nobody's going to do it apart from the government,
-- you
-- don't have windows if you're in a room
that you care about this kind of stuff.
-- Well, that's not true. Uh
-- Like you don't have windows. If there are windows, that's
no, just don't use that room
like,
-- well.
-- So for example, here in Edmonton, we have a lovely brick
square cube down town, the central exchange
and it's got this lovely concrete thing over
the door with the old Edmonton Tell logo over
it and it's like such a big massive hunk of concrete and the logo is so deep,
they can't get rid of it even though the phone company changed name twice now.
And it's got
the building has these weirdly gold colored
windows that are like eight inches wide,
4 ft tall, roughly,
you know, and, and they're obviously shielded, right?
Ok. And it's more about, you know,
shielded. No, if, if you're dealing with
classified info,
you do not have a window because people can
look in the window and see what you're doing
like seriously
oval office,
the oval office is,
yes, it has windows. I'll agree with that. However, however,
however,
I will say that
-- the, the truly interesting class.
-- If you're
behind the oval office looking in the windows, we got bigger problems.
Yeah.
Right. Exactly.
It's,
and, and not only that, I, I don't know this for sure, but I would suspect
that
the layout of that room is
not a coincidence
and,
you
know, they gutted the White House in the 19 sixties. Right.
So,
they, actually, there's,
there's pictures of the White House with structural steel holding it up and
the inside is empty and there's people in bulldozers driving around it.
Yeah, they, well, so, uh, historically because I'm Canadian.
So, you know, the war of 1812,
the reason the White House is white is because the British sailed up the Potomac and,
you know, shelled it and burned it down.
So they painted it white when they redid it all.
So it got rebuilt then.
And like I said, in the 19 sixties,
I forget when I think it was Nixon or Ford or something.
But they basically, the, the concern was, you know,
if a nuke went off anywhere near that thing,
it would have collapsed and killed the president,
right?
Because it was like a really old building.
And so they literally gutted it,
like they put up structural steel to hold it up and they,
they gutted it and rebuilt it to like military, you know, standards,
right? And that was like 4050 years ago. So,
yeah, I mean, well, and no doubt you know,
it's not like they spared any expense because
it's the White House, like, obviously.
-- Right. Right. Exactly. It's, it's like Air Force one.
-- Right.
It's like this costs only $2 billion.
Right.
Yeah, White Hill Reconstruction was, oh, I lied. Sorry, it was in 1950.
And, yeah, there's a lovely picture on Wikipedia here of a bunch of guys,
like a bunch of dump trucks and bulldozers driving around the inside.
I did not know that.
Well, part of it too was the thing was actually, I mean, without a nuke,
it was going to fall down
as well.
So
there was also, you know, like it was,
well, it was,
I
mean, it, it got burnt down once already
100 years ago before that. So,
so
anyway,
we're talking about vault seven and classified
intelligence and the fact that it's,
it's impossible
to
prevent your data.
How do, well, even preventing that,
how do I even know the state of my cell phone or my smart TV?
You have no idea. In fact, that's something I was
about
dump the firm.
No goodness. No.
You know,
you can't and you own an Apple phone which makes it even worse than some of the others.
Not that I've given any better shape. I mean, let's face it.
Well, it's not only that one of, one of the challenges here as well is
I was reading that there are various news organizations reporting that
signal
and whatsapp encryption have been broken and in reality.
Right. Exactly. That's exactly right where
the, the, the apps and the encryption are fine,
they just attack the end points which let's face it
is the easy way to deal with that problem.
Oh, totally. I have a machine with a wireless keyboard.
If anybody ever sets up a, you know, radio sniffer,
they're gonna find out my login password.
And I don't, let's encrypt the data at least.
Ok.
Well, in fairness, I,
I actually looked for a keyboard that said they do
AES encryption and they supposedly do a s encryption.
But like, again, how, how do I verify this? How do I verify that they're using any
for all I know.
Yeah, they're doing a s encryption but every single one has the same key
because you'd have to have the dongle paired to the keyboard
and at the manufacturer they're gonna actually put a separate key on each of these,
like a $30 keyboard man.
Like, exactly. So, honestly, I'll tell everybody right now
the password to the unprivileged account on the Mac Me in my living room is password.
That's
a very bad. Why bother.
Uh Sure.
-- Yeah, I mean,
-- I,
I run,
you know, I,
what's the point of pretending to have a password?
But I'm transmitting it wirelessly all the time.
You just not have a password
on a Mac.
Um,
I guess I could have an auto log into something but it's just
I also want to be able to log in as my cell.
It's basically also my backup workstation in case my primary one, like,
catches fire or something.
So, there's like an unprivileged account that basically lets you do,
like youtube and VL, like, run the media player.
Right. Right. Ok. Interesting.
Well, it was either that or like, you know, set up a Plex box or something, but
that's a lot of work.
Yeah, exactly. Mac mini plug it in. Go,
you know what else is convenient when you buy a TV, with Roku built into it.
Oh, I mean, I used to live in the US.
That's right.
That's right. That's right.
So, and, and just, uh, you know, I
-- was
-- gonna, however, I will say
I can't like kinder eggs, which I think is the greatest crime
against
that. Goes back to a law from the 19 thirties
where you can't have a non-food item in a food.
And, you know, the worst thing is there is a kinder
egg quasi
equivalent that's allowed in the US.
And what they did is they have a plastic shell inside,
surrounded by chocolate
-- with a little plastic pig sticking out.
-- I know
-- I,
-- I've had them the,
the, I
-- hear that they are sadness personified.
-- The chocolate isn't near as good.
And the toys inside made me sad.
So it is not nearly as good. In fact, funny enough is,
uh, yeah. Anyway,
no kinder eggs. It makes me sad.
Well, and it's a $2500 fine per egg
to import them to the U si looked at sending you a
bunch but then when I found out what the fine was,
I decided not to.
That's, that's a risk you should be willing to take.
Well, II I can still send you squirrels.
-- Uh,
-- you can mail me
not African squirrels,
not African squirrels. That's right.
Yeah.
-- Right.
-- We're talking about vault seven or we're trying to
vault seven. Kind of reminds me of this whole Lius
curl thing. It's just like, yeah, it's bad.
But like, honestly, it's just another day at the office for us.
You know, I, I don't think you're wrong and this is where I come back to my,
we live in the Neuro Manta universe kind of view on all this is,
this is the way the world works now is
there's constant security issues, there's constant exploits,
there's constant leaks.
And
I would
say it's worse than that because
we've now entered a world where, like
the majority of my computers
are boot locked to some degree, for example, my iphone and my ipad.
Right. I, I can't like, stick in a SIM card or an SD card and boot it off of that.
Um,
you know, uh,
ignoring all of that, both A MD and Intel
CP us have like that binary blob thing, microcode stuff.
Um,
all my Wi Fi chip sets have a binary blob, all my cell phone chip sets have a binary blob
that can apparently be exploited via like wonky S MS
text messages,
-- the
-- cell
phone
crazier because most people don't realize.
But your cell phone actually has kind of two computers inside of it. Is there one?
Well, ok. Yeah, that's fair.
But there's, there's like the main computer you think of,
say I OS or Android
CPU
and then there's the, the baseband
processor, which is actually the thing that runs the cell phone radio
and that's,
those are like hideously exploitable is my understanding and things like
that text messages can actually kind of take them over.
Oh, yeah. No, that's happened. That's been published.
I mean, we'll put in the show notes. But um
yeah, hang on, sir.
You gotta love it, man.
Uh Yeah, I mean just, oh jeez, that's sad.
Oh
dear
Pack phone S MS Remotely.
-- Hello. It's called hellos spy
-- dot com.
And I would imagine Lord, it still works on many, many things. Right.
Well,
this is one of the reasons I will never buy an
Android phone in Canada because the carriers don't give freaking updates.
Uh No, they do not. Well, even in the US, it's really bad.
I mean, there's some of the phones like Samsung does. Ok.
I own a Nexus which is Google itself and in fact,
I don't get my updates through my carrier.
I get them directly from Google
and
you know, the, the big brands
do. Ok.
And then it's, it's bad once you kind of exit that sphere.
No, I'm looking at buying a couple of cheap tablets for just media players. Right.
Just literally to have something you can hold in your hand and watch a movie on.
I assume that I'm gonna,
-- whatever version I'm getting of Android is what I'm stuck with
-- probably.
And, you know,
just buy like the crappiest cheapest ones you can instead
of the guest wi fi network and who cares?
-- Pretty much.
-- Yeah,
that's, that's the only thing you can do. I mean, let's face it. It's,
and, and again, though,
we kind of bring ourselves back to this neuro mana
world now where you have these devices that were,
they're, they're, let's say five years old,
they haven't had security updates in forever.
And so, like,
the idea of buying a security exploit kit to
use against one of these things is totally plausible
because,
you know, there, there have been five years of security for
that now, work against this device.
I would disagree with that.
There's more than five years because they had security flaws when they were
created because the software, like,
it's not like you build software for a car in one day and ship it.
That stuff is like one or two years old by the time it's shipped.
Right. Absolutely.
Actually, what's really funny if you say that? And so
I was one of the lucky individuals to acquire a Nintendo switch on launch day.
And of course,
being who I am,
what's the first thing I do?
I go into the menu and look at the
licensing info that shows all the open source licenses
and all the things you're using and,
and for what it's worth, uh, this, this is well known now,
but it runs free BS D and it's got uh free Bs D.
Yeah, it's got free BS DC
notices all over the place.
But here's the other interesting thing though,
if you look at a lot of these other libraries, it's using like Lib PNG, for example,
or Lib XML or whatnot.
Well, that's the thing. The copyright notices are all from like, 04 and 09.
And I don't think there were very many that were
in 2010.
But here, here's what I wonder.
Right is, are they actually using old versions of the software?
They are? And I'm sure they are. And that makes me sad. Or
the,
the thing I'm hoping they do is they just happened to download
the old copyright notice using an updated version of the software.
How don't ruin the
stream
card, don't ruin it.
Ok. Ok.
So what they,
what,
what probably happened is when the lawyers were reviewing the copyrights,
they made a Typo
and it was probably from 2017. But they, you know, it's just, that's probably,
-- so,
-- you're, you're ok, you're
all right.
-- So,
-- the good news is,
I guess that means there's a good chance we can jailbreak these things because
that's one of the things holding me back from buying a wii U is I was like, you know, I,
I google like wii U jailbreak and it's like what?
Actually, you know, it's
funny if you talk about that and Nintendo has a bug bounty on the switch. So if you find
a way to jailbreak it,
you can acquire yourself some money.
-- How much do they
-- pay? I don't know. I don't think it's terrible,
but
is it less than those guys in China or whatever would pay you?
I, are there guys in China shelling out for
switch?
Oh, dear. $100 minimum bounty
or Nintendo?
Yeah. I'm just looking
at the page 100 bucks minimum bounty.
-- That's it.
-- That's the only number given.
Well, look at like Tavis, I mean, Tavis Ormon, he finds like,
literally the worst damn bug on the internet ever.
It's like everything that's ever been through Cloer
May or may not have been exposed and we don't know.
And he might at best qualify for a
t-shirt.
I hope they sent him a t-shirt.
I hope they send him a,
like a truck full of t-shirts or a house shaped like a T shirt because
like, seriously.
Oh, interesting. Arm 11 and Arm Nine
Kernel and user land takeover
or the switch.
Yeah. So it's got an arm nine and an arm 11.
Kernel. Well, that actually makes sense. Right.
Because you got the handheld part and the dock part.
Well, no, I thought the dock part was only like, literally just a pass through
like the, the, the, uh,
the circuit board and it was like an inch square or something ridiculously tiny.
That could very well be.
I know when I, I called the toaster, which if you've never seen before,
it looks like you're putting it in the toaster.
And I,
I think my kids are almost on board with this
and I figure eventually I'll brainwash them to the point.
They won't know any better. But regardless of that is,
yeah, when you dock it, it, it works as a handheld
and you dock it and it obviously shows up on the TV at that point.
But my, my understanding is the, the toaster
doesn't have anything in it and it
basically is just passing everything straight through.
And the other thing that's interesting is
when you're holding it in your hand,
it, it obviously reduces performance a little bit in whatever you're doing with it.
But when you dock it, it actually has a fan inside of the switch and you can feel the,
like it gives off a lot of heat.
So they're obviously like, they're cranking something to
it down right when you plug that sucker in doing
it.
No, it's, it's,
-- that's smart.
-- Yeah. Yeah,
it is.
That's one thing that gets me about Nintendo. Right.
Their build quality historically has been amazing. Like my Nintendo, we
um I bought it a year after it came out in 2006. So I bought it in 2007.
So 10 years ago played with it for a little while, then put it in a box
and it's been in a box in the basement, in the garage in a bunch of places,
pull it out,
plug it in.
Uh I had to actually on Amazon buy like a
little adapter for whatever Wonky Nintendo thing to HDMI.
-- I plug it in. Boom. It just works. But
-- you have your, your Wii U
or your regular Wii plugged into HDM. I
Yeah, it's like a, it's like a $10 adapter you can buy on Amazon for it.
Just go to Amazon and Google like Nintendo wii HDM. I, and it's like this little $10
thing from China. Like, I don't know, it just works.
I, I only had mine doing what RGV video,
but
-- it
-- looks like you're watching like a VCR on the TV.
Like it's, it is hysterically terrible. Like,
you know, like, well, no, no, no, it's, it's no, it, it is the, I mean, the,
that poor little Wii is putting out all the pixels.
It can,
it's just, it was designed in a day and age where, you know,
the number of pixels on a TV could be like, counted by a human being in an afternoon
because I think the wii by default only does like, what, 480 P.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah. Well, it was designed for, like, C RT S.
Yes.
Right.
And so, yeah, you hook it up to like a 40 or 50 inch TV. And it's like, whoa.
Yeah, let's stand back a little bit and squint.
Actually, I haven't done that before. I,
-- that's awesome.
-- I don't think I want to. Although, you know what?
I have a, I think it's a 40 some odd inch TV.
And I hook,
-- we
-- don't even know how big our
-- teams are. Like,
-- who cares? It's big enough, right? It doesn't matter.
Uh I, I hooked up my nes, my Nintendo entertainment system to it some months ago and
the games look hilariously bad
-- when you plug them in.
-- Well, the funny thing is you actually need,
uh, and you can buy these, you can get these filters for like opening moon stuff
to essentially the, the old consoles used the pixel layout on the C RT s
to their advantage.
And so you actually have to have like a filter.
That sort of, I don't want to say down samples it, but sort of
shift samples that I guess would be maybe the word, I forget what the word is,
but essentially it
mangle
because the pixels on an L CD and the pixels on AC RT are, are different,
right?
And so it kind of mangles it. Uh But I'm just looking here.
Um, yeah, here's the one I bought. So dial we to HDM I converter 40 P,
uh,
$6.90
big spender. So, actually, you know, you mentioned the, the C RT thing and
have you ever seen, do
you remember CG A graphics from back in the day?
-- They were like, always like pink and blue,
-- right?
-- Managed to skip straight to V
-- G A.
But here's the deal. Ok.
So
anyone who remembers CG A,
they were hideous. But they weren't though, here's the deal. They weren't,
they weren't. And I'll, I'll put a link in the show notes.
There's this guy on youtube called,
I think he's called himself the eight bit guy or something like that.
And
anyway, so, so
CG A graphics relied on analog signals into AC RT.
And so when you, when you combine the colors in bizarre ways,
they actually look really nice. But when it's a purely digital signal as it was,
it's, it's pink and blue and it looks like,
and it's really crazy
to see how these, these obviously, you know,
designers utilize these bizarre nuanced
qualities of AC RT screen.
Well, it was like, um, I forget which video game it was,
but all the sound files were just random chunks of memory
that sound good when you played it through a speaker.
I, well, I, I know on the Atari
you were saying that Y
is revenge, I think is the name of it but anyway, we, we're in the weeds
we're
talking about.
Well, but here's the reality, right.
This stuff matters about as much as this vault seven in the sense of, like, like
this stuff is full of, it's, it's all, you know,
it's all flaws all the way down.
Why,
why are we surprised?
Yeah.
You know, it's like this week.
Oh, look, there's, uh,
I actually pulled up the emails in case I have to reference them.
And then I think I closed the tabs because quite frankly, who cares
to put it bluntly, like,
go to OS S security and like search for Linux kernel
and there's one for 4.5 and up and there's one for
some other version,
it's like a local exploit to root and it's like,
uh OK,
that
happens.
Here's the thing and this is what I wonder about a lot is
if this is the new normal
and I think it is
-- like, what is that?
-- How
-- is it gonna change?
-- Right.
-- What, what?
I mean, are things ever going to get better? And I, I'm, you know, the optimist in me
believes there's always hope and things are certainly going to get better.
There is because, ok, we'll have to put this in the show notes.
But uh this is an amazing page. Um, chrome
security
breaks.
Um
There is a security breaks sheet from the Chromium project.
Yes, I
read that the other day.
Yeah,
it's pretty damn impressive.
Now, I think the reality is something like, for example, chrome or the lungs kernel
will never be correct and it will always have security flaws,
but
we can deal with that. We can work around that.
We can do things like sand boxing, we can do things like,
you know, antivirus and ad filtering and stuff to minimize
the chances of getting nasty stuff
and then building with failure in mind.
So like, you know, assuming that at some point,
some horrible content is gonna come in and hijack it, you know,
do sandbox and do you know,
demarcating the system into, you know, various chunks, you know,
and
that is the new normal, right? Like the new normal is things like cus
programming where you like actually break up
your program into a bunch of like little
cus chunks
with well defined interfaces
that, you know, if an attacker manages to get through hopefully one layer,
they can't get any further, you know,
because the reality is like the Linux kernel is, is never going to get simpler.
-- It,
-- it is not, it will
make it worse.
Chrome or the Linux kernel
are
very high profile projects that let's face it
have really smart people working on them.
And so I think they're in a different league
and let's face it even like we can even pick on the kernel.
Like the kernel has some of the smartest people in the
world working on it and it still has lots of problems.
Well, I mean, my hope is, and this is why I love open source.
My hope is is that these guys in China were not making stuff
rather than build it in house or whatever.
We'll simply like, oh,
let's go download the latest version of Busy Box and keep it up to date.
Now. Obviously, they're not keeping it up to date,
but that's my hope.
Why would they do that? Why should they care? And let's pick on Busy Box, right.
Busy Box
is a phenomenal piece of software, but it is not built for security or failure.
For the most part, it does what it's supposed to do
by stripping out tons of functionality and I'm sure plenty of error checking.
And so how do we expect that
to have any sort of resilience built into it?
Well,
so here's the problem that boils again down to
that economic problem of why would I spend money
maintaining a product for which you are not paying
like a subscription for it, like you paid for it once I shipped it to you, ha ha.
Right.
You,
you know,
so that's, that actually leads nicely into.
There was, uh there's a guy on, on Twitter, I follow Jeremiah Grossman. We uh
we, we met him at RS A, actually, he was a guy from Sentinel one that we talked to,
talked about cybersecurity insurance at the speaker dinner.
And
in any way, he, he put a thing on Twitter today that basically said
the the cybersecurity industry is something like $75 billion.
And
I think 1 billion is spent on
securing the software,
but secure insecure software is basically the problem,
right?
And so
how do we fix that incentive?
And
like, honestly, I
don't know,
like I can't even think of anything that isn't just
like made up crap to even try to address this.
Well, see part of my, my thought process is, you know,
for example, looking at engineering,
there are seven ways to build a bridge.
That's it, seven ways,
-- right? There's seven
-- kind of,
there's a right way and the wrong way.
But like fundamentally engineering is like there's seven ways to build a bridge,
then there's a bunch of different concretes and steels and materials
that have certain properties that are well understood and documented.
And when they're not like a great example, being carbon fiber, carbon fiber,
we think it's awesome.
But you know,
Boeing wants to make an airline out of this stuff.
Well, what happens when it constantly cycles through?
But they spent an obscene amount of money making
-- sure it wouldn't like fall apart
-- because they can't
test it with people inside.
Yeah, exactly.
So that's the difference, right?
Is like Boeing can take a new material,
put it through like say 10,000 pressurization cycles and be like, oh OK, it works.
But with software, you know,
we're literally dealing with stuff where it's like five years from now.
It's not that what I built today is obsolete,
but the entire, like
ecosystem of that thing is obsolete.
So I'm going to compare this. I'm sure inappropriately
to bridges.
And
if you look at, when they built bridges, let's say, in the 14 hundreds,
I'll just pull that number out of flying out of my behind
and
like, like, think about those bridges, how many of them lasted for five years?
Probably not very many.
I'm sure many of them killed lots of people and they were just
like literally a dude piled some stuff up until they crossed the river.
And then he said, there's the bridge it's done.
-- And
-- there's a perfect example.
The Roman, you know, army had engineering that was amazing to this.
You know, they've built piers and bridges and roads but stand to this day.
But, you know, again,
they had a very limited set of designs and
a very limited set of well understood materials.
The Romans because they did it right.
And we're going to think about
what is the difference between a bridge built in
the 14 hundreds in a bridge built today.
Yeah.
No, no, seriously answer the question.
So part of it would be materials, part of it would be actually having a plan,
a
-- plan
-- because you could build a bridge today
with the same materials they had in the 14 hundreds. Ok.
So let's take materials out of this.
-- So what's the part
-- of it would be having measurements and plans?
Like you literally could write down a plan for this thing?
Well, that's part of it, right? Is the fact that like
there are rules
and there are designs and there are expectations around
these engineers and not only that the engineers actually,
like if you're, if you're a civil engineer and you build a bridge and it falls down,
you get in trouble and you might not be an engineer anymore.
Well, even more to the point is, um, there's the whole concept of, um, so I worked for,
uh, an electrical firm for a while that did industrial electrical.
And there was the concept of, we have a blueprint
and we have the US built plans
because the reality is when you're building like an oil refinery or something,
you know, and this is like 20 years ago.
So we didn't have the fancy, uh, biff, you know, software that we have now.
But essentially you'd be trying to build something.
You'd be like, oh, there's like a concrete support in the way or, oh,
somebody put like a mash tank here.
Why did they do that?
And so you'd essentially have a set of blueprints that said, like, you know,
from here to here, you have to like, have this cable and it's like, no, we're,
we're gonna have to run around this thing or through this duct or whatever.
And that would be documented.
So you'd actually end up with a set of blueprints called the US Built Plans,
which were literally, it's like, well,
we had a set of blueprints that told us how to build it.
We mostly followed them. Here's the actual blueprints of what we ended up with.
Right.
And that, that in itself is a huge step for us because now, you know, 10 years from now,
some poor schmuck is looking at what was built and it's like,
what is this?
You know, why is this thing here?
Like you and your window that opens?
Right. Right. And, and
no one knows what that means.
So
I am,
I'm actually in San Francisco right now at,
at the Marriott Marquis down by the Mosconi
and
I'm on the 26th floor of the hotel and the window in my room actually opens like
I could open the window and like hang out and wave at people or something or,
or throw things or whatever.
I just, I still think I, I still want pics or something because I don't, honestly,
my brain can't believe
it.
I can't really care for heights a lot.
So I'm like not opening this window and you'll just have to take my word for it.
I basically like I looked at it,
I thought this window looks like it opens and I
opened it like just a teeny crack and said,
yep, it opens and then I closed it and that, that's enough and just knowing it does,
that is terrifying enough for me as it is.
Well, it's funny because I told a friend and, and they were like, what?
And I'm like, exactly, that's what my brain did.
I
agree.
This seems like unnecessarily dangerous to me because
the thing I keep thinking of is
like, I could see
somebody doing something dumb and managing to fall out
of the window and obviously on the 26th floor,
you're not going to have a good,
uh, any fall.
Well, once, once you hit 20 ft, your risk of death hits 50% and that's 20 ft.
That's two stories.
Yeah.
Yeah,
you don't have to fall far to kill yourself.
-- Yeah,
-- that's, I guess, I mean, I never really
-- and kill
-- themselves. That's true. Your bathtub is more dangerous than sharks,
right?
-- What about sharks in your
-- bathtub?
Could a shark?
I bet any shark that would fit in your bathtub is probably not very dangerous.
Let's face it.
I'm, I'm just gonna guess. I, I don't know.
But,
yeah, whatever. Anyway. Yes. Uh, don't keep sharks in your bathtub
unless you're a zoo or advice for the day.
Even if you're a zoo, you should probably have a proper place to keep the sharks,
right?
Not in the bathroom in this,
this podcast is getting unnecessarily silly.
Oh, man. Ok. So here's, let's, let's bring it home
this, this vault seven thing, I guess. This is,
this is the world we live in now and,
and that's really the only commentary I have on this is
right or wrong. Yes or no.
Whatever you want to think about it like this is just the way it is.
There's, there's not a lot you can do about it and,
and I guess at the same time what
the security industry,
what we need to do now is we need to start thinking about things
in that context, not,
we're gonna keep the bad guys out or we're gonna stop this or we're gonna stop that.
But rather
there are adversaries with
impressive arsenals of exploits and problems.
And so we have to decide
what does that mean for us,
how do we design systems to be robust against this versus
the historical view of let's design systems that don't have flaws,
which we know is just totally ridiculous.
Yeah.
So I was,
I was recently dealing with a customer that basically their security posture was
everything's been hacked.
So like, how does your,
how does your product deal with somebody having like
rude access on the file system or how does
your product deal with somebody having like gained administrative access to it?
And it's kind of like, uh
you know,
um but fundamentally, uh from today
related to this poachers break into paras,
shoot Rhino
Steal
Horn.
That's
crazy.
So here's the reality that Horn was apparently worth about 60 $70,000 us.
I'm guessing most tech companies have some data,
relatively,
uh,
easily to monetize
-- to that amount of money.
-- Oh, at least, at least,
you know, it's,
it's like the,
-- it's
-- gonna be less dangerous to ex fill that than it is to break into a Frein
zoo and shoot a rhino.
Yeah.
Well, it's like that, uh, the, the largest bank robbery in, um,
what was it? The, uh, the Ireland
where they basically kidnapped the guy's family and gave him a choice, like,
either, you know, clean up the bank or say goodbye to your family.
Well, I know I'm cleaning out the bank
in
a
minute.
So, you know, that's the thing, right?
Is,
is how do you design a system that
potentially you have adversaries where it's like whatever,
we'll just spend a million bucks finding a flaw
or we'll spend $100,000 bribing one of your key employees
or
spend $100,000 blackmailing one of them
them
for 20 grand.
I bet you could threaten them for five grand
or free.
Yeah. You know.
Um, but yeah, I mean, that's the reality is how do you, you know?
So I, I'm one thing I'm seeing in the cloud, for example,
is they're talking about having systems where, you know,
one person has access to the, uh,
like SSH key,
but the other person has access to actually like the passphrase
on it or whatever and has to type it in,
you know, and you have like, a dedicated laptop for this or whatever.
I've, I've heard of such things and that might be part of the story.
I, I don't think we know. Right.
I, I think the reality is things like that are such a pain in the butt.
Nobody's gonna do them.
Are you kidding me? Well, not.
Yeah, you're, well, ok. Our, our current tools today make them a pain in the butt.
It's,
anyway, anyway, let's,
we will discuss this another day.
-- I think, you
-- know what reminds me of his bank robberies is which in general is,
we've made them difficult enough that they generally don't work.
But if you come up against somebody who's
sophisticated enough or desperate enough and stupid enough, it will work.
-- But not for a lot of money.
-- I think we discussed this at some point.
I don't think we did on the podcast, but there's,
there's a significant number of bank robberies every day.
-- They just,
-- but if
you look at how
much money they get away with, it's kind of,
that's the thing. Ok. And that's the thing and, and that's another story and
we will discuss that another day. I think it's, it's time to go. Kurt.
We've,
we've been down way too many red holes and
wasted far too much of our viewers precious time.
So, thank you everyone for listening. I appreciate it.
If you want to look up the show notes and any of the ridiculous topics we had today.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
And on there you can find links to Twitter and a Facebook group
and
other ways to contact us. And
if nothing else, thank you, everyone for listening. I certainly appreciate it.
And Kirk, you have a fantastic day.
You too. Thanks, Josh.