Hi, Josh, again,
this is part two of the left pad discussion that obviously go back to last week and,
and start there if you land here.
But we kind of spend a lot of this second
half of the discussion talking about the market forces around
the supply chain and left pad and, and it's,
it's shocking how much still still matters today.
So thanks for listening.
Every single person writing a Ruby gem app that uses like these common things.
They're gonna spend tens or hundreds of hours of engineering
and ongoing maintenance and backing it up and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And the answer is no, clearly we're not right.
You know, because that's what's happened. The market has spoken.
-- Uh
-- and, and maybe it has, I, I feel like I wish we could fix this but you might be right.
Maybe,
-- maybe it just never will get bad enough.
-- I don't know that we need to fix this.
It's like houses, burning down,
houses, burn down and apparently over Christmas that it's about twice as likely
for houses in North America to burn down, I guess.
-- Is that like Christmas lights, I assume? Or I I
-- don't know.
Well,
you would think now with led lights it would
be very unlikely because they're so low voltage.
But I'm guessing it's more like
people having fires and they haven't cleaned their chimneys in forever.
Or people having candles.
Right. Like those big red,
you know, Christmas candles that people seem to like whatever. It's true.
The point is houses burn down and it really sucks when a house burns down,
especially when it's minus 40 outside.
But the reality is houses burn down so rarely now that it's kind of like, well,
you know what?
Ok,
like we, we, we're not going to build like in North America,
we build the majority of our, you know, houses out of wood, right?
Two by four plywood construction
and, you know, once they get going, they burn
right. There's condos locally, four story condos, several 100 units
and they're just all plywood and two by four
with like, you know, cinder block, uh, cinderblock staircases for the fire escape.
Ok. So you are right.
But
we didn't get to the point where Fear House is burned down by luck. Right.
Oh, true. No building codes and you know,
lots of operational changes. Like
people don't heat their houses by, uh, well,
I was going to say people don't heat their houses with, you know, wood fires,
for example.
Although my neighbor right next to me does, you know,
the majority of us have like natural gas furnaces now, which again,
generally are quite safe and tend not to catch fire or burn the house down.
So, yeah. No, we definitely didn't get here by just magic.
You know, we got here through a lot. Well, it's like the whole area
disaster thing last year, there weren't any and we got there through like,
decades of continuous improvement,
like decades of, of technology, of operational changes, you know, things like, oh,
maybe we should not make pilots fly for 18 hours straight because when they do,
they tend to get sleepy and you know,
what is it controlled? Descent into terrain, right? They, they fly into things is
if you look at like the N PM and Rube Jams and all these things,
the number of times we have really bad massive
problems that result in massive pain for people.
It's really rare,
like it's so rare that when we look at the N PM thing,
there's essentially that one instant.
Well, there's two instances. The, the second instance being is that
N PM had some sort of weird technical glitch
and a bunch of packages weren't available for a while
and something went wrong. Some people tried to re register the packages.
And so basically there's two examples for N PM in a span of like two or three years.
-- But
-- there's an example every week we have a
podcast that we never run out of content for,
I mean, Equifax, the Intel bug N PM.
There's a million things going
on. They're just unrelated enough.
Well,
but when you consider how many different technologies
and hardware solutions and things we're talking about,
you know, it's just like the real world, look at how many microwaves fail.
Right. And, and let's think about airplanes.
There are thousands of ways an airplane can fail, right?
But the problem is the end result of an airplane crash is a catastrophic event.
People can relate to
the end result of a house burning down is a catastrophic event. People can relate to.
The problem with software is the intel bug
is maybe catastrophic, maybe not. It depends how you want to talk about it.
But fundamentally,
the result of that problem is different than the result
of Equifax is different than the result of the node.
And I think the fact that we have this lack of consistency as
kind of our outcomes is what makes it difficult for people to understand
that these are related problems, but they are not the same problem.
Part of it is, it reminds me of heartbleed.
So when the openness cell, heartbleed bug came out,
normally these things don't make the national news, however,
it did in Canada because revenue Canada had to shut down
their website for taking tax returns, which
it was a week before the deadline for taxes.
And so the final week of tax filing
electronically
didn't work like they turned it off.
And so obviously that made the national news and they
had to extend the filing deadline and it was a,
you know, like
I remember my mom asking me about this because she heard about it on the news, right.
Like the intel meltdown thing as far as I know, never made the news,
like the mainstream media, you know, like cnn.com.
It, it made the online news for sure. But like, was it on TV? I don't really think so.
I don't watch TV, but it was in the local newspaper for what it's worth
and it did get a little blurb in, in, I think the business section for me.
Ok.
-- Yeah, normal people don't read that. Probably
-- not.
I, I did have one normal person. I know
when they, they, I, I talked to them and they're like, so how's it going?
I'm like, I've had better weeks. They said, oh, this is a chip thing, right?
I said, wow. You know what that is? I'm impressed.
Well, no, they don't know what it is, they've heard about
it.
And that's what I was gonna say is the
next problem is for most of these technical failures.
Ok. Plane crashing and burning. Yeah, that's easy
to understand. House burning down.
Easy to understand the specter and meltdown bug.
Not so easy to understand, like, true or false.
Do you have to patch the underlying hardware host?
-- True?
-- You like, always have to patch the underlying host.
-- It doesn't matter what CPU you're running, you
-- just cert says I need a new processor.
Yeah.
If it's, if it's like an X 86 processor, you, you almost guaranteed have to patch.
Now,
here's a question,
virtual machines
running on top of a patch. Toast. Do you need to patch the virtual machines?
But I know the answer to that because it's yes, but um many people probably don't.
Well, the answer is a little more subtle than that. It's
yes for virtual machine to other virtual machine attacks, but no,
for virtual machine to host attacks
if the host is patched.
Right. And so all of a sudden, like
we've gone from simple to, oh, this is actually getting really messy really fast.
And then what's the outcome of this bug? Well, you can steal some data
in theory, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Right. It's not like
-- it catches fire or it just fails. It's like no,
-- it's nothing explodes.
Exactly. Not like the movies.
And, you know, that's the thing, like
most of these security flaws even trying to explain it,
you know, it becomes
very complex very rapidly. And that was one thing I noticed about the meltdown.
Inspector coverage is everybody on Twitter complaining incessantly about
how the journalists were getting technical deet tells wrong.
It's like, of course, they are like,
ask somebody to explain how to change a wheel on a car and
nine times out of 10 myself included,
I get it wrong because I always forget that you crack the nuts first
and then put the thing on the jack and then loosen the nuts.
Right.
My thinking is always jack the car up, take the, take the nuts off, take the wheel off,
swap it right.
Spin that wheel. Right.
I have done that so many times where I jack the car up and
then I go to take the wheel off and the wheel just spins and,
like, put the car back down.
Then I listen nuts. Then I put the car back up.
I, I done it.
Exactly.
And that's a relatively simple thing that you can explain to a four year old.
-- You
-- think so,
you know, but like specter and meltdown
or,
or heart bleed or poodle like a downgrade attack,
that's not really a downgrade problem.
If
you know, the server has like certificate ordering enabled, blah, blah.
You know what I mean? Like it just all of a sudden, like people start
and I'm talking about like technical people that their
eyes just glaze over and they give up.
Right. My, my take on the specter and meltdown is really easy
if your vendor has provided patches,
you install them.
And as far as microcode goes, you,
we're gonna have to wait for proper good microcode updates.
And as soon as they come out,
you install them and it literally boils down to like my phone strategy,
which is about once or twice a week.
I just run the updater
and update everything
because what else am I gonna do?
You know what else this reminds me of is I remember when stack clash came out,
that one was, it's been, it's been a while.
That was the one where the stack and the heap
you could get them to overlap and then you could essentially
overwrite data.
Oh, yeah, that was sorry.
I spent like three months working on that one and I've already spaced.
I know it's been, it's been a while. I, I remember that one
and
there were a lot of really smart people, I was talking to that, that they, they were,
they were confused.
And I remember one person was talking about how you can become
rute with this and you could because of an attack against,
what was it pseudo I think.
But I said, explain to me how you can become route if we, if we,
if you don't have pseudo on the machine because the
one of the machines in question didn't have pseudo.
And he's telling me about how you can use this to override kernel memory.
And I'm like,
right,
that's not how this works.
And then I spent like an hour explaining the problem, but like that's the thing,
right?
-- This stuff is so hard.
-- Well, that's the thing.
Like, I mean, the stack clash stuff was at least it wasn't hardware. Thank goodness.
And I remember, you know, Wallace found it did a ton of good research they were like,
oh, we think we found a good solution.
One megabyte G
pages.
And then Florian was like, nope, if we're gonna do the guard page route,
we have to go with about 3.5 gigabytes.
And that's not really gonna work on 32 bit
systems because you can basically have three threats,
whatever.
It's not like anything's running 32 bit systems anymore.
Not like billions of devices
connected to.
Exactly.
So, and then, you know, so the whole guard page thing was like, whoops,
that's really not gonna work.
And, you know, and then it was like, ok, well,
and, and then it got worse because it was like, OK, well, now we have to fix the kernel,
OK?
And we have to fix
gipsy
and we have to fix GCC.
So all of a sudden we've gone from like, oh, let's just increase guard size to,
let's start monkey around with fundamental
memory primitives and how code compiles.
-- Oh, and don't break anything while you're at it
-- and, and
right,
and nothing changed
and don't impact performance if you can while you're at it, that,
that doesn't matter anymore.
I think actually
a really funny tweet yesterday that it was someone
said you knew this was a security problem when
someone posted a patch that impacted performance and Linus
didn't yell at them and call them an idiot.
That's
true. That's very true.
So,
and you know, and, and,
and it's funny to hear people complaining about the embargo for the for this uh
spectrum meltdown thing because it's like, no, this was like
crazy amounts of engineering for like seven months
and
like, it's still not done, right? Like
there are, what is it, there's specter patches in the upstream Linux kernel.
And I don't know at the time of the release of this podcast,
whether or not the meltdown patches will have landed in the,
in the Linux kernel tree.
I don't think they're there quite yet.
Like they have some good ideas of what they're gonna do,
but they haven't actually done it yet.
-- Wait,
-- the meltdown patches.
-- I thought they already patched meltdown in the upstream kernel
-- or was it spect?
Oh, no, no, no. Sorry. I got to reverse. Yeah. Meltdown got patched.
-- It's specter that didn't get patched. Sorry. Yeah.
-- See, I, I know.
Seriously, man, I,
I've been like living and breathing this for two months and my brain is just,
I know I can't keep it straight anymore anyways point
being is like like the Linux kernel upstream still hasn't
completely finished dealing with this.
We're still,
there's still going to be micro code updates
that are going to take
a while
uh conservatively to get it this fully, right?
Like we have micro code updates right now that
are causing problems, right?
If you Google it, there's like a lot of people that, you know,
install these microcode updates and they're really not happy about what happened
again because this is like a hideously complex thing to fix.
And so,
you know, we really needed the embargo on this one because
like you said, and I think the last podcast, you know, if,
if you're trying to do like really complicated
engineering with a whole pile of people screaming,
hurry up at you,
you're going to make decisions that are going to turn out to be not so,
so great.
No, I, I totally agree.
And so all right, so, but let's stop ranting about the problems because
I, I totally get that. But
so, so let's come back to the point,
are things so bad
or rather will things ever get bad enough that we will actually ever fix anything?
Well, it's, we are fixing things in the sense of I looking at this.
We've traded prom. So for example, we we now have
developers can trivially
build an application that pulls in a bunch of dependencies and it
basically always works
like I don't know if people remember 20 years ago,
but like what Java's solution was
was
while you in bed.
So like I've literally seen Java apps with 14 layers of embedded jars, wars and ears.
-- And
-- it's great when you have the same jar
in five other jars because they all depend on it
at multiple depths of the chain and everything,
you know. So that,
I mean, well, and back then you got to remember,
we didn't have as much bandwidth or servers.
So like the solution was OK.
You know, essentially statically compile this pile of stuff,
you know, and things like Maven didn't exist for those of you thinking just
Maven.
-- Right.
-- Yeah, exactly.
And so on the one hand,
we've created a pile of security problems, but on the other hand,
we've actually solved a huge pile of real world problems where,
you know, that we're preventing developers from getting their jobs done
and now developers can get their job done,
they can churn out code that works and does useful things
way faster.
And you know what I'll take that I will take risk, you know,
pretty much any business will take, ok?
You can give me a working product with risk or alternatively, no risk,
no working product for six months.
Well, clearly, you know, if we can ship today, we can start selling today.
-- So that's what we're going to do.
-- I, I agree with that 100%.
And here's the beauty too is, is
on the one hand, I hate this centralization of kind of, of power and failure.
But on the other hand, it means we only have to fix it in one spot.
That is a reasonable observation.
Like what if N PM changes the client so that it locally,
it has a switch to locally cash stuff in a really intelligent way.
I know
that fix anything.
I mean,
well, you'd at least have a local copy when N pm.org forgets to renew their DNS,
like straight up, that'll happen someday.
If that happens, there's gonna be way bigger problems going on
than
cashing files locally.
They've only paid for the registration out to 2018 July.
Like I,
I have a bunch of important domains that are
like registered out 10 years that I renew yearly.
With the idea being that if I forget to renew it for like five years, I, I have some,
you know,
-- some time to make sure I get it
-- right. I think I have a domain I need to renew.
Actually, I should look into that.
I,
well, it's a dot Name
and, and I want to move it, but it's,
it's really painful actually to deal with dot Names because
dot Name has such a bizarrely spotted history behind it.
The, the intent being like, for example, if I went Josh dot Bresser dot Name,
I would have bought Josh dot Bresser dot Name, but,
but nobody could ever control like Bresser dot Name.
Right.
With the, that was the idea and then it failed and then they let you buy anything.
So I bought Bresser
dot Name,
which doesn't even do anything. I just own it because,
and, and it's,
yeah,
it sucks down because actually doing anything useful with the,
with that domain is painful.
Yeah.
So anyway,
-- but,
-- uh,
no, I think part of it is on the one hand it reminds me of github.
I am terrified that github
will go evil one day but on the flip side,
by having it centralized and having it well done centrally,
it's made developers lives so much simpler.
Like I look at the CV project and for, for like Miter and CV E to run a proper GIT
server publicly with accounts and with all that other stuff
versus,
oh, it's free at github.com.
No, I, I totally get that.
Well, here's so github
is going to go evil someday. I mean,
remember Source Forge
-- those, those were the good guys for a long time.
-- Oh, man.
Every time I have to download the
Dan dot Iso.
And I love the fact that in Firefox it's like, no,
it like blocks the domains and stuff or whatever the,
you know, because it's like, so
I
know stupid at this point.
No, I know. In fact, I downloaded
Dan the other day and I was like, what is this? This is terrible.
Actually, that's something I was thinking of.
Somebody should put together like a mini
Iso and, you know,
build one of these small container type operating systems that just let's face it.
Dan
doesn't do anything that exciting. Like I could probably do it in an hour.
But anyway,
github
is going to go evil someday
and,
and N PM is probably going to become evil someday
because I think it's just the nature of these things
and
-- when that happens it's
-- not that they go evil.
It's that what their interests and my interests are no longer in as close alignment.
That's fair. That's fair. I don't.
Ok. Ok. I, I like that better. That's, that's a nice way to put it,
but at the same time when that happens,
it generally happens because the world has moved on
github
will become Source forge when we're using whatever comes after github.
And I have no idea what that will be GVR,
right?
He VR source control. That's it.
Right.
It'll be just like uh was the movie hackers where you're flying around the building?
Exactly.
Yeah. So, I mean, as far as actual actionable advice goes to people,
there are like various things in N PM and CP and
whatnot that will help you cash local copies of it.
So, you know, you would at least have those if like I said, N pm.org
goes away or if
somebody, some developer sites to delete something that, you know,
is a dependency of a dependency of a dependency of something you, you know, rely upon
fundamentally.
I mean, it's,
it's up to the central organizations and I think
one of the biggest things that could help here
would be having,
you know, good transparency around what are the rules.
What like what is the behavior we can expect?
Like under what circumstances might this package go away or get deleted or be,
you know, just otherwise something happened that I care about
you know,
and I think that's one of the benefits like
of a lot of open source projects like, you know, Debian, for example,
they have some really clearly stated policy documents about when
and how and why they'll move or remove packages,
right? Like license violations or you know the code blah, blah, blah, right?
-- And so you kind of know what to expect.
-- Well, yes
and I like that consistency, but at the same time,
I think because of that policy and consistency,
Debian also moves a lot slower than some of these other distributions do
well, totally. And and we exist in a universe now where where speed
is seen as kind of the the killer feature for many,
many
-- time
-- to market has always been a thing and
especially with software now time to market is like super
critical, especially with services, right? Because uh
like a great example is Cloudflare cloud flare could have built something totally
amazing and beautiful and engineered even more perfectly than what they built.
But you know, if they'd waited a year,
somebody else would have come along and eat their lunch.
Uh You know, same thing with github, right?
Github.
I remember
github at the beginning, it was, it was good.
I mean it was hosting Git and that alone took away so much pain,
like so so much pain and then, you know,
they've continued to add and add and add features like this whole dependency,
security checker thing.
Is like, wow, that, ok. That's really cool.
Yes. You know, stuff like that will, you know,
and,
and they're getting to a point now where they kind
of have that moat around them where it's like,
oh, I could totally move to some other git
style hosting thing. But I would lose, well, at a minimum I would lose the github
community
right
at
this point. It's,
there's nowhere better. I mean, let's face it.
Yeah.
Well, there's nowhere as popular. It's like Facebook.
Are there other social networks? I guess I, I couldn't even name them.
-- The
-- young people like Snapchat,
which is not controlled by Facebook,
the medium age people think Instagram is neat which
Facebook owns and the old people like Facebook,
that is pretty much the way of the world today.
And, and I think that's actually a great example and I wonder I should,
I should look into this but like, obviously I can understand, like,
if your grandparents are on Facebook, Facebook isn't cool.
Let's face it.
That's the reality of that.
And
-- if you look at development environments, is it generational
-- part of it?
Is it is generational.
Because one thing I've really noticed
is the difference between cloud services being
built by people who grew up with cloud
that is to put up long with people around the age of 20 to 25
and the cloud
stuff being built by
the older generation. A great example being Amazon web services
they wrote the whole thing in Java
and now they're like, would we use a different technology stack if we built this?
Oh God, yes.
Except, uh we've kind of invested in this and, you know,
we're not stupid enough to try and rewrite from scratch and go bankrupt,
you know.
Right.
Like, literally,
if you tried to convince somebody under the age of
25 right now to write a major thing in Java,
they'd be like, you mean javascript, right?
Like no Js like that would probably be their reaction.
Yes, I'm familiar with this problem at the same time though.
I, I will say Java does solve some problems very nicely but speed isn't one of them.
-- Well,
-- Java
is,
it's provably, it gets things done. I mean Aws, right?
That is a heck of a successful software stack. Yeah.
So I mean, I, I think part of, and part of it is the culture of like
you and I are like, I literally remember back in um
oh Lord, 1999
I taught a full day Linux security course at Vanguard Security Expo,
which is mainframe security people back in the day.
And about there were uh eight or nine people in the class
and I kind of had to at one point stop and explain client server computing
in the sense of clients that were intelligent and not dumb.
Like they got client server in the context of like, oh yeah.
T and 3270 terminal, which
I'm guessing most people are gonna have to Google or look up on Wikipedia.
If you're under the age of
probably 40 you've probably never seen or heard of those.
And so I had to explain to them kind
of like why client server computing with Linux and,
you know, smart clients was a little bit different,
why there was a much different sort of security profile around that.
And it kind of, I think some of them were not super enchanted about, you know,
having their security go from like a single machine to like, oh, all the machines.
I, I'm from that generational gap too where I look at a web app and I think about
so how do we optimize processing on the back end versus, you know,
young people now are smart and they're like,
just do it in javascript on the client, right? Scale out 100% right?
For every client that connects,
-- that's a new server.
-- Yes. But however, ironically
that is going to bring with it, many of the same problems where you have,
have issues with having to trust the client because the client could be malicious.
-- Well, and that doesn't really matter in a lot of apps.
-- Right. I mean, certain things.
It certainly doesn't. I, I agree with that.
Well, like banking apps, like, oh, you wanted to withdraw $73 billion? Cool.
Yeah, you probably need to check those numbers on the back end, right?
But fundamentally, I mean, especially with like games and stuff, right? Like
it anyways, the point being is that there is definitely a cultural divide
between, like, as I kind of put it, there's,
there's sort of the the server client application mindset which, you know,
roamed the earth and was supreme from like what about 95 until 2005,
2008.
And then we kind of entered that
transition where clients became like
even the worst client. Like my cell phone is what?
Dual core with four gigs of ra M or something stupid.
Right? Like, I don't even know or care anymore. It, it'll run,
it'll do
-- like it'll do augmented reality games on my phone,
-- right?
-- You know, if it's in my pocket, it,
-- it probably has something crazy like six cars or
it, it, that's a funny thing.
Now,
it's even crazier because they're actually these chips now have like two low
power cores and then they might have two or four high power cores.
So when the phone is asleep it uses way less juice,
which is awesome. Right.
Yeah.
And so,
you know, and then there's this whole sort of cloud native client
generation where like the client is essentially what we think of as
a server as far as power and compute capability and storage goes.
No, II, I totally get it.
My kids, ipads have 100 and 28 gigs of storage each I remember seeing servers with,
well, I remember owning servers with one gig of storage and I was like,
super happy about that.
-- We'll
-- never fill this disk out.
-- So,
-- you know, there is definitely that generational divide with,
not just in language and, but in how they view the world,
it's like those kids that pick up a phone and they're like, like a dumb phone,
like a cordless phone
and are like, what, where's the screen? Like, why, what? There's no touchscreen?
-- This is broken, what's going on?
-- Let's, let's bring this one home.
But you've got me thinking something
is
maybe,
maybe we are solving yesterday's security problems. Oh, very definitely.
And we're trying to project those problems onto the technology of today
instead of building today's security solutions.
Right. I, I, everything you said resonates with me.
Well, I think you're right because
one example of this is, you know, if you do Dev ops in our trial,
who cares if you have a security flaw, we fixed it in five minutes
because you're definitely gonna have security flaws no matter what you write.
Now, now, on that note though, you have to know about them. It's part of the trick
and that can be tricky although I guess maybe just keep updating a lot and,
-- and then you don't
-- care continuous deployment.
Why here's
why bother tracking security flaws in your dependencies
if you update your dependencies every day.
But then we've gotten to the issue of? Ok. So I'm updating my dependencies every day.
Am I, should I cash them locally? Should I care if they're cashed locally?
And, and I feel like
everything we've talked about up till now about the supply chain is very much
the security problems of yesterday.
Now, the security problems of today,
but we're trying to project our solution onto today.
I need, I need to think about this.
Well, I think one thing you and I fundamentally get wrong
is we look at software as something that ships.
The majority of software
is
-- not shipped, it's either used internally or it's provided as a service
-- now.
Well, and as a service is totally the future man.
I mean, if you look even like elastic as a new company and our,
our cloud offering obviously is, is becoming hugely
not that the other, the other stuff is hugely popular also. But
yeah, as a serviceman, it's where it's at.
Well, from the customer perspective, it's easier. And from the
company perspective,
there's no more piracy and there's no more people not
paying their bills because they don't pay their bills.
You turn it off.
Well, and not only that,
the the the dealing with support on something as a service is much nicer
because
you have basically access to everything.
You can see the logs, right?
You can, you can figure out what's going on, you can say, oh, I see what, you know,
there's a mistake here.
I see you're trying to do this. So
it's, it's huge, man. I mean, I think
there are few instances where IC N A service being inferior to on prem today and I
know that that's something that people complain about and
there's a whole bunch of articles popping up.
It feels like since the new Year talking about, oh,
the public cloud is too expensive and insecure.
And I'm like, yeah, you're, who's paying you, right? You,
you didn't make this up. Someone's paying you to say that and I don't know who it is.
But
anyway,
well, I think
there are, well, I think it's like any technology that
things like
the public cloud will definitely take off and eat up a huge
part of the market and there will always be those like niche
situations or you have regulatory guidelines or whatever.
But yeah, to say blanket statements like, oh the the cloud,
like I look at the CS A what we pay Amazon web services and the weird thing is
we've consistently paid them the same amount plus or minus $100 for four years
and we use more and more resources every month and year.
But because Amazon keeps dropping their prices
and they keep coming out with services.
So for example,
I no longer have to buy SSL certificates because
Amazon provides that for free. Right. Amazon certificate.
You, it's just free.
Yes. Right.
And, and like a wild card certificate for a domain is like a couple 100 bucks a year.
And so
two or three of those go away. Like, wow, it's like 1000 bucks a year.
No, I know, man, I know.
Let's call it, let's call it.
So anyway,
let's just say this parents stop projecting your problems and your Children.
Right.
That's, that's what this is us as parents are projecting our security problems on,
on the youth future
and
so
youth, it's up to you to keep giving us a finger and telling us to go away.
-- So there we go. Problem solved.
-- Don't trust anybody over 40.
Just don't trust anybody. Right. It's much easier that way.
Don't, don't draw lines. Thanks, Kurt. Thanks everyone for listening.
We appreciate it. You can go to open source security podcast.com for the show notes.
You can hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag And yeah, and I guess if nothing else, Kurt,
you have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.