Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and annoying people.
Josh Bresser.
Oh, no, that's wrong.
-- Annoying people at scale. Damn
-- it.
Let's do it again. Uh Whatever use it.
All right,
it's fine. It's all good. Uh Do I annoy people at scale? I probably do.
Well, I mean, if we were to insert a high pitched loud noise right now or hey, Siri,
turn off the lights.
-- I'm not
-- doing that. All right. That, that's fine. I'm ok with that one.
I wonder if I could tell,
I wonder if that would work. I always, I always use the room name
-- in addition to
-- light. Yeah.
My theory on my watch is currently asking me which one I meant?
Oh, I see. Ok. Ok. We've just annoyed people two for the price of one.
Now, their Siri is annoying them and I just know that
and this is exactly the show content is,
it's, it's the situations where it's not just sort of that initial annoyance,
but that like then the technology does something
stupid to make it even more annoying.
-- I mean, that
-- is true.
Oh, sir.
Still talking
Siri. Stop.
Which one is? I
lost my phone.
This is why I turned all that crap off.
Wow.
Ok. Wow. Stop Siri.
Oh wow. See this, this is exactly what I'm talking about.
So like a perfect example of this is when somebody sends out
an email to too many people like not using blank carbon copy.
And then you know somebody hits reply all saying
please stop and then it just evolves into madness.
We should start at the beginning before we get into this. Explain the
github issue.
-- That was the impetus of this episode.
-- Two things. It was the github
issue
where basically somebody did like a poll request
on a merge which seems reasonably normal.
But then they did like a bump T
and it
notified 400,000 people.
And, but the second thing is that,
that really triggered this for me is somebody posted on reddit.
They have a, a TV, as one does nowadays
and it has Bluetooth support as they all do nowadays.
And his neighbor keeps trying to pair with it and so on his TV,
he keeps having to hit cancel
and there's no way to like block his neighbor from trying to pair to his TV.
I saw that one.
I feel bad for the owner of that TV.
And I recognize
that
there are a lot of really bad TV. S out there.
And II, I keep thinking like, I don't even know what I do in this situation.
Well, the, the, the one comment was basically just change the name to do not like,
do not use this one.
Maybe. I mean,
I guess,
-- or
-- the other thing I've seen is you, you change it to like a Z,
something so it alphabetically sorts to the bottom.
So they hopefully stop trying to use it.
Maybe. Maybe unless
I wonder if the neighbor is, actually, I, I didn't,
-- I didn't look
-- what if they have the same model of TV.
That's the thing. I don't, I don't know if they've talked to their neighbor.
-- I, I don't, that wasn't in the story. Do you
-- even?
But if you live in an apartment building, like,
do you just randomly knock on every door in 100 m radius?
That's true. Like, because I remember the first time I went wardrobe
and it was interesting because it was kind of
what I expected out in the suburbs with like,
ding a house, ding a house and then I went downtown and it was just like,
right,
because I drove by this one apartment building and all of a sudden and it
was an apartment building that had like the big kind of glass front which,
you know, lets the Wi Fi out, no problem.
And my,
my wi fi thing just basically barfed on me
because it all of a sudden saw like 300 networks
and, you know, that's the thing like modern Bluetooth, the specified range is 100 m.
It's obviously going to be a bit less in a, in a building, but still, even
20 m is gonna be tens of people, at least 10
people
at least.
And so,
and there's no way to like,
make it stop. That's, that's what drives me nuts with this.
Like my fire alarm doesn't have a bacon mode.
So every time I'm cooking bacon, I'm like
it beeps and then of course, the one in the basement, it's like, 000 my God.
The one in the kitchen is angry. I better get angry too.
It's like, oh, there's a fire in the kitchen.
And I'm like the one in the basement, I'm like,
just shut up like nobody's in the basement, nobody cares.
Like, so I'm actually getting rid of my nest smoke alarms because so I had two smoke,
two nest smoke alarms,
traditionally one for the kitchen and one for near the
furnace and they just started beeping all the time.
And I,
this was like years ago and I uttered Nest and they
sent out replacements because this was apparently a known problem.
And if you made enough noise, they would replace it free.
Otherwise they just kind of expected you to buy new ones.
And so I've got the, this, these two quote unquote,
new ones that are a couple of years old
and
it started eating batteries like I would put fresh six fresh batteries in
and like 20 minutes later it would be doing the chirp, like the battery is dying.
Oh, wow. So I'm just done with it.
Like I, I threw it out and I'm going to throw the other one out and I'm basically,
I'll be blunt, I'm looking for a not smart option
that has
a,
like a big button that I can easily get it to
tell it to be quiet for when I'm cooking bacon.
That's it.
That's all I want a smoke alarm. Now in my kitchen,
I mean, ok,
this raises,
I think some interesting points and especially from
the security implications of all of this.
So it's easy to say, oh ha ha. You contacted 400,000 people. It's easy to laugh at.
Oh, the dumb person keeps replying to the email thread.
But the reality is especially when we put on our security hats,
all of us have
-- like a limited amount of cognitive ability each day
-- and time.
This is why spam filters had to happen because I can't wait through 10,000 spams.
No. Exactly. Well, even it, it doesn't matter about time.
It's just the fact that even if I said Kurt,
your job today is to go through 10,000 email messages.
Right.
You're cognitively just not going to be able to do the
task after probably five or 10 minutes because it's just not something
that humans are good at.
And I think all of these kind of alarms
and all of these notifications and stuff,
you end up with the fatigue and you just don't notice it.
Alarm fatigue. Exactly.
Well, I love your comment where you're like,
I did the thing and get up, sent you an email. I'm like, yeah, kid up, sent me an email.
Absolutely. And all of that crap gets filtered into archives.
I mean, I do that too. In fact, what I do now is github
actually has a uh if you go to github.com/notifications,
it shows you all your notifications in a very handy and easy to parse format.
And that's what I use.
I don't even use the email anymore because I was getting way too much email and,
and I tried to like,
filter out the things I wanted to know and I still kept missing too much stuff.
Whereas the notifications are very nice, very easy.
I can quickly look at what's going on
and get a feel for it and
like when something goes wrong and there's like
some bizarro spam thread happening in an issue,
I can be like gone like we're done with you
versus getting 700 emails that I have to weed through.
So anyway, anyway,
my point of all this, I think, I think the thing for us to think about
and, and the real topic of the day
is just the fact that
we have all of these tools, we have all this technology,
we have everything going on around us and it's just like constantly buffeting us
-- with information.
-- No, I wouldn't say information.
It's, it's just random junk mostly.
I mean, information applies value.
Not necessarily. I think
they
like noise is information. It's not valuable information.
OK. Oh, we're going to a classic.
-- OK. Definition. OK.
-- Fair. It is information.
This is something I think about a lot in the context of security
is
how do you make sure that you're communicating in a manner
that
makes it understood that like when Josh comes
and asks something or says to do something,
this is important and you need to pay attention.
And I'm very, I'm extremely aware of this at work and I try really, really hard
to almost never
tell the organization like you have to do something.
Like for example, there was a really bad,
I had a
chrome thing, I think like a month ago where it was being actively exploited,
-- Cisa
-- sent out like three or four update chrome.
Now there's a bad thing happening in like two weeks. It was, I was like,
is this just the rest of my life?
Like every two, twice a week, we're supposed to update chrome now right away.
Perfect example of this, right?
And that was 11 instance where I told the company I'm like, please update
Chrome and please make sure automatic updates are on. It should be.
But I want you to double check
and then then yes, we got another message from S uh
like a a day or two later
and everyone was like, you're gonna email us again.
I was like, no,
I emailed you once like that is going to have to be enough because
-- I can't do this every time it happens
-- and that speaks to things.
So for example, like in that situation, I was
you need to update chrome but yeah, make sure updates are enabled but sorry,
going back to github
notifications for a second, I just logged in, went to my notification settings
and there's like global settings like email, web and mobile blah, blah, blah.
Then there's custom routing.
So for each organization, I'm a member of,
I can route to a different email address but there's no way to selective.
No, it's not nice because there's no way to selectively say, like
for example, I'm a member of the CV project organization.
I don't, I don't ever want to get a notification from that project.
-- You
-- can just unwatched and then they go away.
I have to go unwatched.
You go to the project and then you unwatched it at the top.
So here's what I love is the CV project is list to my notifications,
but it's not a clickable link.
I have to go manually. Let's type this
in.
Yeah, this is not a good U I, it's a U I for engineers which means that
I'm shocked to learn this.
Ah Here's the fun part.
You have to go manually.
Unwatched every repo, I can't just globally unwatched an organization.
So I have to figure out which repo I'm listening to. So, here I go. I have to.
And this is a perfect example. I now have to go click on. They have 15 repos.
I have to open up all 15 repos and make sure I'm not watching one of them
and I don't think I'm watching any of them.
I don't know.
How do I see what I'm watching?
It turns out there's actually if you go to github.com/watching
and I am apparently watching 100 and 20 repost. Nice.
-- Oh, I have to look at this now, github.com/
-- watching.
So it's, it's basically everything you fork by default you're watching.
I am watching 34 repos
and here's the best part.
There's no bulk changeability here.
There's no like little check box at the top where I can check and it checks all of them.
I have to go click 100 and 20 times and change from all activity
to either participating or not. Oh, so there is actually a same setting.
There's participating in mentions,
only receive notifications from this repository when participating or
mentioned.
Why can't that be the default instead of all activity?
Also, it doesn't show me what activity I'm, I have to,
I have to literally click on 100 and 20 buttons
because the U I does not show me
what level I'm I'm watching at
by default.
It just says unwatched. Well, you can click unwatched, I guess.
And so I have to click this 100 and 20 times
and I can't just make a bulk change.
This is, this is,
this is exactly the problem I'm talking about is not
only is getting spamming the bejesus out of me,
but for me to not get spammed, I now have to take probably about a good hour of my day.
Right? And obviously
correct answer.
-- The answer is a script obviously.
-- But you know what I'm saying?
Like this is, this makes me somewhat physically ill in that I need to use github
for work.
And the solution obviously is everything from at
github.com goes into my archives and I just.
Right.
Yep.
That's the answer everyone has.
If, if 100 and 20 times 30 seconds, bam, that's an hour.
Right.
Yep. Yep. And, and so I think that's
like, it's funny
because all of this together
adds up to something important.
And I think this is even true of just a lot of security problems in general.
It's just often. Oh, that's not that bad. That's not that bad. That's not that bad.
And then you add up the 100 not bad things and you have a serious problem,
potholes, one pothole in the city and I'd be like, wow,
like whoever did that, I'm voting for them again.
But yeah. No, we don't have a pothole in the city. We have,
I would have to guess on the order of
millions based on how many are just on side streets alone.
And the thing is, most of them don't matter,
you know. But it adds up the perfect example.
There's a, there's a street train in front of my house
and the sidewalk above it is really crack.
Like if you're in a wheelchair, you would have a hard time getting over it.
Like, remember this is the story I keep telling where I was leaf,
blowing the dirt and dust off my sidewalk.
You know, because it's spring and
I'm trying to blow all the dirt and sand back onto the road from, you know, road grit
and like, I, you know, chunks of concrete came off.
And I'm like, if my little electric leaf blower, like I got the little baby DeWalt,
if it blows up chunks of concrete, that's not my fault. Like that's, that's a,
the sidewalks broken, you know. And so
how long is this going to take to get fixed?
And I just hope nobody in a wheelchair has to navigate these sidewalks because
right, every 30 40 ft you have an obstacle and it becomes impossible to.
I, I remember when I lived in my last place, there was a,
a guy in a wheelchair who used the road and I'm like, I hate this, I hate this,
but I totally get why he does it because
the roads are in better shape than the sidewalks.
I, I get that too.
They're actually, so, it's, it's funny you mentioned that.
So, where you live in Canada, if the sidewalk is crap,
it's the city's job to come and fix the sidewalk.
Yeah.
I, well, yeah, because the city comes out and replaces them every once in a while,
by the way, once in a while, I mean, every 50 to 100 years.
So, where I live
it is my problem to fix the sidewalks.
And if the city,
the city sends people out every couple of years
to inspect the sidewalks and if there's something wrong,
they will send you a letter that basically says
you can fix this now or we're going to come fix it and
we're going to charge you way more than it's going to cost you.
That's annoying because it's the,
they should be fixing this because they do it at scale and they should do
it a lot cheaper than me hiring some random contractor to think one little spot.
Whereas,
you know, the city, like when the city comes through and fills potholes,
they feel like hun like 100 potholes.
We have to stop talking about potholes. Did I ban you from talking about potholes?
And
this is my new thing.
I win a point.
Um But no, this is like, but I'm just looking at this and it's like 100 and 20.
I have to click 100 and 20 times at a minimum.
And then I have to also one click to click on UN watch.
Then I have to look at it and process what it is
and then I have to make a choice
and move on to the next one
or you just keep doing what you're doing now and ignoring all those males.
Yeah, exactly.
Well, and the other thing is moving forward if I, if I,
uh, clone or whatever, any repost or join any organizations,
I again have to go through this and there's, there's, as far as I can tell,
there's no way to set my default notifications to like, just by default only.
Like I'm looking at the notifications and there's,
there's a default notification email.
That's it. That's the only thing you can set. That's a default.
This is getting boring. Yeah. Well, and that's, and that's part of the problem too.
Is this again? This is because it's a death by 1000 cuts on its own.
It's not like whatever, who cares, but
it's like noise pollution. It just adds up and everybody has crap hearing now
because we're, you know, constantly being assaulted.
Ok?
I want,
I want to bring us back around to
the security angle because I think it's very interesting
and we're not talking about it at all
is
this is one of those instances where
there are going to be things from github.
For example, I'll just pick on github because that's what we're doing today.
There's going to be messages from github
that I need to pay attention to, for some reason.
-- Did you change your password? No, I didn't.
-- 00, I don't know if I get those or not.
I hope I get those. I should check that.
Yeah.
But, because you've got so much filtering on you don't know if you get them or not.
Right.
And, and that, I mean, like, that kind of stuff is exactly the point is there are,
or even ignoring those kind of messages.
Actually. No, I do because you know what? I just created a,
a
token,
an access token, forget, um, for a work demo I'm giving later today.
And the access token
sent me a mail that said someone has created
an access token for your github account and that,
that did the right thing.
So that's cool.
But
no, what, what,
what it is is your filters are sophisticated enough that it didn't just eat it
and most people don't have sophisticated filters. They just are like,
you know, filter all email like this.
Sure, whatever it doesn't matter, doesn't matter.
But anyway,
the point is there are things I need to see and there's things I'm going to miss and
this is one of the issues I have anytime I set up filtering on any kind of service is
especially as a security person. I know there are certain events I want and now
I have the choice. Do I
UN filter
and try to manually go through. Do I try to write
some Rube Goldberg filtering system?
Do you know what I mean?
And I mean, this is true of messages from your SIM system,
messages from your endpoint system messages from like everything
you're going to be overloaded with messages.
And of course, if you talk to vendors, they're gonna say, oh,
our super A IML system will filter only what you need.
And it's like, I don't think it will
freaking Google.
If I mark a message of spam, it looks like phishing.
About 20 minutes later.
I get like an administrative email saying a user has noticed a surge
in spam and phishing emails and it emails me and I'm like,
yeah, that, that was me that marked it as that
as
a, as a, as
a,
as a Google administrator. And so,
-- and like everybody like all the admins get these,
-- I'm not a Gmail admin.
I, I won't let them make me one. I'm
-- like, no, I'm too dumb to do this.
-- It's
-- just
-- so unspeakably stupid,
but they don't care.
Well, you know what it reminds me of is so the BC government next door to my province
had a heat dome last year, 600 people died
and there was an inquiry, of course, because
600 people died, you know,
we should probably figure out what happened and if we can make
it less worse the next time around or maybe even better.
And so one of the recommendations is, of course,
is to warn people when there's a heatwave coming.
So they've decided that they will warn people
when there's like a heat dome or heat wave thing coming
by. Using the freaking emergency alert system.
Like, on your phone. What else are they gonna use? Anything?
But that, because there's two problems with that one,
it's way too loud, like it's, it's way too much. You know what I mean?
It, it, all those shift workers that aren't going to get woken up because in Canada,
fun fact you can't disable that crap on your phone.
I've tried
on my, I
disabled mine. I don't know. You can or you can at least make it, not make noise.
I can't
because in Canada they use the, like the nuclear alarm code alert basically.
And it just screams until you tell it to stop.
And it's really awesome.
Like, you know,
with my one son who has his phone in his
backpack and his backpack starts screaming at the world.
But the second thing is also like,
not everybody has a cell phone and
essentially the people most vulnerable to the heat
are also the people who don't own cell phones
because if they could afford cell phones,
they might also be able to buy an air conditioner.
That's, that's probably fair.
The government did something we're going to warn people,
but like, they're doing it in the worst possible way. In my opinion,
I I think
what you just said is the second part of all of these problems is,
yeah,
I think there's a prevailing attitude of doing anything is better than nothing.
-- The goalkeeper's dilemma.
-- Yes, exactly. That,
-- yeah,
-- I have to dive left or. Right.
Right. Right. Yeah, if you stand there, you look like an idiot.
I think just alerts in general kind of fall into that category is
people think they need to do something.
And,
but then if, if everyone thinks that
you end up overwhelmed and I mean, this is like I said, of,
of security alerts is I want to make sure that,
that the people I work with understand that if I mail them,
it's really, really, really important.
And if I mailed them once a week,
they'd be like, oh, whatever, another mail from Josh, I don't care.
Well, I've, I've had people try and sell me a SIM and I'm like, no,
I will not because real simple now we have to, it's a puppy. We have to care and feed it.
-- Who's
-- going to do a lot of work. Yes. And, and
there are times you need it.
I mean, my suspicion is that the cloud security lines might never, we're lucky
because of how we,
how I
like how I've not just engineered our systems but our, like our, it culture.
Yeah. No,
there's literally nothing we can do that would be
better than what Google or sales force are doing.
For us.
It's that simple.
I, I think that's the other thing is people forget the
operational cost.
And now that I say that it's, they're basically externalized.
It's, it's classic security of,
I don't have to care about your pi I,
I'll just externalize that cost because if we get breached your pi I gets
sked,
somebody takes out a mortgage in your name. That's not my problem. Right.
We offered a year of free credit monitoring for $7.
And I'm kind of reminded, this is exactly what this is, is,
well, here's all the alerts we solve the problem.
Right.
-- What do you mean? You didn't read your alerts?
-- Yeah.
Yeah, we, we sent you an alert for that
but you also sent me, like,
I don't even know how many, if I type in github.com in my,
oh,
you know, I'm actually not getting that much email from github.
It's only like 20 maybe 30 messages a day. Now.
Is that all?
Well, it's like every time, well, part of it is,
I actually think I might have de notified myself on a couple of the CS, a repos,
like the main website where the, like
the devs are pretty active there.
Like,
I guess, I think that's what this boils down to because that's, you know,
that's exactly what this feels like is like
the data breaches with the externalized cost.
It's,
it's the same dynamics.
Yeah, alert, fatigue generally doesn't affect the person sending the alert.
It usually only ends up affecting the people receiving the alert.
I mean, this is even true. Think about if you have a SIM,
and you're getting tons of alerts
and you miss the alert of the attacker getting into
the web server and the web server gets hacked.
You know what they're gonna do?
They're going to say, ok, who didn't, who waive this alert?
Oh, you, Kurt, you weigh the alert. You don't work here anymore, right? I,
I fixed it. Everyone. I fired Kurt. He was obviously an idiot.
The problem wasn't that Kurt had 10,000
alerts.
-- He had to look at the problem was, he's just, I
-- mean, ok, I'll, I'll,
I'll tell this tale because it's, you know,
like when I worked at Red Hat Bugzilla sends out a lot of email alerts.
-- Oh, man, it was brutal. Yeah.
-- Fun fact. If you go to,
if you go to Bugzilla dot Red hat.com and search for my work email address,
the site is not broken. You just have to wait 2 to 3 minutes for the query to return.
Right. That's how many bugs I was filing and involved in a Red Hat.
Like, it's, it's into the thousands.
And so when I worked at Red Hat,
I was receiving on the order of 1 to 3000 Bugzilla emails per day.
And I remember some people kind of expected me to read all of them and I'm like,
no, like,
like literally everybody, somebody time somebody takes a person onto a bug or,
and I tried that, I remember trying to build filters
and then with Zimba, you could kind of build filters, but it was pretty
yuck. And then with Gmail, the filters weren't as good.
So I actually,
at one point I was trying to use IMAP sync to download
my mail filter it locally using proc mail and reupload it.
This is clearly insanity.
And so I ended up just filtering pretty much the vast majority of it. And, you know,
only if a bug went public or something major
reading 1 to 3000 emails. That's, that's multiple full time jobs.
You can't do that. And look, here's so here's the thing that
always happens is, is like you'll say, oh, you can't, 1000 emails takes too long.
It, if I gave you enough time to do it,
you can't do it because humans can't read 1000 emails,
it's too boring and we quit paying attention.
It's like
I need to find it.
There's some test a university did at one point where they showed alerts to people
and eventually they changed the language of the alerts
and like nobody noticed because they were just clicking,
-- ok, like, as fast as they could, you
-- know, I'm reminded of, you know,
they've done studies with people with like police snipers and
also the airport security people watching the X ray machines
15 minutes. Then you got to swap them out.
Yeah.
Right. Exactly.
And last I checked those X
machine people.
I don't, I don't know, actually, I don't know how often they, they swap them.
It really depends on which airport and country. But most of them they're,
well, like every time they do the FAA test, right.
The, the airports fail 80 to 90% of the time. Right.
Like, I mean,
there was that famous case where somebody stole a sweater at a
checkpoint and the sweater had a fake hand grenade in it that,
you know, the FAA had been using as a security test.
So
they put the sweater on the airplane and the grenade falls
out and it causes a bit of an incident obviously because,
you know, at that point, you can't ignore it because the stewardess is like,
excuse me, sir.
Is that your hand grenade?
Why? Yes, yes, it is. Thank you for noticing.
Well, I'm always reminded of like if you Google this, like
just Google accidentally brought gun onto airplane
and there's so many cases of where a person is just like, I'm so sorry,
here's my briefcase and the stewardess is like, what? Like, I don't want your brief.
He's like just my gun is in there, please. I, I don't want any trouble.
I'm gonna be here quietly
and it's like, what?
Like I've accidentally brought knives onto planes
that are over the three inch limit and I'm like, whoops,
I've have, I ever accidentally,
I, I don't remember.
I'm, I'm certain I've accidentally brought banned items on airplanes in the past
or more than 100 mils of liquid,
-- whatever.
-- Maybe you smuggled some peanut butter on board. Apparently.
Peanut butter is a liquid.
-- I don't think peanut butter. No, no pastes don't count.
-- Oh,
-- they got sensible. Finally.
-- It's totally different,
I
think. Well, maybe, I don't know. That's the thing. Who knows?
You know, what else it reminds me of.
I remember when,
do you remember when the Ts A had their like warning levels and it was like green,
blue, red and purple and people were like, what, what do any of these even mean?
And it was like, you might as well use a, uh, a fruit as your,
your alert levels because they, they're meaningless to people.
Like, what is the difference between yellow and red? Nobody knows.
Well, that's
apparently today's big theme at RS A today.
So I know we're not supposed to be time temporarily
-- linked in the show because it might come out
-- later.
This will come out at the end of the week.
But so basically, apparently the biggest thing right now at Rs A is,
or was it yesterday?
The, the, the CIA guy was giving a talk about how this whole, you know, they,
they cisa declared that like shields up like
the Russians are getting grumpier than usual.
And basically, he was talking about the saying like,
this is shields up is not going away
like this is the new normal.
-- Wait,
-- wait. So he's saying like,
just every, everything's all right, alarm will never sound again.
Is that what he's saying?
Or is he saying,
like they're going to keep raising and lowering their shield warnings?
It sounds like, well, they issued the shields up warning in, uh, February.
Yeah, February 25th. It looks like,
-- and
-- it's never come down and it will never come down ever again.
Well, it's, I mean,
but now, now here's the thing though,
now it's meaningless,
right.
The Russians might attack any day now.
Well, what am I gonna do about it? Right.
And eventually people stop caring.
It's like, it's like all the, all the COVID stuff, man.
I, I saw some security people are like,
I can't believe how many people don't have masks at RS A and it's like
people are burnt out and they just quit carrying and this is what people do like
it like it just, it,
I believe the current,
uh, what is the current threat level?
No, I, you know, here's the great thing.
I cannot find the current threat level in Canada.
I can find a listing of our terrorism threat levels,
but the actual current
threat level, I, I cannot find it on Google.
So obviously it's not that important brush,
it's too,
pretty
much.
I
do,
-- I do need to go brush my teeth. I just ate,
-- you, brush your teeth every time you eat,
I'm too lazy for that.
Not every time. But when I, when I eat certain things because you can see these gaps.
-- I got like,
-- show me your teeth,
I got like four gaps in my teeth that are just
the right size for food to get jammed in there.
-- I see.
I still have a wire in the bottom of my teeth because when I got my braces,
they put like a wire on the backside of my bottom teeth to keep them straight
and
food gets stuck in it,
but they're nice and straight. So I'm OK with it.
So you have like a permanent, like basically a chunk of rebar in your mouth
to keep your teeth.
-- I did not even know that was a thing on the
-- back side of my teeth.
-- The, the, the, the orthodontist put it
-- in,
it's like glued on like it's permanent.
It's cemented on. I've had it since I was 16.
And what, I'm 43 now, like, I'm very old.
I've had it replaced once because it,
it like enough of it broke off that I went into an orthodontist.
They were like, yeah, we got to replace this.
I've literally never heard of this technology.
I've had it my whole life.
Like I know about braces, but I never assumed they could just,
yeah, we
wild
or whatever.
And then it's funny because my brother had one
and he decided he didn't like it one day.
And he's like, can I borrow your wire cutters? I was like, sure it's over in the thing.
I'm like, what do you need to cut? He's like, I'm sick of this wire in my mouth.
I'm like, wait, what?
Like, yeah, and he took a wire cutters and literally cut the wire out of his mouth.
And how can he get in there?
Kurt, I didn't ask questions. I was like, I have nothing to do with this.
Like, I'm not driving you to the hospital if you like sever something terrible.
-- Like this is dumb. He's going
-- to chip a tooth for sure.
I don't know. I don't know, but his bottom teeth are not nice and straight now. So
not if you're doing dentistry with wire cutters,
that's basically how it used to work. All right. Anyway, we need to wrap this one up.
I, I feel like this.
All right. So, first of all, the story was funny, someone accidentally
alerted 400 people at github.
Like
that's
400,000.
It's a lot, there's a lot of people. It's, it is. It is.
And, and it's funny, we know alert fatigue is bad
and I, I guess here's a funny thing though about it all. We know it's bad.
We know it doesn't work and we still keep sending alerts because we,
we don't know what else to do.
I found our threat level.
I have to interrupt Canada's current level is medium,
meaning that a violent act of terrorism could occur
and has been at this level since October 2014.
-- I mean,
-- is it the definition of a violent act could occur? Like,
isn't that always true?
Yeah.
I mean, yes,
-- terrorists could attack
-- so that the threat levels are very low is highly unlikely,
low is, is possible but unlikely medium is, could occur.
High is, is likely and critical is, is highly likely and could occur imminently.
This is idiotic.
We've had terrorist attacks in Canada, like since 2014,
but we haven't changed the threat level.
So they, they clearly didn't
anticipate or catch them or even have a wrinkle of them.
But again, this comes back to the,
when I'm the alert,
I have to pretend I'm doing something
and the alert
just learn to ignore you
because you clearly don't know what you're doing.
-- And like, that's basically the lesson of all this.
-- Here's what I love under medium.
Additional measures are in place to keep Canadians safe.
Well, no offense.
But if you're doing additional measures for eight years, that's not additional,
that's just,
that's normal. Now,
I would agree. I'd say if it's more than a month or two, that, that's just normal.
If you quit smoking for eight years, I would say you quit smoking successfully.
-- I, I'd be comfortable with that.
-- Yes.
Like if you quit smoking for a week, I'd be like, hey, you go like, good job,
you know, I'll buy you a steak, whatever
a month.
No, but like, eight years that, that is a fundamental, like,
you've now built a habit.
I would agree with that.
And, and, yeah. Right. Right. Exactly.
So, I'm just staring at this page. It is just
what does the threat level mean for you?
Canada's threat levels do not require specific responses from the public? Cool.
Then, like,
what's the point? Then
again though,
I'm doing something. Look at me, everyone
-- that is what it comes down to. Oh, we
-- have
-- a
-- national security tip line,
huh?
Regardless of threat level,
Canadians should always remain alert to the danger of terrorism and report
any suspicious activity to the national security tip line 1 800 blah
or by contacting the police in their community.
Ok.
But they don't, they don't specify what constitutes suspicious activity.
So I guess, you know, we'll figure that out on our own.
And again, this is like,
I'm sorry, but, and this kind of feeds into it again is like,
again, this, this Externalizing the cost of security is like,
tell me about, you know, well, we do this with users all the time.
Like don't click phishing emails, report suspicious emails.
Ok. What's a suspicious email? Well, you know, it's
suspicious exactly.
Like literally what I love is what actually constitutes the
definition of a phishing email versus a spear phishing email.
It doesn't matter because as the person issuing the alerts I'm doing something
and now by me doing something, when you do click the link in the fishing mail,
it's your fault because you didn't listen to me.
And that's what all of this comes down to. All of these alerts.
Everything we're talking about.
Like this is, sadly, the foundation of a lot of security
is just, I'm going to make sure you can't blame me because I did what I needed to do.
Well, you did enough that you could pass the buck
-- and get like plausible deniability.
-- That's,
that's it.
And I think what, what it really tells me in all this, this means you don't,
you don't understand the problem first of all,
and you have no idea what to do about it.
And so it's easier
to issue ridiculous warnings and alerts on a regular basis and be ignored
than it is to actually
understand the problem and solve it.
And that's basically what it is.
And I think there,
there is a lot of security that's more about
making noise than it is about understanding the problems.
I mean, we talk about this all the time.
How many times when you ask someone for like, what is the data behind your decision?
You're like, shut up nerd, go away. That is completely normal in security.
I'm, I'm at the point now where I don't even want the data behind the decision.
I just want like the framing and the context behind it.
Like what does this word mean to you? Right.
Like, just even simple stuff of, like, what, what do you like,
what defines a terrorist act?
Ok.
So, like, if you're going to warn me about terrorist acts, can, can you tell me, like,
this report, a suspicious activity?
Great. I'd love to. Can you tell me what that is?
No,
-- no.
-- Or even a hint
anyway.
Yeah, I,
yeah,
it's time to go but it
is what it is and,
and I don't envision any of this
changing anytime soon because unfortunately this is,
I guess, you know what I would say if you made it this far and you're still listening,
like be mindful of the messages you send
out and try to make them actionable and impactful
and don't, don't overwhelm people because if you do,
they just ignore you
-- and there's no coming back from that
-- on the flip side, I'm going to say if you, if,
if you get accused, being accused of crying wolf is bad, alarm fatigue is bad.
But at the same time, if you don't
cry wolf and it turns out there was a wolf behind the rock that you didn't see.
Yeah, you get thrown under the bus.
So maybe part of it is just a quick bit of education to people because
like maybe part of it is to literally sit them down and say, look, we can,
I can make sure you're always aware of threats,
but there's a catch
and that catch is I'm going to warn you every seven minutes about a threat.
-- Totally
-- reasonable.
-- Yeah,
-- I think that's where we land.
Ok. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not its use the
Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.