Hello and welcome to episode 102 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
Hey, Kurt. And today we have a guest again, we've got Michael fire
tag here from T Cell. Say hello, Michael.
Hi there.
Awesome. So, so thanks for coming. So I guess let's start here. What does T Cell do?
Sure. So T Cell is a service for any company and team deploying their own web apps or IP
services
and our job is to help protect them
when they're running in a production environment.
And so
it's a combination of what you might be familiar with and web app,
firewalls and rasp technologies.
But fundamentally,
it's a solution for protecting apps usually deployed into cloud environments
with pure software, no network changes or software changes,
just kind of lightweight agents coupled with the cloud service
that when deployed gives our customers visibility into
risk, an attack profile or, or risk profile,
the applications that they're rolling out tells them whether
they're under attack and in what way tells them
whether those attacks are being successful when the app
is starting to do things that it shouldn't do.
And then ultimately gives them the tools to
start prevent those attacks to block the Attackers,
to prevent the app from doing
the wrong thing. And so what it ends up doing is it makes it possible for
teams that are, you know, moving towards
ops adopting cloud technologies,
just basically trying to innovate really quickly with software and trying to
figure out how to do that without security getting in the way.
But also making sure that security actually happens.
-- It's a tool designed to support that
-- one question I have right off the bat.
I've actually, and maybe I'm out of date,
but I've never heard or seen a WAF that has an agent
component like this is an agent running on the web server.
Yeah, it's a great, it's a new, it's a new architecture that we came up with it.
If you're familiar with it,
its closest analogy would be some of
the application performance management tools like new
relic or app dynamics, but applied for security purposes.
So the deployment model is we've got a collection of these lightweight agents.
There are ones that plug into the app servers or
the web servers that you were saying like genetic Apache,
what have you like an Apache mod
that wires it in and connects it to our cloud service,
which does all the heavy lifting.
And then we have a similar set of agents that connect in more at the language level.
So java.net PHP or Python etc
and those,
what those do is give visibility into the internal workings of the application.
So for example,
what third party libraries are getting loaded in what A PS
are registered and exposed queries go to the database os command,
shell commands,
executing all the stuff that you worry about inside of an application.
The app server agents give visibility into it
and it does it with called runtime instrumentation.
Meaning
effectively deploy model is you copy the file on the server,
change an environment variable or your start up script when it comes up,
essentially what T cell is going to do
with the lightweight agent is watch the application load
up and then add hooks wherever you might have
done manually into the service inside the application,
which gives us the ability to generate, you know, custom logs,
stream into the service and then,
you know, do security and policy enforcement within the application.
-- That's
-- really
-- cool.
So, so let's, let's start at the beginning.
How about for the people who don't know you mentioned
W A and rasp, can you define what a WF and a rasp is?
Sure uh although they're kind of moving targets, but I'll give you my definition. So
uh a
web app firewall
is typically it's a proxy
that you know,
an HTP proxy deployed in front of a web application or sometimes an API service
and its job is to inspect HTP requests before they come to your application
and look for request payloads that look bad, right?
So it might include signatures that look like SQL
injection or cross site scripting or things like that.
And then to some extent,
they may inspect the HP responses for patterns that
look like stuff that shouldn't go out the door,
like a credit card number, you know, pattern and so forth.
But basically there are a gate outside of the application,
inspecting things going in and out and doing security enforcement
there. Right.
-- And,
-- and I guess from the traditional sense,
there's no agents running on the end point essentially, right?
It's like a proxy.
Exactly. So, you know, they started off as
the bulk of them still out there are these hardware proxies, you know,
basically a box, you know, so if you're thinking old school,
you've got your rack of Dell servers and you got a, you know,
a load balancer and then you've got a box that's
a web app firewall sitting on top of that stack.
Since then it's migrated towards also having sort of uh cloud based deployment.
So essentially hosted proxies, you know, integrated with their C DNS.
There's web app firewalls that are provided by the
cloud service writers like Amazon and so forth.
But they're all doing the same thing which is, it's basically, it's a proxy, like,
you know, an Apache engine
X under the covers blue code
and it's going to just look at a request
is say,
is this again within the context that one hp transaction try to make a decision.
Is this thing good or bad? And if it's good, it'll pass it through.
And if it's bad it'll drop it
just like a, you know,
lower level like a network proxy would make the same
sort of decision based on the A TCP packet.
So I was gonna ask,
so you'd also mentioned filtering the outgoing stuff for credit cards.
Um I'm curious like is there,
do you sort of have a library of the standard, I guess, list of bad things?
Because I know a lot of apps claim to look for social insurance numbers.
Those look also a lot like phone numbers typically, right? 10 digits in the US.
Yeah, you're exactly right.
So I'm describing the feature set that the web app firewalls have purported to have,
right?
So, you know, inspect HP request, look for something bad, stop it on the response,
look for something that looks like a social security number
and stop it
uh or a credit card number and stop it.
The big problem with that older architecture, regardless of how it was deployed,
whether it's agent based or cloud based or,
or uh hardware proxy based or virtual machine.
Whatever it is, the basic problem with those
is that
they're trying to make decisions based on a very limited context,
they don't really understand the application.
And so you end up with either and usually both of
a ton of false positives.
That's a good example you brought up.
So, hey,
I'm gonna look for credit card numbers or
social security numbers going out the door.
Well, you know what, a lot of, a lot of numbers look like social security numbers.
So, you know, a number with two dashes in, it doesn't, you know,
uh isn't necessarily the, the thing and so you get it lights, you know,
it sounds great, but then it lights up like crazy
and you end up, you know,
either spending a ton of time constructing very detailed policies
inside these proxies in an effort to reduce the false positives
or you don't and you just get flooded with noise and you ignore it.
And at the same time, even if you get all the policies right,
you end up usually missing a ton of stuff.
So, you know, take that same example, if a
number is returned and it looks like a social security number, you know,
4 5 dash, you know, 6578, that is fine.
But what happens when the app returns numbers that without the dashes? Right?
So are you gonna flag every eight digit number or uh or nine digit or whatever it is?
So the you end up with this kind of impossible problem
of
trying to
essentially
incrementally export the full logic of the application
into an external thing that just sees individual requests and
responses so that it can make the right security decisions.
And the amount of policy you end up having to develop to do
that ends up looking almost like a full application and of itself.
And so
the net result has been, the technology
is fairly well adopted for kind of basic, really basic stuff, but
it's very difficult to get real value out of in and of itself. And so
companies like T cell and others have been innovating in this area
to try to come up with something that
solves two problems, right? One is
to make the policy model for these things
much more practical so that you can install it.
And with a minimal amount of policy management, you're actually getting,
you know,
real blocking level security without breaking the app and without going insane.
And two,
you're actually effective at it, right?
You're not that it's not like Swiss Cheese where,
you know, in it sounds great in theory,
but the reality is like any attacker would be
able to get around your way about firewall,
like with, with no effort.
So that's where that's where the real efforts are.
And that's where these different B deployment models come in,
like doing agent based things that give
more context introducing these things like RSP,
which is the,
the aspects that go inside the application itself and solve that problem.
And I'm gonna, I'm gonna stop you for a second and make you define. Rasp
said
I
was gonna get to that.
So RSP means A W
A
is a proxy that sits outside of the application
and just looks at the requests and responses
and guesses at what's happening inside the app.
Or rasp broadly speaking,
is a technology to sit inside the application where it doesn't
have to guess at what the app is going to do,
it's going to see what's happening inside the app.
And so when we talk about things like runtime instrumentation, what that means is,
for example,
in addition to seeing an HP request come in that
a, you know, query parameter looks like SQL injection,
A rasp and you know T cell, for example,
would be able to also monitor the the database driver.
Basically the thing inside the app that talks the
database and see what queries that result in that request
are actually sent to the database. So you see the inbound request from the browser
but then simultaneously you can see the outbound
SQL queries and you can couple them together. And so if you see
bad HDP request coupled with
bad
SQL query,
then you have an extremely strong indicator
of not just a SQL injection attack attempt
but a
likely vulnerability found a breach attack basically in progress.
And so that's what RFs does.
It gives you the, the visibility into the application which gives you more context,
which simplifies policy
and it cuts down a lot of the noise because you
can solve for a different problem instead of just saying,
am I under attack?
You can say,
And is it working, which is a much narrower set of things to look for?
-- And it frankly is the more relevant? Yeah,
-- that's really cool.
I'm curious about this. So,
yeah, because it sounds, that's one thing I've always thought about.
Um, I remember one time I was looking at
a,
it was actually a my SQL proxy and one of the things it could do was filtering.
And so yeah, my thinking was, well, hey, wait, if I'm, you know,
filtering for these SQL injection attacks from my wordpress server then yeah,
it would be kind of nice to be able to backtrack and be like,
so what part of wordpress let this happen, right?
Or generated this query.
And so is that something that the agents kind of
allow or help you pinpoint?
Yeah, it's, it's that sort of thing.
And it could be for SQL injection,
it could be for command injection for shell commands that are coming out.
It could be
on the browser side for cross site scripting.
It's, it's, it's seeing that other, the coupling
the inputs to the the actions. And so,
you know, for example, there have been database firewalls for a while.
It sounds like you were,
you were playing with one of those and they struggle again with context.
You know, you're
to say that you're gonna
set a filter that says, don't, you know, don't allow queries to this table.
Well, that's never going to work, right?
Because, you know, at some point, someone have to have to do a query to that table.
The question is under what context are those allowed?
And that's always within the application. And most apps talk to the database
under a single, you know, basically a pooled connection or a single user ID.
It's not the
the database connection is certainly not authenticated based
on the end user of the application.
And so you lose all that context. Whereas
with this kind of technology, you can, you can get that sort of context, you can see
what's happening on the input side as and what happens on the output side. So
as an example,
like people love talking about command injection and struts too.
This has been a major part of my professional life for the last year and a half.
Yeah.
Uh me too.
But that, you know, it's just like, it's,
it's nice to kind of pick an example because it, it goes.
So like there,
you know, you've got,
you know, web app firewalls can look for requests that look like command injection,
right?
But you get flooded with noise is hard to tell what's going on.
But you can't tell, it, can't tell you whether the app itself has a vulnerability.
It can't tell you whether you're loading that that starts
to live or not with a solution like T cell,
you'll know, hey, you load it in,
you know, you're built on struts too.
It's an old version has this critical vulnerability.
So you should pay extra attention to the command injection attempts.
What it can also then say is,
and by the way, your app never shells out because most apps don't, right?
Or if they do it's because one developer is lazy
and like cats a file instead of reading it.
Well, no having seen stuff like that, I know it's true.
I,
I saw one person try to recruit and make us temp
in eight lines of bash when they could have just used,
make
temp.
Uh Yeah. So you see and so with
AAS
you get, you can see that happen. So, you know, if you
and that's kind of part of the kind of come back to the model of
trying to help the teams that are innovating faster and moving fast during the,
you know, the, the Dev ops thing,
like how does the
guy fit into that?
Well, you can't
say I'm gonna do a code review of everything going out the door.
So again, you can, you can
that all that context provides
the ability to pick and choose what you're going to dig into
and what conversations you need to have with uh your development uh peers.
So for example, when you, you can watch the app and say, does it shell out
and under what content
and you know,
in some cases it makes sense, right.
That's uh let's say you're, you know,
there's some report generation tool that you're using that
that runs through a shell that's pretty common.
But in other cases, it's like, why are you doing that as a, as a shell command? And then
you can see it.
And then the next step is if anything, if new shell commands start popping up,
you can,
you can see that happening and you can
ultimately construct a whitelist of what's allowed.
It could be an empty whitelist
or whitelisting that you know those that that seven line
bash script and then but not allow anything else.
And so that
if you do that, if yeah,
if you have something or a third party library has some sort of vulnerability,
you'll, you'll, you know,
you'll know it potentially because you saw the library getting
loaded and it looked up the cvs for you.
You'll know that someone's trying those types of tax scans you,
but
you will have a whitelist added to your application.
That developer didn't have to do that will not let the
app run any shell commands that weren't on the white list,
right?
Or you know, won't let the, you know, let's say on the browser side will, you know,
add a content security policy header
so that it won't let the browser pull content from any
domains that you haven't whitelisted.
And so that gives the, you know, that gives the active protection aspect, right?
Where,
you know, kind of doesn't, well,
you know what's going on and you can have the controls to
block the Attackers.
But you also know is that you, you set up some guard rails around the app so it can't do
really disastrous things.
That's
really cool, man.
So I, you, you mentioned something else just a minute ago that, that really spiked.
My interest
is you talk about not code reviewing every commit
for security specifically and then you talk about using something like
a W A to get around that and, and I feel like
this is a disconnect.
I've seen a lot of security people where they,
many of them still have that attitude of, oh,
we have to do a security review of everything.
But if you're, you know, if you're doing, you know,
hundreds of thousands of commits a day and you're deploying every hour or two,
that's not always a practical thing to do.
And I think anyone who thinks they're doing it
-- is probably lying to themselves
-- more to the point.
You have humans doing the code reviews and it's almost lunch.
-- Right. Right. Yes,
-- tiktok. Let's go. Right. Like, no, seriously, I've been,
you
know,
I've seen that happen, we literally lunchtime results and
-- things happening that shouldn't, you
-- know. Yeah. But a, a
do you know it's time to go.
Yeah, exactly. So,
I mean, obviously, so you should do code reviews when you can,
and
you should be smart about
what you're gonna be
focused on and do you know really in depth reviews of and
which things you're not in which reviews have to happen prior to release
in which ones you're ok saying?
Ok, we'll look at it but the risk, you know, we're gonna look at it but we can get,
we can put it out the door and, and the risk is low enough that if I look at it next week,
it's gonna be ok.
I think that that all that's really important and, and it's,
you know, it's about tools, it's about process is about culture.
Like all these things come come together to support that.
But
what has to happen
is frankly,
you have to essentially take the lead from
the
development and operations teams on what their cadence is gonna be
and fit into it because,
you know,
at least in my experience with the teams that
are kind of moving into this newer model,
as you said, like checking in 1000 you know, 100,000 times a day shipping every hour,
like you're, you're not gonna win the battle of no, you can't ship
uh
or at least you get to pull that like once a year and you got to be right.
Uh You know, when you say don't do it,
you better find something, right?
Because the next time no one, you know, people won't listen,
which is why having like
you getting that context
and just knowing when to freak out and when not to
is a good thing. So I'll give an example
like we, so one thing that we do will give an audit of uh
routes or api end points that get registered by the app.
So basically, you know, like anytime
you add functionality to an application, you're typically going to
create new endpoints, basically like, you know,
a rest endpoint or maybe soap or whatever it is, right?
That, that the browser or clients gonna talk to,
that's some new piece of functionality
you see those are showing up all the time.
It's good to keep an eye on those that like for example, if you see one that's,
you know, that's called like change password, right, then
that's, and
then it's like,
oh maybe that's one that we really do need to
have a conversation about if we haven't done that yet,
right?
Versus,
you know, these, you know, just basic, you know,
generate report type things or whatever it is,
that that's just kind of added functionality that's not,
you know, that doesn't have any obvious security risk, right?
By having that information,
you can then decide when to, you know,
you know, when to inject yourself into the process and when to kind of let it flow.
Um And when you do inject yourself,
it's good to have context to explain why it's important, right?
So if you have your app and says, hey,
this app is constantly under attack, right? For whatever reason.
And in these ways
when you share that with developers, it's really interesting, right?
Then they get into it, right. It's because like no one wants to get,
you know, they don't want to get caught. Right.
So it's, but, you know, if you can make it less theoretical
by using whatever tools you have to get real data on,
you know, what risk you are, you have of the,
you know what the attacks are that are actually happening versus one could do,
then it gets easier to get people to work with you.
I, I feel like this is where the world is heading
and
not everyone has it figured out yet.
And so I'm, I'm curious, tell me a story about,
have you gone into an organization yet?
And, and basically, it's kind of been the old way
and,
and, and how do you, how do you help them figure it out or,
or do they just not ever figure it out?
Well,
yeah, good question.
So people come to us because at least the, the, the security guys that
we're working with,
they are trying to get to the new thing, like we're the tool to get to the new way.
So if they're, if they're,
if they're happy with the old way, they're not gonna, they're not gonna call us. Uh
So we, we had a little bit of a skewed view of the world.
But
what we see is, you know, just because people want to do it doesn't mean it's easy.
And so
we'll see a real process, you know, some, you know,
some organizations like everything's lined up and it just flows and frankly,
they're probably already doing
the right things. It's just a question of getting better.
But then sometimes we'll go into organizations
where they're going through a real transition.
Like, so, you know, uh I'm thinking of one of our customers
that
was making that the transition from being a
packaged on prem software company
to delivering their software as you know, cloud services, huge, huge thing, right?
There's a transformational for the, for the company,
you know, and you know, you can picture
this so this, you know, I should back up as the security team is relatively new,
all bought in, like thinking about doing it the new way, like they're,
they're ready to go.
But what was interesting is that the,
the development team, the operations team was all ready to go as well.
But the development teams, you know, the, you know,
particularly the management side of it,
they've been the people who built the and built a really successful company on,
on Prem software and certain processes.
And so
when they started to
hear that, hey,
operations and development, want
to get engaged with the process earlier on, right?
So they wanna, you know, talk to you,
they wanna they wanna know what's going on as we're developing, right?
Versus
they'll go develop it, throw it over the fence and let it, you know,
let someone deal with it afterwards.
That was a really hard for them. Right. And,
you know, some people were all in, some people were not,
you know, frankly
they had to have some real problems prop up in terms of, you know,
attacks happening that would, you know, an actual breaches occur to get, you know,
to get the real come to Jesus moment or saying, ok,
we have to do something differently here.
So that's, that was a really tough thing.
It's that cultural change that, that is just kind of killer for people.
Um,
but
it happens right.
There's like, I've never seen anyone and again,
it could be a skewed view of the world, but like it,
it's not an avoidable change for
almost any organization.
So it's just a question of whether, you know, when,
when you're going to get there and how painful you're gonna, you know,
you're going to make it.
Um, and it can be like, it can be awesome if you just kind of embrace it, but
it can be painful if you,
if you don't.
Well,
it's always going to be painful and I have
a suspicion you have a lot of survivorship by,
in
your view because obviously someone's reaching out to you,
they're almost certainly
over the hump will say of denial. Right.
That everything's fun.
And you know what, this really made me think of when you, you're explaining. This is
so,
so Kurt and I have relatively young Children and I'm
sure Kurt is familiar with this as well where you,
you talk to other parents and they're talking
about how brilliant and amazing their Children are.
It's like my kids eating paste, you know, like what, what,
what am I doing wrong as a parent?
And I guess this is,
this is something I suspect a lot of people need reassurance of is, is
if,
if you think everything's going right,
that's when you're probably screwing something up.
Right.
Because every,
these kind of changes are hard and they're
never smooth and they're always fraught with issues.
Right.
Yeah. Oh, definitely. There's, and,
you know, I think the,
you know,
and is of course true, just generally for security, but this is doubly true in this,
in this context is, it's
complacency is
the biggest danger. It's not,
you know, adopt, doing something wrong, it's not
misinterpreting something it's, or investing in the wrong area or like, it's just,
it's not doing anything is the, is the biggest security risk.
But also I think it ultimately becomes the biggest business risk
in terms of, you know, adopting just generally adopting DEV
Ops Cloud, like all these pieces that are, you know, helping
every
team and company move so much faster and be better
if you don't do that
unless you're not monopoly.
You're,
they kind of lost too though. Right.
Even those guys have adopted all this.
Yeah, exactly. Exactly. Yeah.
So,
one thing I've been looking at is I was looking at
some web security stuff over the last year or two and
this idea of sort of having the application more protect itself. Right.
Because I think,
well, that's definitely a problem in the close source world. Right?
Is that you get this application and you can't really do a whole lot to it, right?
Other than wrap stuff around it and hope for the best.
And even in the open source world, like, I mean,
wordpress is my favorite one because, you know, it's easy to beat on
and, you know, it's hu it's a rather huge application now and
trying to instrument wordpress to be, you know,
a little bit more intelligent and a little bit less dangerous with some of their,
you know,
their API and XML stuff which, you know, doesn't have the greatest history.
I'm just wondering like kind of where is this all heading?
Because I'm also now thinking, you know,
things like microservices and serverless computing,
-- like does this technology work with serverless?
-- Yeah.
Yeah.
No, it does. I mean that it, so it's a good question. There's,
you know, there's a separate trend, all, you know,
all in service of this general model of how are we gonna innovate fast?
Let teams do their thing without,
you know, uh processing them to death.
I think microservices and serverless is, is in that ilk in that it's sort of the,
it's about breaking things down to their essential elements and then
giving a person or a team complete autonomy on how to execute on that.
So this kind of technology,
you know, lines up with that. Well, in the sense that
if you're a security guy and you need to figure out what's going on in my,
with this application,
which is gonna be a collection of services like that or across my organization.
Well, you're gonna want to have
visibility into all these different components, but even more.
So you can't add additional process, you can't have, you know,
20 different microservices,
all of which have a gate with you saying yes or no or anything like that.
And so it fits in really well and the technology of course works, right.
It's just, you know, it's software so it plugs in with wherever your software is.
Um So that's easy.
Um
There is, you know, I, in my opinion,
there's a bit of a
fallacy is a little bit this word coming to my mind, but it's maybe a little strong,
but there's,
there's a mistake that some folk that some folks are making in thinking that
deve
by breaking up applications into these smaller components and having, you know,
smaller teams execute on it.
Uh You can
100% push security responsibility into the development teams
and security people just become kind of,
you know, uh, coordinators.
-- Yeah,
-- that's because that's worked over the last 50 years.
But it's, it's,
it's, it's interesting
because it's making a resurgence right.
There's, you know, people talk about the shift left and, you know, all, all,
all these different things around how to push security
earlier into the development process, which is very often, which is a, I think,
often a good thing but it's, it's being conflated with.
We just hope that help train the developers and developers will take care of it.
And
the,
it's, you know, it just doesn't, it's not fully credible.
And I think that's the danger with, with that is you, it's,
it's one thing to say, ok, we're going to break things up and we do want to, you know,
train those developers and get them,
get them dangerous and thinking about the right things.
But at the same time, you're gonna have to have
tools, process and so forth to get an overlay across all the smaller components
so that
your security team, which is ultimately works as an overlay with development,
can get their overlay visibility into it and do it in a way that still supports
how the, the devs actually want to,
to do their jobs and their jobs are
ultimately about getting the functionality there and the and
availability there.
And so,
you know, I think it's it that
this sort of thing becomes very, very important
and it's also important to just kind of think
about who are the actors who needs to do what
and not push too much on to the developers just because they
-- have a smaller app, uh, to deal with.
-- I love that statement
and, and I think
that's something I guess you say it and
I know it's true but I haven't really thought of it recently.
It's funny how sometimes people tell you something and you're like, well, duh,
but at the same time, like, like, it's,
it's not a topic I think people are discussing and,
and I do feel like that is a worrisome trend
that we're starting to see again.
Yeah.
Well, you'll hear, like, I don't know if you guys are hearing about, like DEV,
set
ups and so forth.
But it, it's a good,
it's a good thing but it's being moved a little to my mind a little much towards
translating to have developers do the work for you.
Well, I mean, my fundamental concern about this is, is
software development is hard,
fundamentally, it's hard because,
I mean, and this is assuming you have things like
an actual set of requirements,
right?
I mean,
how many people are writing software out there
and they don't have a full set of requirements
and ignoring all of that,
then you also want them magically to do security as well. And, I mean, you know,
I, I don't know. II, I haven't seen it work in my entire career
where you can just magically educate your way out of this problem. Right.
I mean, Josh, we've had that discussion with many people, many different places,
talk about it
constantly. And, I mean,
you know, I,
I'm just amazed that my computer turns on in the morning and, like, works,
let alone that it's reasonably secure.
So, yeah, I know.
I personally,
I don't think we can realistically educate our way out of this as well because,
you know, by definition that means then that the junior developers, oh,
you can't touch anything.
But how do we get them trained up? Right.
And that's my other thought is with this security training thing.
How do we actually achieve it
economically?
Because I don't think most companies can afford to
take a year off to train all their developers.
Well, training doesn't scale but, but tools do
so. All right, I'm gonna, I'm gonna bring it home. I, I like where we're ending here.
Thank you so much, Michael. It was a fascinating conversation.
I appreciate you taking the time to talk to us. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com to
grab our show notes and there's a link there to
a Facebook group and you can hit us up on social media with the Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag And yeah, if nothing else,
you two gentlemen have a fabulous rest of your day.
Thank you.
All right. Thanks a lot.