Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 33 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
-- Kurt. You always say my name. Come on, man, we're face to
-- face.
-- I gave you the,
-- it's actually very exciting.
So we have never been in the same place at the same time while we recorded the podcast.
So that's very exciting. And, and why are we at the same place at the same time?
-- Kurt, we are the amazing extravaganza that is RS A 2000
-- 17.
I don't know if extravaganza is the right word, but this place is a zoo.
I'll admit that.
-- Oh, I
-- mean, basically, it's 40,000 people that are like us,
which to me makes it a
it's ridiculous.
It's like the circus came to town and everybody
went to the circus was already in the circus.
That is the best description I think I've ever heard.
But so we are standing here at RS A at the end of the day
and both of us just finished our sessions.
-- And so why don't we, why don't we talk about it?
-- Sure.
-- You want to go first,
-- Josh, I would love to go first.
So I did a session, a peer to peer session about managing your open source.
And so what that
is, the room holds 25.
And so it fills up with people. And then we have a very quite frank discussion about
in my case, the topic of managing your open source software
and what that means for each organization. And of course, as you can imagine,
there's no set agenda.
People come in, we start talking and then we decide what do we want to talk about.
And the best part is
people discuss these things with one another as it goes on, which is fantastic,
especially kind of from my point of view because
I get to sit there and essentially let other people do all the hard work, right?
Which is the best part by far.
But no, I mean, I mean, in all seriousness, they were fantastic and funny enough.
So I was not expecting this, but licensing
was a really big topic that kept coming up over and over again,
right?
So I'm curious when you say I,
I'm assuming these are people consuming open source projects, libraries code
and they're worried about the licensing
being some sort of problem with cross
contamination or how they ship their products.
So that's part of it. But also the fact that
a lot of organizations didn't realize that open source has a lot of licenses
and it doesn't just mean free software right there.
Are actual responsibilities that come with some of this stuff.
And so that's what really made it interesting.
And in fact, more than one person you could tell was
we say a bit upset by the fact that they were going to have to
go and start talking to lawyers when they got back to work on Monday.
Yeah,
I'm guessing a lot of these people haven't actually read the
open source licenses of the stuff they're shipping in some cases.
Nobody reads. Right. And it's like terms of service.
I mean, how many times do you just click? Agree.
Well, and two, I mean, who enforces this stuff? Right.
There's only literally a handful of cases where somebody's
actually gone and legally enforced an open source license.
Yeah,
I
can only
-- think
-- of
one,
to be
-- honest,
-- there's been a handful of them and in fact, there's a
Bradley Coon, I believe his name is. He's a fellow I met some years back he worked for,
oh, I don't even remember the name of the organization now, but essentially
they were, their job was to enforce
GP L against a handful of open source projects.
And the big one being Busy Box. Right.
Because Busy Box is used all over the place in these days when you buy a product.
It is not uncommon for there to be the GP L
in the back of the book or maybe in the menu or wherever that talks about this. And
you know, five or 10 years ago, that was not the case.
And so these guys were one of the groups that really kind of
helped make that a thing where these large organizations started to realize,
you know, this isn't free code you just take and do whatever you want with.
There's actually a purpose behind this and that there's essentially the authors of
it had some sort of intent and that's why it carries this license.
So I'm curious, I hadn't really, uh
really ever given that thought to be honest.
Um, because quite honestly I throw, whenever I buy a product,
I pretty much immediately throw the manual out.
-- Um,
-- you know, and it's really funny because, you know what I do, I look for the GP L.
-- That's the first thing I do in most instances.
-- And I,
I've honestly had one or two thoughts of like
requesting
the, so the open source software from the vendor.
You know, actually, because I, I, it seems to me when I do see the GP L,
they do have that classic, like
write in,
send us an envelope and like we'll send you a CD burnt with the software or something
like they don't make it available on FTP dot food dot com.
You know, a lot of people do though, in all seriousness is,
well, I bought a Toyota car that has the fancy entertainment,
whatever screen thing that lets you hack the car
and in the menu.
It tells you how to acquire the source code if I want it.
No, I don't care. I just look for the GP L. Right.
I mean,
I don't really want to do any of this stuff and goodness knows if I started doing it,
I'm going to end up breaking my car.
Like that's the only inevitable outcome of this
-- journey
-- or on some sort of manufacturer's blacklist.
Don't sell this man a car.
Nothing would surprise me. I mean, in all seriousness, nothing would surprise me.
But I mean, another popular topic we had was how do you manage all of this stuff?
Like obviously you've got a scan for vulnerabilities, how many things are in there?
What's on it?
And actually there was some really good discussions
people had around kind of internal white lists
saying these are the open source libraries
and projects that the security team approves.
We vetted them, we made sure they're ok.
We looked for security flaws and, and you know, yada yada
yada
kind of the whole nine yards. And I was
impressed by the number of people there that had what
sounded like very mature programs based around this whole concept.
Cool. Uh One thing I'm wondering
how many libraries on average are these people using?
-- Is it like one or two or is it 100?
-- It's in the hundreds without question in effect.
So uh Black Doug actually just published a paper about a month ago.
I think it was talking about open source use in the enterprise.
And one of their findings was that your typical project or,
or product or whatever you wanna call it has
on average about 100 dependencies on other things.
And you can imagine it's turtles all the way down
where, you know, your product might
100 dependencies.
But then one of those dependencies that's 100 dependencies
and so on and so on and so on.
And in fact, this was one of the things that came up was someone was saying that
they were using node and they did their N PM install and
it pulled in 200 dependencies and all of a sudden they,
they said, whoa, like, what's the deal here?
Where did all this crap come from? And that's totally legitimate. Right.
Well, I'd also be curious,
uh so how many of these people are building the software in a
way that actually records those automated dependency polls like node or maven or,
you know, all these modern systems that will just go
and grab whatever library is needed automatically.
It sounds like it is not happening very often.
And that's one of the things that was a topic that
came up over and over again as well is the fact that
how do you start recording this stuff?
How do you understand what is in the software and making sure that,
that people aren't even, you know,
maybe on purpose or accidentally including a whole
bunch of extra stuff nobody really knew about.
And now all of a sudden when it's time to release you take a look and it's like,
holy cow.
Where did all this stuff come from?
Yeah.
Well,
because I know there's also been the
problem with some libraries being taken offline
and all of a sudden then,
uh, what was it? That was that a note
shift? It was,
-- we talked about that as well.
-- It literally broke. I think
every
-- two thirds
-- of no, because everybody used it
and it was like a
-- fine library. I
-- think it was three,
which is just sad, but actually the thing that came up then as well.
And this is something that
I believe node is aware of, but I don't know exactly what's going on.
This is something I want to research.
Uh the fact that apparently someone just wrote a new one and put it in place.
And so there was no
kind of chain of command in that instance where one developer took it off.
A new one, basically unrelated, put it there and all of us
and it's like, whoa, you know, how,
how come people can just start changing this stuff without any sort of checks?
Well, it's actually a bit worse than that. I know in the Ruby Gems world
uh prior to Ruby gems.org sort of being the clear winner of the Ruby Gems ecosystem.
There was another site I can't remember the name of
and they ran into the situation of people would
have a popular ruby gem on that other site
uh say like uh calculation library
and somebody would then squat that name on Ruby gems.org.
And it wouldn't necessarily be nice code.
And the Ruby gems.org people didn't really want to be
like enforcing the name space and taking on all this,
you know, work
um
until it kind of got bad enough that they had to.
And so there's also those questions um because I know
there are definitely there's been uh instances of typo squatting,
you know, where people have created projects
with a name
that is remarkably similar to a popular project and all you
need is a typo and you're sucking in their code,
right? Oh, yeah, that guy did research on that. I forget, I forget what it was.
I, I'll find it and I'll put it in the show notes because that was fascinating
and he had people from like the,
the department of Defense had installed his fake library
by the time he was done, which is, is horrifying to think about in all seriousness.
Well, I think it's uh uh fundamentally a lot of this is Black Magic.
I mean, it just, just the act of getting software to compile
can be, you know, very much a nontrivial task, right?
If you, if you've been in the open source world,
you, you know what we're talking about.
Um There's those whole magic build chains where, you know,
you have to have a specific library or a specific configuration or Lord knows what.
And, um, you know, so when things build
nine times out of 10, we're real happy about that
and,
you know,
asking somebody to create a build system that's completely offline so that they
know exactly what's going into it and can prove what's going into it.
-- That's a lot
-- of work. Oh, absolutely. You have to build the ships. Right.
-- Yeah.
-- Until left shift disappears. Right.
Right. Yeah, seriously. Oh, man.
No, it, it was great though.
The, these folks really, they understood a lot of the problems and fundamentally,
I think
the consensus that we all came to was the fact that
there are tools that can start helping address some of this.
What is the open source in your infrastructure?
But
they're not quite there yet. And I think if you kind of go out on the floor here,
there's a bunch of vendors that can scan your
software and they can look for various things and
they aren't going to tell you that it's perfect, but
obviously it's a good start.
And in fact, one of the topics that came up as well was somebody said, well,
why should I buy this tool?
Why don't I just hire some developers to kind of manually audit all this stuff?
And then
we started discussing what that really means and you're talking about, you know,
probably millions of lines of code and hundreds
to thousands of open source projects included.
And they, they quickly realized that
this is probably something we want a tool for.
This isn't something we're gonna hire out for.
Yeah.
Well, and I've also encountered even in the open source world,
a lot of cases where people embed,
uh, the common ones are Gzip
expat and Lib XML.
So that it will compile on windows cleanly
without forcing somebody to pull in some dependency or
-- deal with it. Basically, it's just they embed a copy and bam it works.
-- Yeah.
Well, I, I wrote a blog post about this a couple of weeks ago actually was Z li
was kind of the wake up call for the Linux distributions back in.
Was it like 04 or something? Maybe even before then?
But essentially, so the story is a long time ago,
basically, every application embedded its own copy of Z.
And then one day a security flaw was found in Z
lib
that meant these Linux distributions had to rev
hundreds of packages to fix one security flaw.
And of course,
the correct solution was to start using the Z
lib library instead of embedding your own copies.
But I guess ironically now with things like containers
and kind of the way development is going again,
we're moving back in the direction of just including copies of this stuff.
And
I'm not going to say we're doomed because that would be foolish.
But I think this time around the solution isn't
going to be kind of that dynamic linking,
let's pull it all out.
But rather it's going to be things like continuous integration and tooling
that are going to solve this because right now if there is a serious problem,
well, I mean, they kind of have been but you know, if there was like a warm
flaw
that was going to really be a huge issue,
there are literally
probably thousands of containers out there that are all going to have to be updated.
And that's not something that's going to happen
in a couple of minutes. It's probably going to take months if ever.
Well,
and I think the continuous integration in the testing aspect is
even more important than because no matter what solution you have,
people will not use it unless they can be certain
-- that their software will continue working.
-- Yeah.
And actually funny enough that was another topic that came up as
well was the fact that one of the people there was saying,
you know, OK, so my developers are using this library,
but the library is changing constantly and it keeps breaking my stuff.
What is the solution to this? And of course,
there isn't a good answer.
But part of that story is things like continuous integration and lots of testing,
making sure you've got like regression testing and functional
testing and unit testing and all these things.
Because
the challenge isn't necessarily how do we avoid the breakage,
but rather let's find the breakage fast so we can deal with it instead of, you know,
hey, we're shipping in two hours.
Oh, crap, everything broke.
Well, and it's also too, I, you know,
I've been in situations like that and in some cases I've
stopped using that software because it was just too painful in that
I have to regress to something with less functionality because quite frankly,
it was more important that I had 90% of stuff working all the time
than having that extra 10% of functionality that like broke every Thursday.
Yeah.
And that was that,
that was part of the story as well is the fact that you
need to pay attention to some of these projects because some of them,
I mean,
it could be just a dude and obviously you have
to worry about some prominence things then or you could
have a project that's essentially hostile to the users in
that respect where they keep breaking things on you and it's
not productive to be using that. And so it, I mean, needless to say
we only had 45 minutes and we covered a lot of ground.
We probably could have had three hours and, and still had more to talk about. But
I mean, this is
on the plus side, people understand this is a problem they need to think about.
And I guess on the minus side is we're still so early in
this problem space that there aren't great solutions to all of them.
But I admit I do have, I have hope. I have tons of hope
and
well, and I think especially with things like containers, you know, we're,
we're in that fortunate case, I think of where
people are redoing a lot of their, it and how they do it and it's,
they're being forced into more mature models of it,
right? Definitely, definitely. All right. So that's enough about me.
-- What about you, Kirk? You talked about CV
-- E? Yeah.
So I talked about the common vulnerabilities and exposures database.
Uh and how myself,
Kent Landfield and the CV board were saving
it with some open source process and methodologies.
And actually more interesting to me
was there's two big misconceptions that keep coming up with CV E
and those are,
what is a CV E?
A lot of people think it's
any number of things but fundamentally, all a CV identifier is, is a CV identifier
with a description of the problem and then some reference URL S
that is it.
Now, here's the problem
Mir
has a CV E database. That is the actual true one source of CV data.
There's also the national vulnerability database,
there's also CV
-- details dot I wanna say org,
-- there's gotta be
so
more than 10.
And so for example, the NVD, the national vulnerability database, nvd.n.gov
is
for the US government that is their one true view of CV E
and NVD actually adds data to their CV E entries including a CV SS score.
So a common vulnerability scoring system basically which tells you how bad it is.
If it's a 10.0 you need to fix it. If it's a 4.3 it's a pro
uh cross site scripting vulnerability and you can probably ignore it.
Uh And then they also very nicely add some
uh C pe some common product enumeration data,
which is basically a way of describing, you know,
what is it Microsoft Windows version X or whatever, what's affected.
And a lot of people seem to think that a CV E identifier
includes a CV SS score. Well,
this is not true. The NVD data view
adds that
but an actual CV ID, like I said is just purely the identifier itself.
So CV hyphen the year hyphen the number like 1234,
the description of the vulnerability. So like
which basically boils down to a
uh vulnerability of type food in product X results
in this outcome when an attacker exploits it,
you know, it's like a buffer overflow in Apache results in code execution,
uh you know version 2.3 0.4
whatever.
And then the reference URL S which are actually really super valuable for a
lot of people because it allows you to do more research into that issue.
And you know, find like really how bad is it what's the context behind this, you know?
Um,
well, and I think it's also important to note that NVD does add the CV SS,
what V three now, I think scores, but the CV SS score can differ by product or by use or,
I mean, there's a million
things that can happen and NVD kind of sticks to a very general purpose.
It's actually worse than that.
NVD doesn't always have all the information they need
to make AAA correct scoring assessment.
So they have to default to a worst case scenario essentially, right?
They can't just be like, well,
we don't know if this is locally exploitable or remotely exploitable.
They have to default to the what, what is worse, right?
And so their CV SS scoring is quite often a little bit,
-- well, it's basically, it's pessimistic because it has to
-- be,
which is the right thing to do, right?
You don't want to have an optimistic score
and they'd be like, oh crap actually, no, this is a 10,
you know, so I,
I get that and that makes sense and they're doing their job in that respect.
But of course, I know like, like us as vendors,
it can create challenges because sometimes
the score from NVD is very high when in the way we might be using it.
It,
it's actually not that bad and then you have to start arguing and convincing and it,
-- it's,
-- or even more extreme,
we've had flaws. Uh
the Apache file commons upload flaw, remote code execution. Very bad flaw.
So in our middleware products, very bad flaw
satellite six shipped that library
but did not use any of the functionality. I had them check the code twice.
So it wasn't even that. It was a lesser vulnerability.
It was not a vulnerability at all.
And of course, we had customers saying why aren't you fixing this? Well,
it's,
it's technically yes, the vulnerable code is present,
but we do not use it in any way, shape or form or have any plans to.
And we actually will be updating this library at some point in the future
in case that happens. But fundamentally,
you know, we also made a note of it to make sure that we don't use this.
Um which is, I mean, and so in all seriousness,
that's a great reason that even if you
aren't necessarily vulnerable to a specific issue,
you should still update it eventually
because someday someone is going to try to use that functionality
and then you're gonna find yourself in a world of hurt.
Yeah.
No, it's, it's incredibly important to know what you're shipping,
what version you're shipping
and what is it pulling in? You know, is it,
if you're building stuff in pretty much any modern build system,
it's going to be very helpful and manage your dependencies,
which is awesome because
my God, I do not want to go back to the days of old
I don't,
I, I, yeah, I
know what you mean.
-- Like getting gnome compile.
-- I, you know, I don't know if I ever did that.
I don't want to. I believe I tried and I'm pretty sure I gave up because it was a night.
Well, it's still a nightmare. It's just that
there's nice ways to do it.
So, anyway, those were the two biggest misconceptions around CV E
and then what we've also found is that people really do want
better coverage of issues, you know,
especially, um,
where we have a lot of cases where we have vendors
that are
not as either maybe mature in their security process or are in
some cases outright hostile to having CV ES attached to their products.
You know, because they, they want to have these products that don't have flaws.
If you don't have CV S,
they don't have flaws. And that's the reality
for a lot of,
uh,
organizations until a vulnerability has a CV E identifier.
It is not a real vulnerability.
Right. Right. Well, actually, so funny enough is one of the guys I had in my session
that something he brought up is, he said,
if this library I'm looking for in the open source universe has no CD E I DS.
That's a huge war
sign. Right. That's not a good thing.
That's a very bad thing because it means nobody's paying attention
or they've, you know, it's
either nobody's paying attention. They've been actively hostile or
nobody's ever looked whatever.
And,
and that's part of what I'm trying to do with the uh the distributed
weakness filing is make it so easy to get a CV E that A
pro
projects will get CV S
and B if the projects don't want to get CV S or don't even know they exist,
which let's face it.
You know,
some of these projects are literally a guy
on the weekends banging away on the software.
And some of these things are super widely used.
You know,
some of these image uh library format parsing
libraries that are used in literally everything are,
are one guy.
And you know,
so what I want is also the model where an external
person who maybe uses this software and cares enough can make
the request to add the CV S and actually maybe do it themselves.
So that essentially you could have somebody who becomes
what's called a CV numbering authority
on behalf of a project that maybe they're not even officially a part of,
you know, a great example being wordpress,
I believe you have a recent experience with this draw.
Yeah, that's right. I, I just assigned so I'm uh what was it?
DWF CV E mentor, number one.
So I, I should get a shirt.
But
so
Kurt and I have been working to make this happen. And obviously, I'm uh we say more
uh uh
willing to deal with, we'll say uh uh missing pieces. So,
so we've been working through it to make this happen.
And
it was what last it was on Friday? I think it was.
I had somebody basically contact me and said, look,
there's this horrible wordpress flaw
that there's actually like they think it's in the millions
-- of sites that are being exploited and essentially
-- all of them
-- prior to 4.7 0.1 which only came out about a week or two ago.
-- Uh 4.7 0.2 was
they fixed it silently 4.7 0.1.
They made it even more confusing and
this is a great reason not to silently fix things anyway.
Anyway, so the issue being like they needed a CV ID,
I could get him one.
And I said I'm doing it because it's way more important to just have the ID.
So people have that common language they can use when they talk about this
versus necessarily kind of doing it the right way of getting
a hold of Miter and working with Wordpress or whatever.
And so, yeah, we threw it out there in the universe.
And, and so I think in that instance,
this is where the flexibility of DWF is going to be phenomenal for the the industry.
Well, and the reality is, you know,
the wordpress people had good intentions.
This was a remote code execution flaw effectively in the rest api
they fixed it silently in version 4.7 0.1. Hoping that
people would update
and then
well, and, you know, some did, some didn't, uh,
I religiously stay on top of my wordpress updates
because they do things like this.
-- You know,
-- everybody learned a lesson here.
And so, and then they shipped version 4.7 0.2 which was a known security update.
It, they listed three security updates
and then another researcher
basically went, oh. Interesting.
And wordpress had to publicly admit to this fourth flaw
in four point
but and even more confusingly, they updated the 4.7 0.2 change log to say that they,
you know, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And this is a great example of why we need a CV
number with like a description and an entry
that makes this all clear because right now,
like I know the some press and some bloggers and stuff were talking about
-- this and it was getting horribly confusing
-- saying issue number four is not helpful
and that's kind of what was happening.
So, yeah, no, it's a great example of why,
you know, ideally the project itself would get the CV E right?
And but if they don't want to or if they're not able to or if they just flat
out don't care or literally there are people that don't know CV E exist and you know,
that will always be the case
and I want people, external,
people that care about it to be able to get those CV numbers in and get it done quickly
so that we don't have these messes, you know, so that we can all talk about CV.
What is it? 1 million, 1000?
-- One
-- million? 1000? It
is. Yeah,
that's right.
Well, you know, so that's the thing, right? Is
the,
the whole power in this isn't necessarily getting it right or wrong all the time.
It's being able to move fast because by being able to move quickly,
we put ourselves in a position where we can
adapt to the environment and what's happening around us,
which today in security is insanely important
because everything is crazy all the time.
Well, I mean, a great example of this is the,
the database format that DWF uses for our CV S also includes a state for the CV.
Like, is it
reserved? Is it public? Is it rejected?
And more importantly,
what happened to it if it was rejected or if it was
merged into another CV? Or if this CV was split into multiple CV S
because that way you can automatically consume and process this.
So given a CV V number
that was, for example, rejected, your system would go oh,
this CV number was officially rejected.
It turned out not to be a flaw
or it turned out to be multiple flaws or it turned out to be a copy of that other flaw.
So go look at that entry.
Um And we've had that happen where miter assigned a CV number. I didn't know about it.
I assigned a CV number.
Oh, miter already did this. Ok. So in my entry it says, go see CV, whatever on Mir's
end.
And
you can now in a very easy automated fashion,
discover the truth
and even better yet. That means we can fix mistakes quickly and easily,
which is key,
which means now we can move much faster because we can make
mistakes that we can recover from easily and quickly and cheaply.
Yeah. Right. Right. And that, you know,
I will say that's one of the things that I
think is a theme that's becoming more and more common
is people are recognizing now,
especially in security that you're going to
make mistakes and it's ok to make mistakes
here. Right.
Yeah,
that's true.
But I mean, I remember, you know, five and 10 years ago,
it was very much focused on the get it right every time
and that,
that never happens in no universe. Are you? Right, all the time. Right.
It's just, it's how it is.
Yeah. Well, and the reality too is like 98% of these cases are not super complicated.
Like it's not,
it's a single vulnerability that we can fix relatively easily
and we don't need this huge heavy process to deal with this stuff all the time.
But, you know, sometimes we do, like,
for example, if there's a, you know, a significant flaw in open SSL then, yes,
then you, you bring out the full heavy procedure
but if it's a cross site scripting, vulnerability and wordpress, I mean,
it's bad but it's not the end of the world.
-- Yeah.
-- Oh, definitely. Well, and that's the thing, right. When you need the big guns,
they're there,
but then they're not bogged down with the easy stuff so you can
use them for what you need them for. Right.
And, I mean, I think that's kind of what happened with CD E to this point is
Miter got bogged down with the easy stuff,
which then obviously hurt when it was time to do the big stuff.
Right?
I think a lot of what we need in security is,
is more of an idea of proportional response and escalation of force as needed
because
in my experience pretty much everybody, it boils down to one, having one response.
You have to make it perfect or we have to completely block it the nuclear option,
right?
And, you know, maybe good enough is good enough.
-- Like, um, you know, enough
-- is the best you're gonna get. Right.
Well, that's the reality. Right.
Yeah, you can, you can try for perfect. But you're gonna be lucky with good enough.
And that's just the reality of it.
Very cool. Good. Good.
So this is, so I, I must admit as the, uh,
official editor of the open source security podcast, I'm,
I'm slightly terrified of this one because we're recording in the
Mosconi kind of in public and there's lots of background noise.
I can't cut this because if I cut it it's gonna sound really weird. Right. So,
I don't know, let, let's hope we haven't screwed anything up too bad.
Well, I guess we just, you know, we go with the go live thing and run with it.
Yeah, we'll figure it out, man. So, so what you doing for the rest of the show now?
I mean, we're, although, oh, I'm not done yet. Oh, man. So
I have a birds of a feather session that they asked me to do,
but it's at seven o'clock in the morning tomorrow
and they told me what time it was after I agreed to do it. Which,
uh, I don't blame him because I don't know if I would have agreed.
-- There's people
-- awake at seven in the morning.
I'm gonna be awake at
seven in the morning.
Yeah. Right.
Well, I, in fact I woke up at 5 a.m. today, which I was pleased I made it to 5 a.m.
So I consider that progress. Right.
And, and maybe if I'm lucky I'll make it to 6 a.m. tomorrow and then I can wake up and,
and come here
and,
and hang out with the other folks from the east coast. Right.
Well,
I look forward to seeing you tomorrow and my plan is to actually catch a few talks.
-- Yeah.
-- II, I went to a handful today. Actually, it was good. I saw Schneier
talk and he was discussing about kind of regulating the internet of things.
And he had, he had some really interesting insights.
I mean, you know, Bruce always gives, gives a good talk. There's no denying that.
But he did the one thing he talked about that really made me think and I not,
I sort of knew this but I didn't really put it together
a lot was the fact that
if you look at the way computing has worked in the past
when there was failure, it didn't really matter,
right? Because you were dealing with a computer somewhere
and it failed. Nobody died. It was no big deal.
But now you kind of look at the other end of the
spectrum and you have things like automobiles and medical devices and,
and heck even to a certain degree appliances in people's homes that
when these things fail, people are literally going to die.
So now it's not a matter of, oh, I screwed up. Oh, well, no big deal.
-- It's like, yeah, oh, I screwed up. A bunch of people are dead. You know, that's
-- crazy.
That's actually come up in CV E discussions and that
we need coverage of these things because let's face it.
CV E traditionally covered issues that while bad
would typically work.
Worst case scenario result in
a loss of money. You know, a bank gets robbed
or, you know,
an airport gets shut down and it's really just inconvenient.
Um, but yeah, with
like with self driving cars,
right? I mean, I mean, cars, pacemakers, um,
you know what the, the diabetic dial,
not dialysis, uh uh the insulin pumps,
right? I mean, there's,
yeah, this is crazy to think about.
I mean, and to be quite honest,
what's gonna be really wild is these things are full of open source.
So
what is gonna happen when you find out like
this git commit literally killed somebody.
It's gonna be, I mean,
I'm gonna feel really bad for that developer because he's gonna have to, you know,
he's never gonna forget it but you think about it, that's,
that's going to happen where we're gonna be able
to say this get commit literally killed a person.
I suspect we're gonna see a model where we have to have,
I don't wanna say like layered security but some checks and balances, you know,
uh a great example is what is a fail safe condition?
For example, a car,
what is a fail safe condition? Quit driving?
Yeah, pull over to the side and stop driving ideally
-- um until
-- you pull over in front of a semi,
right
flies you over, you know, obviously
like with a with a self driving plane, what is a good failure scenario?
I think you crashed? That's
pretty much the fail.
I suspect a lot of what will help is actually figuring out
how we want these products to work and defining how we want
things to work so that we then have something to shoot for.
-- So
-- actually Schneier had an interesting analogy
in
this respect was the fact that if you look at nuclear power,
nuclear power before the Three Mile Island incident in the United
States was on fire and it's all everyone talked about.
In fact, you can buy kits from like the sixties that are, you know,
like my own radiation lab or something for
your house that came with uranium or something,
which is horrifying to think about now. But,
and then Three Mile Island happened and people said, well,
we need to think about this now, the unfortunate thing though,
that he didn't say that I suspect he thinks
is we aren't going to do this until we have some horrific accident
that makes people realize we have to take security
in these cars and medical devices and whatever seriously.
And that sucks that it's going to come to that
well, or worse an intentional attack.
Right?
I would, it, it's gonna be in the same,
the same bucket right where it may be intentional.
It could be an accidental flaw. I mean, who knows what, whatever I mean?
Well, look at you have that, uh, that router. You said that is going to what in a year,
right?
Happens when it's like, all right, we've got,
you know,
4000 pacemakers that in six months are gonna quit
working and kill the people that are inside of
-- what do you do? I mean, that,
-- that's crazy.
Well, it's funny, I mean, in the case of a medical device,
you already have an established legal framework
to deal with this.
And then, you know, ideally the outcome would be, is that, well,
you have to go replace all those pacemakers, which is
not super awesome for the people.
-- And
-- then you think about it,
some of those people will die because they're too sick to be operated
on. I mean, that's, that's crazy.
I mean, I think fundamentally it boils down to what I've been talking about,
about quality of life, you know, did we basically do more good than harm?
Right. And because we'll never answer that in 50 years, I,
I,
you know, I,
because I don't think as security practitioners we can aspire to do no harm.
I don't think that's possible anymore because it's so complex and so complicated
and this is a can of worms.
I know, but the reality is I should, I would like to do no harm.
But at the same time,
you know, what? If we can make a major improvement?
-- We,
-- we should finish this discussion at the pub later tonight. Right.
So, oh
man, that
stuff.
But I guess here's the deal too.
And this is something that gives me hope even though things
can seem crazy is the fact that we are starting to
have these conversations finally and now a bunch of us have
been complaining about this for longer than we can remember,
but it's starting to happen.
And that's,
I'm not going to say
that we're going to solve it quickly. But
the first step is to understand the problem and I think
we're starting to understand at least we have a problem.
Right.
We don't understand the problem, but we know we have it,
which I think is too stupid as it sounds, that's a huge first step for us.
You know,
it's like that whole Dunning Kruger Curve we've now realized, oh,
we're on the Dunning Kruger Curve.
We don't, we don't,
we're now aware that we don't know what we don't know to quote Cheney, you know,
-- that's actually,
-- and that's a big step forward.
That's a really good point, you know that and I, I think that wasn't Cheney.
-- That was
-- Rumsfeld
Rumsfeld.
Sorry.
No, no,
I,
-- yeah, we won't quote Cheney on this one.
-- No, my apologies.
No, no, it's all good. No, I mean, this is,
it's cool stuff and I guess that's part of what makes,
you know, hanging out at a show like this some fun is,
is you get to think about this stuff and
have conversations with people about what's going on and,
and so it's,
yeah, it's, it's been crazy, man.
I, I don't know, we'll see what tomorrow brings, I guess.
All right, man, we got things to do.
So folks, I would like to Thank you for listening.
As always, I'll tell you,
you can go to open source Security podcast.com where I will post
the show notes to whatever it is we've been talking about.
And if you want, you can hit up Kurt and I on Twitter,
we'd be happy to have a chat if you're listening to this
during RS A which I'm hopeful I'll get it posted during RS A
come find us, have a chat. We, we'd love to talk
and I guess until next time, Kurt,
you have a fabulous evening.
Yeah. And I hope you have a great birds of a feather session
-- yet.
-- Seven AM.
It's 10 a.m. for you. That's not even late. Well, that's not even early.
I, I don't want to think about it, man. Uh, 7 a.m. That's all I keep thinking of.
I, I'll get a bucket of coffee and I'll
keep drinking it.
All right. Until next time, folks. Thank you both. Thanks for listening.
Bye bye bye.