Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 55
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
Oh, man, Kurt, I am so excited.
Let's encrypt finally is going to have wild card certificates.
Yeah, I'm actually really looking forward to that because
I, uh, Dirty Secret.
I actually started buying wild card certificates many years ago
because it was just simpler, right? You buy one certificate and you're done,
right? You don't have to get one per host or whatever.
Um, and then of course,
I just outsourced the whole messed cloud floor and just walked away from it.
It's like, it just works
like, and for five bucks a month. Right?
So, yeah, but I mean, yeah,
I love the fact that we'll be able to get wild card certificates for free.
That's, uh, you know, man, I, I just, I think about this is, I remember certificates.
This was back in the day.
They were like hundreds of dollars.
I mean,
it was so expensive and so crazy even getting
a domain was really expensive and really hard.
I remember when getting a domain was free.
Why? Because it was like in the, the hosts file, everyone was copying around.
No, no, no.
Like 20 years ago when you registered a DNS domain name, you didn't have to pay
for top
level domains. They were just free.
That predates me. Everything I've ever dealt with involved money.
Yeah.
Or like I knew a guy that got like,
two portable C class addresses back in the day and
then ended up selling them for some good money.
Well, he was running a quote unquote ISP.
It was basically like an Isdn line, like a 128 Kisdn line for his internet feed.
And then like a
bank of, uh, I think it was 14 4 dial up modems, maybe 9600 bod, I forget.
But, um, yeah,
and the whole reason he did that is so that he could have free internet at home.
Right.
And basically, you know, he figured out if he had like, 12 or what was it, like,
12 or 15 customers,
uh, you know, he did the math and it's like he had like five or six dial in lines.
So seriously, like,
-- he was only double oversold which, you know, most I SPS are 10 to one.
-- Oh, man, it's,
yeah. II,
I worked at an ISP a long time ago and it was, it was bad. I, I remember that.
Well,
if you wanted to make money.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's, that's probably fair.
That was part of the beauty of it though.
Too is when you work for the ISP, there's always a couple of secret phone numbers,
you know, that, that nobody knows.
And you can still use to dial up when, when things get rough.
But, yeah. Yeah, I remember those days, man.
Yeah. Good times. Yeah.
So, yeah, this wild and, and what I really love too is that this, um, because lets,
and crypt does,
you know, they use the
ACME certificate protocol. Um
You can basically automate it and you,
you really will want to because I think their certificates are, I want to say 90 days,
I think it's 90 days.
I use one on my site
and
I, I've automated it so I don't remember, but
it's like I've automated it
right
now.
Now I will say though that it sounds like these wild
card certificates are certainly more work because for just one host,
you pretty much run a script on the host and,
and magic things happen and then you get a certificate
and that's
not
quite it.
-- Does,
-- it does
domain validation at the like web server level, right?
My understanding is right, because it basically talks to the web server gets
the little validation thing, right? And then you're done
and it's basically the same, they do validation at the root of the DNS.
So like, for example, for
creed.org,
uh I would run the client, it would connect to, lets encrypt gets a token, you know,
basically I say the less encrypt.
I want a wild card for secret.org.
They go, ok, here's your token, like your magic little value.
And I have to put that magic little value in a text file
-- in my DNS for secret.org.
-- A
-- text
-- record,
-- TX
-- T
A
TXT record, uh,
which is one of the most wonderfully overused and abused, uh,
DNS records because there's my SPF records and there's my, oh, all sorts of things.
And, um, yeah, and then basically on their end, they
do a DNS query for your text records, your TXT records.
And uh obviously, if the token appears then,
well, basically you control that domain to a point where it,
nothing else they can really do to validate.
It won't matter,
right? And, and it sounds like you will need a new token for every renewal.
So this will definitely need some,
-- some automation with your, your register,
-- every
single major DNS provider now has an API
I, I would hope so
-- well.
-- No, like Amazon wrote 53 Cloud Flare, you know,
um D DNS, right?
These guys have all had API S for, well, since the beginning, basically,
probably,
-- well, you have to,
-- if you have like 100 domains to manage,
I have four, which is,
I won't lie. It's very manual still.
I need, I think they expire soon. I need to
look in and check that.
Yeah.
Well, no, I mean, I remember handcrafting hosts or uh DN ss uh bind you know,
zone files.
Oh,
man, those were the days and I still can, sadly,
but by and large I've, you know, again outsourced all of that to just, you know,
cloud flare or Amazon or whoever because quite frankly, like,
I don't wanna run multiple servers
just to have DNS.
Ok.
Well, and I used to cheat too.
Uh, in the past,
what I realized what I could do is I can actually get
away with um setting www.c.org is one of my DNS servers.
And that way that record with that IP address would be in the
root zone file.
Look
at
you.
And actually that just came up with dot IO.
Somebody realized they could register dot IO
domain
is madness.
-- Well, it's, it's just sloppy coding, right? Like I don't
-- know if it's even coding.
It's, it's poor.
They need to blacklist
they, right. They, you.
So, so the story is, let's explain it first for anyone who doesn't know
is there's the, the dot iotld
and apparently there were a handful of root
DNS servers for dot IO
that were unregistered domains
and somebody registered them.
And of course, that is uh very bad
in, in many, many ways.
And it sounds like once he reported it, people, they,
they kind of crack down a bit on him.
But
it's, I mean,
fundamentally,
if you have root name servers,
like nobody should be able to register those domains
nor should they be unregistered in all seriousness.
Like they should
belong to somebody and if they don't pull them out,
do not
move,
it's
gonna cause performance issues. Right.
Because you're gonna have a lot of clients timing out.
Yeah, that too, because I mean, essentially if you have, you know,
a dozen root domain servers, uh, the,
the other domain servers just, they try one at random and if it's not there, yeah,
they're gonna, they're gonna try somewhere else.
But no, I've also encountered DNS providers where you could specify
your DNS server and in some cases you could specify the IP address
it was and they would like add that glue record and obviously,
then you could potentially hijack somebody else's domain,
you know. Um, so all sorts of shenanigans. Um,
but yeah, back to like the whole lets encrypt thing, I mean, uh yeah,
fundamentally this is not hard to automate.
And,
well, basically if you've outsourced your DNS in any way, shape or form
and your provider doesn't give you an API to put a blunt lead that
you need a new provider.
-- Yeah, I think that's
-- just,
well, not, you know,
I can't think of a single cloud or even any
online service I use now that does not have an API
API S are king man, right?
It's, it's what everybody does,
right? Like, uh what's that famous question? You know, how many,
you know, you can control like one computer from a Gooey.
But if you have like an API, or a scripting language you can control all of them.
Yeah.
Yeah. Sure. Why not?
So,
yeah. No, I, I, what really gets me though about the whole lu
and crypt thing is that we're still going to have ac,
a market because people will just not use it or
they'll be like, oh, let's encrypt. It's all
-- whatever made up reason we're not going to use it. Right.
-- I know.
There's, I'm sure there's going to be various reasons and there's,
there's always going to be those old statue people that do things
the way they do things because that's the way they do things.
And I, I don't know about compliance
because
I, I don't, I, I need to, I should,
I guess
what happen
with, with some of these cas is they get audited by a third party to verify
that their infrastructure they're using like HS MS
and they're storing keys properly and they've got,
you know, all pi I is dealt with in this certain way and
it is conceivable. Let's encrypt.
-- Can't pass some of those controls, which who cares? Uh,
-- looks like.
Wow, if you go to, uh, let's encrypt.org/repository, uh,
there's a whole bunch of stuff.
They,
they've got ISRG certificate,
practice statements like every, looks like quarterly.
Ok.
So that might be good enough.
Yeah.
And more to the point that's,
that's just,
it's a problem you can solve with a bit of money.
It's not insurmountable and
like the number of, well, because there's two CS being, you know, put to,
put to sleep basically.
You know, we sign and Startcom.
What is it?
They got 23 more months before Chrome boots them,
they should have been booted years ago.
And in fairness it's not ok.
So in fairness, Startcom was not always terrible,
but then the problem is they got bought by wo signed W sign.
Who?
Yeah, they've been, well,
they've been caught doing all sorts of shenanigans repeatedly.
Right. That's the part that is a problem. Right.
It's not just that they did one mistake once
they've been caught multiple times, you know, backdating certificate, dates,
issuing certificates for like the wrong people or
pretty obviously like malicious certificates for various, you know,
large web properties.
Um,
and then they
start,
you know, the trust has eroded.
That's a really good point is one of the beauties of having a 90 day expiration time
is that even if somebody say gets a google.com wild card out of a decrypt, which
we assume they can't,
but let's say it does happen.
It's only good for 90 days, which, I mean,
by the time you mount your attack and actually get things underway,
you're probably gonna burn at least 30 of those 90 days,
you know, just getting ready.
Whereas when you're getting some of these other certificates
from these registrars that are good for years.
That's crazy.
Well, and there is that new, uh, we talked about it a few episodes ago and I just,
the name is escaping me, but it's a DNS record type.
Uh, C A cert,
I think is the record type where you can basically specify in your DNS zone file. What
is,
you know, you're sort of willing to allow,
which
in theory is great.
But, well, the thing is all the certificate, authorities have to check for that
before they issue a certificate. And
well, and well, you could simply make that a requirement.
Like chrome could say, look, if you don't do that,
we're booting you out and you'd have compliance,
you'd have to,
right. And that's kind of one of the things I like about
chrome.
And one of the things I also fear a little bit is, you know,
Google can use Chrome as a compliance hammer.
They, they can, that's a good point and they are right.
And the same thing with their search results, right?
They're going to be ranking http S higher than HTP now,
which I'm also,
well, when you consider all the shenanigans going on with, you know,
state level actors
intercepting and modifying web traffic, you know,
um Fin Fisher, you know,
modifying Binaries on the fly to attack human rights activists.
And Lord knows what else.
You know, the reality is you can't do encrypted network traffic anymore.
No, absolutely not. And, and this is one of the things that really just it
Google is doing this
and
III I hear various reasons why people think they're doing it from everything from,
they don't want their ads modified in flight to just, they're great guys to,
you know, they're concerned about the data. It, maybe it is, maybe it isn't. I mean,
I guess at the end of the day this is going to be a good thing regardless of motives.
And so it's, it's probably one of those situations where, you know, maybe,
maybe the ends do justify the means, you know, who cares how we got here?
Well, for myself, it, it basically boils down to is I want a secure web browser,
right? I really need that.
And luckily for me, Google's
self interest, for example, in protecting their ad revenue
happens to align with my need for security.
So cool, you know,
I I don't,
in this case care so much why they're doing what they're doing.
I'm just very happy that we have that confluence of,
you know, needs and uh incentives,
you know. So I get my really great free secure web browser,
you know.
Um
Yeah, you know, I, I love the fact that they're driving http S,
you know,
that's a good thing because uh I, every time I browse the web on my phone, you know,
the ad experience.
Oh my God, it's freaking
man.
It's unbelievable
time. I use a web browser without an ad blocker. I, I just, I, how do people do that?
I cannot understand. I just, I cannot,
yeah, just the speed alone. Holy.
And just the load time is on the ads. All load.
You think,
if you're an ad provider you'd have a huge incentive to load the ads extremely fast.
Right.
Well, part of the problem is they have to go through a broker system to, like, line up,
you know.
Oh, it's Josh, looking at,
-- you know, pictures of kitty cats. So, we're going to advertise with a
-- puppy
wondering what was going to come out there, you know?
Yeah, I had to go to my rolodex of same things.
Kittens are safe.
-- Yeah, I forget. What is the rating on our show? Is it PG or just,
-- we
don't have
a rating.
We're not,
we're not, we're not marked explicit,
we're unrated. So
we'll keep it clean.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
you know, and that, well, that's, and that kind of, well,
actually that kind of leads to another good
story this week is the whole Kaspersky thing.
-- Oh, my
-- goodness. That's,
I don't even know what to think about this
because everything just keeps unraveling in bizarre new ways.
And, I mean, just,
-- well,
-- ok, so for those of you that somehow don't know
whatever future
civilization
listening to us as a way to determine what the,
-- apologize
-- to
them
anyway. So,
uh, Kaspersky Antivirus. Um,
well, two things were cropped up in the news recently.
Number one, the US government has gotten a little bit. Um,
how is it? Put
a senator asked a very pointed question that would tend to indicate
that they learned something in an intelligence briefing
that they're not actually allowed to talk about
openly.
And so kind of one of the ways to get around that is to ask a
pointed question that sort of like leads people down the path to like discovery of,
oh my God, you know, here's this horrible thing.
Um
And he basically asked an intelligence official, like,
would you allow Kaspersky products to be used on your network?
And the answer was like, no.
Um
Well, I guess the sort of second part of that was the whole US,
was it the FBI I think was uh basically went to a bunch of us employees for Kaspersky
uh to ask them questions about like,
how much direction do they get from the mothership and like, what are their,
you know, roles and responsibilities and whatnot?
And then the second big piece of news is sort of that. Well,
uh Kaspersky, you know, um works with the FSB, you know, the Russian, former K GB.
And um
the reality is ok.
Well, that, that's going to happen to some degree for all these providers because
Kaspersky doesn't just do a V, right?
They do also sort of security and threat intelligence.
Uh D do
s monitoring and mitigation.
Nobody just does A V anymore,
right? They all have this suite of
magical products
and I'm using air quotes if you can't tell.
Yeah.
And so, yeah, I mean, the reality is any,
you know, if, if you run that kind of threat,
intelligence service chances are you're either going to
be served with warrants for information or,
you know, they're going to be doing an investigation and they're gonna, you know,
want to work with you or vice versa.
You stumble onto something horrible
and you have a need for, you know,
the police to get involved or, well, whatever, you know, level of law enforcement.
But, you know, of course,
the way it's sort of coming out and the way it looks, it doesn't look that great
and, you know, there's just, there's a lot of mistrust right now, obviously.
And II, I have, I, I have no idea what the facts of the case are.
Um, it could be completely legit,
like they just work with these guys on those specific things
and it's not a case of like, you know,
Putin forcing them to put back doors in their
A V which are running on 400 million devices.
I have no
idea.
The way I look at this is
it is no secret
that the intelligence communities
pretty much around the world don't necessarily get along. Right. There's,
there are nods and handshakes with some groups and there
are other groups that pretend they like each other,
but fundamentally their job isn't to get along.
Right.
And
I would be very surprised
if the FSB has
Koperski putting in backdoors and things like that. However,
even if
Kaspersky isn't cooperating willfully,
they're in a jurisdiction that's going to
certain information will get to people who,
who want, it will say right
-- to the point their employees can be coerced
-- and
there's many ways. Exactly. There's, there's many ways.
And so, I mean,
fundamentally what I think what it comes down
to is if you're an intelligence organization,
regardless of where you are,
you should probably be sticking to security
type products that come from your home country
-- because,
-- or open source ones.
Well, yeah, that's fair. I mean,
you can inspect and understand and even, even if it's your home country,
there's nothing stopping other intelligence organizations from, you know,
going to your employees and saying, you know, here's 50 grand
Wink Wink, make this happen. It's,
-- it's,
I've kind of never really
having issued about, I think 6000 CV S now.
I, ok, backdoors definitely can be, you know, very, um, hard to find, you know,
and exploitable in a way that's, you know, even looks like normal network traffic.
Right. So that it really is hard to detect.
But the reality is, I mean, most of these products have,
like, they have security flaws.
Well, well,
they have security flaws or they have the equivalent of a back
door that's just like built into the thing as sort of,
you know, command and control or home phone,
-- home
-- and a V was pointed out as being particularly terrible for this for two reasons.
Number one, it has to touch all the files on your system
end of story. Otherwise it can't work, right?
And number two,
it gets updates constantly from whatever mothership,
including not just like uh data updates but actual.
Well, like as Tavis Ormandy pointed out, you know, you yeah,
these things stink for security and they need like lots of updates.
Um
you know, so new file types, new un packers, blah, blah, blah.
So like binary components as opposed to just like, you know,
if it was just some sort of, you know, data file format that could be, you know,
somewhat sort of safe if you have like a trusted binary.
But in this case,
you know, the binaries are like updating themselves all the time.
And uh yeah, so, I mean, if somebody, you know,
were to compromise an antivirus vendor or
coerce them,
uh yeah, I mean, they could, you know,
just literally add an update and be done with it.
I mean, well, and that's,
-- that's what
-- happened in the,
I don't think, yeah, we'll get to the Ukraine in just a second.
But I think more importantly is I don't think the threat
is necessarily backdoors and malicious updates directly to the organization.
Right? There's, there's ways to distribute backdoor applications,
but my suspicion is anytime an intelligence agency
has an interest in a certain product,
they just want data about customers
for, for their own reasons. And that is,
in many instances,
a lot of companies would probably just hand
that over thinking what's this gonna hurt.
Right.
Well, you legally would have to hand it over. In most cases.
It, it, you know,
you've gone,
well, even the US has, um,
uh, was it under the Patriot Act where they could basically serve notices that
you weren't allowed to talk about or even that you had been given one?
Right.
And so people started putting up those warrant canaries and blah, blah, blah.
-- And
-- even then I still don't know
many lawyers and other people, I've spoken with. It sounds like they,
as part of the Pfizer request, they can tell you keep updating the warrant canary.
Right?
-- And that
-- seems reasonable because honestly, as a judge, if, if I was a judge, I could,
an argument that's saying that, like, look,
we're going to serve this organization with a warrant and they're going to drop
their warrant canary and everybody's going to know we serve them with a warrant
and we can't have that happening because of these reasons or, you know,
we just can't tell you national security, whatever.
There's a valid argument to be made there in some cases right now,
whether or not it flies.
-- I have no idea.
-- I'm not going to touch that with a 10 ft pole.
Let's talk about the Ukraine.
Something
more exciting.
Yeah. Accounting software which, you know, everybody loves to hate,
-- um, I guess, except for accountants who just generally hate
-- it, but more,
more bizarrely is it sounds like what 80% of businesses
in the Ukraine use the same piece of software.
That makes sense because,
have you ever read the tax code?
-- Unfortunately,
-- my accountant once showed me,
my accountant once showed me the abridged yearly update of the Canadian tax code
-- and it was like a phone book.
-- It's, it's enormous
how
many things are
-- about
-- the size of a novel.
And that was the abridged kind of important changes. And
that's the thing with tax software, right?
Like nobody's ever going to make open
source tax software because nobody is ever going
to figure out all those business and tax rules and put them into a computer.
-- So
-- actually I had something interesting, I, I learned a long time ago is,
I guess in the U si, don't know if this is true everywhere,
but the IRS apparently has like a, a standardized data format
that they send to the accounting software companies.
And I don't, I don't know if it's free or you have to buy it from them. But,
but essentially they found a way to, like, programmatically
explain what the changes are in the tax code.
And then obviously
that makes
-- sense
-- because you'd have way less errors because probably,
I mean, part of it is, right? Is
there's always that, you know, well,
it's like generally accepted accounting principles
there's a lot of wiggle room
and like, you know, all of the companies that do Gap,
they're not generally doing anything even remotely illegal, but holy cow,
some of the wiggle room in there,
you know what some of these companies do is like, wow, you know,
I did not know you deduct pandas,
like, like, you know,
thing you do is right. The lunchroom is R and D, you know.
No, I'm familiar with these.
So, I mean,
but
fundamentally with software, like,
I'm not surprised at all in some countries that there's
only one or two software providers for this stuff because
there's really that,
I mean, to, to maintain this software, you know, it's, it's an,
I can't even imagine because there's, you know, yearly updates at a minimum or,
you know, whenever they pass a new law
that can affect the tax code
or the way taxes are held or,
you know, uh, wages, right?
Because the thing to remember too is accounting software is not just about taxes.
Typically this stuff is also doing your payroll,
your accounts receivable.
You think the Ukraine is not a giant market,
right? It's, it's not like the US where it, it's
huge. Right.
Yeah.
So there probably just isn't room for more than one company to be making the, like,
official tech software of the Ukraine.
Yeah.
Yeah. Well, and like, yeah, in general it doesn't really translate to
any other country because of course,
the tax code is going to be completely different.
Um, but yeah, so basically they me doc, the, the accounting
software firm got popped
and, you know, sent out a malicious update and apparently their whole
coding infrastructure and signing infrastructure was just in shambles.
And so, yeah, I mean,
when you think about it, right.
Uh, it reminds me of, um, did you ever hear about those Bloomberg terminals?
I do know about the Bloomberg terminals, which is actually how Bloomberg,
the company makes most of their money.
Yeah.
Well, how about you explain it then?
Ok.
So, uh,
the Bloomberg organization which obviously is involved in Wall
Street and there's what they have a TV station,
I think, and there's a magazine and,
and I think they do some investing.
II, I don't know exactly. Anyway, but the real thing they do is
if you are involved in Wall Street,
you get these terminals that kind of connect you to the
various brokerage houses and various information about what's going on.
And, yeah, they're just these, these wacky little boxes that you,
you pay and we say a lot of money for
and, and then you get the right to kind of use them for,
for various financial transactions and,
and news
and it's, it's like a huge deal, right?
If you do not have one of these, it either means you're small or dumb
-- and that's kind of the way you
-- basically don't get to play
playing fields. Everybody else.
-- So, good
-- luck. Right. Right. So, what about the Bloomberg terminals though?
What is your story?
Well, so basically the, somebody was pointing out that these things, you know,
they're plunked right into the center of every financial network on the planet.
Right. You can't,
you can't like firewall them up, you can't
restrict access to them
and they have this like connection back to the mothership,
you know, to get the data and what not?
Well, isn't that what happened to swift way back in the day?
Is there was a bank using like a netgear router or something?
It was, oh, no worse than that. It was the, it's even better.
They were buying second hand it, equipment. Oh, yes,
I would.
And
so,
yeah,
I think it was Netgear and some of
their printers got popped or were already infected.
Maybe I'm not, I don't remember entirely.
But, yeah, I guess the moral of the story is
regardless of if you buy first hand or second hand equipment,
but especially if you buy second hand equipment,
you really got to wipe that stuff before you use it.
No, don't buy second hand equipment
-- if you're comfortable saying that just kind of in general if, even if you're,
-- well,
I think the problem is people forget like, printers are not printers anymore.
-- Printers are computers with like a printer attached to them.
-- Right.
Don't, don't sell your gear and don't buy someone else's gear. I mean, for real.
Yeah.
I mean, if you're going to buy first hand,
you have a better chance of getting legitimate
stuff that doesn't have like wacky viruses or
we're talking about the Ukraine. So what happened with this account?
So, Me Doc, they were the, they were the spread of the PEO
virus
or not Petya
or whatever that's called,
called
ransomware,
whatever the ransomware thing that,
that's not ransomware.
You know, it was, it
between the me doc and what Petya did.
It really is beginning to look like, you know,
a nation state level attack on the Ukraine
probably.
And, and you know what I love though
is
there are tons of people who are talking about these,
this company didn't sign their software and they weren't distributed correctly.
We were
doing this and they weren't doing that and
it probably wouldn't have mattered. I, I won't disagree.
But then, you know, what really got me thinking is,
so let's say I'm a small company and I'm running
accounting software.
Where am I going to even go
to get advice about how to sign and distribute my software?
Um Microsoft actually has really good documentation on that
seriously because I was looking, I actually had that exact question.
I'm like, you know, I, I know
I know how uh R PM signing works because
I've had to do it uh
the pain, but it's not fun.
It works, but it's not fun getting it.
It's one of those classic clinic things where you get it set up and then, like,
don't touch it
because it will break horribly.
Um,
I'm
going with this though. Ok.
So Microsoft having good docs kind of ruins my story a little.
-- That's ok. That's
-- ok.
But
you have to know those docs are there and you have
more than that, you have to read them and then do it correctly.
But here's the thing is if you're working with an app store
solves these problems for you. Right.
Well, it depends where the signing happens because fundamentally
here's the thing signing doesn't really matter if you can just
like take over a workstation of a programmer and inject some code in there
and they have insufficient code reviews or
there's OK.
So a great example,
remember we had the core infrastructure guy on talking about
security and the best practices and that sort of whole,
you know, they've got that whole nice document with the maturity model.
David A Wheeler. Yeah. And
so what was the like, I think it was the first thing there was uses source control
because a lot of people still don't.
And I don't mean like,
I'm not talking like use a CV S or some like terrible source control.
We're talking like
no source control. Like there's a folder
shared over Samba or whatever. You know,
I I've actually seen that like where a place had a white board
to kind of control access or
essentially the white board was the locking mechanism
for the shared folder on the server.
Uh They went out of business about a year later. So, not super surprising.
Yeah, I'm, I'm shocked,
you know,
source control is tricky and I mean, it's not like there's a ton of free
services out there,
github. I'm
OK. Ok. I'm gonna say I'm like, it's so cheap at this point.
It's
what else actually comes up a fair bit is
hiding your source code I don't think is nearly
as exciting or interesting as people think it is
because, I mean, let's face it. No one's really going to steal your stuff.
If they did, they probably still can't build it anyway because, you know,
you build infrastructure is a disaster.
Yeah.
The one thing I've seen where people do consistently sort of
need to have their source code secret is all the DEV
-- ops people because they put all their tokens and passwords in there
-- that is wrong.
If they're doing that, there are
-- ways
-- to destroy
secrets
and, and if that's your excuse, that's, that's almost acceptable.
But yeah, whatever. I mean,
here's, here's my point though, back during a developer's workstation
is
it, it's not undoable, but it's difficult.
But if you look at the vast majority of attacks up to this point,
-- it has been during the distribution cycle against a lot of software because,
-- well,
because most of them have such a poor security,
-- right?
-- It's, it's not signed or there's mirrors. I mean, I remember,
oh, I forget,
I don't remember what the last last project was that this happened to. But
they, they basically go after mirrors and replace, you know, like the tar ball
-- and
-- hand on
that.
-- Right.
-- They just
like, yeah, if people check the check some, it wouldn't know,
checked out but nobody checks it.
So,
you know.
Well, it's like every time I get a doc file from somebody,
I run it through virus total.
And what really shocks me is when I get like a doc file from like, um
for example, on the CV side of things, you know, miter
sends out doc files
and you know,
I won't get around to reading them for three or four days and then
I'll run it through virus total and I'm the first one to do it.
And that just horrifies me that, you know,
these people are opening up doc files and trusting the local antivirus
because, you know, this is like a mailing list you could, I mean, this isn't like
these are just doc files flying around, you know,
with Lord knows what in them because
you know, it's not like we use some super secure transport mechanism or anything,
right?
And
every time somebody mails me a PDF, right?
And I have to open it, you know, I grit my teeth,
run it through virus total and then open it in like Google docs.
No, man, I get it, uh,
Google docs is where all word files or presentations
or PDF S are literally anything I get go
because
I love it. It's their problem. I don't have to think about it.
It's like, got a virus, don't care. Google can deal with it. And
it, it, it's amazing. And
part of me wonders what kind of garbage they must see on a daily basis and I think
they bought
virus total. Remember they do own virus total. And it got to be just horrifying.
What, what goes through their systems on a daily basis. I mean, not even on purpose.
-- Right. Just people
-- doing
another argument I have against antivirus, which is
antivirus will definitely catch the older stuff and help you maybe with clean up,
but it won't
protect you from a targeted or other sort of zero
day attack until you have a signature for it.
And if it's a targeted attack you, you're not going to get a signature for it.
And if it's,
you know, if you're close to patient zero,
I hope those signatures come out in a few minutes or hours because
that's how long these viruses take to spread now,
you know? But here's the thing, even the old viruses, like,
no, it doesn't count.
I
mean, like two or three
days
old. And, well, yeah, and the detection rates for a lot of this stuff were like,
I
just, I remember some of them, I think it was like, 50% or 60.
It's like 20 or 30% I think.
Cases. And
you have to think at that point
you're probably wasting more money on this software and the lost
-- resources.
-- Just think of the electricity and CPU cycles.
I hate to see. That's why I got rid of antivirus on my laptop.
It just, I got back about a half hour battery life,
at least. Maybe more.
Yeah, it's,
yeah. II, I don't like antivirus. I'm, I'm not gonna even pretend,
I,
-- I think
-- antivirus makes sense on file and email servers
but on end points it's kind of too late.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Anyway,
whatever Google Docs saves a day.
What were you talking about?
Ukraine?
Well, yeah.
So, yeah, I mean, fundamentally these, you know, well,
you talked about the App Store and that definitely will, you know,
once it gets into the App store
it's highly, you know, I really, um,
how do I phrase this correctly?
A
proper app store that does something like say Google or Apple
is probably very, very safe, you know,
I assume they're using HS MS hardware security modules and all that.
Jazz.
The, the my understanding is though in the Google Android app ecosystem,
-- there are those like not Google app stores,
-- man, Amazon has one of those.
It, it drives me crazy. It's, it's, yeah, don't, don't use alternative app stores.
They're just a bad idea.
Well,
sometimes you have to because my understanding is some of the phone manufacturers,
you know,
set it up so that you have to use their app store because they want
to monetize that stuff and get their cut of the money and all that.
And I don't know of any phones
on
that, but if they are,
that's a bad phone manufacturer and please don't buy their phones.
It's, it's just a bad idea. This is where I know Apple gets a lot of guff
because they have their, their devices so locked down. But you know what? It's,
I think it's the right thing to do and, and I used to not think that, but I totally do.
-- You
-- know,
honestly,
for non it people,
what else can we do
that? Like my,
like my six year old kids, what, what are, you know, you're gonna tell my,
you're gonna teach my six year old kids to, like,
choose the app store safely and somehow,
you know,
you can't teach a six year old to
safe
in this man
I
use,
you know.
Yeah, my kids are starting to try to, like,
find their own Minecraft mods and things on their own.
And I'm just thinking this is,
there's no end of this story that doesn't involve their computer getting a virus.
Like, that's just the way it's going to be.
And I know it is and I'm going to harp on them and I'm going to do everything.
But at the end of the day, like
that's just what's going to happen
and there's nothing I can do about it.
How do I,
uh because, yeah, my one son wants to play Minecraft with MODS on a PC.
So I'm thinking a virtual machine.
But then graphics performance and in general, like,
-- or do I just image the drive and wipe
-- it?
Suck it up and get the computer?
-- That's what you're
-- going to
-- do.
-- Well, yeah. But no, but I'll have to re
like, I'm,
-- I'm just going to reimage it. Maybe
-- you're gonna
have
to
every
now
and then
it,
that's all you can do
because just, I haven't used windows in so long and I bought those windows,
10 tablets.
Oh, lordy. I just, the,
the upgrades,
-- they're so painful and
-- slow,
-- but at least they get upgrades.
-- Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Well, to be blunt, that's why I will never buy an android device because again,
in Canada, you know, I can't get an unlocked,
proper android device
there is, you know, and so I just, I'll get, like, if I'm lucky, like, six months
a year of updates and then oops, like, too bad.
I know. And most people don't care.
You know,
here's the thing though too is there's all these unpatched android devices but
nothing's really on fire,
which I suspect has more to do with the App Store ecosystem than anything.
I suspect part of it is they don't,
most of them don't have enough upstream bandwidth to do.
Anything? Terribly terrible.
Well, not only that, the vast majority of people I know who use devices,
they aren't like browsing the web.
They're running crappy apps and,
and generally speaking in that environment it's a
lot harder to attack that system because,
you know, crappy apps aren't going to random websites in many instances.
So,
yeah.
Well, actually that's something Apple's locking down is, is apps that are self
modifying. Like they have their own, built an update mechanism.
Uh, they're, they're booting that, which I totally,
totally love because my kids wanted this one app
and it's a Russian cartoon character called Booba.
Remember the one you thought was Nightmare
Fuel is
Nightmare.
Anyways, the app is like,
it starts and it's like downloading 80 megabytes from some server in Russia.
And I'm like, you know,
please wait while we configure your accounting software.
Yeah.
So, I mean, I, again, you know,
with Apple totally locking down and owning the ecosystem
on the one hand as an open source guy,
I absolutely abhor and object to it.
But on the flip side, what else am I going to do with my six year olds?
I, I totally get it.
And this is the, yeah, the,
the open source zealot in me is walking a fine line today and,
and I don't know where it all ends
because
I love that aspect of freedom.
But like, I want freedom for me.
I don't want it for my Children who
are going to download viruses under their computer.
Right.
Give them a walled garden. Don't let them touch things.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, that's,
there's a reason we put fences around playgrounds when they're by a busy road,
kids are idiots.
It will be glorious when there are self driving cars
and,
and they just don't run over the Children
anymore.
But maybe the kangaroos
kangaroos.
Yeah. Apparently Volvos don't know what to do with kangaroos.
The self driving Volvos. They're ok with like moose and deer and stuff.
But apparently kangaroos just confuse the, well,
think about it from a, from a,
it's like that. Well, ok. And,
uh,
what was it, those cameras that have the face detection
and they didn't work on
dark skinned people
because I guess in Asia, like when, yeah, when you test them it's,
or?
Yeah. Well, yeah, China, basically
because we also, you're going to go get electronics from anymore.
Um,
yeah, I, oh, man, what did I find the other day?
It was something electronic and it was old
enough that it was actually made in Canada.
I
-- was really old. It's amazing.
-- I forget what it was
something we were throwing out,
right?
E cycle. That stuff.
We, you and I live in northern
regions of the world
and obviously we get snow in the winter, which, which is terrible.
But, uh, Ford
is in Michigan, which is also northern, right?
And I, I remember I was reading some things and said a lot of these self driving cars,
they were
as soon as they got to kind of the north where, where we are
and it was winter time.
They started flipping out because they, you know,
like all of the testing was happening in
southern California where they don't get snow.
They, they don't like, apparently the,
there's that, well, not only that, I don't know,
do they spray the salt down on the road before it snows where you live?
Right? Or
you get
like white lines, if the road is dry, right?
Because they spray the salt and now you have like six white lines down the road.
Oh, they don't generally prep,
they, the strategy here generally is when it starts snowing,
then they start a little bit of salting and sanding.
So you get what we call oatmeal, right?
It's where the snow is kind of that mushy brown. It's kind of
smooshed up with the salt and it's a bit more liquidy and it's got the sand in it.
So you actually get somewhat decent traction.
The downside being, of course, if it like freezes to the road, you are of the creek.
Well, but the point is around here now
they spray this stuff on the road.
You end up with all these basically white lines
and, and the self driving car is like,
flipped out because they're like six white lines.
What do I do? You know?
-- And it's
-- just really get over to the right,
-- I pulled over, I can't pull over
-- anymore.
Well, I mean, at least on the plus side, I believe many of these self driving cars,
at least
just don't they, they pull over when something crazy happens.
-- But
-- here's something to remember. Right.
The thing with the self driving cars and software is
they're going to encounter problems
and they're going to fix them
and they will generally stay fixed.
Today. I was driving, I was in the left hand lane.
There was a left hand turn lane and another like a right hand lane.
So essentially two lanes going straight and one lane for the left turners.
This lady in a huge SUV was in the right hand lane,
uh, as it turns out, she was on her phone,
I guess getting directions because she was in the right hand lane at a
red light started signaling to turn left
and then started pulling into the intersection,
right
and then there was another car, uh, different light. About five minutes later, a
car from out of province, uh, the advanced green, uh, left turn light came on.
Uh, so basically you have a red light to go straight because
both of the oncoming things are getting an advanced left turn,
you know, so they can basically clear out the left turn lanes. Awesome.
Uh, and I guess he kind of thought that flashing green arrow meant go.
Um,
so he got halfway into the intersection before everybody started honking at him.
And luckily the oncoming traffic was, like, smart enough to be like, oh,
-- there's a car coming through but, like,
-- he
probably should turn
left.
He stopped and then he actually kind of backed up a bit.
Um,
-- yeah,
-- but I mean,
yeah, it's just,
if a self driving car does that, it will make the news
and they will fix it.
Yes. Right. That's the reality.
That's the difference between self driving cars and people,
you know, Volvo. Oh, they don't know how to deal with kangaroos personally.
I'm ok with that. I live in Canada.
If you ever end up having to deal with the kangaroo while driving,
go buy a lottery ticket.
Where did, where did that happen?
It was Austria. I think so.
Like the joke in Austria, because Austria and Australia are sort of similar looking
the
same. And so the joke in Austria is there are no kangaroos in Austria.
Right.
Because, well, it's a western northern European country
and, uh, actually it turns out a kangaroo got loose once from the zoo.
And so there was a kangaroo in Austria and of course,
it was huge news as you can imagine as a kangaroo in Austria would be.
But it's uh however, but so this is a really good point actually. And this is,
this is probably a good topic for us to dwell on for a minute and,
and end it because it's, it's
a great one but it's,
they're always going to be one of weird anomalies that happen in any environment.
Right?
Be it self driving cars, be it your, your local infrastructure,
be it the software you're developing.
We're like, you know, you've got that, that, that case statement with the, you know,
if you ever reach here something terrible has happened, it's like, yeah,
someday you're gonna get there.
Right. It happens. It always
happens.
-- You
-- have an exception handler
and, and just like in
software,
right?
Everything went horribly wrong and somehow your network stack disappeared,
And, and that's the thing is you have to, I I'm not saying you have to necessarily
gracefully handle those situations,
but I think you need to be prepared for them
and, and it's kind of one of those,
this is a good question because what is a safe, fail safe?
Right? Because for
-- example, like the
-- situation, right.
Exactly.
You know, and, and what actually really got me as a good argument for A I was
uh there's a really good TED talk on this that we add in the show notes.
But essentially they were talking about with A I like, how do you make the A A I
sort of behave safely and rationally but not like too much.
Because for example, in a self driving car, you probably want to be able to say like,
stop, I need to get out.
But do you want your like six year old to be able to do that on the highway.
Right.
So, you know, like the, the,
the self driving car maybe needs to take into
account things like who's giving me the order,
kind of what's the context of this, you know, much like a human would.
And,
um, anyway,
the TED talk was talking about how the one of the solutions they were kind of
working on and had found to this was to make the A I uncertain of the problem
so that it kind of had to take a more fuzzy approach,
kind of like, well humans.
Um and that they'd actually had some really good success with this. And so
again,
you know,
people are going to publish papers on this, this, you know,
there's going to be questions on what self-driving
dot stack overflow.com or whatever the site is,
you know, like, oh,
I'm working on a self driving car, but I'm having a lot of trouble with those like,
you know, those random airline crashes or whatever bizarre media rights, you know,
like, uh any recommendations, you know,
and there'll be an answer
that's horrifying to me to think that there, there's going to be self-driving
forums where people
-- help each other out
-- and
everybody
thinks, oh, those software programs,
-- they're professionals and they don't cut and paste
-- code.
Everybody cut and paste code doesn't matter who you are, everybody does it,
everybody doesn't, I'm not gonna even pretend and, and I even
man, I just, I did it this weekend.
I was, I was working on something I was trying to,
I was trying to prove that a certain thing could be done, right?
And this is vaguely work related
and I didn't know anything about what I was doing.
And
yeah, I like I hit a point where I needed PHP to print out the headers that,
that it had received from the browser.
You know what I did?
I just went to snack over phone and type in PHP
print headers and I literally copy and pasted the first answer.
I found,
I
didn't even look at it. I thought this, this is fine.
It's like knowing the capital of
most countries now. I Wikipedia.
Right. What's the, here's the question, what's the population of the Ukraine?
I didn't know I looked it up. It's like, what, 43 million or something?
Is it that I wouldn't have put it that high?
It's a reasonably dense European country,
I think for certain things, depending on what you do for a living.
It's, it's good to have sort of some general knowledge.
But yeah, like a lot of these specifics.
Yeah, I,
I actively try not to remember certain things now because I know how to look them up.
-- So why would I try to shove that into my brain?
-- I have to try,
I don't have to try anymore.
I just don't.
Oh man. Anyway, anyway, we were talking about,
er, states
and problems and, and this is,
this is one of the places, hopefully a I can get it right.
Because if you look at the vast majority of security issues,
it's basically mishandled errors.
Right.
And, and more often than not,
-- that is what happened
-- or it was uncertainty in what we sort of meant,
you know, like a lot of encryption stuff, a lot of the flaws boil down to.
Oh, well, now that we've actually built and deployed this and used it and poked at it.
Now we've learned Xy and Z,
you know, things like Poodle or Ghost where it's like, oh, there's these clever
ish attacks, you know, like
uh protocol downgrade, like, oh, you know, we want
two devices
to somehow find a compatible protocol to talk.
Right. That's a good thing.
Well,
it turns out that's actually a really tricky
-- problem to get right from a security
-- perspective
idea.
And I, I hate saying that but it, it, I
tend to agree
with stakes.
I, yeah, I think we're too kind to old software.
We, it's hopefully getting better.
But again, this is, this is one of those places that I'm hopeful that that kind of,
some of the A I type things will,
will be able to deal with this whereas static software cannot.
Yeah. No, I mean, it's,
yeah, I suspect in 2030 years
software that is not to some degree self
modifying or self improving or better yet working as a collective. Like,
you know,
this web server over here saw this weird condition and figured out how to deal
with it and then it kind of shared that with the rest of the ecosystem.
Yeah, I suspect that's, well, it's like the open source world. Right?
To me it's weird that all these poor close source guys have to, like,
re invent the wheel in house all the time.
Uh, nobody does it anymore because everybody just uses open source now.
I mean,
it's
open source one. You're using it
whether you know it or not.
Uh, actually Black Duck, we should, we should go over that. Maybe, maybe next time.
Uh,
they just put a report out this week talking about
just some of their findings on open source software use and
it's basically what you'd expect. Everyone's using it.
No one's updating it and, and everything's terrible.
Which,
ok.
Well, I like this.
I mean, software updating is, you know, that's never, uh, yeah,
that's a problem that's never going to go away.
It's just an economic issue. Right? People also don't update their hardware, their
everything, right? Why spend money on stuff that's not broken.
Yes.
Why,
why spend money on stuff that's not broken because we need jobs card. That's why
I think we'll have jobs regardless.
Oh,
I know. I know.
It's,
it's time.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you. Everybody for listening.
It's been an enlightening and interesting conversation as always.
If you want any of the show notes for the handful of stories we talked about,
you can go to open source at here, podcast.com.
We have links to Twitter and Facebook. You can use the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
Let us know what you think. Get a hold of us.
And yeah, if, if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
You as well stay safe, everybody.