Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Standing.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- That's the worst one ever.
Yes, Kurt and I are both standing. I always stand when we record and Kurt
made his desk go up. So now he's standing and he's all proud of himself so well done.
Kurt claps to you.
Well, it's annoying because I've always enjoyed like walking and eating,
walking and
thinking, walking and talking.
And the other day I was watching TV, while standing and I'm like,
this is better than sitting
and I have,
and I've had a sit stand desk forever.
Like I have, I have one of the original geek desks that
was rated for 350 pounds. Like my kids used to try and ride it up and down.
So I'm, I'm just, yeah, I need to, I need to do more things. Standing.
That's fair.
And they keep saying that sitting is going to
be like the next health epidemic of our generation.
-- So we'll see
-- actually the,
the thing that's actually being pushed heavily this week in Canada
is warning labels on alcohol that alcohol probably causes cancer.
Ok.
Except that, that amuses me because alcohol causes cancer,
but wine is good for you and I don't know what to do.
Well, I also suspect that alcohol
generally is worse than just cancer and we already knew that.
-- Probably
-- like drunk driving.
Yeah. Yeah. There's a lot of negative consequences for sure.
-- Humans, man, I don't know. I,
-- I can't, I'm not giving up processed meats or alcohol,
so I guess I better start standing more.
There you go. That sounds like the right solution.
Love me. My bacon and ham.
Yeah. Get the, uh, the treadmill like
Liis has. So you can do zombie shuffle while he programs,
uh, you know, I've done that
in the past. I haven't in a while.
I got a new treadmill and it's a little more inconvenient.
I, I had like a,
a thing I built that sat on top of my old treadmill and I
put my computer on it and I would walk while I did stuff.
I mean, it was fine. I can't complain.
It, it just then I got a new treadmill and I, I'm kind of lazy and I,
I ride my bike every morning so I don't concern myself with it that much.
I did that when I wasn't regularly exercising.
But, yeah, I mean, it's fine anyway, we have a topic today.
-- Well,
-- that leads us, I mean, this is getting old.
Ashley is literally leads us into the show today,
which is the Noda outage and in a completely related thing, a IX is not dead.
It's just we fired all the devs in North
America and moved development work to a foreign country.
Why do you keep saying this?
You've been pushing me for like four days that we should do a show about
a IX is not dead and I don't even know what you're talking about.
Is there a new, did something happen?
Yeah. So last week IBM basically announced that all the development work for A IX
has been offshored to India.
So like all, you know, all those old people that have been working on A X for decades.
Yeah, they don't work on A AX anymore. It's a bunch of new people in India.
OK. I found, I found a new story here.
Uh
-- This does not surprise me in any way. Well,
-- it's on life support.
Look, it, it's literally like the NOT
M system is on life support. Like there's no future for a IX. Like
I, I posted that video. Uh I, I didn't realize that. I remember the uh the IBM Linux,
those weird Linux commercials. They had, they were 20 years ago.
-- I loved those. Those were so good
-- 20 years ago in 2003. I,
I, so I worked for a Linux start up called Progeny Linux Systems at the time
and
Linux was like unheard of right? It was, you were a crazy person if you were like
basing your career off Linux
in those days and we were like, so excited for those commercials. It was amazing.
And that was in the middle of the skull
-- lawsuit as well, wasn't it?
-- Well, the school lawsuit was like a half decade of, of f
and you know, shenanigans,
it lasted forever. Right. And,
and that was funny too because
so a fun fact that I, I don't,
I don't think I've ever told this story in public before is when I was at Progeny,
they brought on Ransom Love as an advisor and
ransom Love was the what he was involved with sco
in some way as part of that lawsuit.
And we went out for lunch one day and we like grilled him
and he was super honest about it and he was basically like,
yeah, Microsoft told us we had to do this and so we're doing it and, and like he,
he exited
that universe by this time. So he wasn't directly involved.
Well,
-- he was one of the founders but
-- he like totally
threw Microsoft under the bus and it was like,
wow, this is amazing.
-- But
-- anyway, that was literally the decade of throwing Microsoft under the bus.
Well, that's true. And it was everyone knew it.
I mean, everyone knew it, but it was never like officially announced
the Halloween memos where Microsoft is literally, you know,
calling Linux a cancer and saying we have to stomp it out.
Yeah, but they didn't say like, yes,
-- we're going to have a third party file a lawsuit against IB
-- M.
Well, it was pretty obvious
anyway, that's not our topic today. Ok. So, whatever a IX.
So a fun fact also I was in a Ixs
Edmund as my first job out of college.
And I would have confidently said a IX was on
life support back then because it was difficult to use.
It was not well supported. They were not doing a lot of releases.
It was clearly not the growing part of IBM at that time.
Well, and I think the thing to remember is
in the nineties and early aughts, Linux
-- and the B sds were not yet a contender.
-- Well, and, and fun fact when I was in a Ixs
edin,
I would of course suggest we deploy Linux to solve whatever problem we were
going to pay an insane amount of money for a AX systems to solve.
And of course, I was always told like, you're a crazy person. No.
And
yeah, how'd that work out?
Yeah.
Well, but I'm just reminded of like,
because one of the questions I've been asked a few times is like, why?
It's kind of like the car industry. There were how many unixes back in the day? Like
you had
skull, you had
a Ixh pox digi
UNIX.
Actually, I found, I found a video the other day,
I will try to dig this up and see if I can find it again.
I'll put it in the show
but
Apple had a UNIX you can run on the Macintosh
back in like the late like 89 or 88 or so, which I never even heard of
a U
X.
-- Was it
-- a
-- Yeah. Yeah, that's
-- it.
It was literally
like everything was something slash UX or IX.
And there's another video I found I'll try to dig this one up too
that
this person tried to use the Windows. NT Posi
like compatibility layer to like compile and run a program.
And the video is hilarious because it is clear
that
the posi
layer in windows existed only for compliance and only
to pass whatever test nist made them run well.
What else would you have written it to do other than to test to the test?
Well, that obviously it wasn't for compatibility.
-- I
-- mean, what's interesting too is like if you look at it, this is going off the rails,
but NT four had the hardware abstraction layer, remember how
so NT four actually ran on top of Intel and
on top of alpha,
the alpha,
right? And, and the idea was to make it agnostic
and you basically have this hal
this hardware abstraction layer
with running on top of
literally anything that you could plug into a wall with windows running on top of it.
And of course,
it just
that kind of generalization is very expensive and complicated and you know,
just let's go to X 86 and be done with it.
Just like how X 8664 be O Titanium?
Because it's like your choices are write this thing
slightly differently or write this thing completely differently.
And of course, every vendor on the planet's like
I want the first one.
Of course. Exactly. Exactly. That and, and so funny enough you bring up I
Itanic in the progeny days,
we were paid by Hewlett Packard to Port
Debian to the Titanium.
And we had like a room full, we probably had millions of dollars of Titanium gear,
just like sitting in a closet in the back.
And it was, I mean, it was powered on. They were gigantic
and it was, it was hilarious.
I'm sorry. The title of this one article, Linux helps bring Titanic to life
anyway.
And
half
of our listeners probably don't even know what
Titanium is and they're Googling it right now.
Just
-- don't, you know what? It's not, it, it was, it
-- was a dead end
Intel tried to make an alternative chip that in theory was vastly superior.
-- You
-- know what they tried to do.
They tried to out engineer, son.
-- I mean, probably
-- that's no, when you look at Itanic, it was,
they were trying to go up against like the Sun Enterprise
10-K style of thing.
Yeah, probably. And it was a really cool chip, like, don't get me wrong, but it was
like you couldn't get anything to work right on it because it
-- was just so complicated and
-- the performance gains were just not.
-- Well,
-- that's because we couldn't get any software to run on it correctly.
You had to write like special software that
did like weird asynchronous stuff and it's not,
the solution was just threads and cores and whatever, everything's fine.
-- But
-- see, that's the thing with these, with these older systems.
Like, again, iii I now firmly believe that I have a theory of like it adoption where
if a system is
essentially more than a few years old, it becomes legacy like and I mean,
even Windows like windows is very actively supported
but
you know,
like Windows XP at some point gets kind of put
on life support by Microsoft and then killed off.
And I think,
I think a decent rule of thumb is any it
system more than five years old is basically legacy.
-- Sure,
-- sure, I won't disagree with that.
But what's interesting is by definition, it's also super needed.
If you could just get rid of it,
you would if you could just easily upgrade it
or outsource it to a cloud service like email.
Oh man, email. You know what?
Oh, there's like a million kajillions email providers now. Super simple.
Cobalt, Cobalt is my favorite example.
How much I mean, I I have no doubt that if, if Cobalt disappeared today,
society would crumble.
Oh yeah.
No, all literally every well not every, like,
probably 50% of all of your government support payment checks would.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I'm sure there's loads of banks with it and stuff.
So I want to tie this into the thing I actually wanted to talk about today,
which is the, no, T A outage, which no,
T A for anyone who doesn't know we'll kind of give a little background.
There's this system, the FAA in America,
the Federal Aviation Administration has called notice to air mission system.
Is that what it stands for? Notice to air mission?
So,
so basically what happens?
And this is all, what I, you probably understand this better than I do, but I,
I'm gonna talk about it because I can
is there's a system that basically helps airplanes not like run into
each other and stay out of places they shouldn't be in,
in North America,
the
Super
Bowl,
like every Super Bowl, there's a no time air restriction
or, or my favorite is the President's airplane.
If another airplane goes near the president's airplane, it's going to be shot down,
right?
100%.
Well,
and I've actually experienced that because I was flying out of
North Carolina just made it before they shut down the,
the, the entrance to the airport because Air Force one was landing
and then we were actually the first flight out after he landed and it,
we had to wait like a solid half hour on the
tarmac and the and the pilots just like this thing landed,
we don't get to move.
Yep.
That's it. That's my announcement.
I mean, I, I was in Boston,
we just landed and we're sitting there and the pilot's like, oh,
if you look out the left window you'll see air force one landing,
which is why we can't move.
If we do move, they're going to shoot us. So we're just going to sit here for a while.
It's like, ok, that's neat.
Anyway,
so this system, this, this no damn system.
-- Well,
-- this is one of the reasons air travel is actually very safe.
Well, right, right, about a week ago, from the time we're chatting,
this system had an outage
and it,
they, so this is funny because they,
a lot of news stories they were coming out of Europe said the planes were grounded,
which in Europe grounded means can't take off.
And the US grounded means like you're landing all of the airplanes right now.
And that happened
on September 11th in 2001
when there were the attacks on the World Trade Center.
So we literally like every airport in North American
airspace was told to get on the ground now.
Right. And that's what we call grounded.
So we're, we wake up, we're like grounded, what's going on? This is wild.
And so it was just, they couldn't take off, right, which was still made a mess. But
anyway,
there is an outage. No airplanes could take off. It created chaos for a day. And then
there's a bunch of what's going on,
what just happened and it turns out there was a bad update
and a corrupt file on a computer and then everyone says, oh, you know,
this is ridiculous.
And they're, they're talking about, do you hear one person did it?
I'm like, no, one person didn't do it,
literally decades of mismanagement and poor planning did this.
Like,
if you can,
if you have one corrupt file on one computer and
it takes down all of aviation in your country,
the problem isn't one computer or a person, it is structural.
This is like when you hear people be like,
oh
if like we got hacked because this user clicked the link.
It's like, no, you got hacked because your security policies are terrible.
Like one person did not cause this to happen.
-- Well,
-- and it's,
it's almost worse in a way because it's
not even a technical outage that actually like,
it's not like the southwest outage where like their, it systems just crumbled
and they didn't know where their flight crews were and all that.
Like no
time is,
it's part of regulation and the regulations say if not time ain't working well,
nobody's flying,
right. Which
makes it, then it's fine. I'm ok with that.
People could still get the no
tams, but they'd have to do it like verbally and there's just too many damn
noms. Like there's literally hundreds of these a day.
And so typically they split them up by geo
geographic regions and stuff because like,
if you're flying from Florida to New York,
you don't care about
noms in California,
right?
And that's, and this is the problem is also
is that we have like this hyper
efficient system
that is operating right at the edge of its, you know, envelope of capability.
And so when it fails, it, it doesn't degrade gracefully.
It's not like Netflix where like Netflix has
a system where when stuff starts to fail,
they like, oh, we don't give you your preferences,
but you can still find stuff and stream, you can still do the core mission of Netflix,
which is like, I want to watch my cartoons or whatever,
right? When no dam fails, it's just like no bloop, it's dead.
You know, there's no graceful degradation.
-- They, they sort of tried that and it failed
-- quick.
We should talk about that for a moment because I think
it's important to recognize that Netflix is not a,
a safety critical system that if it fails, people will die
trying to degrade a system. Like Notam
will probably result in death and destruction
versus just saying we have to let it completely fail
and restart it. All
right. I
think that's an important thing to remember.
Well, OK, like a better example, might be degrading the phone system where
you know what happens when the phone system gets
clobbered by too many calls or outages or whatever.
Right? And there's, you know, it,
the thing to remember too is like grounding all the
flights can also result in deaths like medical flights,
you know, those people need to go places. But anyways ignoring that
medical, medical flights don't make the news, plane crashes do.
But so what,
what's fascinating to me is let's experimentally like let's mind game this out.
So
they ingest a file to the system
obviously. And the file was processed and then distributed
and a corrupt file caused the system to essentially hang.
And then of course, they passed the, the bad file to the backup system
and it caused the backup system to hang
in the exact same way because they're identical,
obviously.
So
option A, there's no sort of precheck.
There's no like file parser that goes like, ok, it's a good clean file,
feed it into the system or worse.
There is a precheck
and it failed. It passed the file through anyways.
Yeah, that's the thing I've been wondering about
because I'm,
I'm skeptical there was no testing done
because I've done when, when I was at Red Hat, we did some work with like the FAA
and they have
obnoxious requirements, we just say,
and it is obviously for a reason because like when planes fall out of the sky,
it bad, it's bad
or even just bump into each other a little bit on the tarmac it's expensive.
Right.
And so they have
enormous just requirements you have to deal with. And so
I would be shocked if there was no
verification step in deploying something new.
So my, my guess and, and if someone knows, like I would,
I would love it if there was a pointer to what actually happened.
But
like, my suspicion is that
there was a verification step and it passed.
And what's interesting to me though is that they,
they never considered it was a corrupt file because
they passed it to the backup system and then,
you know, messed up the backup system.
They somehow thought it was an outage of the actual
system processing the file, not the file itself, sort of so to speak. It happens.
Number one, you either have testing and it failed,
which is bad or worse in a way you have no testing, which means like a YOLO,
like just feed it the file, hope it's all there, you know.
Um I'm always reminded of these instructions, like,
you know, run curl, blah, blah, blah, pipe it through bash.
And you know what I've never seen in any of these scripts
is a, is a check to make sure that the file downloaded completely
and it's actually really easy to do.
There's a couple of easy ways to do it.
One is like you just basically define a function and then at the very end,
run the function,
which means you got like the whole file,
a lot of the scripts do this where they extract the payload MD
five the payload and then they'll say if it's good or bad at
all,
some do.
But anyways
and so like there's basic things you can do to make sure you
downloaded the whole file and then that the file is reasonably not corrupt.
Like at the GSD, we run it through a JSON parser and through a JSON schema parser to
make sure because Kurt has mangled the files and tried to check them in.
Now, now, here's the thing though. I run curl to bash,
not a lot, but it, it will say it, it's happened in the past.
And do you know how many times that has failed for me?
-- Oh, almost
-- never.
Never,
literally never. I can't think of a single time. It's failed. Right?
-- But
-- if that bash file was controlling planes flying in the sky,
-- I, I might add that check
-- if that bash file failed and killed someone,
I would be
much more vigilant
on what I was doing with it. Right. Versus,
and, and I think that's one of the things we often forget about is
what we do in our work lives and personal lives generally don't
have to hold up to a lot of scrutiny because like,
even if you download a virus and, and you know, curl it to ash or whatever,
is it really going to kill anyone?
And the answer is often. No.
And so you just clean up the mess. Right.
And so I think that's one of the things is I,
I love having conversation with the people where they're like, oh, well,
I can just do it like this, you know, they should have done this and it's like,
that's not how that works.
I mean,
one of my favorite examples is listening to industrial control system. People talk
and like, I am not an industrial control system person.
I'm always like, why can't they just upgrade it?
And they're like, you don't understand how this works.
Like you have a machine that's 20 years old.
Like we don't even own the plugs to hook it up to a computer anymore.
Like we cannot upgrade this even if we wanted to, which we don't
because it works.
It's fine.
Well, it's actually that's what my brother-in-law does.
My, my sister and brother-in-law work in Ska
and he specifically designs
the systems that like when the alarms go off, then what happens? Like, do we,
do we turn this reactor vessel off? Do we turn the vent on? Do we turn this pipe off?
Do we open it up all the way? Do we, you know, like what ha basically what do we do
to create the most safe environment?
And it's complicated because these are like chemical
plants and oil and gas plants and like,
you know, like, oh, well, uh we want to vent this.
Ok. But if we vent this and it doesn't, like
something goes wrong.
Now, we have, you know,
poisonous gas or explosive gas filling the plant that might actually be worse.
Right. Right. And that's the thing, like, when I make a mistake,
it doesn't really matter when your brother-in-law makes a mistake, people die,
like,
uh,
maybe cut that out of the show. But poor guy,
it's all good. Does he listen, you should tell him to listen to this.
Good Lord. No.
What's his
-- name?
-- You
-- can
-- say hi to him.
I'll let him have his privacy.
So one thing that's interesting to me is that
this also wasn't like it was a technical failure that resulted in a,
we're operating out of the bounds of what is
uh legally and regulator
allowed.
And so they granted all the planes they could have, you know, and, and they,
the articles literally said,
like we tried doing it verbally and just keep too much stuff and the system
started falling apart because the air traffic controllers
have to route planes and not just read
this giant list of no
tams.
Right. Right. Going back to this. So,
and then everybody's like, oh, it runs on spark and spark is obsolete and like blah,
blah, blah.
And it's like, well, yeah, because it was built right 1015, 20 years ago. And
I think we covered this another show.
But like, as long as it's running,
why would we spend money upgrading it and making it better.
And of course, now they're like, oh, there's a,
there's going to be money to upgrade it ahead of schedule because apparently it was,
it was slated for
placement in six years. But here's the thing that gets me is like, yeah, the,
like, replacing the hardware is probably a good idea because I,
I don't know how easy it is to find spark replacement parts versus X 86.
You can go down to your local,
whatever your local chain is and get like a really beefy computer for 1000 bucks.
What worries me is,
remember the articles Mozilla wrote about rewriting Netscape
to Fire Fox and how it almost killed them
because you have all this institutional knowledge and all these corner cases that
you've successfully handled and they may or may not be properly documented.
And now you got to recreate a piece of software from scratch
-- that does all that properly.
-- They didn't recreate
Firefox from scratch though. Did they?
Well, not from scratch, but they rewrote it massively and it,
it ate up years of time and effort and it almost killed them.
Right.
And my concern here is, is, are they going to port the software
or are they going to rewrite it from scratch?
I don't know. That's a good question
because I suspect based on the fact that
the FAA is saying contractors broke this thing.
Well, contractors bill hourly.
-- Uh. Right.
-- Right. Well, contractors run a lot of those systems too.
-- So, contractors are probably gonna want to rewrite it from scratch
-- probably.
And, and it's hard to, I mean, so look,
this is always one of those things that I chuckle at
and I mean, I know we talked about this, well,
we talked about curl a couple episodes ago
where
curl supports all these weird corner cases and it's always easy to say, oh,
we'll just rewrite it.
And this is almost certainly the same case where
saying you're going to rewrite something sounds easy.
But it really isn't. I mean,
for anyone who's ever said, oh, we'll,
we'll rewrite that and then they tried to rewrite it
and you realize the mistake you've made about halfway through
and then it's like, all right, what do we do now?
Do we turn back or do we keep plowing forward and deal with the mess we're making?
And there's never a great answer for that because it's just,
it's hard. Like when you have
something that's critical to running your
process or business or whatever,
you, you can't just turn that off. Right. You need, you need it to run.
And if you write a new one, well, now the new one better not freaking screw up,
you know, because then people get mad.
Well, and again, this is a regulated requirement. This isn't like a nice to have or a
like you literally have to change the laws to not do this.
Change the law
seems like
I'm
saying, like, a business could,
like,
potentially do this, but this would require, like, an act of Congress. Which,
yeah, that's not gonna happen
right
now.
So,
the, the other thing I'm curious about is my fear would be is that they, they,
one thing I've noticed with a lot of these systems that are,
especially 10 or 20 years old is not only do
they want to rewrite it but they want to like,
modernize it,
you know.
Yeah. Right. Let's, let's rewrite it in. No Js. That'd be great.
And uh you know,
or like use like Postgres SQL post GIS to make it geographically aware, you know,
to make the data, geographically aware or whatever and like,
nothing could go wrong there.
So
because in my mind,
like it's one of those things where it sounds like a simple problem.
Ok, we have a bunch of notices, they're geographically distributed,
we need to tell people who need to know about them to know about them.
Right?
And
the problem then becomes, is you have regulatory requirements like, oh,
it has to also be available in Spanish on Tuesdays at
5 p.m. because that's what the law says or whatever,
right?
You have these crazy requirements.
I don't think there's gonna be like an ongoing series of outages like
this isn't the system failing and failing to work with kind of reality.
Like it's not like, for example, they, you know,
there's a new place name with unicode character.
And that keeps us that's what's messing up the file,
right? Like it's not like there's more of that happening.
This isn't the kind of technical failure where it's,
you just reminded me of something that I think is really important when
there are failures of this level in an organization like the FAA,
one of the things the FAA is phenomenal at is doing post mortems on things happening.
And so I guarantee they're going to know exactly how this happened and they're
going to create process and procedure to ensure this thing never happens again.
Now, variants of it could happen, of course, but
exactly what happened here will never happen again
because they're going to make a huge to do out of this, which is really cool. I mean,
I would love to say I always do a postmortem
when there's some sort of incident and I do,
but
we'll say
the follow-through isn't always as complete as I
would like for a variety of reasons,
but the FAA is definitely going to get this one.
-- Right.
-- Well, I, I don't know because the the correct answer here is this
needs to be properly funded and maintained.
Well, I mean, yes,
and that's not up to the FAA.
That is a different problem.
I mean,
this specific narrow failure will not happen again exactly the way
it happened this time because they will obviously create some new process
on their checklist. Of a million things you have to do to deploy an update
that now says, you know, check this file name or, or check this thing or whatever.
Make sure there's no, oh, I've run into, um,
uh, youtube file names have dashes in them which some specifically windows
subsystem for Linux gets confused about sometimes, like, if you try,
if you ellis in the dirt
it, like, gets confused.
Yeah, it's pretty, it's, it's only windows
subsystem for Linux.
I need to look at this. Now.
I've never, I've never seen that, but I don't, I don't use it very often. I basically,
so it's actually funny.
I realized the other day I was talking to someone who is basically saying,
I'm trying to find an SSH client for my ipad.
And I said, good luck.
I, I found one, I found one, there's one, it's awesome.
So there's this thing called ish ish
that is like an alpine virtualization layer or something that runs on I OS.
And it basically gives you an alpine system all I want it for SSH, right?
And that's all he wanted it for.
And anyway, I, I, during this conversation,
I realized like I,
this is exactly what I want and I literally only want ssh
this if you're listening and you own an I OS device,
like install ish ish.
It's amazing.
I will say support is maybe questionable. It hasn't been updated in almost a year.
So like I, I pray it doesn't die. But I realize like my windows subsystem for Linux
I have on my Windows machine. I mean,
I literally only use it for SSH, that is the only thing I do with it.
And it amused me when I realized that.
No, I mean, now that I've actually got a server up and running again, I've got a true N
scale box running containers. I'm not running as many workload.
Like I'm doing testing on my work, my windows machine,
but I'm not running actual workloads there anymore.
So, so, so anyway, it's no, but I think the challenge is
there's also something to be said for. We defined a requirement.
We built a piece of software in a system that meets that requirement
and it's been running for 10 or 20 years
and we just leave it alone and kind of keep it on life support
and we're, you know,
some things don't need to be constantly extended and changed and upgraded,
which is not to say
there's not value in that, like uh E 911 is a great example, right? The, the fact that
basically, I think right now we're pretty in the next year or two,
pretty much every phone now is doing E 911.
So when you call 911,
the phone's like, hell, I'm over here,
right?
And that's hugely valuable for 911 operators to know like where on earth are you,
you know, because we can't really help you if you don't know where you are.
And my understanding is that pretty much all the phones do it now.
It's just now also we need to get the 911
centers
to support
it, right.
You know, and there's also talk of like 911 supporting texting and, you know,
multimedia because like every time I've had an interaction, I'm always like,
or with the, especially with the city for 311, I'm like,
it's great now because they have an app and you can attach photos and video to the app.
-- All right,
-- I'm stopping you there because I, I know where this inevitably goes,
which is the ban topic of potholes.
But,
but what I'm saying is there's, there's,
I think a lot of people forget that there's a real value in
having a boring stable system on life support that works for 20 years.
So here's what I'm thinking of as you're describing.
This is we'll, we'll, we'll pick on no damn in this instance. Is,
is it acceptable to have a,
a
software based system
that
you are willing to say this is complete and can continue running the way it is
-- in perpetuity.
-- Well, as long as the regulations don't change,
well, well, ignore, let's, let's say they don't
like a good example is you can go to,
we'll say certain, let's say factories or, or factories are a good one because when,
when I was in college.
I worked in a paper mill in the summers to
earn money to pay for room and board and stuff.
And we had a paper machine there that was
100 years old and it was the only paper machine
the company had that could make a very certain kind of paper.
And that's why they kept it running
and of course, it had weird maintenance issues and stuff.
But functionally like it ran, we ran it,
it had received minimal upgrades over the years.
So, like it was, it was a pretty old machine but it, it did its job. Right.
Yeah,
but that's a very mechanical thing.
Like you can say, I need a new bolt for this and it's a weird bolt,
machinist will make it.
Versus when we think about tech,
you can't, like, like, let's say you have a spark chip that's not made in it.
You can't, like, hire someone to make you that spark chip.
You can't,
you can't upgrade some of these libraries.
They might not even have source code for some of this stuff anymore.
Like, I don't know.
Oh, they absolutely, that stuff's going, like, unless it's archived somewhere,
it's going slowly bit rotting away.
-- I feel
-- like tech is kind of different. Whereas
historically, a lot of the things we have that are really old, I mean,
I live in 100 year old house, you know,
you can generally
work around a lot of this stuff. But I feel like in, in software and computers, like
you really, you kind of can't,
-- you know.
-- Well, let's talk about light bulbs for a second in theory.
Like I, there's this youtube, uh, person who makes vacuum valves from scratch.
It's, it's a beautiful, amazing process.
Oh, I need, send, send me that link. I'll put it in the show notes.
But that sounds like it's right up my alley.
It is.
So it's, yeah, it's, and it's, you know, he's got this little vacuum pumps, like,
you know, sucking out the air and everything.
It's just so pretty because he's like cutting it
with tin snips and like he's eyeballing it and
makes working vacuum tubes. So, in my house, I have light bulbs and, well,
but even, well,
the CFC si I certainly can't build like the incandescent light
bulbs I could in theory make on my own with,
I need a vacuum pump, some glassblowing stuff and like over the wire.
-- Sure. I'm
-- pretty sure
my hue light bulbs, I cannot recreate. Uh
No, absolutely not.
In fact, I took one apart one day I had a failed B I contact Phillips.
They sent me a new one and I'm like, do you want the old one?
And they were like, nope, throw it.
So I thought I'm taking this part. Right. I'm going to look inside of it.
What is it like an ESP 32 or something in there?
No, it had some, it was a pretty good processor. I think it was an arm chip.
You know what Phillips does make chips. That would not surprise me.
It's all encased in resonance stuff. You can't even really work on it. Right.
It's like,
or actually a better example.
So I'm, I'm helping out that robotics team at the high school. Right.
And
they had a board with a broken USB port on it. I'm like, I will buy a new USB port.
I will solder it on.
And they had, they had the boards, it wasn't the kind of resin we're used to.
It's some sort of other coding but it was enough that, like,
it really got in the way of soldering the piece on and it was
-- all
-- the conformal coding stuff. Yeah.
Yeah, it was horrible to get. I mean, I got the old one, I got the new one on.
It still didn't work.
So I'm like, whatever, it doesn't matter, we just,
we can live without it because there's other ways to connect to the board and stuff.
But I'm like, uh, because you can do it over the network. But, but anyway,
it, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It, it's one of those things, like, a lot of this tech is
even if you have a, a, an abnormal level of skill, which I'm not gonna say I'm like,
Ben Heck or anything.
But, like, I'm definitely,
I've done enough work on boards that I can fix most things
and like a Phillips hue.
No, I guarantee I can't touch that and do anything useful on it.
Like, I mean, I'm guessing there's some cut off point, like,
probably about mid eighties, late eighties where
you could absolutely take that chip figure, kind of out how it works
and get somebody to produce it. But a spark chip.
-- No, too many, like the trend, like, too small,
-- sort of, sort of. Ok.
So here's something to think about and I'm gonna end on this because we're,
we're running ourselves out of time.
But now
I love watching
old hardware repair videos on the internet because then I
don't have to buy this stuff and fix it.
I can, I gain my joy from watching others. I know. Right.
And,
and what's funny is I have all the gear in my
basement because every time I see them use a tool,
I'm like, oh, I want one of those and then I buy it and I'm like, well,
I've never used this because I never will.
But anyway, that's another story.
But
anyway,
the Commodore 64 is one of my favorite examples
where Commodore had created some Commodore specific chips.
And one of them is called the SID chip,
which is their like sound chip where they do all the sound processing and stuff,
you can buy new SID chips.
And there's kind of two variants of this,
there's one where people have literally like gotten a chip made.
That is a chip you plug in, that is a new C, it's not as good as the old.
It's not perfect but it's good enough. And then there's people, they've taken F PGA S
program, the F PGA put it on a board. Like the board is kind of big and honky. But
you plug it in and now you have a sit
and so
in the case of something like a spark, could you do that? Maybe, maybe not.
Would it, would I trust that to keep my airplane from falling out of the sky?
Absolutely not.
But it's one of those things that in 20 or 30 years,
the things we think are impossible may not be impossible anymore.
Well, fun fact.
I mean,
uh Boeing 74 sevens and whatnot still take software updates from floppy disk.
And so now they have these USB floppy disk adapter do hickeys.
Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly. Anyway. All right. All right.
I'm gonna, I,
I guess I'll give you the last word on this
one because I can't think of anything particularly insightful.
I suspect
a lot of these old systems that are running
are a lot more robust and fragile
than we think. And I think the challenge is,
no, no, I think the challenge is the things, the fragility we often miss.
Like we, we kind of get the obvious ones like, oh, what if the spark hardware dies?
Where do you get a spare machine
ebay versus, you know?
Oh,
like because it's been eating these files for 20 years and
never fell over until yesterday or two days ago or whatever.
Yeah. Whoops. Maybe we should check more for that.
All right.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com and the show at Susie Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too.
Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye
that.