Hello and welcome to episode 57 of the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner thought crime. Josh Bresser.
How are you? Kurt? It's been, it feels like forever since we've talked
two
weeks. It's been a while. Yeah, I was, I was indisposed last week at
Black Hat
and it was fun. It was, it was a good time.
But I, I must say
if, if I was going to take up my, my kind of my whole experience and sum it up in one word,
it would be a mat.
-- It was, yeah,
-- I, uh
the only thing I actually
saw that was even remotely amusing or interesting was that, uh,
somebody finally built like a $200 safe twiddling machine?
Yes, that was, that was really cool actually. And I like that a lot.
It, it is
not surprising in any way that, that this can be done.
But why don't you explain to the listeners what it
is just for anyone who hasn't read the story yet?
Yeah.
So, so when it comes to safes, you got your classic safe with the big old dial,
you know, and you're like, it's like 37 right, 12, left, 17, right.
You know, you could chunk the little lever thing and the door opens
and uh typically you've got to dial between like either zero and 60 or zero and 100
you know, and you got three numbers you got to enter and then it
could chunks open.
Um
So, you know, in theory,
that's a lot of combinations and to like brew force that thing takes a long time.
But in practice, um, well, like my, my gym lock, my master lock is a great example.
Uh, you know, assuming the combination is like, let's say 1 1020.
Well, you don't actually have to get like one,
it's like somewhere within one or two numbers of one.
Right. So,
right there, you've vastly reduced the number of combinations by quite a lot,
like on a dial with 60 numbers.
Well, now there's really sort of 20
you know,
um,
and then the second thing is there's this clever,
uh because it's not like these safes,
like you enter three numbers and then you have to start again from scratch,
right? Like, as soon as you kind of hit that first number, it dials into place.
And then if you hit the 2nd and 3rd number,
obviously they dial into place and if you don't, well, good luck you keep going.
Um, but there's a, I forget the name of the mathematical formula that you can use,
but you can essentially like
say it's a combinatorics problem
and you can come up with an optimized
like number of, you know, to attempt all the possible combinations, right?
So you try like
instead of trying like 111, 1112113, you try like
113112749, you know, whatever.
And you end up trying a lot of different combinations much faster.
Does that work on combination locks though?
I mean, it depends on the combination lock.
Ok, because I know it works for, in fact, I remember back in the day
when people had answering machines,
you could type in
like a four digit code to
access your messages and someone had worked out a string of like 30
characters that basically hit every four digit code you could possibly hit,
-- which
-- was
one of those classic, you know, it depends on the safe model, right?
Some also require a key, some require biometric, some are electronic blah, blah,
blah, but fundamentally,
here's the dirty secret, right?
If you don't have some sort of back off function that says like, oh, you know,
you got the combination wrong seven times in a row,
I'm going to make you wait a minute,
right? They're just going to keep pounding away.
And the beauty is, you know, most of these safes are, are reasonably well made and,
you know, you can dial the combination pretty quickly.
So that actually,
well, actually we're back into exactly like
the classic security territory of, like,
my hash function is really fast and efficient.
So, don't use it to store passwords
because really fast and efficient.
Um, so anyways back to the mechanical locks,
the idea is you basically have like this machine
that you will probably have magnets on it.
So it just kind of chunks onto the front of the safe and
it's got like a little motor to turn the knob back and forth
and then another little one to kind of put, you know, to try the door basically.
And then the beauty is, uh,
I think this was in the movie, the Saint, didn't he have one of these?
There was some movie that
James Bond film I've seen
with this
and, and, you know, and the difference being,
except that now with a 3d printer and like an Arduino or a Raspberry Pi,
you can build one of these for Tuna Bucks,
which is amazing. Yeah.
And you know, and the thing is like,
you don't, once you've built it, you don't need talent, right?
You just could chunk it to the front of the safe
and like have a smoke while it does its thing.
Um,
and that's the thing to remember about Safes, right? Is,
uh all the Safes I've ever seen or read about,
have a rating and that rating is not like how, you know, burglar proof it is.
That rating is given,
you know, this set of circumstances. This is how long it will take to break in. Right.
The classic ones being is without tools, it'll take X number of, you know,
hours to brute force the safe
and with tools it'll take like 10 minutes.
Um, there's actually some really good youtube videos
of this guy who works for.
I think it's one of the, uh,
it's like insurance underwriters of America or whatever and
they actually do the ratings on these safes.
And so his job is to break into these safes and, like,
make sure that what the manufacturer said, like, it's
20 minutes with tools and he's like, no, it's like five minutes because you do this.
It's, it's a crazy job
and there's various levels as well because there's like
normal tools which could be, you know,
a drill and hammer and crowbars and things and then there's
the torch,
it
changes the rules.
Yeah, exactly.
Or like, in the case of Mythbusters drill a hole, fill it with water,
stick dynamite in and
as it turns out the front of the safe goes a good 50 60 m.
I did not see that
episode
-- but I totally believe
-- it.
It was beautiful
but beautiful.
Um,
so, yeah, I mean, well, the reality is, for example, I used to the last place I lived,
actually, I actually installed a wall mounted safe,
not
to prevent burglars from getting a stuff, but actually
to prevent myself from accidentally throwing out important papers.
Yeah, I'm familiar with that.
That, that, that was the whole point of it was, I would open the safe up,
put important papers in, like, my passport or my birth certificate and then lock it
and I, I couldn't, like, accidentally throw stuff out.
That was the whole point of that safe.
Yeah. No, I, I do, I do similar things.
I, I, although I use the bank because I'm too lazy to buy safe.
And I kind of, I, I did the numbers
a
Costco with free shipping. It was awesome.
Of course you did.
I, I'm a cheapskate and, and what I pay to keep my things at the bank is actually great.
Safe story about my bank
is
I, I switched banks at, at one point I moved and,
and so obviously I wanted to go to the branch near my home
and I go into their vault and this is a relatively old bank.
In fact, I bet it's
more than 50 years old. Ok.
And the boxes are all in the vault. And so I go in the vault and I look at the back wall
and I said,
why,
why was there a hole in your back wall because it was clearly patched? Right.
And my thought is they, they were broken into at some point.
And the guy looked at me and said, uh,
we, we locked the safe wrong one time and we had to pay someone to break in.
And I said what?
And so he showed me, he showed me their safe, which is really cool actually. And
there's like all these dials.
So basically, like you lock the safe at five pm and it will not open it.
You like, you, you still have to use a combination,
but you cannot use the combination to open the safe
until say 7 a.m. the next day or whatever,
right?
Whatever you want to set it to.
And apparently what happened
is somebody sent that those dials to an indeterminate date.
So they didn't know when they were going to be able to open the safe.
And so they called in a company
that he said it took them two days to drill through
the wall in the back to get into the safe.
-- And I was like, that's solid. You know,
-- I actually remember reading about that.
There was this company, a small hosting company back in the day that bought like a,
an old bank building,
you know,
and part of the idea was they would like the ultra secure hosting in the bank vault.
But of course,
that means you need to drill holes for electrical data and air
and you know, it turns out he's like, yeah,
this concrete sucks because it's concrete with rebar
and
they mixed in like these special hard chunks of
some sort of aggregate that like breaks dry.
And he's like, it cost so much money to drill
the holes in these things. Right. Because you're just going through drill.
But it's like Kleenex,
I'm sure I can
just kind of the point.
Right. Right.
Um, but, yeah, no, it's,
yeah, I mean, well, and that's the thing. Right.
Like, so in my neighborhood, generally speaking,
the response time for cops is like, five minutes or less.
Right. So, you know, and that's, and that's generally how it works with banks.
Right.
If, if like, an alarm at a bank goes off at three in the morning, chances are, you know,
grumpy cops with guns are going to show up in, like,
probably less than 10 minutes, probably less than five minutes. Right.
You know, and so if the safe holds people off for five or 10 minutes, cool.
It did its job.
Exactly. Exactly. Well, honestly do,
I would be surprised if most banks have a
whole lot of anything worth stealing on hand.
I mean,
um,
well, in the safety deposit boxes there's,
you know,
I,
yeah, but
like,
so, so my, my bank's vault has like, 2000 boxes in it. Probably.
How would, you know, like, the 10% that have, like, minds full of paperwork?
Literally all that's in it
-- is
-- punch the doors open really quickly.
I
guess it's,
it probably be way easier to just steal Ethereum or something. Right.
Yeah,
that guy that got what, nab, for laundering, like,
$4 billion in Bitcoin because the Mount Gox thing,
uh, that. I don't think anyone was caught for that. Were they?
I, I think they're just, they, they know what's happening.
No, no,
no. Um
Yeah, look it up, look it up
anyway. Anyway. So I will say
that was very interesting from Defcon.
And then also there was talk of voting machines
where,
sorry, I
as a Canadian those things piss me off immensely because we don't do that in Canada.
Ok. I'm iii, I agree. I mean,
good for you. I'm jealous.
-- But for
-- those of you
with circles and you make an X in the circle,
you fold it and then you,
you put it in a ballot box
and then people count it and if the count comes out wonky, they recount it
and people are like, oh,
but how do you prevent the counters from like monkeying with stuff?
Well,
you have people from different parties counting it together and they
hate each other and you have independent scrutineers who hate everybody.
So literally you have the watchers watching
the watchers who hate the other watchers
with a bunch of extra watchers who hate everybody watching all of it.
-- Let's
-- back
it up
and, and you can, you can rage on that again.
I'll give you another opportunity because you're totally right.
But for those of you listening
at, at, at
defcon this year, they apparently had a bunch of voting machines in the I think,
I guess it was a voting village.
They called it.
Yeah,
that's,
-- yeah,
-- why not?
So, like the old pay phone villages of which I,
I only ever saw legitimately leased pay phones.
Right. Of course they were all legally acquired.
Right. But now that there's no such thing as pay phones. Right.
Whatever.
So
apparently all of the voting
they had, they all were hacked, which doesn't surprise me in any way.
They're all running windows.
If you're lucky, they're probably running windows.
I bet a lot of them are running worse than that.
I wonder if any of them are running always to like those old ATM S.
It would totally not surprise me.
It's,
it's, it's one of those things that
anyone who expected these machines to last against,
like legitimately talented hackers is fooling themselves. There's just,
there's no
-- way
-- the
thing that really ticks me off.
Defcon takes place in Vegas and if you look
at the actual rules wrapped around slot machines and,
you know, electronic gambling machines in Vegas and, well, Nevada in general,
like, why aren't those standards?
The voting machines have nowhere near that standard,
right. Because
in Vegas that's real money and then they just bring you into the desert and you,
you dig your shallow grave.
I mean, right. That, that's kind of how that is,
but there's, there's two sides to the voting issues. I see.
So my suspicion is the kind of in person type of hacking
is probably never going to be a huge deal. Because it's going to be very difficult
to
really mess with these machines.
-- And, and again,
-- that's the beauty of democracy in general is to do.
Widespread voter tampering
requires essentially like a corrupt government.
Right?
Where, where, like,
there's only one candidate on the ballot and you have to vote for him.
And if you don't, they take you out in the desert and shoot you. Right. Very
similar
to the
communist thing where
the essentially the vote is premarked.
But if you want to change it, you can go off to the little thing and
change it and then they take you in the desert and shoot you. Right. Exactly.
It's pretty simple.
And, and so you're right, scaling voter fraud kind of in person is one thing.
But I, I suspect the real damage comes from
the ability for a remote adversary
-- to mess with things. And, and again, like
-- when you
say it's worse than that because
you don't need to mess with voter
actual voting to commit fraud.
For example, the electoral rolls who's allowed to vote
and you can very much skew
well, who or what is allowed to vote
and have, you know, because some of these elections are, are, you know,
some of these ridings are quite close, you know, so like
disallowing one or 2% of people to vote
-- actually has a very material effect.
-- Yes, it would be huge in, in many instances
-- it
-- has been.
What do you mean, it could be that fair.
Have you not seen?
I know, I know. God bless democracy.
It's
right.
But
I know that, that makes me sad.
But anyway, your, I think your rant from earlier is very well taken is the fact that
even if we had the best of the best
writing software for voting machines,
they're gonna screw. It would
never have.
Here's the
beauty
with the Canadian system,
which is also used in quite a few other countries.
I can teach my six year old
how to be a scrutineer and how to
spot voter fraud
by
and large.
I mean, that, that's a really good point actually.
And that's the beauty. Right. You and I are technical security people.
You know, we've done this for decades
and I can still imagine, like,
763 ways this could be compromised and I wouldn't spot it.
Oh, totally, man.
And, and you think that the old lady drinking coffee watching me is gonna know.
You know?
Yeah.
No, it's, and, and the thing too I love is then whenever I bring this up with, uh,
other people in larger countries, they're like, oh, but that doesn't scale.
I'm like,
but yes,
it exactly does scale because you have more places
to vote with more people working the voters.
-- But
-- you, you're saying paper ballots don't scale.
No other people are saying paper ballots don't scale and counting it doesn't scale.
And I'm like, yes, it does because you just scale up the number of people doing this.
Like, as long as,
you know, some 10th of a percent or 1% of your population is involved
in running the process then. Yeah, that scales.
Well, you know what else you get to? Actually the beauty of paper
is,
I have seen electronic voting machines stop working
more times than I can count.
We have little pencils.
Right. Right.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. No, I totally get it, man. It's
sometimes I feel like electronic voting machines are a solution.
Looking for a problem.
-- Yes
-- and no. So, so like in Canada it's a little different, right?
Because when we have say a federal election
it's, you know, you're voting for your local MP basically
or, you know, same, well, basically the same with provincial and, you know,
same with municipal,
but we're not voting on issues.
We're not voting on who's going to be the dog catcher or the sheriff or a judge.
So in Canada, for example, we vote on far, far fewer things,
right?
Whereas in the US, especially in some states, like say California, you know,
you'll have a ballot with like 20 or 30 or 40 things on it.
So, actually the state of Oregon has solved this beautifully.
They, they,
they do, they mail you a book,
you fill out your book and you mail it back in and they have the
highest voter turnout rate anywhere in the United States and my suspicion is from a,
from a security perspective,
there is probably little to no fraud
in that environment just because the hassle of going through, you know,
duplicating books, filling out books, mailing books back in
is going to be insanely high.
And additionally, just kind of using statistical analysis on your side is
if you wanted to throw the vote and let's say you, you mail in bogus books,
they're gonna probably number one figure out, ok, like Kurt sent in two books.
Well, you need to like intercept them and place them and,
and let's be honest, people complain incessantly about the US postal service,
but to be honest,
uh like they are incredibly
secure
and reliable. Yeah, same thing with Canada Post. Like
honestly given a choice between who's delivering my package
and this is prior to Amazon Prime, you know, delivery people like Uber.
Honestly, my, my first choice was always Canada Post followed by
ups, followed by fedex, followed very far behind by DH S and uh Purolator
because
with DH S and Purolator invariably,
I had to drive out to God knows where to get my package from them.
-- So,
-- you know what I used to love
a long time ago,
I worked tech support at a little ISP
and we learned you could put a floppy disk in the mail
and mail it with one stamp,
it weighed exactly the right amount in an envelope.
And so we would have
custody
on
the
front.
You could, I be, you could do that legally.
There was
this guy
that
mailed a bunch of weird objects around like
books and stuff and
to find out what would happen and, you know,
of course a lot of them were broken up
to make sure they didn't contain drugs or whatever.
But
no, there's like well known cases of,
um, like that gold for cash thing. They just send you a padded envelope.
Yeah.
Yeah. Right. It's the postal service is crazy, man.
-- Like they're the real deal I love in
-- my whole life.
I think they've lost one piece of my mail.
I've lost a handful of things. I, I won't lie to you.
I, I,
but
regardless,
it, it always, it brought a smile to my face that you could,
you could mail a floppy disk in the mail.
You just literally dropped it in an envelope, put a stamp on it and away. It went
and, and it, it showed up and usually it worked, which was awesome.
Well, I mean, that's not really postal services floppy doesn't work.
I mean, that's,
you know, oh God, I remember buying boxes of,
well, I remember buying boxes of 40 floppies
and then I would format them
and get rid of the ones that didn't work. I remember doing that.
And the best part is you would collect them in an empty box until you had 40
then you take it back to Staples or Office Depot
or whatever and be like this entire box is defective.
Give me a fresh box.
Right.
Yep. I remember that,
man. Those are the
days. Thank goodness,
I do not miss them at all.
I hated that stuff. It was, it was miserable.
I just got rid of all my USB thumb drives and bought a
bunch of 16 gig USB 3.0 drives because the 2.0 are too slow.
You know what I do though? I keep a bag of them. I have a Ziploc ba
literally full of thumb drives.
And when like my relatives or neighbors need something,
I give it to them and I say, please don't give it back and they,
they generally do give it back even though I don't want.
But I figured this way if they do keep it,
I don't care.
So it works out very nicely
and then also depending upon who I give it to.
Like,
there are some people I know that their computers
are generally so full of viruses and crap.
Like I don't even want the stuff back. It's like they give it to me.
I throw it away because I
it's compromised after you've touched it. Right. I mean,
from a risk management perspective. Yeah, that person is bad news.
So
anyway, anyway,
uh point being summing up kind of black hat and, and I was not a de conner be.
I, unfortunately, I, I had events
that, that took up my time there. But
I, I did not see anything
that kind of really made me interested it.
I feel like we're stuck in the same old, same old
period right now in terms of security technologies and just happenings in the
actionable stuff is going on.
There's not very much,
I mean, I mean,
I
had somebody come to me about like a super
amazing CV that they can't tell me any details about
scripting
in
some web form. Right?
Yeah.
Well, it's probably worse than that, but fundamentally, well,
I was thinking about that the other day because um Microsoft, they just um
expanded their bug bounty program. I don't know if you saw this,
they cover windows and
server
and it's like, what is it? A quarter million?
It's between like,
it's like some absurdly low number, like $500 or $5000 and like a quarter million.
So, you know, a bit of variation,
which makes sense though. I understand that.
Well, a great example being that like SMBV, one SMB Loris attack.
So it's a denial of service attack where you basically send
a bunch of packets that eat up a ton of resources.
Um I actually remember writing about the slow Loris attacks like a decade ago and II,
I tried them out on a bunch of,
you know, servers. I was like, wow, that actually really made a mess of things.
Um
But yeah, like again, if you're like, if you're actually using SMBV one, like,
what the hell.
And number two, if you're exposing it to the internet, like,
-- seriously, what the hell,
-- I'll agree with that. 100% don't do that.
Yeah. No, that's,
I don't even know what to say at that point other
than to shake my head and walk away because there's just no
helping that.
Um,
you know,
it's like, and it's like, honestly it's cute and Microsoft's like, yeah, it's cute,
but we're not fixing it.
And it's like, yeah, I, I agree with that.
Like,
that's just stupid to fix. Like that's a waste of time and money and
once you fix it, then, you know, customers have to deploy that fix and that, you know,
that's tens of millions of dollars globally wasted.
Totally.
You know, well, Speedo,
here's a thing. I was curious, what's your take on the whole Flash 2020 thing?
I had lunch at black Hat with a bunch of
the CBE guys and there were some Adobe people there
and I was very clear and I will say it on this podcast as well.
I will die before Flash does.
And I'm going to stand by that
now, granted, now that means my,
my death is kind of the future of humanity depends on it.
So,
so for those of you that don't know,
-- apparently Adobe has committed to killing Flash in 2020
-- and, and
the Adobe guys didn't disagree with me for the record.
-- So, in fairness, how old is Flash? Now?
-- It's really old, but here's the bigger thing.
Nothing ever dies.
That's just the reality of it. I mean, somebody is going to show up with a
strong
big
money.
Yes, there are. But that, that's slightly different. I mean, that's gonna be like,
ok,
actually that's a really good point you bring up because there are
horse drawn carriages but you can't use them on the interstate,
just like
-- not the interstate.
-- Well, in Canada, the Amish put those little triangle
-- on
-- the
-- interstate or just on the
-- road highways and they drive on the shoulder and
roads, not the interstate
highways different,
not the interstate.
Yeah, here they go on the highway.
-- Sometimes
-- some of the highways probably not like a 12 lane divide
or the right.
Exactly.
You going to die
right away,
the day will come when we say no more humans are allowed to drive cars on the highway.
It is going to happen. I guarantee it.
And there will still be, you'll be able to go to the, like,
car zoo or something and drive cars, whatever, you know,
and the
right, it'll be just like, I can go ride horses at a farm.
I, I, I'm not going to do it on the road because that would be crazy.
And it's illegal on the interstate.
But I can go to a farm and I can ride a horse and be like, thank goodness,
I own a car as I drive off at the end of the day.
Right. And it will be the same thing
now. So, so I guess
technology can change if there's
the right amount of will and regulation behind it.
Because let's face it.
No, no, no, no, no.
Hang
on.
There's still, what?
Punch cards in
there?
-- No, no, no, no,
-- no, no, it's different. Here's my point.
If the government didn't say it's illegal to ride your horse on the interstate,
some idiot would do it.
Ok.
And the only reason they don't is because the police can arrest
them and say it's illegal to ride your horse on the interstate.
If we don't say it's illegal to run flash in your computer,
there's always going to be flash on someone's computer.
There is a legit case.
Uh, so there's like a petition to keep to open source flash and keep it around because
there is that huge amount of software written for flash.
Um, like just today, actually,
my son played a flash game at the local science museum.
You know, they had the, uh, the Mackie. Mackie,
you know, that, uh, it's like the sort of classic nez
controller but you can, like, hook it up with the alligator,
the
TF
or whatever.
And so, like, you, you, like, hold the one ground and like,
you press these bits of tin foil and like, you know, for six year olds,
this is amazing.
You touch the banana
and.
Exactly.
Yeah, touch the banana, touch the orange, whatever.
And so he was playing like, uh they had like Space Invaders,
Tetris and Pacman and like they were clearly flash based, you know,
they were using some flash based website.
Here's the deal with that though.
I agree with you that I don't think there's
anything wrong with sending flash to a farm.
Like, look at, look at archive.org where they have old like M sds and Apple two and,
and crazy old games and applications you can run in an emulator, right?
If they added flash to that, I would certainly not be opposed to that in any way.
But my view of that is
that's the farm, you go ride the horse on for fun,
right?
And unless
it is somehow
and in my honest opinion, basically illegal to run flash, people are going to do it.
Well, here's the reality, right?
Unless Adobe sends out an update that like where it commits suicide,
people will just be running whatever the last version was.
II,
I don't think they would do that. I, I would love it if they did.
In fact, I remember a million years ago
that that real player
kind of ran into this where real players stopped being supported on Linux and
a bunch of distributions sent out an update that caused real player to essentially,
yeah, commit suicide and wiped it off the system and it was just gone
and, and there was much wailing and gnashing of teeth,
but now it's fine.
It's like, you know, can God microwave a burrito so hot you can't eat it.
Can you have an R PM post and all script that R PM hyphen
itself?
No, no, it didn't delete itself. It was just an empty package essentially.
Right. Right.
Exactly.
-- And then there were, there
-- were binary and
-- like,
-- if you
-- wanted
-- to kind of stick with the old one,
there were some steps you could take,
but it was certainly like you really wanted it at that point.
Right.
This wasn't an accident.
-- We,
-- we need to let people do stuff like that because for example,
um,
well, like, you know, Bonte.
Bonte
have to, at some point train with real stuff
to some degree. Right. Like
firemen, firemen have to train, you know, in
scenarios that
potentially.
But again, this is, this is the
-- farm with the horse on it.
-- Exactly. It's a controlled,
right.
The firemen don't like, go light your house on fire and then save you from the fire.
They live, you know. You know what I mean? It's a controlled environment.
-- Well,
-- yeah.
And that's, yeah, and that's the thing.
But, I mean, I guess a lot of people,
II,
I think the problem would be probably there's enough
people that want it and will pay some tech,
like 50 bucks to make it happen and then, you know,
-- two years later it's a problem.
-- Actually. That's a good point.
You figure come out the day after flash is end of life.
I bet you can make a decent sum of money with a flash installer
that
anyone could download and use,
even though it would be horrifying.
Yeah. Well, I mean,
yeah, II, I just, I don't know,
part of me just would love to see Flash dead and gone forever.
But on the flip side, I get that there's a huge
corpus of software and content, not just software but content.
You know, it is part of our history.
It is and give it to archive.org and give them like a freaking emulator and,
and that's enough, right?
That's the solution. The solution isn't to keep running this crap.
They just need a copy of flash running on Windows XP.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. That should be no problem. Right.
They have no, they have Windows 31 running just fine.
I'm sure you can get flash going on it. Right.
Do you ever see that video of that guy that did a screencast of like upgrading from?
-- I think it was like D OS one
-- to
it was Windows
one point. Oh, all the way. I think it was past XP. It might have been in the vista
and it was, it was fascinating that it worked.
I love that.
I'm also impressed that you could get a machine
that would actually run all those different versions.
He just did it in a VM, I think, didn't he?
But still, I mean, from AC P architecture point of view,
I feel like if I'm remembering correctly and I could be mistaken,
but I believe he had to basically
build the VM,
do the install and then basically take the disk and import
the disk into like another VM that had different architecture settings,
right?
Like different video and sound and things like that.
He did a little bit.
Right? Because
I don't think you could expect to run windows one point. Oh, on
any modern
art,
those customers that feel that way.
No, nobody should do that. If you do that, you're a bad person.
All right, I'm just gonna say that now
you are the person riding their horse on the interstate.
You're gonna get killed and you're gonna deserve it. Right.
That's basically the way it is.
Yeah.
Anyway,
no, that's what gets me about the last, I don't know, the last 15 years,
I've kind of paid attention to black hat and defcon.
There's been precious few talks I've seen where it's been like, wow, you know, and,
and conversely, it's interesting because you look at the whole Dev
ops agile development thing and that came out of a conference. Um
It's a, there's a Wikipedia page about it. We can put it in the show notes, but
that has actually changed the world quite a lot.
You know, this whole Dev
ops agile development thing where you know,
we went from like waterfall development to a
bunch of Kanban
Trello boards
and
you know, freaking Netflix.
That's the thing now.
So,
so here's kind of my take on that is we may
never see super amazing security research ever again at a conference.
It, it, it, it would kind of surprise me if we do at this point.
However,
I,
I think there's immense value in going to these shows
because you get to talk to people and in fact,
I didn't even get a proper pass this year.
I had a booth pass from elastic.
I'm like, this is good enough. I don't, I don't need anything else.
And yeah, I just, I, I hang out and talk to people and,
and I went to parties and talk to people and, and it was, it was fantastic.
Part of it too is, I mean, no offense. Even if you show us an earth shaking, like,
hi, here's the hack where you sneeze funny and like you compromise windows,
it's like we call that Thursday.
You know what I mean?
Like, it's just things are so fundamental, like voting machine tampering and,
you know, shenanigans.
Like,
no, they're, they're computers, like, of course, they're terrible.
Right? Like, it's just,
it's like a web browser. I found a hack for all the web browsers. Yeah, like,
yeah,
that, that just happens every once in a while,
you know,
so part of what this kind of, this whole thing reminds me of is like, car safety in the,
let's say, fifties to seventies in that.
Like, we know, cars are incredibly useful. Right. They make life better
and, yeah, people die in them a lot,
-- like a lot.
-- It was banned
and computers are kind of the same way right now. Like,
even like these windows, 10 tablets I have, you know, they,
they want basically an hour a week of me managing them and
God,
it just
so frustrating,
but at the same time they're quite, you know, sort of useful and handy.
And,
but the, the difference being is that, you know,
I, I don't think anybody's going to come up with the magic three point safety belt,
anti lock brakes
and airbags
in
this.
And I have a, a talk I've been working on for a long time and, and I,
I've tentatively titled it.
It's going to get a lot worse before it gets better
if you look at.
Yeah, it is, it has literally zero call to actions at the end.
-- I like that. You think it's going to get better?
-- It, it, it,
it
better unless it gets a lot worse. That might be a better title actually. But
here's the thing is part of this.
I did research into things like pollution and car
safety and industrial safety and like mine safety.
I remember telling
you all these terrible things,
right? And all this stuff and
you look at like, so I'll pick on car safety.
I mean, Ralph Nader basically stunt hacked
the government into caring about car safety.
I mean, that, that's essentially what happened
and
it's one of those things that the automakers just kept wailing about how, oh,
we can't possibly do this.
We can't possibly do this. Right. It's too hard. It's too expensive.
It's impossible. Sound familiar.
It's essentially our industry where we just keep saying, oh, we can't do that.
We can't do that. Nothing's fixable. It's impossible.
But then one day when the government showed up and said, you know,
you have to do this or else they were like, ok, I guess we can do it.
And now, granted, I'm not necessarily saying regulation is the answer.
It is a possible answer I will say. But I don't know if it's
part of,
uh, I, well, so the problem we're going to have with the regulation though is
the, the world of security and computers moves so fast
that
it's
international. Well, that too. Yes. And, and so,
I mean, a
great
example
though.
Right.
Well, yes and no, but you have imports,
software is a little different because like
when you physically import a car, you have this nice 2000 pound thing
-- that you can relatively easily intercept at a dog. Ok. So
-- I'm gonna get to that.
All right. That, that's part of something I, I think about a lot is
so, yes, regulating software would be difficult,
especially with github and stack overflow and open source and all this stuff.
However,
companies that sell things and, and I use the word things loosely,
not just software because literally everything is full of software.
Now,
there, there should be certain expectations around that.
And so the trick might not be regulating directly,
but rather having some sort of liability
where if you have a device or a product
and it runs software
and it does something that, that damages a person, be it, you know,
financially or physically or whatever,
there should be liability against that software perhaps.
And that could get really interesting because then
we're not dealing with regulation necessarily,
nor do we have to worry about kind of the,
it's not keeping up with the times because, you know, if your product maims someone,
it doesn't matter what the latest, you know, version of open SSL is,
you just maim someone, you know, don't do that.
That's bad.
So, basically the class action lawsuit theory of responsibility.
Yeah. Yeah, essentially. And, and it's a possibility,
-- I, I know it's
-- not. And then the challenge becomes though, is that
some of these companies just don't give a
damn or they're structured to deal with that or
an extreme example being the Grenfell Tower disaster
where apparently the police have now said that.
Yeah. No, we don't think like any charges are needed.
That is interesting
and, and sometimes that might happen
where,
where it's difficult to necessarily blame someone or, or,
well, in this case, there's a relatively clear,
a chain of events where they approved this cladding that was not,
uh, correct, you know, for that application.
Um,
uh, but apparently it seems like, you know, I, I think part of it is if they did that,
then it would set a precedent where like
Britain's housing market would be kind of up the creek
and, and right, that, that could be part of it. And this is,
this is one of the really interesting things about liability
because, well, at least in the U SI can I can speak on,
I don't understand it necessarily elsewhere, but obviously,
judges use precedent
of past cases to determine their decisions of today.
And as well, one of the things they will consider is kind of
what does this mean for kind of the, the public good.
And so if it's something that would like just totally screw up society,
-- they're not gonna do it. And, and I
-- don't know, it's the loss basically,
right?
Like to put it bluntly sometimes, you know, we, we have situations where it's like
to make it right.
We would essentially expose ourselves to so much liability or so many lawsuits.
That
-- sucks to be you. I
-- mean,
it, it, it's tricky to say the least. And
my point is though of, of all of it, regardless of how things get better,
assuming they can get better is
I think we have a long way to go
before it gets so bad. People care
because let's face it. I mean, look at kind of the problems we see today.
There, there are annoyances but for the most part society continues to function.
Right.
I actually personally suspect it won't get bad
enough to get bad enough that people care because
it will get bad.
But it will offer so much more benefits that people will be like, yeah,
this totally sucks.
-- But hey, it's worth it.
-- I mean that, that's totally possible.
I, I will not disagree with you. It is very conceivable.
My one example for that would be alcohol.
-- Uh, there's no way alcohol would be approved nowadays,
-- whatever.
-- We, we banned it in the US and look how well that worked out.
-- Right.
Well, and that's the other part of the problem, right?
Even if you ban alcohol, it's like, well, I've got like fruit and a bucket.
So
I, I saw a thing one time. It was a grape juice manufacturer from prohibition in the US
and the instructions said
do not put in a bucket in place under your sink for three months, you know,
like will result in
fermented alcohol or something. And it was like, this is hilarious.
Yeah.
But see, that's the thing, right.
It's like cars, right?
I think in 20 years from now when we have self driving cars,
we're going to look back on the number of deaths
caused by cars much like smoking and be like,
that was completely insane.
But like, right now we're like, yeah, whatever,
you know.
Um, I did a bit of
a,
I did like a 3.5 hour, um,
drive to and from another city over the weekend and, like,
we saw three accidents. One pretty bad.
We almost got killed twice. Um, a guy in a guy with a truck towing a large camper van,
uh, uphill onto the highway. Uh, the highway is about 100 and 10 kilometers an hour.
He was doing about 60 sweet.
Uh, and he, like,
made rather rude gestures at us and then he pulled off at the next exit
half a kilometer later because he basically didn't want to drive through the town.
He wanted to take the highway as a bit of a shortcut
and just stuff like that. Like it's just,
oh God, we just,
uh,
yeah, so much, so much,
you know,
I,
I, but I, I, you know,
we'll look back at this and be like that was clearly insane and terrible.
But I suspect with computers
here's the thing with a lot of computer security. Unless
a great example being a defcon, the whole car wash, you know, will kill you thing.
Um,
unless,
but unless somebody actually takes control of that car
wash and tries to use it to kill you.
Uh, computer security probably won't kill you.
And,
well, ok, so
I would compare it more to pollution in that regard where pollution
didn't really directly kill anyone in the manner a car would.
But it eventually things got so bad.
Society had to basically say, ok, like this river lit on fire. That's bad.
Uh, funny story.
It wasn't society that had a problem with that.
It was the railroad companies because their bridges were being damaged.
That was the problem with the Hudson catching fire
is the railroad
that is unacceptable. It's messing with our bridges.
-- And
-- ok, so even if that's true, which I, I don't know, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna research this now,
but it's all on the Wikipedia, I'm sure. Of course it is.
I'm ok with that.
Right. I, I'm perfectly ok
with,
with kind of the side effects of the
badness being what actually gets the attention because
I'm looking for the outcome
of secure software,
how we get there is
not quite as concerning to me
that goes back to my discussion with some Google people about how
I don't fully trust Google, but the fact that Google is based on ad revenue
and they want to protect their ad revenue through a variety
of means like a secure web browser and http s everywhere
that meshes with what I want.
Yeah,
the enemy of my enemy is my friend. Right? I mean, that's totally what it is and I'm
comfortable with that as well because I think
there are many enemies
and
it, it's, we're losing,
right. But we're not losing bad enough that anyone really cares.
Yeah, exactly.
Uh, anyway,
anyway,
all right, there, there's one last thing I think we should talk about and, and we,
we brought this up from, I don't know, maybe, maybe a couple of weeks ago and,
and we just never got to.
It is
Schneier
wrote a thing about password masking and how it's on the way out
and you seem to think password masking is great and I legitimately.
So
let's, let's argue, man.
I don't think password masking is great.
I think it solves a legitimate problem of, for example, my six year old
the protocol is now that he must turn around,
bury his head in the couch and go la la la la la
while I tap in my passwords
because he shoulder surfs passwords constantly.
-- Ok.
-- But, but you, you have mass passwords and you still do this
because you can see my fingers on the keyboard or on the thing.
But if I didn't have a mass password, then you could just, you know,
from across the room with a pair of binoculars do it or set up a phone or God knows what.
And so
fundamentally,
I think masked passwords should be the default with the option to unmask them.
I,
that's fair. I, I wouldn't, I wouldn't disagree with that. I, I think
because if I enter my passwords in public, for example,
I don't necessarily want, you know,
somebody might not be able to see what I'm typing,
but they might see what's on the screen or,
you know. Um,
I just, I think it makes, here's the thing, I don't see a, I don't see any downside
to masking passwords by default and then
maybe optionally allowing people to unmask them.
-- So,
-- here's, here's my, my downside is when I'm using my phone
and I'm typing in my absurd password.
I get it wrong like 10 times in a row
because I can't see what the freaking
so on an iphone, when you type the character into a password field,
-- it shows the character for like a brief part of a second and then
-- starts,
I type it too fast or I try to
and then I get many of them wrong or if I can just unmask it, I can say, ok,
that's not my password.
I'm, I went to go fix, this is a four and not a three.
And my second comment there would be is you're doing it wrong.
-- You should use a password manager.
-- And that's what I do.
Actually, it's, it's generally unlocking my password manager.
I mean, although, although I,
I do have a password manager now that can do a fingerprint on my phone.
So I'm,
I'm happy and I,
I refuse to research if Android is storing any of
that correctly or safely because I'm pretty sure it,
-- but regardless
-- what could go
-- wrong,
-- it makes me happy.
So it's good.
Well, I mean, honestly that's why I'm looking at,
buying a new Macbook is for the fingerprint scan.
Yeah, this is a place like the eye stuff. Definitely does a much nicer job.
Yeah.
Well,
using those windows tablets,
I'm so annoyed that I have to type in stuff and I can't just, like,
swipe my finger on something or push something with my finger.
Why do you even have passwords on them just to, they're crappy windows tablets.
Who cares?
-- Oh, why do I have a
-- password on them?
Because
the
paranoid
it was
my kids from just camping out on them.
I see.
So
it was to sort of,
you know, time limit my kids a bit,
like 1245,
pretty much because essentially the parental control software I've researched
is
garbage.
It's terrible.
It's, it's like, I mean, here's the thing,
Tavis Ormandy went and looked at antivirus scanners and
found all the horrible stuff.
I would bet a lot of money, like a mortgage payments worth of money.
But
-- parental control software is far worse.
-- You know? It's terrible.
I, I would be amazed if it's not completely horrible and just mostly awful. Right.
It's, it's one of those things that
let's face it. Anyone who knows how to do it. Right.
They're not going to work there. That's just,
you know.
Yep.
Anyway. Anyway. All right. So that, that was much less arguing than I'd hoped for.
Well, it's, it's, I think it's a good thing to have on by default because
the thing too is, I mean, well, here's a great example.
I was walking home today and uh canceling one of my bank accounts and,
um,
because basically I had like a 5, 10 minute walk home.
So, you know, rather than just, you know, use the time productively,
but at the same time it's, you know, there's nobody around me hearing me like,
recite out account numbers and stuff,
you know, even though the risk of that going wrong is quite low because,
you know, some random dude, uh reciting random numbers while he walks by,
chances are somebody's not going to hear that and be like,
oh ho I'll get into his bank account and like, wipe him dry,
you know,
but still like,
I only did that because I knew that nobody would overhear me on the walk home, right?
I wouldn't do that and say at a party or something.
Uh
Yeah, I,
yes, I agree with you and I totally understand,
I think from a risk management perspective that is relatively low risk.
Yeah. And I see no issue with that.
That's fair.
Uh I guess one other interesting point
before we go
is
during the CBE lunch
that I attended.
Uh I did forget my credit card at the House of Blues,
which was super embarrassing for me actually.
But that, that's another
story. Um
I left it at the House of Blues and II,
-- I forgot to take it
-- because in America you have to
give
it to the
-- server. I
-- paid
and then I was talking to somebody and we just like left
and it was still sitting in the little book where you pay.
And
it was,
that's something that's so bizarre to me. I,
I don't have the little term. At
least they, they had it,
they gave it back to me and I don't have any fraudulent charges on it.
So there's that.
But
anyway, anyway, uh
well, I was talking to these guys,
I mentioned that I had put all of the CV data into elastic search and I like I
could do fun things with it and I kind of showed it off a little bit and stuff.
And then I mentioned there are uh what like 419,000 references.
And I said, I wonder how many of them are valid?
And they said, man, I wonder how we could do that.
I said I'm going to do that on the airplane ride
-- through.
-- W
well,
basically.
Oh, and just for so for those of you wondering what the hell we're talking about.
A CV reference is a URL pointing to something
that references that CV.
It could be a vendor advisory, it could be a security advisory,
it could be a change log.
It's just something
you know, of value and related to that CV.
Either it's typically the patch, the vulnerability or
other information related.
-- So anyway,
-- 419,000 URL S it took me about 24 hours to tear through them.
And, and would you like to guess
how many of those URL S returned? A 200?
Well, so they might return to 200 but they actually return content
only looking at
return
response codes,
codes.
Uh
Well, I know we've gone through and tidied up a whole bunch of, I think it was neo
haps
recently and some other word,
a
bunch of those.
So all the
s Yeah.
Well, no, no, no,
but so there's been a bunch of websites
that have gone away or changed significantly.
I would guess
I'd be really quite happy with 5 50%.
It's about 50%
give or take. Uh And, and then there's also three,
-- vary by year. Like is the recent stuff
-- I haven't made up into that yet.
That's the next thing is to graft them by year and understand.
Well, then I'll tell you now,
-- the
-- old stuff I would say also graph them by year end vendor,
please because for example, sun.com,
yes, that's a good point. I, I, well, that's the beauty of it.
I can do all those things now because I just,
I have this data sitting in elastic search.
But
to give an idea, I can look at the breakdown here about half or 200
about another quarter, give or take are 30 ones and 30 twos which are redirect.
And I did not log any of the redirect information, but it's not very many.
Well, it'd be easy for me to just tear through just those.
Right, because they, they're small.
But then
probably around 12%
where
basically, like the web server just doesn't exist anymore.
-- There's no domain there, there's nothing. And, and, well,
-- roshi.org,
that's true. That was a great site.
It, it was, and it's crazy too. I'm looking at this.
I've got some really weird areas like this. A 523 is in here.
Like, I don't even know what that is.
Uh 521. No clue.
And so it'll be fun to just kind of looking
up with some of these weird error messages are that,
that came back.
But
-- no, it's,
-- oh, you know what? Those are cloud flare errors.
Oh, really? Oh,
523 origins is unreachable.
Interesting.
Well, cloud Flare or somebody else was using, you know, a proxy in front.
Interesting. Wow, that's wild.
Well, and the other thing I was thinking could be fun is,
I don't know if archive.org has the ability to check like a URL,
but it could also be interesting to look at some of these ones that failed
and see if there's an archive.org copy.
But that's, that's, that's the next phase of the project.
So we'll, we'll get to that.
-- But anyway, anyway, if, I
-- mean, that's just a simple said script,
-- you know. Nothing
-- simple. Kurt don't, don't say that
it'll be Python
and talk to last
because that's more fun.
So anyway, anyway, if I actually I put my graphs on Twitter,
if anyone wants to look at them just, just find me and take a peek.
So.
Alright, man, I think it's time any parting words
uh
if you're gonna buy a safe,
make sure your six year old doesn't get into it but beyond that, like,
who cares anyway?
Ok. Ok. All right. All right. Thanks Kurt. That's, that's fabulous advice.
Thank you for listening. Everybody.
If you want notes from any of the fascinating topics or,
or to get a hold of us and yell at us
and tell us how fantastic defcon and black hats still are.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
We also have a Facebook group there that you're welcome to join and harass us.
And yeah, I guess if nothing else. Thanks for listening, everybody.
Thank you, Kurt. It was fun as always. And I guess until next time, take care, man.
Yeah. See you guys next week.
Hopefully. Now you've doomed us. Right.