Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 132
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Pressers.
-- So,
-- what's new? Kurt?
-- I cleaned my desk.
-- Wow, that's fun.
It's nice.
I actually have some space now. It's not covered in,
well, whatever it was covered in before.
Very important things, I'm sure.
So, actually I moved my office over the Christmas break.
It was, it was a little before actually. And
when I moved, I basically just threw everything away and said, I'm not even like,
if I need this,
I will buy a new one was basically my stance.
And of course I've not bought any new things and I don't expect
to either just because when you've been in one place and like,
this is true of just having a desk in general, you amass things and it's always, oh,
I need to keep this because I might need it someday.
And the reality is you probably won't.
And even if you do,
you can probably buy one for less money than it's actually costing you
in terms of just like mental sanity to keep it on your desk.
Right.
So, one thing I've done is I got rid of drawers.
I, I'm not allowed to have drawers in my office except for my filing cabinet.
Yeah, I know that feeling too.
I had a huge desk with a ton of storage in it and my new
desk has one little tiny drawer on the front of it that I keep,
like my wallet and pencils in
and
all the other garbage I literally threw away and, and in fact,
I was cleaning up the jars and it was like, what is like, where did this even come from?
You know, it was, it was crazy. I had no idea what half of it even was.
-- It's,
-- it's always amazing to me how fundamentally the same human behaviors are.
Right. We've never, well, like
we're, we're from different countries.
We've gone through different education systems.
But like you give us both a desk and with drawers and
it'll look identical after six months.
Yeah.
But I have a suspicion that's kind of just
like the evolution of the human species where,
you know, historically speaking,
the only things you would amass were food or maybe some sort of crude tools
and, and generally speaking,
you needed to keep those because like, if you didn't, you would die,
right?
Whereas now we've reached a point where we love to hoard
and keep things and we have all our shiny treasures.
But the reality is none of us are going to die
if the crap in our desk is thrown away.
Right.
Yeah. Well, speaking of thrown away. So these bird scooters,
those things, I, it's fascinating to me because it's
so, I don't even care about the technology piece so much. It's just
one of the things that's fascinating to me is so
back in the olden days and by olden days,
I mean, like 10 years ago,
the days of yore. Well, they are, the olden days.
It was a fundamentally different world. We didn't have,
let's say, 13 years ago, we didn't have smartphones,
we didn't have, you know, you couldn't put a computer into a device for $5.
But anyways. Right. Right.
So what would happen,
say, 13 years ago if you left a $300 piece of electronics on the street?
Yik, like,
yeah.
Right. There's no way to, to do DRM on it. That was reliable enough.
There's no way to put, like a cell phone and GPS tracking system in there.
So, yeah, if you left like a $300 thing on the street, somebody would, um,
take it,
you know,
they might try and return it to you if it had a phone number or something on it.
But fundamentally it would probably get stolen.
-- And it's fascinating
-- to me that end up in the river when they were.
Exactly. Yeah.
Um, well, and, and even in Holland when the, when they did the, the,
the free bike share thing back in the day.
They just, you know, Miss Koreans, chuck them in the river
or in the canals. Sorry.
So, actually speaking of that, I'm going to interrupt you for a moment.
I was in Amsterdam. It maybe a year or two ago. I forget it. It's been a little while.
But anyway, uh, I saw a bike in the canal and I asked one of my friends, I said, you know,
what's the deal?
I, you know, there's some bikes in the canal. Why don't they, like, take them out?
They're like, oh, yeah, they fish them out every couple, every couple times a year
and then they, I guess, take them, fix them up and resell them.
It, it's, but apparently there's like,
there's so many bicycles in the city they have serious problems with, like,
tourists will throw them in the water or people will just get sick of their
bicycles and the way they deal with them is they throw them in the canal.
Like, it, it's easier than trying to throw it out or, or whatever.
Well,
I guess it's better than just leaving them on the
-- street because there's already
-- a lot on the street.
Well, like every time there's a garbage strike, right, you end up with like,
piles of trash on the street and like,
you know, even three or four bicycles on a street would create a serious hazard.
Like, it would, they
show a
lot of room when they're on their side.
They do and there's lots of bicycles in Amsterdam anyway.
-- I'm sorry, we were talking about bird scooters. So,
-- yeah.
So, so for example, I mean, back in, you know, nowadays the bird scooters,
what they have like ad RM on the board so that you
can only unlock it with your smartphone in the app and blah,
blah, blah.
Right.
As I understand it, they, they have GPS and something to report back so that those,
there's people that, like,
it's like collecting cans except they collect bird scooters and then plug them in,
which I was kind of wondering how that works. Right.
Because, you know, bird scooters run on batteries, batteries need to be recharged.
You know, we,
we had a show about this a couple of months ago actually because there's like a crazy,
I guess internal fighting something where with all these
people trying to collect from scooters and charge them,
guess what's happened is, you know, these,
these bird scooters go from being legally owned by bird to,
I guess being abandoned property and seized by the city or some other lawful means,
some entity is seizing them.
Right. Like you and I, I don't think
can just legally pick them up off the street even if they're abandoned.
And I was kind of looking, trying to look into this to find out like,
what is the general
sort of western law on
if I abandon?
Well, see the problem is number one. It's not my property, it's Bird's property.
And I'm
technically, I'm abandoning it because I don't intend to come back and use it.
-- Right. I'm done with it. So
-- I, I actually do know how this works due to a mishap.
A friend had a long time ago with a vehicle.
So what actually happens is like, let's say you park your car somewhere,
you're not supposed to and it gets towed.
right?
And it goes to like the impound lot
and the impound lot isn't just cars like they have every crazy
thing you can imagine at an impound lot because people forget or,
or misplace things in crazy ways
and then the, the police,
they, they make a best effort to contact you and basically say we, we towed your crap,
come get it right.
And then after a certain amount they have to contact you a
certain number of times I forget all the gory details there.
But basically what happens then is after making an effort to contact you,
if you don't come and get it
like they, they sell it, they auction it off.
Well,
there's a second issue there is that the impound fees
typically charge or the impound lots typically charge fees.
And so at some point,
uh, retrieving that
thing,
it becomes economically unjustifiable, right? If I own a $2000 car
and I own, you know, 1000 or $2000 on impound fees, well, then you know,
I might as well just go buy a new car
or whatever.
Um, and that's the thing with these $300 scooters, as I understand it, you know,
the impound fees add up quite quickly
and don't really make it justifiable to go and retrieve these.
The other thing I was wondering, for example, if I leave my wallet on the street,
they don't
auction it off.
So there's certain types of property where if they're abandoned
in public they don't get seized and auctioned off.
I don't know about wallets, but I would bet you anything that it totally would,
where they,
they would put it in a box and then they would
auction off like a box of wallets or something like that.
And granted it's totally empty.
Well, the, you, you, they can't legally sell your driver's license.
Well, I'm sure they would take out things like a driver's license. Right.
But, I mean, in all seriousness, like they, they impound and they find,
like if you bring a wallet to the police
station and there's literally no identification in it,
they're either going to keep it and dump it off like
we just talked about or they're going to throw it away.
Right. Because what, what else do you do with it?
There's, they're not going to keep it forever.
Yeah.
But anyway, so
the deal is apparently, is that
bird scooters have DRM and whatever to protect them.
So you can only use them with the app, but
there's a simple way to deal with this, which is you,
you take the motherboard that's in there, you, you remove it,
throw it away and you put a new one in that doesn't have DRM and bam,
you got a $300 scooter for the cost of this motherboard kit.
It's not
the D MC A bypass because you're,
you're throw like you're literally throwing all of the copyright protection out.
Like you're, you're not touching it, you're not looking at it,
you're literally putting it in the trash bin, right? And by,
you know,
tried to go after Cory Doctorow for copyright infringement and DNA violation and
-- quote, un quote and said he
-- picked the wrong,
the
wrong.
Well,
yeah, no kidding. Like, have you ever read any of his books?
You know?
Right.
So,
but I was wondering, for example, if the motors had,
for the sake of argument had a chip with built in D MC A?
Well, then you would have to maybe bypass that to make the motor work or for example,
what if the motors had
a custom patented plug design
and you couldn't, you know, buy that plug apart from through bird. Well,
you know, and I feel like that might be the next step of birds evolution.
All these scooters come from one or two manufacturers in China,
you know, they, it's not like birds
designed and made these things.
They, you know,
essentially partnered with a Chinese manufacturer who
did most of the heavy lifting.
But what really we, and you and I were talking about this is, you know, the,
the law to deal with this need to catch up because so
we have generally we have laws to cover cars and pretty much every
case a car can be in, in a city,
you know, if it's broken, it gets towed.
If it's abandoned, it gets towed,
if it's parked too long and there's too many parking tickets on it, it gets towed,
you know.
Uh, no, you can't take that car just because somebody said I'm going to leave it here.
You know,
people who illegally park their cars and leave the keys in it.
I, I can't get in their car and drive it away. That's
theft.
You know, even though it's really
sometimes, like, for example, at the ski hill,
they have like a small loading zone that fits five or six cars and
people will just park their cars there. Right.
And it just annoys me immensely because it's covered
in no parking signs and no stopping signs,
you know, and it's,
yeah, anyways,
obviously these laws need to catch up a bit. And part of me was wondering,
you know, how much, what's the responsibility of the company here? Right.
Should they have dedicated people to go get these things out of impound quickly?
Should there be a city bylaws saying, for example, if an electric scooter is left
on a sidewalk outside of a designated scooter leaving zone.
You know, if it's there for 12 hours or 24 hours it gets towed and by towed, I mean,
somebody throws it in the back of a pickup truck because for example,
locally there's a, a company that collects all the shopping carts.
Right? Because people take shopping carts
and
use them to, you know, for can collection or, or they, to put it, sadly,
they live out of them.
Um, but so there'll be, you know,
or people will take the shopping cart to the bus stop and
leave it there and then take their shopping on the bus.
And so I used to live in a not so great neighborhood
and there was a couple of abandoned shopping carts in the alley
and it was getting to the point of actually like
driving your car past there was getting a troublesome.
So I phoned, you know, the city 311
and they're like, oh, yeah, you know what, like who owns these cars?
Like what, what are the handles saying?
And I'm like, oh, there's like a safeway and like a,
like a superstore. And I think like the, there's like a Lowe's or something.
They're like, ok, what's the address? Tap, tap, tap. Ok. The guy will come back.
And so it was interesting is,
is they came up by and they picked out three of
the four shopping carts and they left one that was,
like, really beat up and I didn't know who owned it.
So I actually ended up cutting it up with
a Sawzall and taking it into the recycle stage
because, like, well, what else? Like the city won't take it and it's
sitting in my back alley, like, I don't really want it there.
So I, I cut it, you know, and, and II, I feel like I had made a good effort.
So I cut it up with the
-- sozo.
-- You probably committed some sort of crime
-- and,
-- and it went in for recycling. So,
and, well, can I do that with the bird scooter?
I have a suspicion that if by leaves a
scooter on the street in a place that doesn't belong
as, as private citizens,
it's almost certainly illegal for us to just take those things.
Right. Because like if I park my bike on the street
and I don't lock it up,
it is not legal for people to take it.
-- But for example, I can move it if it's in my way
-- and, and I'm ok with moving things,
but I also lock my bike up.
-- Well,
-- but how far can I move it? A foot? 20 ft,
-- 100
-- feet.
There is almost certainly a level of reasonableness to that
where moving it to my house is probably illegal.
Moving it to the next bike rack to make room for something is probably fine
right now,
when the police impound a bird scooter.
Obviously there's legal frameworks around impounding things and,
and this is where I think,
uh, I'm gonna pick on you specifically.
I think you've, you've fallen into the old security mindset of perfect or nothing.
My guess is by, knows what it costs them to go get a scooter.
And I bet it costs more to go get it than it's worth
because you figure they might pay $300 for it.
But as soon as they drop it on the street, it starts to depreciate.
And so, I mean, once that scooter has been in use for, let's say a year,
it's probably only worth $200 or less.
And my guess is paying someone to go to the impound lot.
Pay the fine.
You know what I mean?
I bet you're, you're probably very close to $300 per scooter at that point.
See, but then the problem is, for example, there's a $5 fee on recycling tires here
and I, I assume most of the world as well.
So can I just start leaving my old tires and appliances on the street?
-- Uh
-- No, because you own them
and dumping them on the street is littering,
right? And so
how is the bird scooter different?
I would argue it's not littering because it's a device
that's meant to be used and do a thing.
And now
I would also say that if, for example,
let's say you had a bunch of broken bird scooters on a street corner.
You could totally go after bird for littering
and, and I guess most importantly,
it's just the fact that a lot of the
city laws and state laws and federal laws and whatever
they're, they're not caught up to all this yet.
And I, they will, I mean,
I have no doubt they will because you look at all
these cities that are either annoyed or welcoming the bird scooters because
I think it's one of those things,
it seems like a great idea to you get them and then it's like,
oh these freaking things,
it's like before we hit record, we were joking where I was saying,
I love bird scooters when I'm using the bird scooter.
But like
if anyone else has one, I hate them.
It's kind of like actually drones are the same deal.
So I got this little like crappy drone for Christmas and it's super fun to
fly
when I'm flying the drone. It's awesome
when someone else is flying a drone.
I'm like, oh, that thing is so noisy and annoying.
Like, can't you do that somewhere else? And it's like
everything is like that, right? It's like when I do it, it's fine.
But if someone else does it, man, that's annoying and I hate it.
-- No,
-- I, I suspect you're right. The laws will have to catch up.
But I think we also need some better frameworks for behavior because
you know,
for example, where is an appropriate place to leave a scooter?
Like I know with bicycles in, in a lot of Europe,
they'll have signs, you know, because they have those lovely old metal fences
and they'll have signs on them saying, you know,
don't lock your bike to this because like every
night at midnight we'll come through with bolt cutters and
cut all the locks and throw all the bikes in the back of a truck.
You know,
because we don't want the courthouse being surrounded in crappy bicycles.
You know, locally.
For example, there,
there has been a bit of an effort to put bike racks in at some of the newer, you know,
developments.
Although it's quite comical how
terrible some of these bike racks are or where they're located, they're like,
literally have a shopping complex and then like,
half a kilometer away is the bike rack, like
somewhere just completely random and looking at the bird scooters,
I'm not sure you can even lock them to most things,
-- you know, because there's, you don't
-- have to lock them.
They're, they're self locking
and, and look, I love having rules about where you can and can't put things.
And if I lock my bike up somewhere I'm not supposed
to and they cut my lock and haul it away,
that's my fault. That's my problem. Right.
And I think it's totally true with bird scooters
and it's totally up to the bird people to solve that problem if
they have people just dumping scooters in the middle of the street,
like they can,
they're using technology to kind of make things work the way it does
and use your technology to make people park them when they're supposed to.
Right.
Well,
part of the challenge I think is back to our
desk thing is people don't actually own these bird scooters.
Right. They're just using them. And,
I mean, you've been in rental cars that are pretty nasty, I assume.
-- Uh
-- no, I don't take them. I will go back to the counter and say that car sucks.
It stinks, it's dirty, the seats ripped and I'll say I don't want this,
like give me a different car and they always do.
I've never once had them say like, no, you have to take it.
And, well, that's kind of my point is, you know, when,
when people don't own something, they tend not to be very careful or take care of it.
And that is something I think will be a real challenge
with this sort of gig economy slash rental economy slash,
you know, some of the horror stories coming out of airbnb, right? We need some
new norms for,
you know, how do I treat
-- an airbnb? How do I treat a bird scooter?
-- See, I would argue. We don't though.
So I mean,
so I'm going to pick on airbnb here if you
look at the history of the hospitality industry and,
and now I'm not a fan of airbnb, I'll just say that up front.
Right. I prefer hotels for a large number of reasons.
But the big one being like hotels have legal
frameworks and they have ways to deal with issues.
And so when I have a problem with a hotel, I go to the desk I can
to them and they fix my problem.
Basically, every time, the only time I ever had an issue was when I was,
it was actually when I went to see the total solar eclipse
and it was I was staying in some scary hillbilly hotel
man and I went to the desk and they're like,
this is the only room like you can use it or or not use it like it's your choice.
And it was literally the only hotel room for like hundreds of miles. So I stayed.
But anyway, the point is so like we'll pick on airbnb here,
the legal framework that exists for the hospitality industry,
they're already skirting around them.
All right,
because like we've talked about this
before airbnb is knowingly breaking countless
laws and just ignoring them and they're getting away with it.
But now at the same time,
the the many of the laws they're ignoring exist to protect things like like
hotels. Like if you trash your hotel room, they're going to come after you, right?
Whereas if you trash your airbnb,
right? Like happens next. It's not a good question. Oh, yeah.
I know there's been horror stories of parties and, you know,
all sorts of shenanigans going on.
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
And so this is, this is where, like,
it's time for airbnb to grow up and they need to work with their,
their local regulators to actually make this stuff work correctly.
And I think bird scooters are the same story and this is,
in fact, I'm going to tie this back to the whole security industry in general is
we,
we have existed outside of like the normal structure of society
and we think we're special and we're always talking about how,
oh, you can't possibly regulate security, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
But it's,
you know what you can't with today's laws and rules.
But one of the things we need to like,
like in all seriousness do is start thinking about
how can we
get to where we need to go
and no, the rules and laws today don't work,
but we need some that do because the world around
us is changing and same thing for bird scooters,
man.
-- Well, see,
-- and my take on this would be, is the problem with rules and laws is that
it's hard to get them
a sort of applied equally, right?
Like what you'll have between Canada, the US or, you know,
New Mexico and New Hampshire.
And that's why I think it's important to come
up with the sort of standards of behavior,
whatever man, that's never going to work.
Well.
It, it, it does though, for example,
like in the U SI was reading about how there's a lot of cities where,
when there's a snowstorm, people go out onto the street,
they shovel out a parking spot and then they put their chair on it
and that means they kind of quasi
own that spot because they shoveled it out and,
and, you know, and, and the same thing happens locally, people will, uh,
for example,
we shovel our sidewalks usually and some people will
shovel the road in front of their house so they
can park on the road easily and they feel
a certain amount of ownership of that space and,
and I would be sort of inclined to somewhat agree with
them because they put the effort to shovel that darn thing,
you know,
and that can be a nontrivial amount of work sometimes.
And so
I, I think part of the challenge with laws though is that
we get laws but they tend to be applied really, you know,
are, are the police really gonna want to spend time enforcing these laws?
No, they, they actually have real crime
to deal with
and that's why I think it might be
in some ways better to get people
to, to sort of come up with. Ok, you know, like,
for example, with bird scooters,
I think in general people wouldn't leave them
literally in the middle of the sidewalk.
As a tripping hazard. Or at least, I hope people would not do that.
-- And they would
-- realize I've seen many of them really
in the middle of the sidewalk in San Francisco,
man.
Yeah, it's,
and now granted there's plenty, not parked in the middle,
-- but there's plenty that are, well,
-- because for example,
so many wheelchair then is up, you know,
up the creek without a paddle if the sidewalk is covered in these things.
Right. No, no, I, I agree. I agree completely. And it's,
but it's like any system, right,
99% of the people will follow some basic set of rules
and it's always that annoying 1% that ruin it for everybody.
But I, I think it's like, it's kind of one of those instances where again,
where we get, let's say, in a situation, like if,
let's say that that person who parked the bird scooter in the middle of the,
the sidewalk, if you park your car in the middle of the sidewalk,
like they just come tow it and then you'd have to pay to get it back.
Right.
Something like a bird scooters.
It's going to be up to them to, let's say someone impounds a bird scooter.
Whoever left it in the wrong spot is going to
have to be responsible for dealing with that outcome.
Well,
the problem is what if the person who left it in the spot is an activist
who hates these things and it keeps moving them into the way so they get impounded.
Well, and that's again,
a place where by is going to have to use
some technology to figure it out because for example,
let's say I end my trip and it shows it's in the designated
parking area and then 20 minutes later in the middle of the street
I didn't do that
or, or if I did
II, I don't know, it seems like something insane that I, whatever.
See, and this is why I don't think the laws will work for this because
it's like, I mean, we have laws against littering and unless, you know,
they have a crackdown on it and actually go downtown and have people watching for it,
you know, these, this and I'm making air quotes here,
this crime or this infraction is so quick and so tiny,
you know, that enforcing it is the cost of enforcing it is
far more than sort of the impact of society.
And so from a cost benefit perspective, I'd say, well, yeah,
I don't really want the cops spending their time and money on this.
You know, they should be getting drunk drivers who destroy,
you know, cars.
I, I think they, they do more often than not. So actually you just reminded me of,
I actually just published a blog post this morning.
It was, well, auto Publish Magic, right?
And
I was talking about the fact that uh at ce S A computer electronics show,
I saw a lot of security people being like, oh,
none of these companies are taking security seriously.
They're not talking about security
and here's the thing and this,
this totally relates to what you were just talking about is
you need an incentive to drive any sort of behavior.
And from the perspective of security yelling at companies for not doing security.
Right? Isn't an incentive.
You're just being annoying and, and their incentive is to not talk to you.
I think more to the point you're reminding them that they can
get away without doing it because all of like last I checked,
all the Fortune 500 are still doing ok.
And none of them have fallen out of the
-- Fortune 500 because of a security incident
-- and,
and even the ones who have been hacked
their, their stock price is great. Right?
And so anyway, this is the same thing with bird scooters.
This is the same thing with littering.
This is the same thing with anything that's going to happen at
all. And it's especially true with security and we, we suck at it is
you need an incentive
and now often the incentive is money.
And I mean, this even kind of goes back to our,
our conversation about the eu bug bounty, right?
Where the only incentive a lot of people understand is money,
but it's not always money.
-- Sometimes it can be other things, but we can just focus on
-- money.
Well, money is one of the most accessible incentives.
Right. It's something I can easily get and hand out
-- and,
-- and it hurts to lose. So
most people don't want to lose it for no
reason.
And like that's what it comes down to.
Right, is if you need to modify someone's behavior,
you need to start finding by
or airbnb or Uber or whoever, if they're not behaving the way you want them to
and then it's up to those companies to basically find the passengers or riders or,
or whoever, what do you call a person that stays at an airbnb?
Do they have a name like guest?
Airbnb guest is what airbnb says?
Ok,
that's fair.
And, and you know what I mean?
If you trash the, if you trash something like you should be on the hook for that,
you know, granted I know that if you cause say $400,000 worth of damage and,
and you have like a net worth of zero that creates some issues,
but that's also where things like insurance need to exist.
-- Yeah.
-- No, I think II I agree that we do need laws but I don't think the laws will,
I, I can't think of a good
way to phrase the law also without, you know, for example,
basically giving activists the way to,
oh finally we can get rid of these damn scooters by just,
you know, kicking them over. So they're in the sidewalk and then
oops, it fell over and then, you know, they call 311 and have it towed.
I, I don't disagree with you.
I think you are correct that the,
the structure and way we do laws today doesn't necessarily
keep up with some of the technologies we have.
But I also think,
rather than just saying
I give up, it's too hard. This is one of those places
to say, how do we, how do we start to fix this in a meaningful way?
Well, I think part of it, for example is if the people using bird scooters were,
how do I put this nicely, less annoying about it,
then people might not be so angry about this. Right?
Because I,
I've seen some of those videos where these people on scooters
or hoverboards or stuff are just bombing down the sidewalks,
-- you know, and they end up knocking somebody over.
-- Yeah, it's terrible.
Well, this exists, this is freaking bicycles, do it to me.
And I mean, I was actually on my bike, it was on the, during the summer, the last summer
and I remember I was,
I was biking along and I saw this guy came whipping past me at about a
million miles an hour and of course he
didn't announce himself or anything just like,
flew by me and there was like a family with little kids in front of him and I'm like,
oh my goodness.
No.
And like, this dude ended up crashing because he, like,
nearly ran into a little kid and I thought you freaking deserve that.
You big jerk. But it's like, you know, I mean, the scooters are no different.
There's just, there's some people who, who make it miserable for the rest of us.
Oh, yeah, I know there's a walking path, uh,
here that's infamous for cars driving on it
because Google Maps sort of indicates and then they, they, they don't have those
boards in front of it for some reason. So,
uh, we've, I've almost been run over.
The funny thing is that the path used to dead end,
but now it actually connects to a parking lot.
So people will, like, literally drive down the whole thing and
it's
-- a nightmare
-- and I assume it's about the width of a car,
right,
with a yellow line down the middle
and, and so they're like driving over the top of the,
they know, right. Those people know you can't do that.
Well, the majority of them honestly are Uber and taxis.
They're just following
because, like,
there's some wonky geography in that area
with some fences in some apartment buildings.
So it gets, if you don't kind of know what's going on and you're
like,
we can't get an Uber to my partner's place because they wait on a
block and a half away on the other side of this fence and,
like, refuse to come into the parking lot to the door.
Right. These, these people are following the Uber instructions.
Google Maps knows how to do it. But, yeah, Uber, no.
And, uh, but anyways back to this, so that's why I think we need to,
-- I don't know, an education campaign or just no
-- education won't work.
Well,
there's some fundamental behaviors.
Like, if you are moving faster on some sort of, I'm going to say the word vehicle.
Be it a bicycle, a hoverboard or an electric scooter,
you know, you're going to be moving faster than people who are walking.
-- And then I would say it's on you to watch out for them. I would
-- argue. No.
Uh, here's the thing.
This is just like, so I,
I remember trying to build some security education program some years ago
and,
and I've given up even thinking it's possible because
people don't care and they don't want to learn.
And I think expecting people to change their behavior voluntarily, like some will,
don't get me wrong, but there's many who won't and there's enough who won't that it,
it basically ruins it for the rest of us.
And so like, I'll, I'll, I'm going to pick on by here as the example. But like
the only plausible solution to bird scooters existing in your
city is to have bird scooter lanes in the street.
Like we have bike lanes, stick the bird scooters in them and let's face it.
They're about the same speed as most bicycles anyway. So get them off the sidewalk.
That is the only solution to bird scooters in a city is to get them off the sidewalk.
I suspect long term that
that will happen is more of these alternative transportation,
sort of that last mile thing happens, you know, between public transit
self driving cars, you know, carpooling and stuff,
having that last mile be solved by bicycles or bird scooters,
I think actually would be quite nice.
-- But yeah, like you said, having separate lanes or having
-- it,
it's the only way it's going to work, expecting people to change their behavior is,
is not an option.
And I think
the sooner the security industry
and I'm especially security industry realizes that trying to educate people,
like you can't educate most problems away.
I won't say you can't educate any problems away,
but in the particular instance of what we're dealing with, you can't.
Well, I think you, you said something important there
where even if we do educate and we get 90 or 99% compliance,
for example, car driving,
if 1% of people decide to drive on the other side of the road,
that's going to be bad
-- like that, that's going to be objectively really bad. Even one in 1000.
-- Right.
Right. Exactly.
And, and like that happens sometimes and it makes the news every time it happens.
Right.
When,
like some crazy old person drives down the wrong side of
the highway because they just caused a huge accident generally.
So I guess the moral of the story
is
all right. I, I can, I can cover this one. Number one,
don't go after Cory Doctorow because he will beat you. Right.
That's rule number one.
-- And I'm comfortable with that
-- rule.
He has the eff and the internet on his side.
Right? Like the whole internet, right? Not just like the scary part of the internet.
So number one, leave coy doctor alone.
Uh number two is we can't fix people,
period.
Like just stop trying to do it like security. I'm looking at you here, stop it.
And I guess rule number three is uh bird scooters are awesome
if you're on them and they're horrible if you're not.
That sounds fair.
-- Yeah. All
-- right, man.
So I guess we'll end it there. So thank you for listening. Everybody.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up some show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the