Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in compiling software from source code.
Josh Pressers,
-- not anymore, man, like compiling things is terrible dot
-- slash.
What is it dot slash configure dot slash make dot slash make install.
-- Oh no, make test, then make install and hope for the best,
-- make test.
What, whatever new you don't need to make, test, you just make install that stuff.
So uh some, some interesting news.
Um Number one ubuntu flavors agree to stop using flat pack.
-- Really? I didn't hear that well
-- because it like literally came out like an hour ago.
Oh,
well, there you go. It's funny because we plan on talking about this for a while.
You say an hour ago except we don't know when this episode will come out. So, whatever
and then what actually triggered this episode happened a few days
ago was somebody wrote a really good article about Pip install
and it's titled one does not simply Pip install,
which anytime you can fit a Lord of the Rings Me in.
I am in.
It's a very subtle problem, but back in the olden days
we had an operating system
and we would install software on it and you would have a
piece of software that required library version 1.2 or older or newer.
And so you would install that and things worked
until you had another application that required
a different version of the library.
And this is where we get the expression, for example, Windows dll, hell
for anybody that's dealt with Windows and this, you know, it's not very much fun.
I mean, there used to be R PM. Hell, like same idea.
Oh
yeah.
And the,
and I'm making big air quotes here.
The solution to this was to have a vendor like Red
Hat basically control everything and make sure it kind of worked
and ship all the packages.
And if you wanted to do something on your own, you were kind of on your own.
Like if you installed a new version or a
different version of something like good luck to you.
I mean, ok, so let's explain this a little more because
when I started my UNIX career,
there weren't packages, there weren't package managers,
you installed UNIX and you,
there were Tar Balls.
Yeah, it was basically tar files and you might have like an optional CD,
which is where slash opt,
you know, comes into play.
And I could install random tools and utilities that
usually ended up in slash opt and they often carried
whatever libraries they needed. There was no, like shared
Lib Jpeg or something like that. This was
random balls of garbage.
And then what would happen is if you had something you
liked that was built on like some version of Solaris.
I don't even remember what the versions were anymore.
But you know what I mean?
If it worked on like Solaris five and you went to Solaris seven,
it probably broke because the libraries it was
linked against were gone or versioned or,
or whatever.
And so
it was a pain in the butt. And this is where the Linux distributions
really changed the world
because now the idea was you go to your
Linux distribution like Debian or Red Hat or whoever
they give you the installer, it installs all of these packages.
And if you install more packages,
it has a well defined dependency tree.
The dependencies of each library are very well understood.
And generally speaking, as long as you played in that sandbox,
everything basically worked
well.
What's interesting is all the dependencies had to be
manually put in and sometimes they were wrong.
Like I remember I have filed more than a few bugs saying like
this R PM
does not have this declared dependency that it needs.
And so you might get lucky and happen to have that installed.
And I,
I would always run into this because I
would do a minimal install of Fedora or whatever
and then install stuff and it would break. And I'm like, well is it broken?
Oh, because it's missing this package in the minimal install.
That's in the more workstation or server install.
My favorite example of that was
I was building things for a time on. It was like Red Hat Linux seven maybe.
I don't remember which one.
Yeah. Red Hat Linux. Not Enterprise. Linux. Red Hat Linux,
the one that came on a CD from Best Buy.
Uh Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And
I, I was setting up these like build farms
and I found out the fortune command which is like you type fortune
and it would give you like a random fortune out of a file.
For some reason, the build system needed that package or something.
I built, I don't remember exactly what the details were but
it wasn't installed, nothing said it was required.
So I always had to install my build system computers
and then make sure I also installed Fortune
and there was no like answerable back then.
-- So you just like SSH D in and why did you install things back then? It was Rh
-- nr PM.
-- Hyphen capital UVH space package name or URL.
-- No,
no, no, no, you downloaded it. There was no Yum or DNF. It was I think Red Hat.
Yeah, it was R PM. No, no R PM.
It you would use the Red Hat network to download the packages
like this is this is old school man. Like this is uh these were the before times.
-- So
-- what's interesting,
but hang on, hang on, let's, let's finish this story.
So we've got Linux distributions, they're doing this thing.
And then
the idea was in the perfect world you just like
did an app to get installed or a yum install of the things you needed, right?
And this was true if you're running Python or, or C code or whatever PHP.
And then eventually we end up in the world we have now where
there's this mass explosion of open
source and we're seeing people using containers
and virtual environments and things like that
to get around the limitations of the operating system because at the same time,
you don't want to just like pollute the crap out of your system, right?
You want to put things
in a place,
you can clean up the mess later and that is kind of
the root of the one does not simply pip and stop.
Well, the thing is the world changed. We went from having 100 Python libraries
to 100,000.
Now when you have
like 100 core Python libraries.
Yeah, you can package them all up.
It's, it's a couple of weeks work for a human being to do that.
It's, it's totally doable
-- and even look at
-- Debian, right? Debian now comes on like, what is it?
-- It's like 16 or 18 CD. Si mean, it used to fit on one C
-- DS. My first dis
-- drill was on floppy disk.
-- Well, that's Right. And I remember, yeah, I remember 16.
I think,
-- I feel like my first Debian was like, 10
-- floppies.
I'm always reminded of people saying, why do we do this stupid thing?
Well, because the stupid thing was actually really intelligent 20 years ago
and it totally worked 20 years ago.
And so, for example,
20 some years ago, having a distribution with several 1000 packages
that was pretty much the known software world that mattered.
Yeah, that's right. You know,
and then Python exploded and
javascript exploded and
like the Pearl Comprehensive um package archive network, you know,
was sort of the beginning of the end
of a distribution of being able to do the packaging because see the problem is,
it's not just that Red Hat is doing all this work to package up this stuff.
It's also Debian and it's Fedora and it's sent to and it's
the 15 million flavors of Debian and the
15 million flavors of Mint Linux and whatever.
And so at some point, the amount of poorly replicated work
goes out of control, it becomes really inefficient
and the, the sort of package ecosystem falls apart because
like you can't package up 100,000 Python packages now
and have them all be compatible with each other.
That's part of it as well. Because
if you're running a Linux distribution,
you have probably one version of Python, right? Probably.
And these days, like it is expected
that you will just install the specific version of Python
or node or Ruby or whatever it is you're using
and then you will use that because sometimes there's weird reasons you don't want.
The latest version
-- R
-- PM depends on Python.
So every red hat system had Python,
which is one of the reasons I actually started doing Python early on is because no,
because it was guaranteed to be installed just like V I.
That's why I learned how to use V I because it's always there even on Sco
UNIX that pile of garbage,
you know,
but that's the thing I used Python because it's installed by default.
It was a dependency of R PM. And I'm like, it's always there. Good old Python,
you know,
and it also turns out to be a really good language with really great libraries,
which is nice.
But that's one of the reasons I wouldn't use
other languages because I'd have to install them.
And if I'm not the administrator of the system,
well, now what,
you know,
and installing it to your local directory was not an option 20 years ago.
I mean, you could do that sort of kind of, but it was
complicated.
And so I think what a lot of these
languages and ecosystems realized is
OK.
Do we want like 100 or 1000 distributions trying to package up all
our packages or do we build the thing that does this properly?
Because the other thing to remember is
Python
and
the way Python does stuff is a different culture
and mindset than the way R PM does stuff,
right.
R PM is for an operating system. Python is a programming language.
These are two very different things
in some ways.
That's right. And
it was always funny because I remember
especially,
I feel like Debian was worse at this that
I'm sure there's plenty of examples for Red Hat,
but the packager would, will say make decisions for you sometimes
that like I, I still complain about this.
So I run Debian on all of the machines I have in my basement
and it is like
the the eye watering pet peeve of mine
that the Debian vim enables the stupid click.
Like you let the mouse cursor click on the screen to like do stuff
like I don't want that.
I want my vim to be dumb and the mouse cursor
is only there for highlighting text and copying it like no,
do not like let them respond to my mouse cursor clicking.
Is there not some easy global you can set or something?
Yeah,
I turn it off but I like never remember until I run it and then I'm filled with rage
and it's like this is not, it's not the default either. That's the thing.
It's literally only Devi and systems that do this
and it is like uh even talking about it,
-- it's making me angry,
-- Kurt.
So I, I can tell you probably why that is that behavior
because the package developer likes it.
-- Yeah,
-- of course, it is. That's exactly what it is.
I mean,
I had some packages that did some goofy things because
I built them and I liked it that way.
Yeah.
And that's what happens when you're the packager,
you get to make decisions for me and I can hate them.
And
anyway, so then, so then we entered a world where, you know, Python built
pip N PM.
You know, all these different ecosystems built their own,
not just tools but like back ends to store the
packages to have name spacing because that's another thing,
people forget name spacing is a really hard problem.
And for example,
if you like,
so if you have Python dash name, OK, you're probably safe. But
there are sometimes libraries and stuff that have like overlapping names. And
there were cases of this is back in the olden days,
like you'd have Red Hat and the official Red Hat stuff.
But there was also, I'm trying to remember,
what was that Dutch guy that did all that R PM packaging?
That was amazing.
Um
dag dag, that's the guy. Remember Dar PM.
And like I would go uh was it dag wear?
Let's see if it's still around.
Yeah, there we go. It's still there man. And shout out to that guy.
He did a ton of work that saved probably humanity several million hours.
But for example, like there would be packages that, you know,
third party packages that had the exact same
name as system packages and like kind of.
Now what
and, and look this problem
still sort of exists
in the Python and
node
and everything world.
I mean,
this is where you hear about all of the typo squatting
type attacks and all of those sort of weird backdoors because
there's like, like for example,
but I think Docker got this right where let's say you upload a container,
the container is in like Kurt siefried slash container name colon version, right?
So I know everything you put in. Kurt siefried is your stuff.
And if I create a container of the same name, who cares?
Because that container is actually in slash Josh Bresser slash
whatever.
And that's great. Like that's the right way to do it. Whereas
in the Python and node world, if I do pip install like Kurt sucks
and if I spelled it sucks and then you create one called Kurt sucks. Sux. Like
-- those are totally different but it it's hard to tell them apart.
-- Right?
Well, and the other thing too is, and this is a very subtle thing.
It gives a much easier attribution of where did this come from,
right?
And most package managers have some metadata where you can
dig it out and figure it out at some point.
But having it be like in the name or in that thing makes it so much simpler,
-- you know, so much faster.
-- Sure. Right.
Now, now I wanna,
I wanna tie this all up into the little package I expected us to talk about, which is
so in the, in the operating system universe
in, we'll say the case of Red Hat,
Red Hat and Debian has this as well as does in Buntu.
They have security teams that are paying attention to what is going on
in the larger world
and they're creating updates,
they're triaging issues,
they're making sure the important stuff gets fixed right away.
And in the
kind of Python and node and the packaging ecosystems, it's not like there's,
there are, there are security teams,
but they obviously can't track all of the stuff because there's just
too much and they certainly do a kind of best effort.
But at the same time,
it's also not part of that universe where like when you set up your environment,
you do your PIP installs,
you generally don't do a whole lot about it after that point. Right?
It's, it's kind of a set it and forget it, sort of thing.
What's fascinating to me is like, so brew on Mac Os,
when you install a new package and brew, it also runs an update typically.
But for example, sometimes if I pip install something, it doesn't do a global update
and nor should it by default, some would argue
that.
But on then what that means is, you know, how often do people do a pip global update.
And the answer is like, probably never,
probably never because look. So here's what happens.
And this is where we kind of come back to
the point of that one does not simply pip install is
if you are like, say do pip install is root,
which you can totally do and it just
starts crapping Python stuff all over your system
-- and your system packages.
-- Yes, that's right.
-- You can overwrite system things
-- well or, or worse,
it doesn't necessarily overwrite them, it installs them in parallel.
And then depending on how the fight goes with LD configure,
-- you know, basically roll ad 20. So
-- anyway,
pip install,
pip install global installs.
Now you're stuck with all this stuff and it'll never get updated right
in a million years because that's just not what we do now.
You can create virtual environments which are really cool.
They have them in Python, they have them in lots of languages,
but I'll just talk about Python because I think they got it really, really right,
you create a virtual environment
and basically when I do pip install, it only goes in the virtual environment.
So I can obviously have a virtual environment per project
or even multiple.
That's the beautiful thing about virtual environment.
You can have multiple virtual environments for a project or for.
So you can test updates.
Right. Right.
Well,
and that's my point is so what I find I do more
often than not is instead of trying to update my virtual environment,
I just make a new one
and then I do my because the other thing I do is in my requirements dot TXT,
which is where you can tell Pip like take everything in this.
I like to remove the version numbers for everything
because when you create a requirements dot txt,
it will pin the versions.
But when I'm doing development, I often want the latest version of something.
And so I make sure I don't pin them too hard because that way
I can get my updates and I just blow away my virtual environment,
create a new one,
install all the new stuff and then see if everything works the way it's supposed to,
which is convenient
and not at all how
like Red Hat or any of those things would work.
Yeah, I think what's interesting to me is that
it used to be that installing libraries and getting
them to work and behave was so hard.
It made sense to have some experts at your operating system level, do it.
But now, you know, with Python Pippin Virtual and for example,
that expertise and that knowledge has been put into
those tools and it's been made so easy.
Well, I mean, OK, so there's two pieces to that.
First of all, it's because Pip didn't exist at
one point in time.
Well, and that's what I'm saying, right? Is we went like why did we get here?
Well, because we, we didn't have here.
Like, that's right. That's right. You know, why didn't we have a boat?
Because we didn't even have trees. We had rocks.
They weren't even sharp.
No. Really?
Like when you look at the state of,
when you look at the state of tooling
for managing software and libraries 20 years ago,
it's laughably terrible.
Well, it, it's the best we had. I mean,
that's the thing and, and that's,
that's the one thing I always have to remind myself of.
And in fact,
this is funny because when I work with those kids
as part of the robotics mentor thing I'm doing,
they're always like, this is terrible. Why did you do it like that?
It's like, because we had nothing else like this is, this was it, this was all we had.
There was no decisions we could make other than this one.
And
it's funny. And it's even funny too when I
talk to people who've been in the industry for a long time
and they talk about like all the technical debt of like, oh,
we can't get rid of this system because if
we needed to build this Cobalt thing or whatever,
and it's like, oh, OK.
And like my favorite example is
I was telling someone about my first job out of college.
I worked for a company that wrote insurance software.
It was written in Cobal of course,
-- and the build system was a custom build system in this language called object
-- Rex.
But what else would it be? It's not like you could get an off the shelf.
No, anything except object rex.
Object rex was an IBM created scripting language and
it was basically only ever used inside of IBM,
I think.
And so
I was stuck with it and they were like, we need to build system updated.
You're young and smart.
Like you go figure out this terrible language, nobody knows.
And I did.
But like it was horrible again, like people are saying, why did you do that?
I'm like, well, because I wanted to stay employed like that is why I did it.
And so what's interesting to me though is that there's,
there's always trade offs with these things.
So for example,
um well, like flat pack and sort of go binaries are a great example of, well,
we made a static binary effectively that works like you go,
you run it and containers.
Yeah, basically containers are the ultimate static binary in that the only,
the only possible dependence we have is you need something that looks
kind of vaguely like a Linux kernel and a container environment.
And there's a and you actually have choices, right?
It's not just like you can take a docker container and shove it into pod min,
boom,
it'll work.
Um
So
well, but I I like to tell people that pod man is containers with hard mode turned on.
And in fact, I love using pod man in all seriousness
because we use a lot of containers at work.
And I purposely do things with pod man because pod man finds weird bugs.
It's like the gen two of containers where like things that just shouldn't happen,
happen.
And so it's a great way to find a fix bugs
anyway.
-- You were saying
-- well, but basically the,
the problem is now we have binaries that you turn on and they work, but to update them,
you have to rip and replace, which again has its own downsides and benefits of,
you know, well, rip and replace means I can like swap to the new one,
see if it works or not downgrade to the old one easily.
Whereas,
you know, there's a lot of things where you do an R PM upgrade
and while technically RP MS are supposed to be, you can
downgrade.
There are cases where like, no, no, no, it touched a config file and
I have had R PM downgrade work essentially zero times.
I never tried to use it like it has never worked for me well,
-- for
-- anything meaningful where it touches config files and stuff.
It's just no
kaboom.
Like I don't have a good flow chart in my head of this,
but I do know what some of the tradeoffs and some of the benefits are.
But fundamentally I think what a lot of this boils down to
is, do you want to do the work? And could you do it better
than Pip?
And the answer is no.
Uh, it, let's be real.
This is the same thing.
This is the whole point of open source is,
could you invent a better X than the open source one?
And the answer is probably no.
And even if you tried, it would take so much time and effort and it would be terrible.
-- You're better off using curl lip
-- curl. Ok.
I, I don't, I don't think of it like this at all. Actually, in my mind,
I think the way I think of this is, is it's the tiktok of, of progress
where
-- we had UNIX, we had the
-- ability,
you mean Tik Tok the noise or the website?
-- Just
-- no tiktok, like think of a, a back and forth motion, right.
We had
UNIX, then we had
crap you can install into opt
and it was hard to update.
So then we landed with package managers which solved the updating problem.
But now it was harder to upgrade, we'll say to
new or better things
and we ended up with these package managers,
but now we don't have our upgrades again because it's not
doing a good job of telling us what to upgrade.
And when and then
now we're back, we understand what's going on.
So I think we have that kind of the tooling now is going to catch up to where we're at.
And we're going to have tooling that helps us stay more
current and pay attention to security vulnerability and things like that.
And then the next thing will happen and then we'll lag there.
And so I think what we're experiencing right now is we saw the leap of progress into,
we'll say new ways to manage software,
be it containers or pip or virtual environments or whatever.
And now the tooling is catching up, this is where we're seeing things like, you know,
s bombs and vulnerability scans and, and managing all this stuff going on around us.
And so I think it's just we're getting there.
It's just,
-- it's taking a while
-- and that's what I'm trying to say is this goes back to the classic,
if you build a tool that makes developers more productive,
they're not gonna care if it creates a security problem,
they're gonna be more productive.
And then at some point,
either the security debt becomes big enough that you
have to deal with it or maybe it doesn't.
But at some point, the tooling maybe
shows that it lacks maturity and that there's other things like yes,
we made the devs more productive.
But now there's a higher cost on the operational side because the poor ops
people can't update this stuff because it's just a giant static go binary.
-- You know, they can't upgrade the library in it, so
-- they just don't update it,
like just don't ever update it.
But
and,
but what I'm trying to get at is we don't have like an alternative.
You can, you,
you can't do this yourself and you definitely can't build a better system yourself.
Because when you look at
the number of people and the amount of work going into something like Pip,
-- it's
-- amazing.
-- It's a lot of people. I, I had the number once.
-- If you look at Pip,
it has, yeah, just under 14,000 commits
from
625 contributors.
So if you think you can build something that even does 1% of what Pip does,
-- you're wrong.
-- Well, no one's suggesting that though.
I think you're, you're creating a false dichotomy. I think what we have is
the tooling to manage. It
is catching up to the reality of the tooling we have.
Well,
and that's what I'm saying is embrace this and
lean into it because we don't have an alternative.
There is no alternative and no one's suggesting we stop using any of this.
Well, I
-- think people for not
-- an option.
Well, so for example, Ubuntu is ditching flat pack because they're like, oh it,
blah, blah, blah.
OK.
Look the flat pack stuff and I'll, I'll even pick on what does, what does Red Hat have?
Fedora has something. Um Snaps. No snaps is
no snaps is
Buntu, right? And flat
pack is Fedora.
Maybe
they're, they're,
they're competing platforms. My guess is
Muntu isn't getting rid of snaps. They just don't want to support
flat pack anymore is my guess.
Oh,
there's also app image. That's the third one.
Yeah.
And there's a bunch of stuff and, and the point is like, none of it's going to go away.
But when you're, uh, when you're an organization, like
tu,
the
maintenance burden on creating this stuff and keeping
it security updated properly is very high.
If you're a random person who's gonna build your app image
or flat pack or whatever and never update it ever again,
your maintenance burden is very low.
And so
I think as a responsible open source vendor, which canonical is
they are unwilling to take on all of this additional burden. And that's fine.
I get that.
Yeah, because if you,
if you somebody did a nice comparison chart and
literally the only difference pretty much between these is
sandbox is mandatory in flat back but not in snap or app image
and
running without root access is possible after installation or all
the time with app image and that's pretty much it.
Yeah, they're functionally the same. The sandbox does create some
difficulties. We'll say in the I know this is in the Fedara land because
it's fedora and they've got Se Linux
and
it's
-- a horrible user experience
-- still to this day like remember and there used to
be a gooey tool to help generate Se Linux policy and it went away.
Well, it had to go away because the policy it was generating was broken.
And the problem is when,
when you have no,
when you have security policy,
broken security policy is worse than no security
policy because at least with no security policy,
you know, there's no security policy.
See with broken security policy,
-- you think there's security policy
-- or you could have fixed the,
we could have fixed the tool to make better security policy,
unfixable. It was unfixable
because Se Linux is too complicated
and that was the reality.
Se Linux
is a amazing tool for very specific use cases.
It struggles in the general purpose world and that's fine.
It is OK. That, that is the case because the alternative
is you end up with
a weaker policy engine
that is
very easy to break out of.
And in that case,
people think it's providing benefits when it's not and that's even worse,
but that's like a conversation for a whole another day.
But so I think going to this, the, the other reality is that
these tools are
actually quite mature
compared to like if you look again, if you look at what we had 20 years ago,
we would have killed for these.
Yes,
they're mature for what they do.
But what they do isn't what we need anymore. We need the ability
to audit what's installed
to understand the risk that comes with our installations. Be it
unmaintained packages, the security vulnerabilities,
it could be malware and stuff.
There's a million things that can be happening.
And that is the thing we need now
because the world started using these tools,
but then the world changed and now the tools have to
change and in some cases they are because you look at like
N PM and PIP now have like their what audit commands
or something where they'll tell you like what's out of date.
But there's still more to do
because there's still weird security things.
There's how maintained is something, there's how many developers does stuff have.
There's a ton to happen still and it's, it's happening and it's going to happen.
And that's
the beauty of open source is we're using these tools and
we're going to get all of these amazing benefits for,
for free, basically.
Well, and I think that's my takeaway here is,
is none of this really matters until it gets that critical massive adoption,
right? If there's six people on the planet using Python tip,
ok. Who cares about the security of it? Really?
But
we're, we're well past six people now with all of these.
And I think that is to me, what is amazing is,
I mean, I'm seeing reports saying that something like, you know,
uh 60 to 80% of software being deployed is
open source and like 97% of software uses open source
because you know, everything has some buried acknowledgment screen,
you know, your car, your TV, whatever.
And
when I think about
the expertise being baked into these tools and then being used by the rest of us.
I don't want to go back to anything but having these amazing tools and
this maturity piece,
the other thing to think about too is we don't,
you can't know about this maturity piece until you actually go and do it.
You can hypothesize saying like, oh if we build a tool that mass produces software,
we'll probably have to handle security updates better.
But you don't know what that means or what that is until you actually do it
and discover. For example, like
IOT is a great example. Like there's
different use cases in it. Like it turns out that people will buy light bulbs with
no hope of ever getting a software update
because they don't care.
And it's probably ok because they're behind that
in most cases. I mean,
look, I have a bunch of Phillips
huls in my house. Are they, do they get software updates?
Probably, I don't know. Do I care? No, not really. Like I just want my lights to turn on
like that, that's, that's its job security.
I'm a security guy and like security updates aren't on my checklist of things.
I expect my light bulbs to do.
Like the literally only thing on my checklist is turn on and turn off,
maybe change colors maybe.
But even that I generally don't care.
But although I will say I put,
I bought one of this really expensive bulb to
put on my front porch and it's like ungodly pricey
and
it, at, like Halloween, I could turn my front porch light red.
I got some color changing bulbs from my dining or for my, uh, breakfast nook.
And I've got the
Christmas, I've got the app where it'll listen to music and, like,
strobe the bulbs and make it do stuff.
Oh,
no. You know what that reminds me actually, for Halloween for trick or treat,
I could turn on like a, a fire mode which it flickered like it was a flame.
And I'm like, oh, this is cool. It was very fun.
I just checked the Phillips Hue app and under software update
it has green check mark for everything is up to date,
automatic updates at 2 p.m. That's weird.
Um, and then it actually tells me the software versions of all the bulbs and they,
uh, there's a whole bunch of different versions here, 0.2 and 0.8.
-- So something's not
-- going by
end of life or something.
No, no, these are all, no.
What it is is a lot of these things are turned off all the time,
right.
Uh, especially I don't use my lights at 2 p.m. because it's daytime.
That's true. Although I leave my lights on all the time and I let
the various
like robot turn them on and off.
Well, now that I say that, yeah, because if I say, you know, blank lights on,
it turns them on
so they must be plugged in and turned on anyways, but they're not getting whatever.
So, but
like I said,
the thing I think for people to remember is part of this too is learning
how to use the tools because a lot of these tools are gaining capabilities.
Like VNI I kind of vaguely remember when VN came out and I'm like, oh OK.
That looks cute. But now it's like, I cannot imagine life without VN.
It would just, it's so gross and painful.
That's the Python virtual environment tool for anyone playing along at home.
You know,
because like I don't wanna poop random Python packages all over my system
or even in my home directory and be stuck with a certain version.
That's right. So I, I have a good lesson for that actually. So
I am writing as part of my, my robot mentorship,
which I feel like I talk about too much but too bad you're getting it.
So we're using open CV to do color detection on the feed to detect cones and cubes,
right?
One of the cones are yellow, the cubes are blue,
which sucks because detecting blue is really hard because everything's blue,
everything's blue, there's tons of blue all around it.
That's the problem anyway, it doesn't matter.
So
where
we're detecting our yellow cones using open CV,
which is a like color and object detection visualization
tool or whatever it's written in C++ there's Python bindings
and
we had one person
that was using the open CV installed by
Muntu
and nothing was working, right? And I'm like losing my mind.
And I finally realized, wait a minute,
you're like literally an entire version behind by using the
ubuntu system package.
This is why everything is broken and nothing is working.
We create a virtual environment
install like the newest open CV and holy crap, everything just works.
And I was like, oh my goodness, what a nightmare. And at the same time, I think like,
I come from a world where I think to check things like that
young people don't
because
they don't like things just work and install. And I'm like, oh my goodness.
So of course,
the next thing was we created requirements dot TXT and put everything in there.
But you get the idea.
All right. So anyway, I want to wrap this one up because we're running out of time. But
I feel like the, the the conversation is fun. I think these are hard problems.
But I also think like we're making really good progress as an industry.
It is easy as security people to
just wail and moan about all of the bad things happening and all of
the security vulnerabilities and all of the malware and all the type of squatting.
But I think honestly as a whole, like our graph is going up into the right here and
yeah, it could go faster but I'm pretty happy with everything I see right now.
-- I, I feel like we are definitely on the right path.
-- I built web finger dot A O by myself
in like 30 or 40 hours.
Plus I had to relearn how to program in javascript on cloudflare,
which is like a subset of javascript.
Like you don't have a file system
and like I got that
and I got that whole thing working and,
and have you checked your dependencies lately?
Uh I ba I basically don't have any dependencies. It's quite lovely.
There's a UU ID dependency and
like there's two dependencies or three.
No, no. OK. Look, no, no. Here's the lesson for Kurt for the day
when you
install. No
stop
when you install any N PM package, it installs like 600 other packages.
You need to look at your entire list of N PM packages.
There's not a lot
I pull in a UU ID library and that's about it
and that doesn't pull in anything else
-- and I pull
-- in the cloud flare thing, which is their problem. But yeah,
-- no, it's, it's literally
-- just
public somewhere. I'm going to look at this later.
Uh uh Send me I will put the link to the repo in the show notes and I'm going
to go look at this and see how many dependencies
there actually are versus what Kurt thinks there is.
But um but the point is
like 20 years ago, there's no way somebody could have built this on their own
in a month or two
of like not spare time but like not full time.
Well, it would have been PHP also but
was there PHP 20 years ago? It was 20 years ago.
-- 2000, there was PHP in 2000. Yeah, it would have been PHP.
-- Ok.
Yeah.
So the,
the validator API is PHP because PHP lets me
do a clever thing of like accept a connection,
acknowledge it,
close it and then do the work so that the cloud flare worker can be like, yep,
I sent the request out.
-- It's good. Oh my
-- goodness, Kurt, I don't think we can be friends anymore.
It works.
No,
III I did a lot of PHP programming and I
have a suspicion PHP probably still runs the world.
It's like the
coal.
See the trick is I have, yeah,
I have one dependencies and it's that UU ID library that
has no dependencies because it just generates you U I Ds.
Oh, and Wrangler technically is a dependency as well,
but I use that to deploy it and then there's a couple of little things, but that's it.
I'm cutting us off.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to OSO
security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, U
Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag do hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye. Bye
the.