Hello, everyone. Josh again.
If you didn't listen to the intro from last week, I cover why?
This episode 42 is a Remaster and something we already did.
So, go back and listen to that if you haven't heard it. But otherwise,
thanks for listening. And here is the thrilling conclusion
of podcast episode 42 on Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
If we continue on with the story, we end up on a Wit
Woodle
Six
which is the, I guess planet of Huma
Kula,
which is the leader of, I forget the name of his religion,
but they worshiped the great Arkle seizure.
They're waiting for the time of the Great
Handkerchief. Is it when the world ends? Yes.
The coming of the Great handkerchief because the universe was created by a sneeze.
Right. Right. And they actually touch on this a little bit
at the, uh, on the rest of the end of the universe, but they obviously don't, that,
that's not part of the movie.
But, but anyway, this part, I found really bizarre because
it, this, this story arc isn't in the book or the radio show
and they, like, show up at this planet and
ZFA,
like,
kind of goes crazy and they go down to the planet and it's a bit ridiculous and it
doesn't really fit in any way and I don't feel like it even adds to the story.
Um,
I don't know, it's debatable.
The only, I mean,
I don't, I don't like it.
This is one of the things I really hate about this movie is this particular scene.
-- I suspect they were trying to maybe do some character development. I don't
-- know.
The one thing I wrote the one note I wrote from this whole
event other than it being ridiculous is that the Vogons are worse,
worse shots than stormtroopers
because they're shooting.
But then actually later on in the movie towards the end, let me,
let me find the note Marvin at one point says, well,
you get shot in the back of the head.
Bogans
are the, no, no,
he says,
I don't know what you guys are worried about.
Bogans are the worst marksmen,
marksmen in the galaxy and then he gets shot at the back of the head by the Bos.
-- Well, that's how Murphy's law works. I
-- know. Well, it's Marvin the robot.
It's awesome. Anyway.
Oh, actually,
so one thing I was wondering the background checks they did on Zaho,
right?
Because you can't become a president of the Galaxy without background checks
and apparently brain scans because he had to cut out parts of his brain.
-- Remember
-- that's what they say in the, the,
the movie and in the book he wipes his memory or something like that and,
and he buried certain thoughts very deep and that's why he,
and that actually ties into the total perspective vortex plot arc as well later on.
-- And a bunch of other things.
-- Yeah, that was missing from the felon.
Well, it comes way later though.
Well, I guess maybe that was sort of the gun was replacing that.
Yeah, that's true. The gun is, I think meant to be the total perspective. Vortex.
But you got to remember too, the Hitchhikers got to the galaxy.
-- The book is really like five or six stories.
-- Well, it's five books of alone. So,
yeah.
Right. Right.
And,
and so in the radio show actually does it
the last season of the radio show number five,
I think it is, they kind of go off the rails a little bit.
But other than that, they stick to the book pretty well and they,
they rearrange a couple of things, but for the most part they get it all.
But, but anyway, anyway, the Vogons capture Trillion, which,
yeah, whatever, not, not, not a whole lot of crazy security going on there.
But I will say that.
So then they go to Vos Sphere
and this is where I think things get
kind of,
I, I feel like the story starts to pick up and,
and from the security theme perspective, there's all kinds of crazy stuff.
One of the things I love is the spatula things that hit you when you think
religion.
That's fantastic.
Yeah. They were feeding off the mind energy if memory serves. Right. Right.
And the beauty of that though, in this, like
I
can so relate to this kind of,
from the standpoint of security is when you're dealing with a ton of
bureaucracy and crazy rules like thinking is obviously not a part of that,
right?
You're expected you follow the rules because you're supposed to follow the rules
and don't think about
it. I
can't help it.
Like some of our security stuff is totally like that where we have these rules about,
oh, change your password every 30 days.
Why? Well, because change your password every 30 days.
Granted, I don't dis is change of guidance on that. You kind of get the idea. Right.
Well, it's the, the problem part of it is, you know,
these rules may have been valid 30 years ago when they were
formulated for a specific subset of situations for which they were validated.
But then the problem, it's like PC I compliance.
Everybody's like, oh, we're going to require PC I compliance even though you, like,
don't process credit cards or whatever.
Well, a great example, the European cookie rules, right? You have to notify people.
You're using cookies on your website. Well, of course you're using cookies.
-- It's a website. That's how that works.
-- I
know, man. That's like,
I hate that.
So every single bloody website has that stupid warning.
Now that takes up like a big chunk of the screen, you have to, like, get rid of it.
And then the best part is if you actually do
clear your cookies and stuff every once in a while,
then you get it again and again and again and again,
-- you know, and it's just, oh, it's so annoying.
-- Right. Right.
And this is very,
I feel like a lot of security rules are like this
or my favorite now is everyone needs to run antivirus.
And this is basically every compliance thing in the world
says you need antivirus on your servers
and let's face it.
I think Tavis has shown us like antivirus is potentially
worse than what is trying to protect us from.
I mean,
for sure,
the lower end level, which is basically all of it. I mean,
the biggest thing I always come back to is, you know, when you ask people, like, why,
why are you doing this?
Why should we do this?
And you know? Yeah, I mean,
because,
yeah, exactly, because I mean, is there actually,
can you actually even get antivirus for mobile devices?
-- I think there is some for Android.
-- Oh, yeah.
Yeah, you can get these terrible apps and they, like,
kill your performance and they don't really work because they don't, well,
you can get some things that will run his route if you let them don't
and all the other stuff just, it's, it's, it's garbage. I mean, I'm not going to lie.
It's kind of garbage and it's the sort of thing, people who use it are ticking boxes,
let's face it.
They're not doing it because they need it. And,
but I feel like there's, there's a fair bit of security like that, you know,
this is, but this is always going to be a challenge
is
you will always have security compliance and security rules that were put in place
probably for a good reason a long time ago.
But getting any of this to change
is very difficult. Like here's a great example is
I I watch a TED talk one time from this guy who basically,
he, he, you know,
he was complaining about car seats because people with small Children,
like the vast majority of them install their car seats incorrectly
and it's actually more dangerous at that point because the seat has
the risk of like your child flinging out of it in an,
in an accident.
So anyway,
what he did is he took like the crash test dummy of a two year old,
put it in various car seats and crashed, right?
Got the data off the dummy.
Then he put the kid in a seatbelt, like literally just a seatbelt in the seat,
crashed it
and he brings all his findings to uh it was some like safety organization that,
that specializes in this and he shows it to him and they're like, yeah,
all this all looks great, you know, whatever these would all pass.
He's like that last one there. That's just a seatbelt.
And they said, ok, that's fine.
And, and then he's like, what do you think of that?
They're like, look, man, we know putting a three year old in a seatbelt is just fine.
But he said,
where are you going to find any lawmaker that's
gonna be willing to talk about changing these things?
Because, you know, the first kid who dies in a car accident
in a seatbelt,
people are going to lose it.
Well, it's like the whole self driving cars,
we're holding them to a much higher standard than we hold human drivers.
They're still going to win because they, they are a much higher standard.
Well, and the fact that, you know, we have these like,
self-driving car crashes where it's like the self driving
car is just mos along and like gets t-boned,
like, you know, somebody rolls a red light or, you know, and,
and people are like up in arms about it and like, well, you know, at least,
like in theory, at least a self driving car has a chance of avoiding this, you know,
whereas a human driver definitely doesn't.
And
yeah. Right.
Well,
I've seen plenty of instances where the self
driving car actually avoided a bunch of problems.
One of my favorite is there's a video, I saw where there was a bicycler coming.
It was like an intersection, a kind of a four way stop sort of deal.
And there was a truck next to the self driving car.
But as the self driving car was pulling up to the stop,
it saw the biker way off on the left.
And so he knew there was a biker basically coming, pulls up and it waited longer than
it should have at this stop
as the biker drives past it because you couldn't see the biker because the truck
was next to it and it's like a human would have hit that dude.
Right. Like, let's face it.
But the car knew it was there and like, that's awesome. Right.
And if I had to guess there are probably 10 to
1 instances of self driving cars doing something better than a human
versus them, maybe making some sort of minor mistake.
And much more importantly, you know, once they identify the cause of the accident,
they can hopefully create some sort of software fix or something and then, you know,
update the fleet.
That's true. Yeah.
You know, because it reminds me of like all these airline accidents,
I'm reading about where
something terrible happens. So they come up with a corrective action and apply it
and when they don't, it's, you know, because there's this one classic air crash,
I forget them on the plane.
But like the door would fall off from the cargo hatch man,
you know, and of course, the thing would depressurize and everybody dies if the,
you know, pilot's really not on the ball.
And then it happens again three years later and it's the same,
uh it's like the same investigator.
He's like, he basically, his response is like, God
damn it. Like, I know what happened here.
I, you know, and like they were supposed to fix this and, you know,
that time around the FAA actually made it, like, mandatory to fix
as opposed to, like, please fix this. We think you should. Sure.
You know, and I mean, that's the biggest thing. Right?
Because like, how many times, well,
the fact that we have red light cameras in like a lot of cities, I hate this.
You know what I mean?
Like
that, that alone should tell you that people suck at driving,
the fact that they can't obey a red light typically at a busy intersection.
It's not like some,
you know, I could see like some rural intersection where there's like,
no traffic ever,
there'd be no economic value to putting it there because let's face it.
The purpose of red light cameras is to make money.
It's not to make anyone safer of any sort. Right.
Uh, I, I would disagree a bit because I mean, they do here.
Well, maybe it's different in the US than it is in Canada with the,
with the, the fine structures and how that money is allocated.
But the point is like here, I mean, there's red light cameras and speed cameras,
they, and they publish where the locations are, like,
they have to legally publish the locations even for the ones where it's like,
you know, where it's the mobile speed enforcement, like the photo radar trucks
and like, we know all the locations like
it's behind the stonehouse on the way mud and like on the pull off, you know,
pull off on the an, you know, on the whatever blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And yet people still, you know, get nailed by these things constantly.
But the point is basically humans can't obey red lights and basic speed limits and,
you know.
-- Right.
-- And
yes. Exactly. Exactly. Right. Is, humans are terrible at this
and that's like the red light thing, especially that, that matters.
-- That's a safety thing.
-- Let's stay on this topic of self driving cars and when the
heart of gold gets to
Mathia,
they have uh IOT controlled missiles launched at the ship.
Now
this is a terrible idea.
If you
have missiles, please don't make them autonomous.
Well, but you kind of have to, to some degree because when you
don't know, reaction times are incredibly small in some situations.
So you have to have automated systems that can just, you know,
take care of the situation because
I mean, what happens when you only have 10 or 22nd?
Like, you know, I mean, the classic example of this is the US,
has been sent shooting down a civilian airliner
because they basically just, they didn't have the room to maneuver.
So they're like, well, crap, we have no other option. Shoot it down. Right.
They only had like, tens of seconds to deal with the situation,
which was a major part of the problem. Right. They were under that time pressure.
And do you think an autonomous system would have done something different?
Uh,
well,
I, well, it depends on how it's programmed.
I mean, part of it would be the autonomous system in theory.
Well, no part of the reason they shot it down, they got the time zones mixed up,
didn't we just talk about how bad software is there?
They had actual data that there was that flight
coming out of that airport at that time.
But because of the way the time zones were all
up because there were like three different time zones involved,
like where it was taking off from where it was going to and then like the time zone,
the US Finns
or something,
they, like,
basically messed that up and didn't recognize it as a scheduled civilian airliner.
Ok. Ok.
And also the transponder code,
what happened is the military was flying jets out of the same thing.
And so the guy initially picked up a transponder code from a
military flight and that got attached apparently or something to the,
like
the civilian you know, radar track.
So again, I mean,
potentially an autonomous system would have identified it correctly and been,
like, nope,
-- that's a civilian airliner taking off on time. I don't know.
-- I don't know.
I still feel like autonomous missiles are bad.
Well, the reality is, you know,
weapon systems of the future are going to be more and more autonomous and again,
part of it is that reaction time, you know,
how are you as a human being going to deal with a drone
coming in at you with like a couple 100 ft away from you?
Yeah, I mean, I'm not generally in favor of like auto
responses because then, you know, we always had World War II.
What was it in like 1983 when the Russian, you know, launch detection system
-- was like,
-- right. Right.
It picked up something else and thought they were under attack.
It was, I think it was a reflection of the moon or something.
-- It
-- was
-- something ridiculous.
-- And,
and luckily that, you know, Soviet General guy was like, I don't think this is real.
-- Let's just wait a few seconds and minutes and see what happens. I love
-- it.
So, so the next thing
while they're being attacked by missiles is
they're, they're freaking out and trying to escape.
And Arthur says, why doesn't someone just push that button?
And everyone's like, oh, we can't do that and no one knows why though.
And he says, well, why
and I feel like
this comes back to our kind of compliance based security
advice or rather just old security advice maybe is,
you know,
people will say things like,
well, you need to change your password every 30 days or 60 days and you could say,
well, well, why?
And they don't know. Right. They, they don't know.
-- And,
-- yeah,
because I can't imagine an tacker is going to sniff your password and then, like,
wait for 90 days to use it.
-- Uh, well,
-- they're going to use it. Like, right away.
The bigger problem is just that people change your password a lot.
They either pick a really, really bad password
or they,
or they make other foolish choices around it.
Versus anyway, the idea is we have lots of security advice where you're like, oh,
you can't do that and then they'll be like, well, well, why not?
And we're like, I don't know.
And I mean, this,
this comes back to a lot of the discussions
we have where we try to talk about security from
a very practical standpoint and there's a lot of security
people that will disagree with the things we say,
but they probably can't back up their ideas
with any sort of RR reason.
Right.
No, it's, I mean, well, even I, you know,
I've stopped running antivirus and I do occasionally reinstall it,
scan my entire system and I'm like, well,
either I've got, like,
the root kit installed that is avoiding it or I don't have any viruses
and based on the fact that I still have money in my bank account,
you know,
it would appear that, yeah, you don't, well, and, you know, more to the point, like,
especially with, on Linux,
like, I know there are some Linux viruses but they're so rare.
Like they're literally, you know, it's just all advanced,
persistent threat in the Linux world actually.
You know, you know what's really funny about that is
I read a story about Os X last week showing that
the number of OS X malware detections went up by,
by like 1000% or something
last year.
And the researcher who found this basically said, look,
I know this looks really bad, but we're still
at
like tens of thousands.
And you got to remember like the Windows world is in the tens of millions.
Well, you, you cannot run Java, you cannot run flash,
you cannot run PDF or apparently Microsoft office again.
Microsoft office has zero days floating around again for it. I know,
you know, if you're not running in protected mode, your bones.
Well,
shouldn't we all just be using like office 365 now and then
-- it's Microsoft's problem
-- that still installs like the clients on your machine?
Oh, does it really?
I have no idea. I haven't used
-- it.
-- I had to edit some slides for RS A and keynote.
Their keynote templates were just like screwed up.
So I ended up having to use powerpoint
and yeah, it installs.
But what's interesting is, for example, like when you do a file, convert it,
like ships it off to Microsoft to convert the file and then ships it back to you.
Like it doesn't do it on the local system. And I'm like
Bar right then, you know, that's interesting.
-- And
-- there's a local client and it does some stuff in the cloud.
Why not just do like Google Docs?
Well, and when I say a local client, like, you know,
it's still like a couple 100 megabytes of installed stuff, right?
But there's a lot of stuff that goes on in the cloud that seems bonkers.
Well, it makes sense because you want to be able to have here's the problem, right?
People will still need or want but maybe need even
that full offline working experience.
Yeah, but like you can still do that. I mean Google Docs says offline mode, right?
But we're talking about stuff like Excel and powerpoint where you have like
97 billion features of which like,
you know, a 0.03% of people use that feature.
But it's like, you know,
all the different people using all the
-- different features ultimately
-- may maybe that's fair.
I, I admit that's one of the things I love about the group
docs experience because it doesn't have very many features because I, I like,
-- I'm really bad at word and
-- I use like three things in Excel
and I look at the rest of the interface and I'm like,
I don't even know what that does.
Like, I know how to use, like drop down filters and like,
you know,
you know what's actually really funny about that
is my wife is really good at spreadsheet.
She,
she got all this training in college and she
took all these classes and stuff and it was,
it was like a huge deal
and
every now and then I'll ask her for help.
But like, usually I just write a pearl script that does whatever I need it to do
it, like reads in a CS V file.
It does what I need done and then it outputs
a CS V file and then it just reimport that file
and it's really funny because every now and then she'll be like, how did you know how,
how, how do you have to set up to calculate that?
I'm like, and I wrote a Python script and
-- it's just funny.
-- No, I do the same with like
akin said and cut and people are like,
how did you make Excel do this?
And I'm like, I have no idea how that would work in Excel.
I know they say like, I know exactly what you mean. You gotta love it.
It's ridiculous. But anyway, anyway. All right. Uh
So
the Mariia
scene is also bizarre because it kind of magically shifts from Mariia
to earth
-- because they're rebuilding the earth.
-- Well, yeah, like the whole Sl
Bart
fast threats thing was like, I just found that scene so awkward.
You need to listen to the radio show and listen to SL
Bart
FSS conversation with Arthur. And it's
fantastic.
They, they really screwed up the conversation in, in the movie,
but on the radio show it's to die for.
It's one of my favorite scenes actually the way
he kind of threatens Arthur with the late,
the late Arthur death.
It's, it's very good and the voice is very funny
and just the whole thing is great.
So,
so find the radio show and listen to it and you won't be disappointed in that scene.
So anyway, I can ignore that just because I, I have the,
the happy memory of the radio show.
But then so, so they're on meth
and nothing overly exciting happens and then they go to the earth
because they're, they're making a new earth which is insane, whatever,
they're going to finish the
-- job.
-- But that,
that's actually like a huge point actually is
in the original story,
they were going to rebuild the earth,
but it would have to run again for like 10 million years.
It was just cheaper to come up with.
Well, that's when they thought, wait, Arthur Dent has the answer in his brain.
We'll just give him a bunch of money if he gives it to us is kind of where that ended and,
and, well,
whatever.
And
they, they kind of go back to Earth
and Arthur uh brutally murders the mice, which
I don't feel too bad about
-- it. But it's
-- like, well, they're just a manifestation of that.
-- What is it, like, 1313 dimensional entity or whatever?
-- So, are they dead though?
You think they get mad and, like, kill you or something? Right.
-- Like, I mean,
-- seriously, maybe they're more forgiving than us.
They were going to cut out Arthur's brain,
but that was just a purely practical thing.
And remember they remember from the book,
it was like we're just going to replace you with
like a whatever a little script that says like what?
No, I don't let's have tea,
you know, and then, and that's basically like 90% of what he said.
So yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Really? How many people could we replace with like 10 lines of dialogue?
You know,
judging by the fact that we have interactive voice response systems on phones now,
I don't think we should discuss this because I think there's many
layers of nuance and misappropriation that could come into play here.
So we're just going to move on.
We we eventually get to the scene where the vo guns are shooting everyone.
Marvin says vo
guns are the worst marksmen in the galaxy, which I love because
if you had a group of terrible marksmen, why would you make them your,
I guess physical security.
It's, you know, the lowest bidder on the contract maybe.
I don't know, it, you'd think if you were overly bureaucratic, like the bogus.
Well, but think about, I mean, haven't you read about, like, those, you know,
these stories, like, I know locally there's been, you know,
there's a variety of officer involved shootings and like,
there's been cases where, you know,
they try gunfire with somebody and there's like, you know,
50 or 100 shots fired and they, like,
the guy's not critically injured.
Ok. So
-- that's a different problem.
-- So these things aren't as simple as, you know.
Well, no shooting at anything is surprisingly difficult to do,
especially in a very high pressure situation.
Actually, you and I were just talking about this before. The show is I shot,
I was,
we were talking about firearms and I, I shot competitively when I was younger.
Like, I've shot like millions of rounds probably because I was like, I,
I was in AAA team that we would shoot 22 rifles at targets.
And like, I, I've got a box full of trophies actually, I was really good at it.
But, but anyway, the deal is though,
one of the things you have to learn to do is how to basically calm yourself.
So your heart's beating very slowly because obviously,
if your heartbeat you can't shoot.
And you got to think when you're in a situation like that where things are crazy,
your heart's going nuts.
You can't shoot straight
and honestly hitting a moving target is insanely difficult to do, even if you're,
like, fully prepared and rested.
Now, add in chaos. I get it right. I understand.
-- Well, and a target maybe even shooting back at you.
-- Well, that's true.
I, I've never been in that situation. Right. I've only ever shot a paper that c,
so anyway, I, I can, I can forget that. Right. But
anyway, anyway, Bogans are terrible. I love the part where Marvin shoots all the
Bogans with the prospective gun
and they all, like, start crying
on the ground.
The point of view gun, not the perspective gun
-- but the
-- point of view gun. That's it. Sorry, that, that's, that's something else.
And I was going to say we need the point of view gun.
Not so much because we need to make people see security,
-- but
-- we need to understand them.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly.
Like,
seriously we need like normal people to shoot the
whole security industry with the point of view gun
so we can grasp their frustrations with us and what the actual problems are.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Anyway, I love that, that part. I actually did enjoy
and,
and I must say that Ellen Rickman doing Marvin's voice is
awesome because I love Alan Rickman and I love Marvin.
And
again,
uh, now that I, I feel that, that I keep bringing this up,
that the radio Marvin in the radio show is
unbelievably awesome.
He makes the radio show and, and in the movie, he was kind of minor. Honestly,
he put a reason big role.
I mean, without him, they, they wouldn't have gone anywhere.
I mean, he's a much better driver
remember in the escape plot
and with his hand and all that. But, um,
the other thing, uh, going back to that scene where, you know,
Marvin shoots all of the, uh, the Vogons
just before it, remember there was a group of
Vogons coming around the back. Uh
Ford Prefect charges them with his towel doing his little war cry.
And I mean,
and I think that's a really important point is like
you have to be able to actually identify real threats,
you know?
Not. Oh my God, what was it? Oh, yeah, he's got a towel run away.
Now, realistically speaking, if you actually read the books,
the towels can have some pretty significant powers, you know, like his,
for example,
has it soaked in micronutrients and it's got some
wires threaded into it for strength and some other,
you know, things and
you can apparently buy specialty towels with, you know, various other things.
So, you know, I think
that
the towel could be a realistic threat in that universe.
That's one thing I look at, you know, in our infosec is like
people, you know, a perfect example. Oh, here's a great example
tying back to passwords.
Uh Do you remember a few weeks ago or two weeks ago, somebody threatened to, like,
wipe a bajillion Apple accounts if they weren't paid a ransom.
And did you hear what the real deal on that is?
I did not.
So they have a password dump from like a bunch of other stuff of which some
are valid icloud accounts
because people use the same password everywhere. Oh, certainly.
Like if you've reused your password
and it's been dumped elsewhere, for sure. Yeah. So you can get into your icloud, like
from orbit,
assuming you don't have two fa enabled, which, you know,
Apple is becoming more and more aggressive about seriously,
you know, like I just set up a new ipad for my son and it, like, make, like,
I don't want to use two of a on it.
Right, because he's, you know, it would just be frustrating for him and, you know,
his kid's ipad, you know, and I had to make sure, you know,
that thing didn't get enabled and, you know, that's the thing.
And then the guy pointed out, you know, that Apple too has this list of accounts on a,
they're taking proactive measures,
you know,
maybe making people change their accounts or whatever.
But, yeah, I mean, and that's the thing that really gets me is, you know,
how often do we correctly identify the real threats?
You know,
just what always gets me about PC I compliance is every
time there's been a major data breach of credit card info.
They've always been at places that were PC I certified.
Yeah. I mean, that's everywhere with credit cards is generally certified.
It's,
it's complicated how it all works together and I
don't think it's a huge surprise to anyone that
PC I Compliance isn't a magic bullet.
Now, the one thing I would say though is
imagine what a lot of these organizations would look
like if they didn't have a PC I Auditor,
do they think they make certain changes?
It would be a total train wreck.
Well, like, back to that, what was it? The Dutch one, I want to say, did you
notar where they had, like, the viruses on their, you know, that certificate,
authority with the
workstation on the internet with viruses and stuff.
-- I mean,
-- how many, how many times have you heard about,
like flash drives or other gear that shipped with viruses on?
Because they're using literally someone's computer
to provision the software. It's crazy.
Well, yeah, the manufacturers, those, uh, digital, uh,
picture frames are shipped with the virus or
no, the phones now that are shipping the android phones that are shipping with, uh,
-- Trojan stuff, pre installed. Biwa
-- built in.
-- Yeah.
-- Like what? That was a couple of weeks ago and it's,
they still haven't pinpointed where in the supply chain that's happening. Which is
crazy to me. I mean,
I know it's terrifying.
I, I own one of the phone, the phone I have isn't on the list,
but it's part of that supply chain, which is horrifying to me.
You know what this reminds me of.
I don't remember if I've ever told this story before on the podcast and if I haven't,
I'm sure I'll tell it again.
Is
long ago
I worked tech support in I PE and when someone would need the installed discs,
we just literally made the disks off of the
local laptop that the tech support guys used.
And every now and then someone would call up and say, hey,
my virus program says you just have a virus.
We'd be like, oh yeah, that's a false positive. They have nothing to worry about.
Right?
And then one day I
was working on a Saturday,
it was a slow date and I thought I'm going to buy or scan
the computer here because I don't think we've done it in a long time.
And I wonder if the people calling are calling because there's really a virus
and there was really a virus.
And so we, we basically infected like everyone's computer.
And I remember I went to the boss and like, what do we do?
We, we've been, we've infected almost all of our customers.
-- We
-- clean it and we
bury it. The guy was like,
nothing, we're gonna do nothing.
Just don't talk about this. I don't want you to tell me about this.
-- If anyone calls and asks you send it to me, don't don't
-- worry about it.
I have to assume this is one of the reasons, you know,
a lot of I SPS now offer a security package which
is typically like a rebranded a V scanner from whoever,
you know.
Well, not specifically this but just in general, it's like,
-- you know, we tried, we offered something.
-- It's,
yeah, that's probably part of it.
But I mean, man, I just, I remember that it was, it was madness.
Anyway. Anyway, uh and that, that basically brings us to the end of the movie, right?
Is there any, any other points you want to hit on before we kind of sum this up here
a well back in the middle of the film, one of the scenes I most enjoyed
was the authentication scene between
Sao
and Ford.
Remember when he gets on the ship and he's like Ford is that you
-- the crazy handshake thing with the feet and the hands and
-- you know, yeah,
the whole little handshake, that little authentication dance they go through,
you know, with the heel clicks and everything.
I mean, the world has had secret handshakes for a long time. Is it a secret handshake?
I don't know. Is it a movie? Maybe whatever? But you, you have a valid point is
that that would not be unreasonable to have secret handshakes and whatnot in,
in an environment where you,
I, I guess had a lot of silly things going on.
So anyway, I enjoyed that.
So anyway, here's II, I wrote a little summary here for the very end is as,
as I'm sure anyone has figured out at this point that I'm not a huge fan of this movie,
but I love the story and I suspect a part of that is
a movie can't capture a lot of the nuance that a book can.
And the reason the radio show captures some of it
is because the radio show is like 23 hours long.
Well, it's like the original, the BBC TV series, right? Like it was,
-- right.
-- And that's really, that's like eight hours, right?
-- There was a lot of content and
-- that's true. And that's true.
And so anyway,
but the thing I kept thinking of as I was writing down my
notes and re evaluating what I saw and what was going on is
I, I feel like security has the same problem
where we have a book sized nuance
as to how things work together and how we explain everything,
-- but we only have the amount of time of a movie to explain
-- it.
-- Well, it keeps changing.
-- It does. And this is one of our struggles is
we can't distill a lifetime's worth of security knowledge
into a one hour class or a one page
like a little diagram or something like that. And
this is what I feel like is one of the challenges that, that we have to figure out.
And I'm not saying this is optional.
We have to figure out how to
tell people what they need to know how they need to know it.
And I feel like in the example of this movie
they failed
now, I think it might be impossible.
I don't know if I had to guess it's not, I think you just need someone who's capable
of telling the right story.
And, and additionally, Douglas Adams is not a screenwriter,
so he might be the reason
this wasn't very good Lord forbid. Right.
Well, you're also going up against, you know, the, the, the books just have.
It's like the, you know, it reminds me of Lord of the Rings.
But basically I think what it boils down to is apple pie. I knew this baker
who would not make apple pie
just wouldn't make it. He'd make Saskatoon pie, he'd make peach pie.
-- He'd make all the other pies.
-- Saskatoon pie,
Saskatoon berries.
You just gave me the technically correct answer.
I don't know what you're talking about.
It's, it's much better than a blueberry anyways Google
Saskatoon berries.
But the point is he would not make apple pie under any circumstances.
The reason being is everybody was like this isn't as good
as my mom's apple pie and then bitch about it.
So he's like, you know what?
No, I'm just, I'm not competing with your childhood memories
-- and he's
-- not wrong.
This is a huge problem people have is they remember what they want to from the past
-- and even security people do this and
-- even if it's corrected,
it might not be corrected.
You know, this whole thing of like, oh,
you know, don't let the Attackers into your network.
Well, yeah, now we have this thing called platform as a service
and we're going to sell them access for four cents an hour. It's true. Right.
You know, it's, it's,
I like almost everything I've written at the meta level
in the Linux Administrative Security Guide 20 some years ago
is now wrong. Like it's literally now the business case is no. Do exactly that.
Like, yeah,
let people install the software they want and run it as route if they want.
Like, who cares that they're paying us? Sure.
Yeah. You know, let them have access to hardware.
I remember Google talking about PC fuzzing because it's like, well, wait, you know,
we're selling access to GPUS and somebody might hack one of those Gpus and
then use that GP U to attack the rest of the hardware system.
Yes and no, I mean, they're,
they're overly altruistic compared to most or maybe they're not altruistic,
they just have different problems.
But you get the idea.
I looked up these Saskatoon berries and they don't grow anywhere near me,
which is probably why I've never heard of them before.
It's only a Canadian thing as far as I know. And it's very seasonal.
It does swoop down into portions of the US.
But,
but for the most part it looks like it's kind
of to the northwestern ish region of North America.
Yeah. It's like Alaska gets them too lucky. Alaska.
We've been, we've been going out and out about this movie for quite some time.
Uh, fundamentally
it's,
I won't complain.
I don't feel like I wasted an hour and a half of my life re-watching this
to take notes and talk about a security
episode based on Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
But I didn't lie.
I probably would have had more fun with the book,
but it would have also been a 6.5 hour long podcast episode.
So there's that
of it as well. I mean, you figure we're over an hour now.
Well, it's like the Lord of the Rings, right?
You know, it's just, it's a big book and the movies, you know,
-- I don't,
-- I could, I could go on about that one too, but other security themes today,
there's probably some, I don't think there's a ton.
-- Oh, there's tons.
-- It's complicated.
-- No, we're not doing this.
-- Is that your new go to? I think that's your new go to.
It's a very easy way to stop a conversation. It's complicated
and people generally are willing to accept that as an answer I found.
And so it's kind of one of those, uh magic weapons, right where,
where it's, it's, it's not unlike again, we,
we talked about navigating bureaucracy or navigating people,
you can tell them it's complicated and more often than not,
they'll accept that as an answer.
So
there we go. There we go, everybody. It's complicated.
All right, folks, thank you so much for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com
and see
there will be no links for this show
because it's just about the movie.
But you can look at past episodes, for example.
And at the show, links on that, we will have links over to Twitter and Facebook
where you can connect with Kurt and I
and send us various notes.
I'm sure many of you will have opinions about this episode.
Please let us know, especially Kurt.
He loves feedback and you can yell at him all you want
and we will probably respond
and I guess nothing else. Thank you so much for listening.
-- Until next time folks take care and Kurt, you have a fantastic day. You
-- too.