Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 116
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
I almost feel bad for, for making you.
You show up as, as everyone can hear, Kurt clearly has a cold.
I'm actually over and I feel fine.
-- Yeah,
-- that sounds like a lie.
But anyway, we have a guest today which is why I forced Kurt to,
to come in and talk to us.
But we have,
we have Michael
Piacenti from Hitch Partners. Why don't you say? Hello, Michael. Hello, everyone.
Awesome. And why don't you tell us what hitch partners does?
I'm actually really excited for this conversation because it's going
to be a bit different than we usually have.
Absolutely. Thank you for having me. First of all.
Yeah, Hitch Partners is a boutique executive search firm.
Uh We handle most of the US and we are
really focused in a very particular niche which is in the
executive search area for C OS and heads of security,
particularly in those areas where companies are
looking for their modern version of their co
in what most people call these days. DEVS CS or security engineering
where the emphasis is less on infosec and compliance and more so on
protecting the assets in the clouds. So that, that's really the main,
the primary focus of the company.
We are a small group, uh kind of spread out throughout the United States and
handle about uh anywhere from 6 to 8 searches at a time. Give or take
that. That's awesome.
And, and the thing I'm really excited about here is we met at RS a last year
and, and you were really talking about kind of the modern co and,
and how the rules have all changed.
And that,
that made me so excited to talk to someone about that because I often feel like
we, we still have that old mindset in many ways.
So why, why don't we like, what, what is the, let's compare,
what's the old cio and what's kind of the, the new modern Cio?
-- What, what should we be talking
-- about? Just to make sure what is the co again
chief information security officer,
which there and lies half of the challenge because the eye is what's going away
some from a nomenclature perspective
and it's being shortened to a chief security officer or a CSO. But see, so
ciso is the more common nomenclature that uh is sort of,
it's sort of like saying a Cio would be the uh the common language in the it world.
So that's what a CIO is.
And that this is the person that would run
the leader that would run the teams and the compliance, the information, security,
application, security and, uh, as of late, um,
or the cloud security functions and product
security functions depending on the company.
Awesome.
So, ok. Ok. So back to my question now,
what is, I guess,
what did it used to be like?
And, and what, what is changing?
And I guess why it would be, I'd love to hear about the why?
Because I suspect you see things most people don't.
Yeah. And I'll give you a little bit of history.
It just sort of ends up being my history.
But when I first started in executive recruiting, I was in it for about 13 years,
mostly tech ops and I was a storage architect or storage,
storage engineering before that.
And, uh, what we noticed, um when I first got into executive recruiting,
we were doing cio searches, um, heads of it and cio searches and
the CIO, the head of security was always kind of a deputy under the CIO
and this had been going on for a decade or so
where you had a chief security officer reporting under a CIO.
That was a pretty common
organizational structure. Right around 2011, 12, we started noticing
that the, the chief security officer started not reporting under the CIO
and then it became by 2014, 15, it was pretty common that, uh
in, in at least smaller to mid size and growing companies
still is the case for enterprises that ac O reports under the CIO.
But in most of the other population, it has moved
into other areas.
In fact, you know,
at the beginning of the year we had eight
chief security officers reporting to eight different functions in,
in in the executive level um from board level to
CEO CFO coo so on and so forth, but almost only one of them reported to a CIO.
And so that's, that's where we started seeing the change um from,
you know, what was a chief security officer to
what is now a modern version. And the thing that, of course, uh like many other
trends in technology, uh technologies that have changed,
it was really the kind of move from VM to
the cloud or VM to open source um containers, microservices.
And even before that,
just moving the data that you're trying to protect into the cloud
and we can get really deep into that what that means.
That's really where we saw the change in the
uh existing co definition versus the uh the modern,
what you had was um you had an emphasis
on for maybe 1520 years for a chief security officer
that was really protecting the network perimeter.
And uh what we would commonly call information security.
There was also a pretty strong uh focus on compliance and
regulatory depending on uh the the industry that the company was in
and then we started seeing uh the introduction of apps E
and, and by the way, I should mention that these nomenclatures and these,
these terms um
change from one company to another, which makes
the challenge, right?
And that's one of the things we, we do on our searches,
we come up with a common language first that the com the company can,
can use when they go out to search. But that's, that's later in the conversation.
But the, the network perimeter is really what we were trying to protect.
Um, trying to keep the, the company from doing irresponsible things
uh internally and try to keep the bad guys from coming in uh to the, to the fortress.
Um When the cloud came about now you have a totally different
uh mode of software development
where
you now are putting, uh, you know, your, your,
your crown jewels in the cloud from the developers and the product uh teams,
uh engineering, um are really driving, you know, much stronger,
faster products into the cloud using, utilizing the cloud,
which is wonderful. Um But, um, the hygiene piece
uh, that we didn't quite get in original CSOS carried over into the cloud and, and,
and in fact, has gotten worse.
And so really the modern day co um, the way I would define it
is really more about adversary hunting and, and really, and,
and being able to define that for your company.
So it's not just so much about protecting the network assets
and the network perimeter.
Um But it's really more about what, why, how, how do I as an executive leader
focus on um educating, guiding,
not often telling uh because developers don't necessarily
listening for that.
Um But really partner, I would say partnering with them politically,
with the developers to say, you know, here,
here are a group of controls that we would like to
make sure that you see in your application in your product.
And um you know, we don't need, we don't need to be perfect here.
Um But, but this is the reason why you need to put this,
these, these best practices in place or these,
these controls in place because this is exactly where the adversaries are getting
in and they can get in using your code as the vehicle,
you know, Mr and Mrs developer.
And um so having the uh having the developers really understand
those motives um and how they're, how they're going about that, in my opinion,
is the difference right now
between what was AC O and what is currently ac So this
this common language,
uh this understanding of how systems and data work within the cloud really
differentiates um the modern day co and being able to have that conversation,
being able to,
being able to go through and,
and um really guide the rest of the company and the product,
the product side of the company, the engineering side that,
that's really the key issue right now and this is why it makes it such a unique, um,
probably one of the hardest searches
technology has seen and most companies
are really struggling with that, which we can get into.
Yeah.
Oh, man,
definitely one thing I've seen obviously working with the cloud security lines,
you know, is, is security has definitely gone from sort of a, well, let's be blunt,
gone from a third class citizen to a second class citizen.
And now security is being, you know, a first class citizen. Right. It's something
we have to do because, you know, the age of, oh, I might not get attacked is gone.
Right. Everybody gets attacked.
And one thing I'm still kind of not quite understanding with our industry is why,
why do you think we sort of still have this security is very much
split, I don't want to say separate, but it's sort of, you know,
we have a cio and a cio why
something I've never understood is why isn't the cio
also, you know, doing the duties of the CIS or does it need to be split?
Is there sort of that,
you know, protect attack,
-- adversarial piece that needs to be split or something like that or
-- that,
that is a fantastic question.
And there's a lot of his,
I, I believe that there's a lot of history in this so
we watched and this won't be a very popular statement,
but we sort of watched the demise of the CIO S
scope over the course of the last 15 years or so
where they were, you know, at one point managing infrastructure.
Um when we had actual physical assets and data centers, that's the world I came from
to the business applications which at one point were managed by the CIO.
And now a lot of times the business certainly
drives that. And then when breaks, they come to the CIO,
they were running governance, they were running compliance,
they were running security
and slowly the CIO s role.
And, and again, I'm,
I should probably qualify this by saying this is a kind of a mid size
some larger.
But, you know, again, the, the, the,
the Fortune 500 fortune 100 probably still have the more traditional
model for the most part. Um What I'm referring to is this sort of mid size company.
They, they really do have
a challenge in that their CIO is no longer
managing some of these key functions that
the CIO would be responsible for protecting
the, for instance, the CIO is for the most part,
not managing anything in the cloud that's usually handled by DEV
ops or in, in security terms, Dev
se
ops the leader there.
Uh the head of cloud operations uh is very different than the CIO.
And so you have this sort of uh divide in skill sets and,
you know, whatever it may be
that this really divide, I would say in scope, that's where,
that's where it came from.
At least that's where we believe it came from.
Uh Again, very rarely do we see C cells even reporting to cio S now.
And when they do, as soon as the cloud piece comes up,
they have to figure out how to embed it into engineering.
And that's just, that's kind of an allergic reaction.
So therefore, the CSO tends to be on, on their own and build their own organization.
Sometimes they're embedded within product or engineering,
sometimes they're a separate unit, you know, reporting in, directly into the CEO.
Um There's just so many different combinations
but that, that's, that's sort of the history behind it.
I, I do think that we need a separate function.
Uh I know in our searches when we hear that the CIO will report into the CIO and,
you know, essentially security reporting into it.
Uh for what it's worth,
we are fine with that as long as um
they understand that that if they're developing products that are
going to be put in the cloud or they're
developing software that will be delivered via the cloud,
that there's a, uh there'll be a time where the
cell will need to split off from it and uh remain independent
and there may be some really tough conversations to come.
No, I, I like that.
And in fact,
this is something Kurt and I have talked about more
than once is no company has a Chief electricity officer
and they, they probably did at one time, right.
Whereas
kind of the, the thanks to the cloud,
the traditional view computing is changing quite a
lot where it's becoming really a commodity service.
And now it's more about using that commodity to add value versus it,
it kind of existing in its own.
Right.
Well, simply put there are entire companies and
well, I won't say entire industries yet, but
there are definitely entire companies based in the cloud, you know, Netflix.
Uh there's a couple of banks now, you know, the cloud security lines. We,
the first thing I did when I took over uh it director
uh eight years ago was I made sure we had no servers, you know,
I made sure everything was cloud based because
no,
I used to have servers and they would fail at three in the morning and I'd have to wake
up and drag my butt down to the colo to fix them and I don't care for that,
to be honest.
Um And yeah, as you said, you know, like
people, yeah,
I think we're definitely moving to a trend of people
just buying the services and the systems that they need
rather than, you know, building everything in house.
And so I, like, I'm really wondering, is there just a generational?
It's like there's almost like a different language
or a different culture with this whole,
you know, comfort of outsourcing to the cloud, you know, sometimes what are very,
-- the things that support very much the core business.
-- Right.
Absolutely.
I, I think that's part of the challenge is um there's a nomenclature channel,
there's nomenclature difference, there's a cultural difference.
There's a,
um
there's, there's just an age difference, um just to put it out there.
I mean, you know, we have um a majority of cloud based
um developers um kind of in the, you know, millennial category and maybe Gen X, um
you know, where I might be uh that are, you know,
trying to work through um sometimes their counterparts and security,
sometimes not.
Um sometimes, you know, the engineering and product teams uh
definitely have a different technology or
a different conversation or different language.
And that's part of the challenge is that you
really need to have someone as a head of security
today. Not, not that network uh perimeter security or infosec and
traditional info
compliance are any less important. I should really stress that. Um
I think the challenge with the position
now is that everything has become important,
the position has gotten so large from a scope perspective
that really uh in the, in the recruiting world,
we call it the Purple Squirrel and it's just, it's just not obtainable.
Um Sometimes we're having to guide our customers with,
you know, what you want,
what you need and what you're going to see and
what you're going to get are actually 33 different things.
And uh and the reason why is because now you have a whole,
a whole different to your point.
Kurt, you have a,
you have a whole different understanding language nomenclature around dev
se
ops or security engineering or product security.
I see those terms as interchangeable.
Uh Some might disagree but from a recruiting perspective
that that's really the skill set. That is a totally different language.
It's a language of how do you speak to your developers.
And at the same time, how do you take what dev
secs
is doing and then explain it to your executive team.
And oh, by the way, how do you explain that to your audit team and to your board?
Um And, and essentially, it's all about prioritizing the work. Um
If the work is coming out of um
if the work of trying to chase the bad guys is happening
um at a, a DEV ops level,
um then you need you as the executive leading security need to try to
find a common language to explain that to every different faction of your company.
Um That is a,
that is a skill set that is very difficult to learn. Uh It means that the candidates
that we work with would have to have been exposed
at a scale that would have been a cross functional
and they would have had to work on projects that are cross functional.
They would have had to work at executive level developer level.
It's, it's really a fascinating challenge right now.
We, we're building an entire company based on it, but it's,
you know, how do you build apps um
that are defensible at the same time,
how do you communicate and how do you do
that to different walks of life within your organization?
Everyone has a different experience and everyone
has a different definition of security.
I would say, um we have a process uh within our
uh our discovery process, it's very intrusive.
So we'll spend a few days on site and we'll
sit in product meetings, we'll sit in engineering meetings,
we'll interview all of what we call, interviewing the interviewers.
I mean, just, you know,
short meetings to get an understanding of
what everyone's definition of the security is
partially,
we do this to come up with a common language so
that when we go through the search and let's say,
Kurt, you're the, the candidate for CISO, you're going to hear from the CEO,
they're looking for an
infosec leader.
But yet, uh Josh is the head of engineering and he's talking about Dev
ops and then the candidate comes away from the interview saying I,
I don't know what they're looking for, really, they are looking for the same thing,
they're just using a different language.
And so, um it,
it really helps us get a better understanding of
what that company's um IQ is around security.
Um, but everyone has a different experience.
It's, it's, it's a fascinating time for security and, and it really has come from,
uh, a second class citizen to, you know, what?
We go to the back room to the boardroom almost instantly over the last few years.
-- That's, uh, it's wonderful.
-- That's awesome.
So, I guess let's, let's ask like a, a slightly more direct question, let's say,
let's say I'm looking for
security talent.
What I, I guess
what, what would you
say are some of the more important qualities today specifically?
Because I know you mentioned things like being able to talk to the board
and be able to talk to developers and like those are two drastically different
skill sets, right?
Mhm.
Do you, do you,
do you have like a ranking of which
particular things are more valuable than others maybe?
Or, or am I just talking crazy?
No, not at all actually.
Um What we find is that the, now again, I'm going to qualify this,
um if a company is delivering their service or product
via the cloud, which it seems that, you know,
majority of companies in the majority of industries are moving towards,
it may, may not be their mainstay product or main main all the way there.
They may be running in a hybrid environment um or private
gated cloud versus public cloud um using AWS or TCP or
Azure
and they may not be all the way there.
They may not be all the way into microservices or running
goer neti they again, they may not be all the way there.
But the, the key differentiator
is this ability, I'd say the number one priority when I look at um
you know, why did this client pick this,
this candidate over this one? It's, it's, it's,
it's how the candidates, how the cio leaders were able to explain
this very complex challenge of
the adversaries or after my code,
how do I teach everyone in the organization
um how to protect against that from writing the code to
dealing with controls to the audit process, everything.
And that, that's probably the number one priority right now.
Again, in, in the, in the small subset of clients that I work with, which are
small to medium businesses running. Um
And these are everything from start ups to multibillion dollar companies,
but they're, you know, they're not the largest companies in the world.
And these are, uh you know, this is,
this is probably the biggest differentiator if you can find someone
and everyone has a different definition of what that is.
That's either
someone that's currently writing code all the way to,
I've been there, done that.
Uh C so that is just able to explain it in a way with a really strong command
and control that everyone believes in and, and there's, there's trust.
Um but that,
that's probably the number one priority a after that
um I think really having a very strong and,
and by the way, this is tied to
the general principles of a really strong uh co is is having those builds blocks from
kind of more traditional infosec the understanding of how the internet works,
understanding how networks work,
um how to protect both physical and cloud based perimeters.
These are, these are areas that probably would be, you know,
definitely a second priority if not right there up at the top, it's really having
such a great recipe for security hygiene at
a, at a growing organization.
Um And that stems from just uh kind of the been there done that in the infosec world
and an
AEC world again that these are terms are kind of interchangeable in some,
in some cases.
So those are the big ones, the, the, the other ones that we see that the,
the two others are,
like you said, the ability to communicate at,
at the executive level and this is everyone from board level.
Um We have had positions that report directly to the board CEO level,
communicating with the CFO so that they understand what level
of compliance and governance they need to uh drive.
That is a big one for sure. That's uh some candidates tend to fall.
We, we call that, you know, they're not a finished product yet,
still working through,
you know,
their executive gravitas and a lot of it's just because they haven't been exposed
to that level.
And quite frankly, they, you know, they've just been dealing with major
complex technical problems and may not have presented more than once
or twice to a board or something along those lines.
So
we try to let clients know this is,
this is what you're going to see if you want the emphasis on DEV
SE
S,
you might have to give up a portion on the gravitas
piece and it takes a little while for that to happen.
The other, the other key area is sales enablement.
C OS have always been sort of the, the, the, the front runner,
Cio S and C OS for the most part have been the front runner to say, let,
let's get on the phone with partners,
get on the phone,
with clients be out there at conferences and talk
about what XYZ is doing within our security.
Um That makes people feel comfortable and confident about their ability to,
to make this product uh whole or secure. Now, more than ever with
a SAS, you know, with
SAS being the predominant um architecture or methodology.
Uh We, we've seen CSOS being hired in companies of 50
um whereas before they were first being, you know,
the first time you would see a CSO in a company is when they hit, you know,
500 or 700 people
at 100 million. Now you're seeing a totally different dynamic which is
now the CEO is being not only,
not really used as a sales engineer but to really say we have major, you know,
you take a small SAS company and
of course, if they're going after enterprise clients,
they almost immediately need AC O when they're making the sale.
Um The first one that's going to be asking the questions
about whether this SAS space application that's running in the cloud
is, that's, that's, that's holding my, my crown jewels and my
and my um my treasure trove of data.
I want to be on the phone with the CEO of that of that small software company to ensure
that they have the right methodology and the right recipe.
So that I feel my, my, my uh data is protected, my company's data is protected.
So the sales enablement piece is becoming a um or has become over the last few years,
a major decision maker. In fact, we've seen some CSO searches
that are really focused on that alone. In other words, the technical pieces are,
you know, we just need you to understand well enough,
but really we need you to be customer facing and out there
again, not as a sales person, but really, I need you to be instilling confidence
that our applications that our products are
are sound and uh you can get it by the litmus test of a of a Fortune 500 co.
So those are the kind of the main areas
that's one of the things I've been wondering about,
you know, from my work with the CV project is
how do companies signal security maturity?
Right.
In their process and conversely, you know,
what actually does security maturity look like?
Right. Because there's a lot of companies that
I've heard about and I'm like, oh, I've, I've never heard of them.
I don't know what the heck they're doing in the
security space and it turns out they're doing really good
things and then there's other companies that appear to be
doing really good things in the security space and then,
you know, they get hacked really badly.
Um, so it sounds like that's definitely, I mean,
it sounds to me like with, without ac, so number one, I mean, yeah,
how can you be expected to have sort of a secure maturity response
if you can't even put enough value on it, you know, to hire somebody to lead it? Right.
Correct.
I would say most of the time that we are called in again, keeping in mind that our,
our primary targets are these fast growing, either start ups or, uh, you know,
pre pre IP O or even post IP O.
And, uh, but a lot of them come to an, uh, oh moment, you know,
that is that they have a very technical, um, a fantastic team running
and probably embedded in engineering or the product side that's running DEV
Sec
ops. Um, they're part of engineering,
they're part of the product team.
And uh at some point,
the sale cuts to the point where they're no longer just managing RFP requests
and responses.
It's now, uh we need to speak to your co and uh and by the way,
the VP of engineering is not going to cut it or
the head of product is not going to cut it.
And some of the
discussions, you know,
despite best efforts, putting a DEV
ops engineer
on the phone with a Fortune 500 co just won't cut it. And so
that's when the uh oh moment comes and they say we, we, we really need to bring a,
a professional co on board.
And uh and those quite frankly are some of the tough researches because you have to,
you know, this is a, this is a candidate pool
that probably in my experience is the amount
of pummeling that they get from vendors,
from recruiters, from people trying to sell them things is, is just,
it's off the charts.
It's probably more so with security officers than, than any other single,
even more so than CEO S if you think about who's trying to get in touch with them.
And so
if you have to really make a compelling
argument or narrative from that company to say,
this is what's interesting, this is what's challenging about our security story
and this is why we want you to join.
It's a pretty fascinating thing we,
we actually started doing last year we started doing these, uh ciso dinners
and, uh, we, we call it a sanctuary because we don't pitch to them. We don't sell them.
We don't allow sales people to come in.
And what we found is that the C
OS are almost like numb to being invited to, uh, to events because of course,
when they get invited, they're getting pitched to or
someone want something from us.
So we, we just say, you know what, let's just get together.
We're gonna, we're gonna co-host a dinner
and you just, you just get to know each other and we're, we're just here to listen,
you know, selfishly, I want to get to know you.
So when I call you, I'm not a stranger, but other than that,
I'm not really selling anything to you.
What else I found is that C
OS are pretty horrific networkers.
They're, they're, they're very bad at reaching out
and they're great at reaching,
they're great at reaching out when there's a problem.
They have, they have wonderful ecosystems to um to use. They're,
they're really, you know, the, the White hat mentality of helping one another is,
is pretty fantastic and it's a very community spirit.
But when they just get together for networking,
I've had so many people come up to me these dinners like this is great.
You know, we, I never really knew this person over here. And now I know and, and
that,
that's kind of what we need to create for the cio community because they just said
they're being pummeled by marketing messages and um it's it's kind of tough to see.
-- Totally.
-- Alright. Alright.
So we're we're kind of nearing the end of our chat and let's let's assume
I make poor life choices and decide I want to be ac O
do you have some advice for me?
Just from kind of a career and personal development perspective of some
of the things I should be focusing on or paying attention to?
Well, first of all, I think that is a wonderful career choice because I,
I think that uh and, and I'm not just being selfish about that comment, but it's,
I think really the see, so is the amount of growth that we're seeing
at that level right now and the amount of growth in that particular position,
it's something that I would recommend for everyone. And again, I'm, I'm extremely,
I'm extremely biased uh clearly,
but I also see this uh just having been around technology a long time,
I see this as a fantastic place for people to come in.
I I think that the the base the best advice I would give you,
you need to find a couple of mentors,
one that can help you with technology uh challenges and you know,
the proverbial bat phone
and then the other one would be more on the executive layer.
You know, here's a problem. My company came to me with how do I solve this?
This is not a technical problem. This is uh
it could even be political, but it, it's something that you need,
you need a couple of people that are really in your corner that you can reach out to,
that will um that will really tell you what, how you need to approach it.
And the other thing is uh I would find
a really good set set of recruiting professionals,
you know, that, that you can,
that you can focus on because they do know a lot, you know, they,
-- they do know a lot and um you know, find out how you can partner with them
-- effectively.
Yeah. No, I, I actually, I, I do agree with that.
Having, having good recruiters makes
an enormous difference and
awesome and, and obviously,
uh we'll put links to hitch partners in the show notes.
If anyone's looking for an executive recruiter named Michael,
they can, uh
they can go to, they can go there to check it out.
Well, the thing that always gets me is, you know,
like with cars or houses or other big ticket items,
sure you can buy or sell one yourself.
But,
you know, maybe hiring somebody who does this literally 10 times a day
is a better choice than, you know, doing it yourself when you like,
because honestly, most companies should not be hiring AC O like once a year, right?
That should be once every couple of years that they do this thing ideally,
you know, and so I, I see a lot of internal hiring that goes kind of sideways because,
yeah, they only do this like, once a year
and, you know, like it'd be like me selling my car.
I would, I would end up naked in the street
with all my money gone
at the, yeah, at the same time we,
we appreciate when companies come to us after they've attempted to, you know,
manage their searches on their own because they have
a great appreciation of how intense this network is.
And,
and, you know,
you know,
people hire an executive recruiter specifically us because we
have a very defined network across the United States,
some parts of Europe that are the, the, the, you know,
the kind of the cream of the crop.
And we, we spend so much time developing those relationships every day,
even when we don't have some, some position to manage, you know, we're, you know,
just educating them and, and being there helping,
I just helped someone on an offer yesterday had
nothing to do with any one of my searches.
You know, we're just, we're trying to be there as a, as a guide.
And, um, you know, this is a, this is a long, this is definitely the long play.
This is not a short,
a short uh relationship. These are 1015 year relationships that we've had.
So it makes a big difference and I
think the clients hopefully recognize the value there.
-- That is
-- awesome.
All right,
this has been
a marvelous conversation.
So I guess thank you so much, Michael. It is.
It's always fun to talk to you and I really appreciate you taking the time.
So for I guess audience members, you can go to open source security,
podcast.com and hit up the show notes
which will contain a link to probably a couple of things about me.
I
don't think we touched on a whole lot outside of hitch partners and you, which is,
which is great though.
And then you can use the Pound Os podcast hashtag to hit us up on Twitter.
-- And yeah, I mean, Michael and Kurt, thank you guys so much. Have a great
-- day.
Thank you. Get some chicken soup for you, Kurt.
Seriously,
the