Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in wondering
why we even bother with certificate authorities.
Josh Bresser.
-- I don't
-- wonder why I know why we bother with them because
the foundation of modern society is built upon our certificate authorities.
-- I know. Right.
-- Yes. It's a very shaky, disastrous
foundation. Yeah. And I love that.
It literally every connection now is
-- what matters is TLS are encrypted.
-- Basically,
I have a fun fact for you. Actually,
we're recording this right after like B sides and
black hat and Defcon happened in Las Vegas.
It's the week after
and I was there and I went to an event and there was a guy from let
encrypt. I honestly can't even remember his name.
So I apologize if you listen and I've forgotten your name, send me an email.
He said now let
and
is
delivering literally billions of certificates per day per day.
I'm like, oh my goodness, it's, I have a suspicion.
It's all of the other certificate authorities
added together and multiplied by a large number and
it's still more certificates and like that's a mind
boggling number
and and that actually leads to you were mentioning earlier,
like about certificate pinning and why nobody uses it anymore.
Like, OK,
so let, let's,
let's backtrack a bit and do some foundational C A stuff because I was talking,
you know, a lot of people.
OK. Number one certificates do not essentially prove who you're talking to.
It proves you're talking to food.com.
Not that you're actually talking to Food Corporation.
So, like you're talking to td.com
now, whether or not that's TD Bank, I don't
know.
Right. Right. Might be, might not be.
And, and in this case,
td.com is actually TD Bank until they forget to pay the registration, I guess.
Well, no, it happens. Right.
So that's the first thing. It's like there are, you know, and,
and this leads to a big thing. There's,
I was looking at this. So historically, there was,
the security people have focused on
Attackers are going to try and hijack
certificates. So you have to protect them.
You have to have a private key and a hardware security module.
It has to be double triple encrypted with a very ravenous dog tied to it
and no attacker cares or oh, certificate authorities are gonna, you know, they'll,
they'll get
a,
a
air quotes fake certificate, like it's a real certificate,
it's just not assigned to who it should
be and they're gonna fake out the certificate,
authority provider and like,
you know,
intercept traffic and like, do the response and blah, blah, blah.
And so like we have things like where, you know,
the C A request it from multiple locations to, you know,
make sure they're not being spoofed or anything.
And again, Attackers don't do that
because what they do do is they register Walmart
with the number one instead of the l.com.
That is exactly what happens in most cases. Yes.
Yeah.
And then number three state level actors, well, they own AC A so they don't give a crap
of them do. Yes.
Like
-- it's just that simple.
-- This is the attack
that I think
a lot of people think about now is
there are a bunch of cas
with questionable owners.
I mean,
we did a whole podcast episode when like Kazakhstan
was going to make browsers add their root certificate,
right?
And that happens independent of whether or not they have AC A, well,
they have AC A and whether or not that C A is in
the route and obviously it's not because they're forcing people to add it.
Right. You know.
So, yeah, when the nice men with guns show up and tell you to do something, you
-- should maybe do it.
-- It's the XK CD cartoon with the Wrench, right?
Like it's literally that, I mean, yeah,
if a guy shows up with a gun and tells me to do something, it's going to get done,
that's how it works.
And so, and then there's ok and let's also cover,
there's a couple of sort of supporting tech friends here.
So there's, there's DNS sec
and DNS security basically means that I make a DNS request to seafood.org
dot org replies it's signed and it can be altered
in transit.
But also one very important thing is an attacker can't spoof
a reply so they can't block my reply and create one,
like
see your.org points at 1.2 0.3 0.4 or whatever, right?
And DNS EC
is actually very important for certificate authority security. In that
the vast majority of certificate validation is now done through uh DNS checks.
But going back to it is,
but Attackers are not manage in the middle and certificate authorities,
they're not, you know, they're not hijacking you.
So honestly, if you don't have DNS C
in stat,
that's fine.
And then the other one is HSTS http strict transport security,
which mattered about 10 years ago because basically you could say only talk to me via
-- HTTP S except no unencrypted and
-- don't most web browsers just default to http S now
they pretty much all do because a few summers ago, Google changed their seo
prefer http S.
So all the websites finally like,
like I keep saying I have a spreadsheet and it used to have a column.
Does this cloud vendor support http S
like
which is hilarious to think about now?
-- Like
-- I finally deleted that column because I'm like, yeah, I know this.
Like if they don't.
-- Then obviously I'll notice because
-- create a column for when they don't.
-- Well, more to the point my web browser won't let me go there.
-- That's true.
Like
I just set up a new local server and I had to
go to the IP address and it doesn't have a certificate.
And of course, my web browser is like, I don't think you should do this.
I'm like, yes do it. And it's like, no, I really don't think you should do it.
You're gonna have to click on advanced security.
I click on advanced security and then it's like, I really,
really don't think you should do this.
I'm like, just, yeah, it's, it's a pain in the butt.
Just show me the local IP address, web page, please. For the love of God.
So I can configure the server.
So HSTS used to matter
and now it doesn't
-- really.
-- Yeah, I agree.
And then the one you mentioned, certificate pinning,
certificate pinning was a perfect example
of some of the worst engineering security
mindsets ever because what certificate pink did?
And this is the stupidest thing that you could ever do
is you're basically saying we have a certificate with like this serial number
and we're going to have a DNS record that pins it
and if it's not that certificate with that serial number,
then it's not us.
Yes.
Ok.
So like now you need to roll
over certificates suddenly because something happened.
No one knows how to do that.
-- Well,
-- and, and if you roll over the certificate and then the DNS cache
is everything still broken for five minutes or a week or whatever.
That's
right. It's just certificate pinning. Made life.
It, it, it basically made life so hard.
It's like that old security diagram, you know,
where you got that little gate in the middle of a
field with the tire tracks going around it in a semi
circle. That's exactly what certificate pinning
did.
Feels like a good idea in theory, but in practice, it was not a good idea.
It's a good idea. In theory.
-- If you've never operationally run a web server,
-- that's fair. Yes.
-- Which uh most security people haven't or
-- they haven't done it at scale.
And there's a big difference, you know,
I ran into this a lot at Red Hat where developers would be like, hey,
it works on my laptop.
It's fine and I'm like, that's great.
Now, what happened with 100,000 clients connecting to it and it needs to work 24 7.
Or else people get yelled at, oh, side note.
Speaking of which revenue,
Canada is having a scheduled web server outage this weekend
from like Friday close of business till Monday morning.
And I'm like, ok, so they're like 99% reliable now because they're taking 2.5 days.
I mean, 99% reliability is what, like 3.5 days per year. Yeah.
-- So they're taking two,
-- they got plenty of offer.
Well, that, but that's the thing.
Like, I've, like, it's the tax people. So, like,
they can, they can turn their server off for 2.5 days and, well,
you just have to wait till Monday because you still have to pay those bills.
Go to their competitor,
switch, switch tax agencies. Good luck.
-- No, I need to go. Set up an Irish entity.
-- There you go.
Because it's funny because companies do go
to their competitors which are like Ireland
-- and Holland and like all these weird Bahamian islands
-- companies can do that.
-- Us peons cannot.
-- No, no.
But so,
so certificate pinning was just literally the worst idea possible
so much so that like it's nobody does it.
Now there's one thing that is kind of sort of useful and that is certificate,
authority, authorization records
and what CAA records are is very simply put in your DNS. You say
the following certificate, authorities can issue certificates from my domain.
And so in my case, it's like in trust digit
and like
I want to say, maybe commodo or something,
basically,
it's whoever lets them crypt uses and like Amazon
and a couple of others in the group right
now, that is kind of useful because then
now if somebody goes to Turkey,
what see
in theory,
the certificate of authority, when they get a request, they check the CAA record.
OK? But the client doesn't.
So the problem is by definition, if you have a malicious C A,
they're not checking these records. So
CAA records are essentially kind of, they,
the only hole that they close is like somebody somehow got into
your DNS or email so that they could validate for a certificate
through some and then they are dumb enough to like, use
AC A that you don't have listed.
So CAA records basically don't do anything.
Like they don't,
they don't address any real world attack scenario
where the attacker is actually going to be
skimmed by it.
And, and again, a good example of this would be every major domain does not use them.
That could be, I, I honestly don't know it.
-- No,
-- I, I looked at a bunch, nobody uses
them.
You know, we should also predicate this conversation even though we're what,
like 10 minutes and now at this point or something.
But
this is a topic, Kurt cares about a lot and this is a topic I don't know very much about.
And as I, I think my literal words to you where this,
I feel like this is my water supply.
I turn the tap on and water comes out and I don't care
because someone else's problem to figure this all out.
Well, and the thing is, there's very few people who care about this.
Like if you look at the certificate authority mailing list,
there's like five people being active on it.
And it's the same five people for 20 years. So,
what's interesting to me is like,
the vast majority of security stuff like C A pinning
CAA records is to put it bluntly it's security theater.
It doesn't matter at all. And even better example is
there's three kinds of certificates. Right.
There's domain validated, extended, validated and organizational validated.
-- I thought they got
-- rid of the EV.
Exactly. It was security theater.
So they did get rid of them
because, like, oh, you know, I, I, actually, my bank used to use one. Weirdly,
Toronto Dominion used to use one.
-- Lots of
-- sites, lots of big companies had them, like,
Amazon had one and Walmart had one and,
-- and
-- nobody cared because they go to Walmart with the number one instead of the l.com.
I understand the theory because it turned your
address bar green or something.
-- I remember
-- they had like a little thing instead of the walk.
It actually had like a little
green thing
but nobody cared.
And, and the thing is, I don't know,
the TD
has one. So I don't know, to look for it.
-- Exactly. Exactly. Right.
-- Yes.
Like I know when I go to a restaurant to look at their food handling permit
or actually I just look them up on the,
the website where I can check out their records and see what they failed.
The number of times I've looked for that is basically zero.
-- You know,
-- it's, to me every restaurant that's clean and nice.
They proudly display it and it's like right there when you walk in and see it.
Right. That's fair.
The best restaurants almost certainly fail their health inspection.
Oh, everybody fails.
But it's usually like you want it to be normal failure, stuff, like, oh,
-- there's a bit of grease on the, on the grease hoods, like, yes,
-- that's, that's true.
-- Not like they found a body in the freezer
-- or, you know, uh mouse droppings in the food,
right? That's fair.
-- That's,
-- you know, like I'm ok with a little extra grease and like, oh, they, you know,
every single time the dishwasher cycle,
they're like the PH balance is off and they had to recalibrate it like they had to,
they don't use the testing strips, put enough uh blue stuff in or whatever it is.
I forget the color.
I don't know.
But anyway, so,
so what's fascinating to me is like the vast majority.
So though one of the few things that has actually worked for C A security is
the public transparency locks because it let us see how bad some of these cas were.
-- Sure.
-- But how many cas have been removed
from the, the root store?
-- Uh three or four
-- out of how many
and several have failed to join.
Uh There was that Brazilian one that wanted to join and we looked at their, I,
I looked at their certificate transparency logs and
they were issuing certificates for IP addresses,
which is super not allowed
for single names, like not a domain name like food.com dot Corp,
but like just
a word, right? Like there was hundreds
hundreds of misu Ands and, and so they lacked maturity to do this.
Oh, and they were specifically to look up email records for DNS using,
who is they were specifically using a website that said
do not use us for this kind of activity,
right?
So what this all boils down to is
there's really only a few things that even remotely matter.
And I would say one of them is the ability and, and willingness of the C A
to revoke certificates when they are mi
misis
issued, which that's how trusts,
that's one of the big things that got entrust booted
is because they had issued a lot of bad certificates
and they weren't
like dealing with it properly.
I need to explain this because I don't even understand this situation.
So the, the in, in trust story is what kicked off this whole,
I guess
-- line of discussion to how we got to right
-- now.
So in trust behaved badly enough that they got booted out of Google and now
-- Mozilla's Certificate store program and in
-- trust was
a root certificate or were they just,
uh, ac a
major root
-- certificate? They are
-- root certificate.
They are,
um,
like they're one of the original kind of top five us
entities that have been doing this for 20 or 30 years,
right? They are also like for b
for the brand identification mark certificates. It's only in trust and dider
-- that do that
-- or it was in trust or is it still in trust?
Well, that's a server thing with email. That's not a web browser thing? Ok.
So it's different.
So, but in trust basically behaved badly enough that Google booted them out.
And then of course,
Mozilla did because essentially once a major player like Google or Apple or, well,
Mozilla
are based and I guess Microsoft those, there's four that matter.
-- And
-- it should also be noted that every
web browser carries their own root certificate.
Is it a database? I don't what you call the root cert
-- store,
-- it's a store, it's called a store. Root Certificate store.
-- Ok.
-- Yeah.
And, but they're all pretty much the same in that they're all the kind of the,
the cab forum one.
And so in trust actually, because they got booted out, like,
how do they keep selling certificates?
And the answer is they basically became an ssl.com reseller,
right? They, so they literally are like, you know, you'll get a
ru
branded email from ssl.com when it varies, you know, blah, blah, blah.
So they literally have become a glorified reseller.
And so because for example, their inability or unwillingness to,
to revoke a certificate means they're not like willing to do
this is the the entry level of security for a certificate authority
because the problem is I sell you a certificate, it has a serial number,
it has a digital signature.
Well, I can't like take it back. I can't,
I can't revoke it in the classical sense if
I actually like physically revoke it from you.
So how do I make people stop using it?
I, I actually don't know because there was what the, like the OS CP is it O CS P,
I forget the acronym.
So the original way we did it
was what was called certificate revocation list. And it literally was
every certificate authority was supposed to run a server
with an endpoint
that would have a list of certificates that had been revoked
and you could query it.
And of course,
none of them could run a web server good enough for this to actually work.
And so what happened is, do you remember for about a decade,
there was a period of a lot of web browser updates
and one of the main notes in all the web browser updates would be this certificate,
revocation list is being updated.
Yes.
And so literally the solution to revoking
certificates is we're gonna update your web
-- browser with a list of stuff that's been revoked
-- and issuing 4 billion certificates
a day or more is
very reasonable.
Well, no, that's actually the solution.
-- Are they still doing that?
-- Well, no, the solution now
because the problem is certificates used to have
long lifetimes of three or five years.
That's right.
And now Apple, because basically Apple said, no, this doesn't work for us anymore.
One year max.
Well, in and let's encrypt uses what, like 30 or 90 days or something.
-- I forget what it is. It's pretty short.
-- And
this is the most important thing for
security certificate because it forces people to automate
that
and it, but it's not just automating getting a new certificate.
It's also by definition, if you, if let's encrypt issues a bad certificate at most,
it's going to be good for 30 or 60 days or whatever.
Right.
So, the amount of damage long term is, is vastly minimized, right?
This is the whole idea of password rotation.
Oh,
you need to rotate your password in case an attacker found out
and he's using it to log into your system and use it
and then you rotate your password and lock them out.
And it's like, well, that's,
but then they'll just get in the same way they
got in the first time by fishing you or whatever.
Probably because just add a one to the end and
-- it works.
-- Yeah. So, certificate revocation. We had uh OS CP online certificate.
-- Oh God. The s always evades me something, protocol.
-- No, I, I just looked it up.
It's called
online certificate status. Product
status.
O
CS P. I had to look it up because I couldn't even remember what the acronym was.
I knew it had those four letters in it, but I didn't know the order.
And the best thing is you tried enabling it and living
with it once for like what two days and then no,
a couple of hours
every, the whole internet just fell over. It was unusable.
And didn't we did like a show on this, didn't we? I think we did.
-- Yeah, we
-- did. That was years ago.
And so again, that's a perfect example of
you cannot check
that every certificate you're interacting with is valid
every time you use it because you have
to check it every time you can't check it once a week or once a month,
it has to be checked.
Like every time
a
the, the, the services to provide this don't exist reliably enough. And B
is, there's also a huge privacy problem
that
every Os CP endpoint knows where you're going and when you're going there
-- O
-- CS P,
-- you keep saying Os C
-- P. Oh did I
-- O CS P?
-- You know, I keep thinking of omni Consumer Corp.
Anyway.
Anyways,
that was a great, that was a great original film, Robocop. Anyway. Anyway,
so back to this. So, so like all of these things that like certificates,
the,
the cab form and everything did.
I mean,
pretty much every single thing they've done for security has turned out
to generally be so bad that like even Google won't do it.
-- Like Google tried pinning for a while and then stopped
-- because
-- it had too many problems
the answer
much like software is automation and rapid rollover.
Like just renewing certificates, getting certificates, like same thing with. So,
like being able to patch rapidly trumps pretty much every other
security measure because it's what you're gonna have to patch anyway.
So you might as well get good at
it.
What it boils down to is that the vast majority of this certificate,
authority stuff is security theater.
That doesn't matter. Or in many cases was it made things so bad that, like,
people tried it and then gave up
and then invented something new to try and make it better,
which turned out to be even worse.
And so a great example of this is digi
cert. So Dider
Misis issued some certificates.
Now, when I say misu, that's a, that's a loaded word in this thing,
they didn't give them to the wrong people, we don't think.
But the,
the way they did the issuing and the C the DNS checks was not correct
because they made some changes on their back end and then their one front end.
Is this fairly,
or is this the very old digit
probably like a week ago,
like a week ago or two weeks ago?
And one of their head people stepped down over it?
Yeah,
basically. Well, because here's the fascinating thing, did GT,
basically, you know, tried actually kind of responded quickly and,
and is like here we're, we're,
we're doing this to fix it and we're going to
do this long term and code reviews and blah,
blah, blah, blah blah.
But then a company that uses them,
sued them and got an injunction so that they couldn't revoke the certificates.
Oh, interesting.
What happened is there's this health care
adjacent cloud company that I guess does a product and you know,
you have a domain name and obviously need a
certificate for it and they get it through digit
and clearly they don't have any sort of automation to roll this over
because they literally sue Digi cert to get an injunction to like,
stop them revoking all these certificates.
Now, this puts Digic
Cert in a bit of a pickle
because if they don't revoke these certificates in a timely manner,
like basically 24 hours,
they might end up getting killed, like in trust.
Interesting.
-- But a judge said you can't.
-- Ok.
And what was like,
what was wrong with these certificates that they were used by a business?
The way they did the DNS checks to validate them wasn't secure. It.
It had a technical glitch basically,
which meant an attacker could potentially actually get
-- certificates relatively easily.
-- I see.
So they didn't know if Attackers had maybe issued certificates for this company.
-- Well,
-- the attacker request the certificate digit
would issue it.
Right. Right.
So the, the digit certs,
like we're just going to revoke them all and you'll have to re, you have to redo it,
-- which is the, that's the correct answer. I
-- mean, yeah, that, I agree.
-- That would be the right thing to do. And if
-- it's automated, guess what? It's easy,
it would just magic.
Yeah, exactly.
But like I said, they got an injunction and they were prevented from doing this.
And so they went kind of, then even a little bit further.
And I think that's why that head guy stepped down is because they, they, they like,
in trust don't want to get delisted and become an ssl.com reseller, right?
Because
it used to be actually, I'm gonna say this and I'm not using air quotes.
It used to be easy
to become a root certificate authority and get into the root store
because the process was fail open. It was essentially you went
and you applied to Mozilla and there was one person
who I'm not gonna name because she does great work.
And she's like one of those load bearing internet pillars,
the foundation of the entire internet in modern society,
right?
So
I
to be clear, like she's doing great work. But
the process and because we came from a simpler time, we were all, you know,
-- things were innocent and lovely
-- and everyone probably knew each other.
Yes.
But well,
more to the point is we weren't like if you basically stood up what looked like a
root certificate authority got your audit report from
some auditor and like some of these audit reports
as far as I can tell were a s, a company that is a single individual.
Now, if you look at the audit reports for like Verisign and well,
in trust and did you're certain all these people,
you're going to see accounting firms with names you recognize?
Ok.
And then you look at some of the dodgier ones and you're gonna see
company names that you look them up and it's like a single person.
So you're beginning to see there's a bit of shenanigans maybe going on.
You know,
it's like I got a sock two report like let me put it this way if somebody said to you,
hey, Josh, here's my sock two report and you saw it was signed by Kurt siefried.
-- Like, would you trust
-- it? I wouldn't untrust it.
I think there is, there are circumstances where a single person
company is just fine. I mean, I think for a root C A
the bar should be a bit higher
but,
but there's, I'm not, I'm not discounting like single person audit companies.
They are legit and some of them are very, very good
and, but, and some of them, for example,
-- were delisted by the Canadian Auditors Society and
-- blah, blah, blah.
Yeah. Well,
and there's, I, I remember there was some story I heard I can't, I, I just, I,
I'm certain I won't be able to find the details, but I'll try, but there was like
there was basically some,
a business auditor was using,
like their cousin that was running like a one person company.
And when they got, like, actually audited by the state, they were like, oh,
this person hasn't even done any like this.
You haven't been audited at all.
And yeah, it was their cousin, like,
was just rubber stamping whatever they were given.
-- That's actually a pretty common thing.
-- It probably is,
that kind of shenanigans
happen.
So, back to this.
So digits are kind of fell on their sword and is trying to do the right thing. And
what's fascinating to me is, yeah,
the vast majority of people don't care and don't know.
And they don't have to.
Yeah, like, I had no idea.
I'm literally in the industry, but I now,
granted I've been on the road for three weeks prior to this,
so I have no idea what's going on anywhere but still, yeah, I,
I had no idea this was happening.
No, I, no, no clue.
And if you look at the certificate, traffic, like mailing list traffic,
it's the same small group of people,
like, straight up, like, one of them is a professor from Calgary, you know,
south of me who, like,
got ac a booted out a few years ago because they were so bad and he did some research,
you know,
the Turkish one where they got broken into and
they didn't know for possibly a few years,
you know,
and they straight up had like public
facing services with like default administrative credentials.
Good. Right. Like,
and somebody found it and reported it and then was like,
they're like, yeah, we don't think an attacker did this and they're like, ok,
that's one way to answer that question.
So
fundamentally, I don't know, kind of what the,
the point of all this is. But looking at this, I think a big part of it is
security
needs to involve the people who actually are going to use this also at scale.
Yes. So it's funny you say that, that, that was a topic
that came up multiple times while I was in Las Vegas last week for B sides
where
specifically around S bombs and vulnerabilities
-- that's going to be a prom at scale.
-- A lot of the people,
like we say
in the boat
for S bombs and vulnerabilities
haven't actually been using them for years, maybe ever.
And they're speaking with authority and making decisions and
it's obvious to anyone who's actually like in the dirt
that like these people have no idea what they're talking about.
They're, they're so far removed from reality,
but unfortunately,
they are in positions sometimes where they're
speaking with authority and they're getting,
they're, they're being listened to.
And so it's really hard to be like,
hey, I'm just like a nobody down here in the mud. That guy's an idiot.
Well, so the problem is the infosec industry tends to like,
for example, I you know,
brought up that the cas are doing bad things and people are like, Kurt,
why are you doing that?
You're being mean to them.
Like, why can't you just leave them be like, they're like,
they're causing problems and it's like I'm trying to
get ac ad listed that is like objectively bad
and needs to be delisted.
Well, you see that all the time in this industry where somebody bring, like,
everybody shoots the messenger
a
great example, the, the two thread on Mastodon where I'm like,
I would love to use Firefox but like, where is my easy profile manager?
-- There isn't one? You have to install a plug in and it's not great.
-- Exactly.
And it doesn't actually quite work the way I want it to
and it doesn't make it easy.
And all these people are kind of like, well, Kurt, you're holding it wrong,
you're doing it wrong.
And I'm like,
I think this is a common use case and actually a few people piped up saying
I too have this problem and I too would love to use for
ha, but I do have multiple business things and a personal thing and I need to blah,
blah, blah
and it just doesn't work. I've tried it and I've done it and like it, it's a pain.
Like I've been using Linux since Slack or one point. Oh,
I understand
painful software and using it
like,
well, and you're old and you complain a lot now. So there's that
too
-- because I'm also like, well, chrome did it relatively easily. Why
-- can't?
Yeah, the chrome,
the profiles or whatever they call them. They're very good. OK.
II I have a question related to the topic because I don't want to go down this radical.
But OK, so one of the things that comes up around the, the certificate root store
is I do a lot of work with, we'll say us public sector,
which is the US government oftentimes the Department of
Defense and the military and things like that.
And they will say they have a particular sensitivity to certain countries.
-- Let's say China, North Korea,
-- I wasn't going to name them. But sure those countries,
I had someone come to me the other day. It was like,
have you seen all of these Chinese cas
in the root certificate store?
And I was like, yeah, what about it? They're like, should we trust them? I'm like,
we don't really have a choice like they've been there forever.
So here's what's frustrating to me
is there's actually some security stuff built in where for example, I could issue,
you can create a root certificate
that
it has specifications on what kinds of things it can do.
It can sign email certificates, it can sign webs
can sign code certificates,
software,
software, sorry.
Um
And uh like be like the brand identification
soft and so typically certificates have that limitation.
Like this is a web service certificate. This is a
code uh software signing certificate. This is an email certificate.
You can also restrict their domain names. So you could say, for example, like, ok,
for the sake of argument,
this country's post office will be given a root certificate and
they can sign dot whatever the TLD for the country is
-- like
-- dot CN for China, for example.
Exactly.
And in that case, then I'd be like, yeah,
I don't have to care about that certificate authority anymore because,
well, like
I just, you know, they, they, I only sign stuff for.cn and that,
that I don't really mind.
Fun fact. Guess how many of the root certificates in the store
have that sort of domain limitation enabled.
So I know nothing about how many root certificates are in the store.
-- Let's start with that
-- question.
It's um over 100 hundreds. It's low, hundreds of memory serves.
And that's a fun thing is just getting that list is
kind of tricky it.
So the C A forum has a list of root certificates that generally speaking,
almost everybody kind of uses, but each C A kind of has their own thing.
So there's actually PK
ic.org/ltl, which is the list of
uh trust lists. And so it's like 360 Adobe Android Apple, Chrome Cisco
in alphabetical order, you know, a bunch, right?
Uh
Visa has a really good list. Uh I, I honestly, if you're an American entity,
use the Visa list.
That's funny.
I mean, I'm not surprised that they have real money on the line so they care a lot.
Like,
generally speaking,
the companies with actual money in the game are the ones who do the best job here.
If you want a US centric version of the list, go use Visas.
So, the, the problem though is you're thinking of root certificates as
root certificate companies and that's how
certificates gets issued and you're wrong.
Ok.
The vast majority of certificates are issued
by intermediate authorities like Lutz and Crypt.
-- Well, no certificates. Yes. No, I know that.
-- But here's the fun part.
We don't know how many intermediates there are.
I believe that 100%.
Yeah, like just like we don't know how many certificates there are.
Well, we think there's about six.
The last number I saw a few years ago is we think there's about 6000 intermediates.
That doesn't surprise me even a little bit because the
prompt too is you've got some that are like,
are obvious, like let's encrypt
and some like, ok, well,
Amazon issued certificates for their web services and
they became intermediate a long time ago.
So they can,
all of the cloud providers are intermediates
-- pretty much. Yeah, pretty much is
-- an intermediate or intermediary
intermediate
because basically they have a certificate
signed by a root certificate.
But without the limitation, like normally when they sign a certificate,
they say you also can't sign any more certificates.
Well, in that case, they
or you're constrained to a domain,
right?
Well, no domain constraints are almost never used.
I looked and, well, how would you constrain Amazon, right?
You can't constrain Amazon,
constrain them. But I'm saying for like you or I, for example,
-- no, they, well, you just get a wild card certificate in that case.
-- OK.
And that's fair. And again, I, I'm way out of the game on this.
And that's a good example of domain constraints in theory, but in practice,
domain constraints don't work because now we have over 2000 Tl DS.
Uh
Yeah,
like minor problem even just listing them all
in the ticket would like it would break.
That's fair. Right. Well, I'm, I'm,
I'm guessing if you add 100
domain constraints to a certificate,
-- we're going to find out a lot of broken implementations for
-- sure.
Yeah, I'm sure every, most of the,
-- the low end phones would probably collapse
-- low end.
I, I don't know, maybe it's,
it's cute that you think like the high end stuff would handle it because it never,
well, and, and it's also funny because
-- the, the, the libraries that parse all this crap are like ancient sea code
-- and worse,
it's all based on a SN one which is that itu the
International Telephony Union Standard and a SN one is not a standard.
-- It's a horrible format. Well,
-- no, a SN one is like a family of documents.
Let's say that are sort of a standard because people use them as a standard.
Interesting. But if you actually look at it like
there's, it's kind of officially technically a standard,
but it's also kind of officially like,
here's a pile of documents that everybody sort of agrees to.
Perfect example, curl just issued a security update like a week or two ago
and it was an a sn one person problem.
Well,
and this leads to another show we need to do
on undefined behavior and why that's such a problem.
But anyways, we don't know how many there are to start.
Well, we know how many root certificates there are. And so here's the thing.
Now, I asked you to pause.
Now I want you to go, you're in Firefox, go into the certificate store
thing under security and tell me how many there are.
-- I have to figure
-- out how to do this.
-- You want to click on settings and security
-- certificates, view certificates.
There you go.
Uh It doesn't show me there's the list is gigantic.
-- Hundreds, hundreds and hundreds
-- easily. And you can't export it easily.
-- Can you,
-- I can I select all I can select all? No, I can select one. I can export one,
the interface to these things in the web browser.
Also, let's say for the sake of argument, you want to like
-- remove a bunch of them
-- again, one at a time. Can I can I control click?
Oh I can shift click, I can export them all. I can go to the top.
Wait, there's a certificate named CN that seems safe. Anyway,
then I can click on the bottom.
Yes, I oh, but if I select them all, I can't, the export button is grayed up.
I have to select one to get the export button to
re
so or, or delete or distrust is also, I have to only
-- select one at a time.
-- I don't mean to laugh but
it's 2024.
And
in every web browser, it is effectively impossible
and even better on Apple devices, Apple Mobile,
they stopped pretending you you can't even look.
I I think the point is like, I think the reason,
the reason I let you do this show even because honestly,
I think this topic is boring and no one cares.
Yeah, I agree. But the reason it
matter
is this is like
this is the foundational infrastructure of modern society.
-- I won't even say the internet.
-- This is plumbing,
it's not even plumbing.
This is like this is the bedrock upon which society functions.
Every computer, talking to every computer on the planet
uses this.
Yes, is using this and it is
-- an unmitigated disaster.
-- Oh, it gets worse though, from a browser perspective.
So tell me which ones you're using, which what
which root certificates ultimately you're actually using on a daily basis.
-- I assume all of them.
-- Well, the answer is we don't really know.
And the best answer I came up with somebody was like, run Linux
and use pie notify to monitor the certificate store in
slash etc and see when the files are being read.
I see which would work for applications that use the system store
and have their own but not a web browser.
Yeah, the whole thing is like, it's wild and, and this is again,
I think back to that email.
I got not long ago where the guy was like, look at all these Chinese
certificate authorities
and it's like
we don't know.
And I love that all of these organizations make a big deal about oh Chinese
developed code or we don't want contributions from
people outside of this country or whatever.
And the reality is like this is one
of those extremely a key foundations that thank goodness
has basically worked.
No, I mean, because of a couple of people, you know, doing miracles
and probably what is free time.
Yep.
Well, and uh one also thing uh for example, Atos is a certificate authority, right?
A big one. They have multiple certificates actually in the root store.
A majority of creditors of Atos se have signed
the lock up again agreement that will see them
take control of the embattled French it services provider
following its restructuring according to a statement on Monday.
So the other thing to remember is like
if you start looking at these certificate authorities and
trying to track them down unless they have
a really obvious name like Beijing Certificate Authority,
which
literally is the name of one, then you can be reasonably sure that's a,
probably ac a in Beijing
or
Atos,
-- you know, being that big it company. I've
-- never heard of Atos before. At this moment.
They're massive in Europe.
I,
I used to know people that work there. You know, they're like one of those.
It's like accenture if you're not an accounting. Yeah,
I've heard of accenture.
-- But if
-- you're that name,
I've heard of because they sponsor some program on public television.
Yeah.
But, um,
if you start looking at a lot of the certificate, authorities,
about half of them are really hard to track down and figure out like,
kind of if they're legit or not.
And I'm sure we never take anything out of the list.
And the intermediates of course are,
-- it's a complete free for all
-- unknowable number. Yes.
I, I don't know what the answer is here because the other,
the thing is we're, they're talking about getting rid of certificate,
transparency logs because of the privacy issues of like,
because the problem now is you stand up a server and of course you have
to get a certificate for it because otherwise your web browser screams at you.
Yes.
And the moment you get a certificate, it shows up in the logs
and the Attackers see it and your server gets hammered.
Now on the on the, on the other flip the flip side of that,
I know
a bunch of security
researchers that watch the transparency logs to
look for probable phishing domains where,
when you have a website registered that looks like walmart.com, they're like,
that's almost definitely phishing.
Let's add that to the list of places you can't go.
Yeah.
And there was that famous club floor hack incident where they
talked about that where they were monitoring for these domains,
but didn't, didn't catch it in time.
And yeah, so I,
I personally think we should keep the certificate
transparency logs and just make it all public because
trying to rely on
Attackers not knowing that the server exists.
-- It's not, I mean,
-- yeah, that's stupid.
But at the same time, like if, if,
if there are literally billions and billions of certificates issued each day
like that transparency log has to be bananas.
And that's kind of part of why we're looking to get rid
of it is because like running it is expensive and not chore.
Oh, I'm sure, I can't imagine what it's like to even just keep the thing alive,
much less do anything with the data.
Yeah.
And I mean,
this leads to interesting things of where this actually in
some ways will help Attackers because if an attacker,
you know, if they get a certificate that lasts 5, 10 minutes, they use it,
they do the attack, they send out the smashes, you know,
the S MS s or whatever it gets used and then it's just gone kind of without a trace.
You know, it, it's very hard to investigate because it's, well, it's gone.
I mean,
this is, oh, man, this is such a weird problem. And
the answer, the one, the one answer I know it isn't,
is creating like some sort of governmental or UN type organ to
try to manage this because it would be
no doubt a disaster.
-- It, well, even if with good intentions, they would screw it up
-- for
sure.
I think what terrifies me is the lack of sort of new people getting involved.
And like,
I've seen new people try to get involved and then they
kind of get booed out because they do unpopular things,
like point out that there's no pants.
Right.
Not that we're not wearing pants, there just are no pants,
-- that is a difficult problem for
-- sure.
And we, we,
I see a lot of that in Infosec and I think that's kind
of one of the biggest problems INFOSEC has currently because especially with,
like, we're turning away newcomers.
-- I mean,
-- well, there's some of that we also talked about like,
where are all the young people at open
source? Not very long ago?
And there's,
there's an aspect of people just don't want to get involved because quite frankly,
like,
this is a boring job.
I,
I actually got rein involved with the certificate
authority stuff
and I basically gave it about a year and then I gave up and left
because it's a terrible thing.
It feels like the sort of work you definitely have to pay people to do.
Yes.
And
that's
-- about all I have to say.
-- It's one of those things where there's very,
there's almost no
incentive
to actually make the whole c a landscape more secure because, well,
essentially all the cas are, like, in trust are making money selling certificates.
They don't want to, you know, disrupt that.
This is like the story of security,
like the security that actually matters and works
isn't the security V CS are funding.
It's boring stuff that you have to pay people to do
because it's boring and no one wants to do it.
Same thing here. All right, we got to call this one, I think. But
yeah, I guess in summary
we're doomed. Maybe
it's, you know, it kind of runs. It's like, again, like roads,
potholes.
I wish we had better roads, but we
don't
it. Yeah.
Yeah. Well, we'll see, I guess we'll see what happens.
Thank you for enlightening me with this horrifying information. Kurt.
I appreciate it. And thank you, everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not Su Z Pound
Os S podcast. Hashtag to find us on Mastodon KT. Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.