Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
I am ecstatic today. Kurt, we have a guest.
It is a repeat and funny enough, this person, when I publish this episode,
it will be five years to the day
since the last time they were on the show.
So I'm pleased to welcome back, Dr David A Wheeler,
the Director of open source Supply Chain Security at the Linux Foundation.
-- David. Welcome
-- back.
Thank you so very much pleasure to be here.
We are ecstatic to have you, the Linux Foundation with the open SSF has been doing
so much that I thought it is time to bring you back to talk about just the,
the amazing amount of things happening.
So I guess, set the stage for us. What do you, what do you want to talk about?
Well, a whole lot of things, I'm sure.
So I, I guess uh we should start with a quick recap for the last five years,
quick recap uh that we're still having security problems. What a surprise.
I'm shocked. You're shocked.
So,
but I think the good news is that a lot of
people have started to notice that all of society depends on software
and maybe we should start actually making it secure for a change.
That that's a little bit of a, of a,
of a swap because obviously some people have been working on this.
But
nevertheless, there's a lot that needs to be done
so much, much more recently,
the open ssf the Open Source Security Foundation was created.
The challenge was that we were trying within the Linux Foundation,
which is now where I work the Linux Foundation, however,
had a challenge creating a new foundation during the beginning of a pandemic.
Uh
There's no uh there's no script for this.
So they started the foundation but because there are a lot
of work organizations that were not sure what the impacts of the
pandemic were going to be.
I was decided for the first year,
they were going to do it with no member fees or anything like that,
which made it easy to join, but not many resources,
but it was always anticipated, you know what, let's get it started.
And then hopefully in the next year, we'll switch over to a member funded model.
And of course, that happened, maybe they switched over. And
in the meantime,
a whole bunch of other folks noticed how important security was including
the White House cybersecurity executive order put out by the Biden administration
really pressed things forward.
So all of a sudden we've, you know, we,
we started with an open source security foundation and then this,
just recently, there's been an incredible number of folks joining it,
putting in funding.
Frankly, I'm pretty excited to see, uh, what's going to be happening
-- in the next year.
-- Awesome.
That's so exciting and, and actually so fun fact, as we record this just yesterday,
the open SSF voted to what, what, what is that?
I don't know what the exact terminology is, but you basically, like, took sig store
into
the, I guess, into the tent with, with the project. Right.
Right. Right.
Uh Basically the, you know, what a little bit of insult side baseball is,
is kind of helpless
really inside this is all public.
But basically the way the open SSF works
is actually like most Linux Foundation uh foundations,
there's a governing board that oversees, you know, basically decides things like,
like where the money goes and then for the technical decisions,
there's a group called the T
A, the uh technical Advisory Council, I believe. So that's, that stands for.
But when you say t
over and over again, you forget what the abbreviation is. That's right.
But anyway, so the T A voted to bring in
s store and the s
store folks had already uh proposed this. So it's a,
you know, whenever there's a,
there's a ma moving of somebody in both sides have to agree,
but I think this is going to be great long term, it's going to be a lot easier.
Uh S
Store already has some commitments of funding.
I think it'll be a lot easier to raise money.
And there's one organization that people can send money to and they can designate,
hey, some of this funding should go to this specific project if they want to.
But, you know, that doesn't mean that money solves all problems,
but there's a lot of problems that money can help with.
And so it's very, very nice to have some resources.
You know, I just realized I didn't explain what
s Store was. Maybe we should do that.
That's a good idea.
Right.
So, yeah,
so Six Store is a new approach to enabling cryptographic signing and verification.
We've had the technology to do crypto signing for decades.
And in fact, you know, the,
the tools to do signing are a little bit of a pain to use a little, you know what?
That's, I will argue that that's not the main problem.
The problem is, yeah, you're right.
It's, they're not as easy to use, but it doesn't matter
because verifying is, is uh too hard for most people. So no one does it.
And it mean if you don't,
no one verifies signatures, there's no point to it.
Now, there are, you know, specific cases where people do verify,
but we want that to be used all over.
So SIG Store is a very different way
to tackle the cryptographic signing any more importantly,
verification.
You know, people say, hey, does this solve all security problems?
No,
there's no server brought no single thing that people
do is going to solve all security problems.
But if we can get things signed and then verified,
then at least we know where the software comes from now. Is that
ok? Software to install?
Well, maybe, maybe not, but at least I can answer that first question
so that when we're analyzing it,
we know we're talking about the same thing and
then we can do other things to make sure that
that software and which we agree was signed
was in fact, OK to, to bring in.
So we're, we're, we're gonna need multiple things,
not just cryptographic signing but
-- cryptographic signing will help.
-- Well, I, I think, yeah, because uh cryptographic
to me boils down to at least you know
what you're getting. It's not some random, literally pile of bits.
But the one thing I keep coming back to uh ignoring signatures are hard and,
and verification is tricky.
How do you combat this whole mindset of?
Oh, the signature failed, whatever, smash that install button anyway,
like the solar winds situation, right?
Where literally
for months
they had people going, hey, these signatures don't check out what's wrong.
And they're like, yeah, it's fine.
Just, just really push harder, you know,
smash that pig in that hole because I keep coming back to
the fact that like the whole point of these signatures is that
when they do fail,
you have, oh, we, we need to investigate this, like,
either some internal process went really wrong or we were attacked.
Right.
And, uh, how do you kind of overcome this mindset of? Oh, the signatures failed?
-- That's annoying. Not even that, that's like a problem. It's just, that's
-- annoying.
There's a stick. I sometimes like to use that.
Uh, I, I find hilarious because there's truth in it.
It's the, you know, security is hard but with a little effort we can get rid of it.
Yeah.
This actually, I would like to subscribe to your newsletter about this topic.
The thing is, I think there's an answer uh, to that.
I'm not sure it's not a simple answer, but I think it's the right answer
and that is we need to make these things so reliable and so easy to use
that people won't want to reach for that, that hammer that says, ignore it anyway.
If you are.
I think today right now and, and frankly,
some interpretations of like the cookie laws uh,
in Europe are really causing security problems, you know,
we're training users to say, yeah, whatever.
Yeah, whatever. Yeah. Whatever.
OK.
If, if,
if they've never seen an error message before like that
and they don't see anything like that for say,
six months or a year,
that's gonna give him a lot more pause than,
yeah, this is the 3/100 time I've said. Yeah, sure. Whatever today.
So I think we basically have to move to a case where it's reliable. It works.
It's easy.
And man, when those things happen, it's so weird and strange that it gives even,
you know, people who aren't experts pause because it's strange.
I realize that we're not in that world fully today.
But that's the, I think that's the only real answer is it's got to be so easy, so much,
the default that people aren't tempted to.
And I do think actually there are cases where you really do have to, you know,
you know, uh sort of they break you, you know, use hammer, break glass.
There are sometimes where
you do need to do that
but you should,
you should be aware and, and you know,
and probably call in somebody who's an expert before you do that.
And we, we, we need to get to that world.
I'm gonna cut us off because this is not a podcast about
SAR,
but this is, this is a hugely interesting topic for sure.
So I want to steer us back
into the open SSF David, you kind of gave us an overview.
But
I think the real star of the show here are the,
the technical working groups that are part of the open SSF
and there are six technical working groups that I'm aware of.
So
I will not test you to ask you if you can name them all I can name them all. You can.
All right. All right.
All right. You name them. I'm looking at the list. Let's, it's quiz time.
Let's see how Dr
David A Wheeler does.
All right, best practices, vulnerability and disclosures,
identifying security threats, securing critical projects, security tooling
and the recently renamed Supply chain integrity,
which used to be named the digital identity at a station where
I was, I was hoping to catch you on that one.
Yes. Yes, absolutely. So I guess uh we, we'll go by the list.
I'm looking at on the website and let's just start at the top and go down.
So identifying security threats, explain that one to us.
That is probably the, the quirkiest named group.
The idea there is to try to give metrics and measures for
open source software projects to help people decide whether or not to,
you know, bring them on and, and that sort of thing.
And by the way, all these working groups have particular areas,
sometimes specific projects could easily fit multiple groups.
And right now, the goal has been, we're not going to worry so much as long as you know,
there's a home for them and they get moving the security metrics.
Folks have been worried about things like we
want to capture all at least link to every
security evaluation by some third party of open
source software so that you can find it.
You may not agree with their results, you may think,
but at least we can easily find them.
Another one has been trying to create a dashboard so that
you could get some metrics to learn more about specific projects.
Bring in data from things like criticality score and C I best practices
and lots of other things to try to kind of capture the information.
There's a kind of an early draft of an early version of that that exists now.
But right now,
we're trying to figure out how to integrate that with other tooling that exists.
So I, I suspect that there's going to be changes as we go along.
But the goal there is to try to eventually get to the point where
it will be easy to get information about. I'm thinking about using this project.
-- What can you tell me?
-- Yeah, absolutely.
And in fact, we just did a podcast a couple of weeks ago about the, the scorecards
-- for open SS
-- F, right? And they're one of the inputs to this.
So scorecards calculates a lot of stuff and then the
dashboard basically makes it easy to display that information.
That's right. That's right. Awesome. OK. All right. We'll keep going.
Uh Security tooling,
-- security
-- tooling. This is, has
this group has actually kind of had the most challenge. What way
has been one of the more challenged ones?
Uh They've got some things,
probably the more interesting one is something
called the CV E benchmark where basically
they're trying to measure how good tools are
by having a bunch of basically test cases
to figure out well, which tools find them, which ones don't,
in all honesty for the past year,
it's been kind of a rolling conference of tool makers
as they just try to figure out some things.
I think that they're the most recent working
group meeting now that there's some funding available,
they're talking about becoming more aggressive income things they do,
but I don't know yet for certain what that's going to look like.
Totally. All right, best practices.
Ok.
This one's super busy because as you can imagine,
best practice is pretty important and there's a
whole lot of activity going on there.
So let me just list off a couple there, the CIA Best Practices badge,
that's actually a project that I lead probably eventually that's going
to get renamed because technically the ci I doesn't exist anymore.
But
that's its name for now. That's basically a set of criteria.
What should open source software projects do
focusing on, you know, how can they develop secure software,
but it also bleeds into quality and sustainment because low quality software
and software that's not getting sustained probably isn't gonna be secure either.
Right?
So, and I always encourage people, hey,
if you're running an open source software project, please, please try to earn,
earn yourself of
that CIA best practices. Batch.
We've got, I looked at the numbers recently, but we've got over 4000 projects
involved. Yeah.
And it's, we, we actually, what's,
what's cool is that the website automatically generates graphs?
And it's been almost a linear growth.
I don't understand why that's a linear growth, but
that's OK.
We just continually get new people joining and that's great best practices. Badge.
The goal was for that one was one of the
most important questions whether or not they can be automated
and we do automate some
and in fact,
we'll override things that uh that humans claim if we can show that they're not,
they're almost certainly not true.
So, so yeah, there are people who, who, you know,
there are other ways we try to counter that.
But one of them is, is automation. But some questions are hard to answer
or hard to verify through automation.
But sometimes you just like to be able to get some information about an open a project
with full automation. And so scorecards takes that in the other direction.
What can you figure out about a project purely through automation?
And so scorecards tries to do that.
There's a new project that is just getting started.
We're still very much in the planning stage.
But I think this is gonna be interesting and just have a funny name.
It's the great M fa distribution project.
Oh,
yes, this is awesome.
Yeah.
So um first of all,
I do want to give a quick shout out to both Google and github who
have basically offered up to the open SS fa whole bunch of M fa tokens,
uh two fa tokens, you know, the hardware, hardware-based tokens prove who you are.
And the idea is we're going to try to work
or try, we're going to identify some open
source.
So developers of critical projects
offer them free tokens. And I think even more importantly,
point them to very pointed simple tutorials on
how to do typical open source software tasks.
I mean, not just, you know,
you need to do whatever it is to get your your token working,
but then how do you log on to github
or get,
you know, how do you post to PI P I or
to N PM your your packages?
So there's a number of open source packages where the developers are fine
but their passwords got stolen and suddenly
there's uh some malicious bit mining going on
or some other, you know, some other nastiness going on.
Yeah, I mean, the, the last handful of N PM
attacks were literally that
where it was reused credentials and, and I actually just read yesterday as well that
the N PM folks are going to require
multi factor off for, they're going to start with a subset
of N PM packages.
And then obviously, I think the intention is to expand it to all N PM packages,
which is pretty awesome.
Yeah.
Now we're not gonna be able to provide free tokens to everybody,
but we can at least we can at least try to make a very simple docks
for everybody for at least a couple of
common tokens and a couple of common situations.
And
I do think that getting them into people's hands, um, is, is going to help me.
They're not a lot of money, but here I've got it right here.
There, there's something that helps when you have it in hand versus.
Yeah, maybe I should do it someday
now. II I, I think I've talked about it
but you won't easily. If you go hunting, you can find out about it.
But we haven't done anything act in terms of actually sending out tokens yet.
We're working out some details because it's really,
really important that this not become the world's best supply chain attack.
Yeah,
this is something that has, this is something that's been talked about briefly,
but this is one of those things we kind of need to get right the first time.
So, you know, so,
so we're, you know,
we, we are, we do much, we, we are very much going to do this,
but we do want to make sure that we do it in a way that doesn't make things worse.
There's some collaboration with oas particularly on the common requirements,
enumeration and their educational system on the security knowledge framework.
And Oh, yeah. And finally, um
I
probably should have mentioned this first on the best practices, badge,
best practices, working group includes a set of three courses on Ed X that are,
that are free called the Secure Software Development
fundamentals courses. I'm really excited about that.
We've had over 5000 registrants.
Now, I don't understand why we think that our software is going to be secure
when we don't teach the developers how to write secure software. Um
I,
I went to, I, I just came back from the LF uh member summit. My Uber drive
to the summit was a senior in computer Science at Purdue.
I thought that was amazing.
So I asked him, well,
how much have they taught you about how to write secure software?
And the answer is nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
I mean, that's extra shocking as well because like Gene Stafford is at Purdue.
I mean, he's like the grandfather of computer security.
Yeah, they, they've got expertise there,
but that doesn't mean it trickles to the people coming through the school
and of course not everybody who develops software goes to college or universities
or even if they do, they don't necessarily
get a computing related major. So
we've got, we've, we've
um in the long term, we've, we're going to have to change this.
We need to make it so that everyone who writes software knows the basics about how to
help secure software. So this is a free course costs you $0 to learn.
If you want to get a certificate, Edex will, will want to charge you some money.
And that, that's how they make their money, but you don't have to get a cert
to learn the material. And we also post the material on github.
If you want to snag it and use it for other things. It's under a creative commons
attribution license. So
you can,
you know,
if you want to grab some of that material and stick it in a course in your university,
please.
Well, I think, I think one of the challenges.
So from what I've seen and this was actually just
driven home yesterday on a security call with a,
a
security board
that the security people view software engineering
and secure development as totally separate things. And then
sort of like some, I, I don't know, but from the software development point of view,
the one thing I keep coming back to is every developer.
Basically, it boils down to do.
I want to spend time learning how to add value or do I want to spend time
doing security? And
they,
there's not that immediate payoff with security like there is
with adding a feature and making your boss happy.
I think it's part of the challenge like
uh and this was in a previous podcast where I think just a lot of people
don't understand the value of security and kind of that it actually does have value,
right?
Because there's no,
you don't get that immediate payoff of, oh, look,
now the product has spell check and more people will buy it.
Right.
But, but I, but I think, um a
lot of this is one of those, you know, you invest, you invest in learning and you,
they pay dividends from then on a whole lot of the stuff that
involved with developing secure software.
You know, I, I reject the notion that it's always more money.
In fact, you know, what costs you,
more money is trying to retrofit stuff after the fact.
Sequel Injections. For example, if you know how to use prepared statements,
uh, once you learn how they're easier to use, they're faster, they work better.
And, oh, by the way, they're secure as opposed to the nonsense you're doing.
I mean, it's the old saying though David of there's never enough money to do it.
-- Right. But there's always money to do it twice.
-- It's cheaper,
it's cheaper to do the prepared statements.
No, II, I agree
with
you. I agree completely. Absolutely.
-- Yeah.
-- So the, the problem isn't that, gee, it's more costly in development.
The problem is we need to get people to learn it.
And now II, I do have a degree in computer science and information tech,
but I also have a degree in electronics engineering.
It's very interesting for me to compare
my classes for engineering versus the classes for computer science.
I think it's a shame that they're that distinct because
I believe that if you're developing, you know, what is engineering
engineering is solving human problems using
the resources and knowledge available.
And if you're writing software, you're doing engineering,
but we don't treat it like that way so many times.
And
so we, you know, if, if you're,
if before you're allowed to graduate from engineering,
you need to learn about not just how to build dams or make circuits,
you also have to learn about economics
and safety and lots of other things and we should have that same expectation.
You know, what do you, you know, you're gonna learn about software but we're not,
we're not gonna talk about economics, really.
We're not gonna talk about ethics or safety or security.
Really.
You, you don't think that the software will affect society. Of course, it does.
You know, we,
we have to get that in those broader context because
we're building things that impact society just like dams,
just like uh lots of other things.
Absolutely. No, I, I agree 100%. All right. All right.
I want, I want to keep this moving.
OK. Sorry.
No, no, this is, this is why I love you, man. This, this is so much fun.
Uh Next up, we got vulnerability disclosures.
All right.
So the big thing that they've done is they have
released this thing called guide to coordinate vulnerability disclosure for open
source software projects.
And so basically, it's the little, you know, hey, before you get a vulnerability,
uh why
you,
what you should do a little prep work ahead of
times because especially if you're building a larger project,
you're gonna get a vulnerability report sooner or later
and the wrong time to figure out how to handle that
is when you get a vulnerability report.
Because then, well, first of all, nobody knows how to report it.
So they'll spend incredible amount of wasted time just figuring it out
and then you don't have anything prepared to handle those.
Most people want to do co-ordinated uh vulnerable disclosure.
I think usually that's the better default.
I understand the arguments for full disclosure. But,
you know, I think in most cases, it's much better to try if you find a vulnerability
to find the supplier and work with them privately to get it rapidly fixed.
Now, if they're not gonna fix it in a timely way, that's a different issue, then,
then yes, go ahead and tell the world there's a problem here.
But uh try to get it quietly fixed so that the Attackers have less time.
But that turns out to be a challenge. How do you report it quietly?
How do you make sure that,
you know, you can have those private discussions?
So you and, you know, you need to have some things set up ahead of time.
So that's, I think that's probably one of the main things that uh vulnerable.
I mean, I,
I,
I'll, I'll remember later some other things but, you know,
that's one of the main things and they've got a,
they've got some templates and stuff like that.
Probably gonna ask me about
-- securing critical projects next working group. Next,
-- aren't you on my list?
Next up is
supply chain integrity,
which used to be called the digital identity at a station working group.
OK. All right.
You know what, there's a story behind this and I think that would be,
I think a lot of people listening in would be interested in the story.
So this this working group actually um slightly predating the open SSF itself.
There was, it was actually part of a different group that got merged in.
And the, the theory behind this group was, was originally called,
I even had another name.
But you know, the most,
the, the second, the penultimate name is digital identity at a station.
And the notion was, hey,
you know,
everybody seems to be doing digital identity
differently and at testing them differently,
let's have everybody present how they're doing things.
We identify the commonality and then we'll all agree on the common thing.
And so what it turned out to be for a number
of months was a number kind of a rolling conference,
you know, show up every meeting and somebody else,
maybe two people are going to present their approach.
And as a Roman conference, it was interesting,
the Linux kernel folks have one approach.
There's oo uh
there are other folks have other approaches. There's just,
and
you know, it was interesting, but there is a problem as a working group,
the goal was to OK.
Now we've learned we're gonna combine it all and here's the answer.
Yeah, you, you can guess how that worked out from my tone.
The goal of trying to find the commonality and working out that out,
made sense to some people.
But that assumed that there was a commonality and when the Venn diagram has,
has nothing at the intersection, that was a challenge.
So they said, well, we still really are worried about provenance, but
uh
we're kind of struggling with the way we're, we've been talking about this.
So let's shift our gears a little bit.
So they mooted, in fact,
they just recently officially changed over their name to supply chain integrity.
They've also brought in uh a project
called supply chain levels for software artifacts.
And that's also called SALSA. Salsa is basically a set of criteria for um
um uh providing integrity on the supply chain uh both within and without uh
franco. The best thing to go is to do is to go to Salsa dot DEV, SLS A dot DEV.
And you can see,
you know, they've got multiple levels and criteria for each level.
Um It's originally developed ba basically what this is is, it's
a,
it's an attempt to
capture the key criteria originally from Google
because Google does a number of things
now because they're worried about that.
And so, well, you know, what,
there's a lot of things that we Google do that probably lots of folks should be doing.
And the good thing is that we can say that, you know,
these aren't just abstract concepts, these are things people really,
we're really doing.
And so they, they tried to abstract away, OK,
what are the things that make sense for everybody as opposed to just, you know,
some particular organization for their particular situation?
And so Salsa's stone development,
but it's basically a set of criteria to counter a number of those kinds of attacks.
Uh If you're curious about more, go to the website,
it'll give you lots of more details.
What's what have we not talked about?
-- The last one is securing critical projects,
-- critical projects. OK.
The goal here is to identify those critical open source projects.
Um This is so, for example, you know, for,
you know, eventually we'll probably talk about Alpha Mega,
we want to identify some critical projects and work really hard,
especially for those critical open source offer projects.
Um So there's several different things that are involved there,
there's AAA metric that's called criticality score which tries to score out
uh and estimate just from external, a few external measures
uh whether or not software is critical.
Now,
I think there's been some rightful um complaints
about that particular score as it's implemented.
Um For example,
um it really likes projects that are super, super busy.
Uh and, and, and OK, if you get now, I think if there's an argument for it,
um if there's a huge number of commits to a project from a lot of different people,
that must mean it's probably important to a lot of people.
However,
it is true that there are some projects which are
maybe are almost dead or very get very few lib.
J peg. Yeah, we can make a list,
you know, just being dead doesn't mean they're not critical. So
I think the criticality score, I think is helpful.
It takes one slice at a hard problem and gives that a try.
Um Another thing that lives, there is a lot of work that's being done by Harvard.
Uh It's actually a group within Harvard,
Llish. The H is Harvard. I can't remember what the lis states are.
But uh anyway, um they're trying to really dig in and gather dependency data,
do dependency analysis across the entire, across the entire ecosystems
and start from, you know, actual app application,
uh large sets of applications and use that
working with a number of uh sc a tool makers, uh
tool suppliers
um to gather data to basically try to identify critical projects,
including that kind of criticality data that
just looking at, you know,
number of busyness of commits won't necessarily capture.
So um and there's some other things that live in there too.
There's uh package feeds and package analysis,
you know, it's not just identifying critical projects,
they they are trying to do some things to counter some problems.
So
uh they're trying to do some simple identification of malicious code
and warn about it. Now, now they have to be careful about this.
This is just like any virus check or anything else
just because you got code that looks and it
says I don't see anything that doesn't make it ok
if I'm an attacker,
the first thing I'm gonna do is run your tools and see if you find it.
But
there are a number of naive Attackers and this will
at least catch some of those and you know,
catching naive Attackers at least gets rid of some problems.
-- So this is not crazy
-- and, and look, I think in the world of security, we have this
terrible history of all or nothing
where if it's not perfect, don't do it.
And this is a great example of start small
and, and grow into it, right?
Like yes, we know it has problems but you have to start somewhere because you just,
you can't build a perfect solution,
right? And, and, and, and I'm big, big, big, big on risk management.
You know, what are the, what are the biggest risks focus on that?
Uh My phd is on countering malicious compilers.
Do you have how that existed? Yes.
Is that where most attacks are happening? No.
So, so that now that doesn't mean that I think my phd,
the dissertation is a terrible horrible thing if you're interested, go read it.
I've, I tried to make it readable, but
as from the point of view of I'm trying to counter, I, I'm trying to counter attacks,
I'm way more interested right now in
eliminating unintentional vulnerabilities trying to make supply chains so that
-- the top problems like type of squatting are
-- countered.
Actually seen
that happened unintentionally where like
literally the Devs were discussing something
in the shop if I had a package named one thing and
there was a legitimate other package with like an off by one character
and they couldn't figure out why it wasn't working the way it should be.
And it's because somebody,
somebody had just type like because the like the N PM namespace is crowded, right?
All the good names are taken,
you know,
and somebody had made a Typo and it took them, you know,
the better part of an hour to like,
oh, hang on a sec. We're, this is the wrong word.
If you're interested in open
source software supply chain,
there's a couple of papers I would hardly recommend that you look
at sonatype and synopsis have both done uh 2021 reports that are interesting
and for a larger view of, of things and over time, it's,
it's hard to over recommend a paper with a spectacular name.
It's uh I can't remember the full
name but it's Backstabbers Knife Collection which is
um and where they go in and examine every
open source software supply chain attack they can find
and try to categorize them or what's the most common.
And basically what they found was that through the,
through the period that they were looking at the
number one attack by far was type of squatting.
And
it's,
it's, and it's well, exactly type of squatting attacks are super easy to do.
It's trivial to create, to find the common packages
and it's trivial to create other packages with similar names.
And now you mentioned it's trivial,
but it's also trivial to counter as a developer before you bring in a package,
double check the name.
You're gonna have to learn how to use the package.
So, you know, you, you know,
if you're gonna have to read a doc to figure out how to use it,
it won't take you more than a couple of seconds to figure out. Is this the right one?
You know, if this is the package everybody's been using for the last five years,
maybe the package that just was created last month and it
has 20 downloads is not the one you're looking for.
You know, so it's, it's one of those things where you know,
just knowing that this is an attack and knowing, hey,
do this 12th double check can eliminate it.
Now, I will say that that there if the developer makes a mistake,
the US government for example, is starting to demand software building materials.
Tell tell me what's in the software
and, and this will let them also
be able to double check and say now, wait a minute,
you're bringing in, you know, fu with three Os, you probably met Fu with two Os.
This is a problem.
So I, but, you know,
basically asking once developers know this is a common kind of attack, they can
double, they can do that five second uh analysis
and others got
customers can use
software
materials to double check that. That's
-- right.
-- That's
-- right. No, it's, it's,
-- this is one thing that frustrates me is people,
Attackers go for the easy stuff because well, why not?
Like at work
they should,
you know if I, if I'm an attack, if I'm an attacker, I mean,
the Attackers have a cost benefit ratio to look at too.
You know,
Attackers are going to are going to at least the
smart ones are going to take the easy path.
And so what we need to do is make the easy path, not easy for them.
And I realize that there's some people saying, oh my gosh, this will never be solved.
It can't be, I
don't see it that way.
The goal is not really to make it impossible.
The goal is to make it so impractical and so
costly that they will give up and try something else.
-- That's
-- right.
That's right.
Or even if we don't, like, even if it makes it 10 or 20% better at, not a large cost.
Like, for example, the token thing. Right. Like I get it because tokens cost money
and, yeah, you can't just mail out, like, 10 million tokens and eat the cost.
But at the same time, if it makes it 10 or 20% better for, you know,
a reasonable amount of money, you know, like fixing roads.
-- Yeah. Shouldn't we be doing that? Doesn't that make sense?
-- Right. Right.
And you know what, there are roads we,
we focus more on to make sure that they're paved.
Well, I mean, there's infrastructure where,
oh, well, of course, we can talk about Vancouver's lack of roads right now. But,
yeah, seriously.
But you, you know, you know, barring natural disasters and such, you know,
we try to make sure that, uh, our infrastructure works,
um, at least, you know, in, in functioning societies and, you know, I,
I fully get that there's challenges in various parts of the world, but
I, I think we can all agree that it's, it's good to,
you know, have a functioning infrastructure
and since you have limited resources, focus on the ones that matter.
So, you know,
coming back to that m fa they're gonna start
by trying to identify the folks who are the,
like the key maintainers on some of the most important projects.
Let's get those.
And you know what I think that there's also a,
once there's a certain number of people who do it it's a lot more,
there's a lot more incentive for other folks to say, you know, it's not that costly.
I could get one of those.
-- It would be ok
-- also, just to get help because one thing I've noticed is, you know, we,
for example, we rolled out password management at the CS A
and now that
the majority of people are used to it, you know,
I'm no longer the point of contact always.
It's, they can just ask anybody else. Oh, hey, I'm having this, you know,
this doesn't work or it's not behaving. Oh, ok. That's how you make it work, right.
And so that, that knowledge of just how to get this thing, like
with tokens, I'm still,
yeah, like the instructions for actually getting
multiple tokens registered with a provider because people lose their tokens.
You know,
I've got five or six of them in total because I want to have
backups in case I lose my keys and the instructions for getting multiple tokens,
like, uh, some of these providers, they make it really obvious.
Like here registered Token register more than one
and at some, like you gotta go digging.
-- No, like they, for whatever reason they, they hid that option.
-- Yeah.
No, I, I have a two fa token but, uh, you know, I've been using for quite some time and,
you know,
I am sure that I will as we go through this thing, uh,
I'm sure I will learn things and that's great.
And now I agree with you being able to ask other people around is really,
really helpful because, you know, if it's, if it's spread across,
but we also want to provide
some, hey, you type into Google or, you know, some search engine
and poof, there's your answer and it's not a, here's the 300 page doc, it's the,
you know,
I'm gonna go off field. But what the heck, uh
uh there's a recent posting about random number generation
being totally messed up for billions of IOT devices.
And part of it was,
you know, hey, they found out how to use the hardware, it was like page, you know,
3000 and something and such,
you know, and, and,
you know,
I'm sure sure that the developers are going
to read every single page of that nonsense.
Uh No, we, if it's that hard then of course they're not going to do it correctly.
-- So we've got to make it easy. Gotta make it easy.
-- Absolutely. And, and I think
that is the message we should leave on is
if the easy way
isn't the secure way,
then
there's just not going to be a secure way. Like
that's the sad truth.
-- You
-- can post that picture if you remember the gate over the road with
the tire tracks going around either side of the gate and the snow,
like a 20 year old picture. But it's still true.
It's
true. And it's still funny.
All right, David. I want to thank you so much. This has been an absolute treat.
Having you come on the show again.
My pleasure.
I'm happy to come back anytime,
anytime we would love to have you. All right. So thank you everyone for listening.
All the stuff we talked about is going to go into the show notes.
So worry about trying to scribble down and any
of the project names and you can go to open
source security podcast.com. Find those show notes use a Podos
podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt and David have marvelous rest of your days. Thank you.
-- You too.
-- Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.