Hello and welcome to episode 39 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
Kurt. I have some amazing news to share with you.
Did you get a Nintendo switch?
I, I got that a long time ago. No, no, this is
maybe it is good.
Super Mario run has finally come out for Android.
I go
over the, the real one. That's right.
The one from Nintendo, not the one from uh Super Mario run.ru, right?
This is the actual real Super Mario run from Nintendo
is now on my Android phone
and it amuses me, which gives me great joy.
Yeah.
My uh my six year old, one of them is pretty,
pretty emotionally invested in that game.
What,
how are you emotionally invested in Super
Mario?
I, I, every time he die, you know, every time Mario dies, that's, you know, it's bad,
right? Every time Bowser dies, he's so
happy you need to get him on the original Super Mario Brothers. Then
you get to kill Bowser eight times.
We're
gonna be
doing that.
Uh I just don't know why I didn't figure this out earlier.
But I can use my Nintendo Wii controllers on with my Mac and open
emu.
Uh because the problem I've had is finding good Nintendo classic
controllers like they don't exist anymore unless you buy the originals
and the uh the, the connector to the USB and blah, blah, blah. And
honestly, the Nintendo Wii controllers are pretty faithful to the original.
They're not bad. However, I have something even better.
Is there is a company I believe they're called eight bit D or do or whatever
and you can buy a Bluetooth Super Nintendo.
Well,
and Nintendo controller remakes and I have the Super Nintendo one and I went and got
one of my actual Super Nintendo controllers out of the basement to compare it to.
And other than weighing a teeny bit more,
it's like spot on in terms of size and feel and everything. It's fantastic.
See,
the biggest thing that gets me about all of this original Nintendo stuff is just the,
the build quality like it just never breaks.
And I, you know, and I used like the,
the heck out of my net like those things got dropped and stepped on and smashed and
they just always worked.
And then I'm really sad that I sold my nez and all the games, you know, back in the day,
you know what man, I still have them in the basement and I took them out one day
and it was such a headache to get it working and plug it
in and figure it out and I had to clean all the cartridges and
I don't think you made a mistake at all.
Well, just, no, I wish I would have kept the controllers
and
what would you plug them into
one of the USB adapter
things,
I suppose, I suppose. Actually, you know what's really funny is a million years ago
I built an adapter to plug a super
Nintendo controller into the parallel port on my computer
so I could use it as
like a joystick. Yeah.
And they were even, it worked on Linux,
even someone wrote Linux drivers to make it all work together.
Remember the?
Yeah. Yeah, it was great, man. It was great.
Yeah. Now we're all just trying to buy switches.
I have a switch. I can bask in, in the awesomeness of owning one.
I, I will say that the legend of Zelda game is
an amazing game
in almost every way.
And, and I, I don't, I don't, I don't wanna make you feel too bad here, but like
I've seen some of
the youtube play through stuff and like some of the tricks they use,
like attaching explosives to the floating stuff and then
shooting it down and blowing up the guys or
getting the chickens to attack the bad guys.
And I mean, it looks awesome.
It's pretty good. They did, they did a good job.
Yeah. Yeah.
And,
and part of the beauty of it is from the very kind of security perspective I always
like to take is there's a million ways to
do everything which is part of the fun because
I'll sit and watch my kids play and I would never dream of doing half
the stuff the way they do it or they'll watch me play and they're like,
why are you doing it that way?
That doesn't make sense. I'm like, it makes sense to me. Go away
so
well.
And that's what always frustrated me about these, uh,
sort of video games is like where you,
you, like have to use,
uh, like you're a ninja and you have like a sneak ability,
but at some point in the game you like have to set off
the alarm to get the guards to clear the room or something,
you know,
versus rather than just like sneaking into an event and dropping a
hand grenade into the room or poison gas grenade or whatever.
Right.
And that, you know, you have these like very linear storylines and it's not like
you kind of have that flexibility. Yeah, you have this effect on these objects.
So therefore you can do it like
17 different ways.
Yeah, it's super cool. I love it.
Yeah.
So
related to that I think would be Symantec versus Google
is that related
is,
well, in so much that we have, like, we have the old stuff, which used to be cool,
which is probably not nearly as cool as we thought it was.
And then we have the new stuff, which is actually cool and pointing out
they're both pretty old man.
I, I wonder what year was Symantec founded in, probably older than Google.
But I bet, I bet they're comparable.
I don't know, we'll have to check later.
But, uh, so, yeah, I mean, I, well, this seems to boil down to a classic case of, uh,
I guess of too big to fail really.
Otherwise they would have gutted them by now. All right.
So firstly, Symantec was founded in 1982
was founded in 1998.
So
neither is young,
in my opinion.
True. But regardless. So why don't you recap this crazy story?
Well, basically what's happened is as we all know, uh,
some cas are by C A si mean certificate, authorities, a certificate authority,
so fancy speak for people who essentially have
a root certificate that they managed to convince
the fine folks over at Mozilla and, or Chrome and,
or Microsoft into including in their web browser trust store.
And, uh, then they can use that to essentially create certificates, uh,
for websites, you know, for email identities, uh, for code signing.
I think that's really the three use cases we have,
they're the big ones and those are the ones that will probably affect people in
this context. So, yeah,
and so the deal is though, is like, well, well, like any business you know,
some businesses are, are good at what they do and they,
they put out a good product and they have good quality assurance and testing and,
you know,
the products don't randomly explode and kill you and then other companies,
you know, do less of a good job.
And so what's happened is, you know,
we've kind of always suspected that some of these cas were doing a really poor job,
but we had no idea what they were doing.
Right.
And so Google was smart, came along and did this thing called, um,
certificate Transparency which really boils down to
is the certificate authorities had to,
uh, make a public record of the certificates they were issuing.
Seems logical.
Yeah, exactly.
I mean, so that way a company like Google could, you know, watch the, you know,
watch which certificates are being created and be like, oh, you know,
Symantec just created a certificate for google.com.
Uh, no, we didn't buy that. So that's not us. Uh, that's a problem.
Um, and conversely too,
like there's some rules around what you can and cannot issue certificates for.
So, like,
theoretically speaking,
certificates should really be issued only for a domain name
that is generally publicly available or at least kind
of maps to a domain that is public,
right? So, like,
you know, microsoft.com or google.com
and not like, you know, some fake domain, like,
uh, you know, Microsoft dot Internal,
right?
Like those, you know,
internal domains that people use that should never be on the internet.
Um And also things like you should never like,
create certificates for like local host
or, you know, IP addresses, you know, and, and those are actually something,
there's this thing called the uh the Cab Forum, the certificate authority.
I don't remember what it stands for, like something, certificate, authority,
browser, whatever form,
you know,
and they have these rules and these rules have been around for over a decade and,
you know, it turns out some of these cas are violating these rules like a lot, like,
pretty consistently.
Um, and so they, you know, they get spanked a little bit, whatever, no big deal,
but it turns out like Symantec at least.
Ok.
So Google claims Symantec did something like over 30,000 bad certificate,
you know, issuances
Symantec, of course, claims it was like, oh, no, it was only like 100 and something,
you know, we totally have like, yeah,
we got a little problem but not that big of a problem,
you know, and Google is basically saying, like, look,
it's pretty clear that Symantec and, or their subsidiaries, uh,
don't really have control over what they're doing and see.
And here's the dirty secret.
Ask me how many certificate authorities your web browser trusts.
Oh,
man, it's a lot. I haven't looked.
No. The correct answer is we don't know
because
here's the beauty.
You can have a root certificate in your browser.
That's more than one company.
Essentially somebody owns that root certificate,
but they might essentially be reselling access to it to multiple sub
certificate authorities
who essentially through like whatever means an api snail mail pigeons.
I don't know what,
but essentially can, you know, talk to the actual root certificate authority
and get certificates issued.
So the act, here's the beauty is
the actual number of certificate authorities on
planet Earth that your web browser trusts.
We don't know.
We know how many like root certificate authorities are in your browser.
But how many of those are
a single company or
possibly more than a single company? We don't actually know.
And so these, some of these, you know,
sub cas that essentially piggyback on the real CAS,
you know, they do a really terrible job because like, what have they got to lose,
right.
You know, they're basically just printing money while they can
and, you know, 500 bucks is 500 bucks.
So,
yeah, I mean, we're essentially at a point where, uh, Google put out a posting,
uh, talking about how they're essentially going to be.
Well, I don't wanna say they're phasing out support for Symantec,
but what they're doing is they're allowing
the Symantec certificates to only be valid for, uh,
shorter periods of time than you would normally expect,
which, you know, essentially forces people to get new certificates more often,
which in theory
should be safer because it makes people kind of
prove again who they are to the certificate authority,
right?
Because one of the dirty little secrets is,
uh, let's say, you know, your big company.com and you go bankrupt.
Well, part of your assets could be your certificate authority,
you know,
and that gets sold off. Um,
you know, so by forcing these people to sort of reprove who they are once in a while,
uh that, you know, in theory could make it better for end users,
right?
So in realistically speaking,
the system is such a mess and such a disaster right now,
it just flat out doesn't matter.
Uh Yeah,
you're probably correct. Which is sad.
Well, you know, what got me is back in the day when I,
I tried to get involved in this to try and help make the world a better place.
And then after about six months I gave up because it was just such a mess. But
one of the things that really got me was when
you asked to be included as a certificate of authority,
essentially the process was you would be included unless somebody could
prove that you should not be included.
So it was essentially fail open instead of fail closed
in my mind, something like this should be,
you are not getting in until you really prove
that you can be
trusted and safe and secure.
And there were cases, you know,
where uh there was that certificate authority in Holland that was you know,
completely
like their, their,
the machine they used to do all the certificates
was like a workstation that was riddled with viruses.
Um, and they were totally certified out by,
I think one of the major accounting firms,
um, I looked at some of these other, you know,
certificate authorities and tried to track down their,
who had audited them and said they were, you know, ok to,
to be trusted.
And I found this one firm,
an auditing firm.
Uh and Google Maps showed it as an office in the middle of a farmer's field
in Texas.
Normal, I believe
when they don't know where.
No, no, no. It actually turned out it was,
oh no, it was a legit address. So I actually
I phoned
and it was a one man operation
that does not surprise me at all. And, and so here's
what I think we should
kind of steer this conversation towards is
regardless of what you think of semantic or
regardless of whether Google is necessarily right or wrong
in the context of semantic.
I think the fact that they're willing to stand up to
ac A in this instance is a big deal because I remember
when the digit
order thing happened, talking to the Mozilla security guy specifically and saying
we need to kill the C A
and
they didn't want to,
they were afraid to because they thought there would be
too much backlash against like axing a whole C a
because obviously this doesn't just affect one thing.
It's going to affect hundreds or thousands or as you say,
like we don't entirely know.
And so I give Google tons of credit for standing up here.
Now, granted, at the same time, like this is Google,
no one else could do this except for them because they are the
million pound gorilla in the room.
Even Microsoft probably would struggle here because I bet Microsoft and
Symantec have very deep partnerships that I I bet if the,
if the browser guys at Microsoft tried to pull this stunt,
there'd be some uh help wanted signs in the window
the next day
to
be,
there'd be people calling people who wear expensive
suits and they would deal with this.
Yeah,
the biggest thing that's frustrating to me is
just the whole lack of transparency around this.
And
you know,
it has to be somebody like Google pushing really hard
for transparency and even then the cas are fighting it.
And
you know, it really strikes me that in,
in a situation where you literally have companies selling trust,
that's essentially what a certificate authority is,
is they are selling trust in the sense of like Josh came to us and said he owns,
you know, breer.com and we confirmed that he owns pressers.com
or.net or whatever I
own breast.net.
Sorry breast
was taken.
I didn't buy it.
Yeah.
So, you know, we've confirmed that he is breast.net through the following you know,
mechanisms and it's legit cool or, you know,
an extended validation certificate where we've actually
confirmed that he is Josh Bresser's and,
you know, all these things, you know,
and so they are literally selling trust and,
you know, the problem is that uh when it comes especially to things like
selling trust, you know,
things can go really wrong really fast
and therefore we need transparency,
you know, we need to know what's going on. Like who are they selling trust?
That's, that's part of it.
But regardless of transparency and this is where I think let's and crypt gets a lot of
this right is they use very short lifetimes on
these certificates because if something does go sideways,
it's only valid for what, 90 days.
Yeah, I think that's a big part of it.
Um, because some of these certificates that are being sold, I mean,
I think the last time I bought a certificate,
it gave me the option of up to five years or something.
It's, it's a long time.
Generally it's at least one year, sometimes even more, which is kind of crazy,
which also means the cas are trusted for
many, many years. Some of them are decades.
That would not surprise me. Some of them are 2030 years old.
Like seriously, I, when I looked, I was horrified
what could
possibly
go
wrong.
Um because, you know, this whole thing reminds me of that.
It's, it's similar to the whole crypto
agility argument. You know, if, if we find out it uh uh
an encryption, you know, algorithm or cipher is bad, we need to be able to, like,
use something else.
And same thing with certificates, right?
Like if this certificate is compromised or, you know,
turns out it was issued to the wrong person.
Um I mean, here's the dirty little secret, right?
All the mechanisms we have around certificate, revocation
don't work, right. Certificate, revocation lists don't really work.
And the online certificate something protocol, I know it's OS CP.
I can't remember what the s stands for ever.
You know, it doesn't scale and it also has privacy implications. Right?
Because every time I go to a secure website, I'd be like,
you know,
checking for that
thing. Right.
Um Funny enough to, you can, well, in, in the Os CP stuff fails all the time is
I, I remember at one point you could enable in Firefox basically, if it can't
OS CP info just fail
and the internet is un brows
if you turn that on because everything is failing all the time.
Yeah. Well, I remember when they were talking about the Os Co
CS P responders, there's no actual requirements about their up time or anything.
And, you know,
so I remember somebody measured it and I think
they were getting like one or two nines,
like these things work down all the bloody time. Nine fives. Right.
Yeah,
like 9.999.
Right. Right.
And uh
yeah, so the whole thing is just, you know, and, and
obviously we've come to the point where, you know, Firefox and, you know,
Internet Explorer and Chrome are
every month or two.
You know, you, you look at the updates notes and it's like, you know,
here's a bunch of extra certificates we revoked because it turns out, you know,
like this dude in China bought a microsoft.com certificate or, or whatever,
you know,
that's always a treat.
Although on that note, did you see somebody went through the let's encrypt
data and found what, like 400 domains that it
was
like,
oh, was it that many?
Well,
here's the thing, I mean, it's, they don't,
um
uh as far as I know, lets and Crypt doesn't have like a, a restricted list of keywords.
Like what paypal Bank Walmart? Like who decides that list?
You know, it becomes a pain in the butt because a
great example of this is cloud flare has um a list of restricted keywords.
And I know this for a fact because when
I moved the cloud security lines to cloud flare,
you know, part of the whole shick was everything's automated,
it'll take minutes to set up and I did this on a Friday and like it didn't work,
right. And so I flipped back and I was like, what's the deal?
Well, because the domain name includes the word security, it needed like
the C A, the certificate of authority that, uh, cloud flare goes through,
which I think was Komodo back in the day.
Don't quote me,
but essentially the certificate of authority was like, whoa, whoa, whoa,
we're not giving you automated issuance of this domain.
Like we are gonna have a manual check, which of course, a human being involved
would, it took several days,
you know,
which seems reasonable. I, yeah, I just looked at the story
14,766 L SSL certificates.
You do paypal phishing sites.
Yeah.
And see, that's why we need transparency because for example,
I think that's actually a good thing because then
that lets you take those 14 or 15,000 domain names
and like,
you know, blacklist them and, or look up, you know, where are they being hosted?
You
know, and maybe,
you know,
talk about like not letting people talk to those
sites or if they have talked to those sites,
go through your logs and warn them,
you know. Now, of course there's the flip side of all sorts of
snappings, you know, I,
I register fake paypal things and point them at your site to get you in trouble.
Maybe, you know, things like that, right?
But fundamentally, I mean, could you, I mean,
maybe it's uh it's, I mean, if you don't want to grieve somebody or troll them,
you know, it's like the old, you know, sending like Joe
dropping,
you know, Joe
dropping the spam email where I send it out is from, you know, Joshua
breast.net and then you get like a million angry replies,
you know, because people just hate replying, like take me off your list
and they still do that 20 years later.
Um But I mean, realistically it doesn't matter that much.
I mean, what I really want to see is that transparency. So
kind of we know how bad the problem is and then, you know,
people can take action like block those domains or check
their DS logs for those domains and you know,
notify whoever went there or clicked on those links.
Right. Right.
Well, and actually I suppose you,
you also bring up a good point is by publishing all this and making it easy to get,
you could
put something into your like threat hunting tool kit or log analysis or whatever,
looking for this stuff.
And additionally, then you can start correlating.
Well, why did they click this link? Did they get an email?
Was it, you know,
some sort of spear fishing thing or water cooler attack or what's the deal here?
So,
yeah, I mean, that is cool
and you know, you do something with that.
This is uh, well,
sort of commercial plug for the cloud secure lines and the true Star stuff.
This is, you know, this is some of what true star is doing, right.
It's like, oh, this IP is associated with this fishing campaign,
you know.
So if anybody at your network talked to that IP, uh,
you might have a problem with passwords being, you know,
being sent to Russia or whatever.
Um,
because I mean, that to me,
I think is the biggest thing is you can't keep the bad guys out all the time.
You know, and banks have learned this right. Banks aren't robbery proof.
But what banks have done is they've made it so hard to
get a large amount of cash out of them that it's,
you know,
you can rob a banker but you're going to get a couple of grand at most. Typically,
it's really not worth it. You'd be better off fishing people
for.
And as we were talking about offline, I remember, you know, there's, oh man,
I lost the article but there's that bank.
Now that's essentially
um
they're going to a model where there's like
the only cash on the premises is essentially like
in ATM S and it has to have like valid transactions to get the cash out,
you know.
So it's not like the teller,
like because they currently have machines where the
teller goes up to the machine and like,
you know, beep boop, boop
and like out comes 500 bucks,
but you know, you do it. So it has to be tied into a legitimate transaction.
So now, you know, the bank robber would have to like put a gun to my head and be like, ok,
I need you to, like,
do a cash withdrawal of like 500 bucks from your account. Right.
So, you'd have to, like, hope there's a bunch of high rollers in the branch, you know,
with
large, you know, withdrawal limits.
Um, so that you could then force cash out of them. And, I mean, you know, and
that's also going to cut down on fraud and that's
going to cut down on all sorts of insider attacks.
So, the absurdity of this
is, it would take 25 minutes to rob a bank instead of four.
And I suspect, I don't know what the number is.
I'm sure someone's done a study of this, but my guess is after about 10 minutes,
your odds of getting arrested by police are probably very close
to 100% bank robbery unless you're in the middle of nowhere.
I mean, and that's what's actually started happening here in Alberta
is, people are essentially stealing ATM S from rural locations
and by stealing atms.
I mean, like using heavy equipment to, like, go take the entire ATM.
Right, because you can't crack an ATM open on the premises without again taking,
you know, at least a few minutes or tens of minutes.
Um, so, yeah, they just basically steal the entire ATM, take it somewhere, I guess.
And, like, chisel it open or whatever.
Right. Right.
Which is not, I mean, the whole smash and grab thing has been a, I mean, that's,
that's not new.
No, it's a classic.
I think we've been doing it since, like, what
ages forever.
It's the beginning of the first person to pick up a rock.
Probably created the smash and grab Robertson.
So,
yeah. Anyway, anyway, we're, we're in the, we're
in good
times.
Uh,
so well related to the whole encryption thing I guess would be, uh, the open SSL
the licensing. That's crazy. This is such a wild story.
I'm,
I'm glad they're doing this because the open SSL license
is kind of a mess and silly and I hate
it. So explain how joyful this, this archaic license is to us
it.
OK? So
for those of you who don't know
most open source, well, all open source because it's not open source,
but it doesn't have, it comes with a license
which basically says
the copyright holders
and in most instances,
it's an s there's many copyright holders are giving you
permission to use their copyrighted source code in this way.
And so obviously, like the Linux kernel has a license, you know,
Firefox has a license.
Open SSL has a license.
Literally,
every piece of open source software has to have some
sort of open source license associated with it because obviously,
if it didn't, it wouldn't be open source.
In the case of open SSL. Open SSL is really old
and the license was kind of created based upon
the three clause BS D license very long ago
and
it's not an ideal license.
And there's a lot of people who suspect the current open SSL license,
which is called literally the open SCL license
is incompatible with the GP L for example.
And there's a lot of back and forth and
it'll probably never get actually tested in court.
Thank goodness.
But, but fundamentally to simplify this, the open SSL guys now want to relic
open SSL under the Apache 2.0 license, which is a very nice license.
That's very BS D ish in terms of just giving
a lot of permissions to everybody to kind of do
almost whatever they want to do with it.
Yes, my understanding is, it's generally the,
the Apache 2.0 license is one of the
most uh commercially acceptable licenses like in the
sense of that's what corporations that want to
ship this are willing and happy to accept.
Yes. Yes, that's absolutely correct. But, so here's the trick. You can't just say
I'm gonna relic
open SSL.
SSL
has more than
if they had assigned copyright. They could, but they did not, they didn't.
And the SFFFSF does that the free software
foundation does this for this exact reason?
Because here's what's happening
is in order for Open SSL to change their license,
they have to contact more than 400 contributors who are
also copyright holders on this code and they need their permission
to change the license. If one of them says, no,
they're kind of screwed
and they,
they basically have to either rewrite that
code and get the original author stuff out
or just not change it are basically their options at that point.
See, and I think that might actually not be the worst thing because, you know,
some of this code probably does need a rewrite a
lot
of it,
but I can help. I don't know if you remember. Um,
this is going back ways uh the channel,
you know, the channel tunnel between Britain and France.
So one of the strategies for the people that hated the channel
was to buy up the farmland at either end where, you know,
the entrance and exit would be
and then to further complicate things
to sell off that farmland in like literally one inch
squares to like just all sorts of random people,
you know, through newspaper ads and stuff.
You hate a tunnel so much you would like, try to,
there's somebody that hates every,
there's always somebody that hates something no matter what,
right.
You know.
And so the idea being that, you know, then they would like, try and, you know,
they want,
they need to acquire the land to build the train tracks
and the tunnel entrance and stuff and they'd be like,
nope, sorry,
you got like acquire this land and it's owned by like 10 million different people.
So good luck with that. Ha ha we win.
And of course, you know, the judges were like, yeah. No.
Right. Too bad. So sad. Uh, we're invoking eminent domain and off we go.
And so, you know, that's the thing, like, when it comes to land and all that, there's,
uh,
in most jurisdictions, a lot of history of, you know,
the courts invoking eminent domain basically saying, like, quit being a jerk,
we're going to let them build this useful thing over here because it clearly,
you know, it's in the best interest.
Right? I
don't know. And it's
copyright is very different. Well, exactly. And that's,
first of all, is there,
uh, is relicensing to the Apache 2.0 license? Is it like, clearly a good thing?
I mean, it's
better, I would say in many ways, but it's not like, you know,
you have Swampland and we're gonna build like a nice city there.
Clearly a nice city is better than Swampland in most cases.
Are you for the record? Are you calling Open ssl a swamp or
I will take the fifth even though I'm Canadian
anyway.
Yes.
Like you said it, it's, we're now, well,
and the problem is we're not only into copyright law,
we're into multiple jurisdictions of copyright law,
potentially. Yes, copyright is very complex
and
I know far more about it than I wish I did for a variety of reasons.
But so the fundamental problem being that
if you write some software,
you own the copyright on that
and you can attach an open source license to it which gives certain rights to the,
I guess, user or receiver recipient, whatever you wanna call them.
But you still own that copyright and I mean, you could write,
you could write software on the moon
and
you still have that copyright. It doesn't matter where you do it.
Copyright.
Ottawa signs in.
I know the US and I believe Canada and then most Western jurisdictions,
for the most part, a lot of these,
these countries have treaties that recognize one another's copyrights.
In fact, I know the US
has done a fabulous job of strong arming most
other countries into accepting kind of their copyright terms.
Thanks to,
we'll say a handful of large media corporations that resigns.
Right.
It's, it's so complex though.
Well,
I'm actually glad in a way that copyright Auto was
signs because otherwise you'd have all these people who just
either can't be bothered to, you know,
go submit their copyright or whatever.
Um,
but the problem is now we've gone to the term where copyrights are what,
like 90 years plus
dead.
Yeah, exactly.
That's the problem.
This is such a complicated topic and
we probably shouldn't get in the weeds on this right here right now. But I think
fundamentally
this is a great move by open SSL.
I hope they're successful, but they have a ton of crazy pain
in front of them. I mean, this is, I know
there's been talk of this for example,
like in the Linux kernel to look at maybe relicensing it
as some something else other than GP L version two.
And,
and very quickly it was decided that this is impossible
and there is no way to actually do it.
And you have to think there's people are dead,
there are people who, nobody knows where they are anymore.
There's people who don't care anymore. There's people who wouldn't like it.
It's completely
crazy
question. How do you even know?
Like, I mean, in some cases these people are literally just an email address.
Yeah. Yeah. In a lot of cases that's going to happen. And
I, if I had to guess open SSL is trying to contact more than 400 people,
I bet 10 to 20% of them will be uncontacted,
which means you have to figure out what are we going to do now?
Well, they
put up a website where you can search to see if
your name or whatever your email address is in the,
you know, responsible for any of the code.
Right.
Yes. But
there are people who are dead
like
there,
I guarantee there's people who've worked on openness as l who are no longer alive.
And so now you have next of kin issues, for example, that you have to deal with.
See,
part of me wonders are they gonna go with sort of a best
effort to contact them and then just do it and see if anybody,
because the reality is, unless somebody, like, actually
complains and by complaints, I don't mean, just, like,
sends out a nasty email but actually, like, takes them to a court of law.
Right. I mean, you're basically gonna get away with it.
Kind of like Uber with their whole, like, oh, we're not a taxi company
and we're just gonna ignore all these rules and, you know, and until cities started,
like,
finding them and taking them to court Uber was while getting away with being Uber.
But here's the problem with something like open SSL is if they
don't have explicit permission for every line of code from every contributor,
you now have something that yes, they could say
it's covered by another license.
But what would happen if Lord forbid one of these,
we'll say disagreeable copyright holders showed up one day and started demanding,
you know, royalties or, or whatnot out of
some other organization.
Now, granted,
I know there's a lot of nuance to this and that's really probably not
something that's even remotely plausible given it
already has an open source license.
But you can,
you understand the unknown
it's introduced here that would make this even less palatable I think,
which is the whole reason to change the license
is to make it more palatable to more organizations.
Right.
Well, I think realistically, one thing to keep in mind is, you know,
if somebody's written code for open SSL and that code has
existed in open SSL for say five or 10 years unchanged
and,
you know, obviously
not really maintained otherwise, it would have been rewritten by definition,
you know, uh
I'm guessing a lot of that old code would actually not be super hard to replace.
I mean, it would be a chore and a pain. Yes.
But I mean, from a legal point of view,
it's obviously it's probably gonna be a lot less work than trying to chase down next
of kin or some estate and trying to get them to sign off on this thing,
you know, and that's assuming you,
after you spend 20 hours explaining to them what the heck is going on.
Right. Right.
Because, you know, I know, even if I got a phone call like that, I'd be like,
what in there, you know,
like what's going on here?
Right. Right.
Oh, my goodness.
So I, I'm just, I'm also curious as to why they're actually changing the license.
Like, yeah, it's definitely a good thing that clarifies things, you know,
the A PL 2.0 is a lot more clear than the open SSL license.
But it's not like people aren't shipping open SSL because of the license? Right.
Or am I missing something?
No. Well, people ship it but there's some
shady area
kind of around this. And so I, I think this is the right thing to do
and I suspect that part of this is because open SSL
has very much had an awakening over the last couple of years
where they're, they're fixing a lot of things and like,
this has been an elephant in the room
forever
and I,
I commend them for tackling this because this
is monumental to the point of almost impossible.
So
good luck. God bless. Right.
Yeah.
No, I, I, personal preference would be because I've seen people use, like,
just made up licenses and it's, you know, it's just, it's annoying
because I'm,
I'm not a lawyer and I don't know whether or
not this license is even remotely valid or complete garbage,
you know, whereas if they use an O si approved open source license, it's like, well,
I don't understand it
but these O SI guys claim that they do and they claim that it's ok and
really there's not a lot more I can do without spending like 50 to 100 grand on a good,
you know, lawyer.
Right. Which
nobody's going to do,
just try getting it into Fedora as part of the Fedora package review process.
It gets a legal looking over if it has a strange license and,
yeah, it's,
it's very interesting
reading the emails that come across the Fedora legal list.
It's, it's awesome.
I can't even imagine. I don't want to.
No, it's good. It's good. It's
all good fun. All good fun. Yeah.
So moving along, I guess we, uh, we have
World
dishwasher.
We have to talk about the dishwasher,
the directory traversal attack and a dishwasher.
See,
I love this because like a dishwasher is something you
could use to actually really mess up somebody's day.
Like, you know, fill it with super heated steam and say it's OK to open,
you know, you pop the dishwasher open and out comes a bunch of super heated steam.
No,
maybe, I mean, just
why is there a directory Dre
deck in a dishwasher? Because it has a web browser.
It has a, I don't think it has a web, web server. I don't think this was a
browser
or web
because there's,
yeah, I, well, there was that smart TV.
I was just watching that smart TV that has a built in web browser
that supports flash, right? Because it's a, you know,
well, no, because it's a smart TV. And you might want to browse the web on it because
flash.
But that means that flash doesn't work on arm chips, does it?
Well, no, it wasn't quite, you, you could get flash, I forget.
But anyways point being is that you could attack it through flash, which
I mean, basically the second you have uh Adobe flash on something, it's,
it's just a matter of time until you get hacked.
Right. Seriously. You know, like that fedex $5 thing, right? Like,
so fedex
has apparently some label printing website or something or software. I don't know
that, you know, relies on flash to work and create these labels.
And of course, you know, like I, I've banned Flash from my household and it's,
it's actually pretty easy because, you know,
we're an Apple household so all the mobile devices by default just can't have it.
Thank goodness.
Um,
and so, you know, fedex is like, offering people, what is it,
like a $5 coupon if they install flash and use the software,
it's not worth $5.
Well, exactly.
I mean, just, just in, in the, the time you're gonna spend updating flash every month
or every two months or whatever it is, a
loan is going to eat up more than $5 of your time. The fact that you're gonna get,
you're, you're, you're definitely going to get hacked by a flash at some point.
Like it's just statistically, you know, it's not gonna happen.
And um
yeah, I mean, to, in my mind, like the III I don't have strong, like,
I don't ban a lot of things,
but the two things I've banned in my household are
like Java for the web browser and Adobe Flash.
I like how you add for the web browser
because there'd be no Minecraft if you banned Java
ipad man,
which probably still runs Java.
Yeah.
Anyways.
Um But yeah, I mean, it's, you know, I'm not anti Java per se. I'm just really anti
Java in the web browser.
Uh
Yeah, I, I think it's safe to say at this point that web browser plugins,
especially when they're running, turn complete applications are a bad idea
and especially when they're running in sandboxes that are, you know,
not very well done apparently.
Right.
Ok. So back to this dishwasher.
I love this story and
here's the real reason
that I love it is
ignoring all of the hilarious jokes we can make about a dishwasher with Wi Fi
that has a directory. Traversal flaw
is
the bigger problem is people who build
dishwashers probably don't know anything about computer security
and why would they? Right.
Well, that's, that's the reality. Right. Is, is
outside,
I was gonna say, outside of the it industry,
outside of a small part of the it industry, everything is now the it industry.
Correct. Exactly. That's the problem. Right.
Uh,
you want to build cars while they're gonna be self driving and
that means you're gonna have a ton of computers on them,
you know, you want to build apparently appliances now
where everything's gonna have, you know, a computer, like a,
a legitimate computer in it.
Not just like some little CP, uh, you know, not some little custom chip that, like,
controls your toaster, but
heck might as well put an arm CPU in there that can run
a, you know, uh, wifi and some other stuff so it can talk to other stuff.
Yeah. I mean,
so
the cost of installing flash, you too can have Wi Fi in your dishwasher. Right.
So, yeah, No, it's, I, I kind of wonder because, uh, at some point
are we going to be able to buy things without this capability?
No, we will not.
And I think we're, we're rapidly approaching
the,
I guess, universal iot
just point of no return that event horizon where now everything has
wi fi whether you want it or not
and more of a concern.
A lot of these things are running servers that are like,
really insecure or they're running update systems that are really insecure
with the web server. Yeah.
You know,
and that's true. You think that? I wonder if this thing has an update method?
I bet.
I, well, if it does have an update it would only be for several years.
And I, it's funny actually because CBC marketplace was just did, it did, uh, uh,
some articles on sort of this whole appliance industry
and how it's just a complete disaster now because,
ok, let me ask you this.
How many major appliance makers do you think there are globally?
There's, there's probably only, what, four or five, maybe
Bingo four.
Yeah,
it's really small
and
it's the same thing when people are, like, what computer should I buy?
And I'm like, there's like two companies that make them all.
It really doesn't matter.
There's Foxconn and the other one.
Right. That, right. Exactly.
You know, the reason, you know about Foxconn it's because of,
like Apple and the Happy Nets.
So,
the happiness catching nets.
Right. Right.
It's like a big hug to show we care.
Welcome to the future. This is the good news is they're replacing
the robots.
Yes, which is hilarious because obviously
the whole reason Foxconn is in China is because of the low wage
that they get to pay the employees. And apparently robots are cheaper
and they make lots of mistakes.
They
don't.
So I should.
But
no, it,
it, it
really
is.
So. Yeah. No.
So there's basically four appliance manufacturers
and the majority of the appliances
that are being built now only last 2 to 5 years.
Like we're talking and we're talking major things like fridges, washers, dryers,
you know, and, you know, and granted,
I don't want an appliance now that lasts like 40
years because the thing is gonna be so energy inefficient,
you know, 40 years from now and
so laughably obsolete, you know, it's,
I don't necessarily want that, but on the flip side, I,
I would like to have a dishwasher that lasts at least 10 years,
you know, a fridge that keeps my food cold.
Like, fundamentally, I want my fridge to do two things, you know, have an,
I have like a freezer area and have like a cold area
and show.
But you can, you can have wi I in a web server for
the low, low price of, uh, you don't get to choose.
Yeah.
And I mean, what drives me nuts too is when I, I've looked at these smart fridges.
None of them have like a really good say for example, barcode scanner so I can like,
you know, drink the last cup of milk.
Barcode scan the milk and boom, it gets added to the grocery list.
That sounds like a useful feature. But I bet it can watch youtube. Yeah.
Well, and I've seen ones that have like you can kind of, you know,
talk to grocery list or whatever, but, you know, I want something a little bit more,
you know,
that I can integrate with my existing systems, you know,
and I mean, my classic favorite is there was that smart fridge that was, um,
it had software to talk to Google calendar.
So it could display like your calendar kind of like, you know, on your little
vaguely use,
you could do the same thing by just printing off a piece of paper.
No, but here's the problem. Uh, Google depreciated that api some time ago
even better.
And of course you're not going to get a fridge update for it. So,
well, that was a nice feature that you no longer get to have.
Whoops,
you know, and see,
that's why I'm really hesitant to go with these smart appliances is like,
um, didn't youtube have some API that they, they deprecated a long time ago and,
you know, a
whole
bunch of
Samsung or LG or
one of their TV S quit working. I do remember that. Exactly.
So, you know, and this is one of the reasons why I prefer having,
say something like an Apple TV or a computer hooked up to my TV.
Because I, you know, I,
in general,
I feel things like computers running Mac Os or Linux
or Windows are probably gonna get updates for a while,
you know,
same thing with the Apple TV. And, you know, versus the Samsung TV.
S or the LG or whoever.
Um,
well, funny story too is uh when we were talking the other day,
I was trying to remember what brand of TV.
I own.
We and II, I don't know anymore. Right. They're, they're black and they're flat.
I only know because mine comes with Roku built in and insignia
is the only company that does that
I've never even heard of them.
After doing a lot of research, I think they're an off brand sold by Best Buy.
They may only be sold by Best Buy.
In fact, because like when I go to Costco now and I, I mean, I recognize,
I think they sell Toshiba who I've heard of,
but then there's all these other brands and I'm like, I never heard of them.
Well, you, you know what part of it is though, is,
it's probably this similar story of,
I believe it's the giant mountain bike company is they used to
make all the parts for all these other mountain bike companies.
And when did you like, why are we making parts for everyone else?
Let's just make our own bikes.
And
are they?
Right,
they basically started making their own bikes and now they're
very popular and obviously they're high quality because they,
they knew what the supply chain was.
And I imagine a lot of these off brand things you see are just,
the manufacturers are like, well, screw it.
Let's just put our own logo on it and,
and dump it into the US market and people will
buy them and they will because let's face it,
people generally don't care.
But this also we can bring back to this dish dishwasher discussion of
if, if these ODM type manufacturers are able to just
make them
ODM. Now there's like OEM which is original equipment and ODM
original
original device
manufacturer,
there's a level beneath the OEM
and the ODM
are
just
screw it. Let's just skip these guys and, and do it ourselves.
And so this is what you're seeing happen now
is
and, and additionally, so here's the thing. So let's say you want to regulate
the, the IOT and you say if you're gonna sell the dishwasher with Wi Fi,
you need to get this license here.
Well, what happens if someone just makes like, you know,
whatever happy brand dishwashers and they,
they dump a couple million of them on the market and the,
and the regulator show up say, oh no, no.
You know we're gonna come after you guys, you need this license
like, oh yeah, uh Happy dishwasher went out of business. Now we're selling, uh,
you know, joyous dishwashers and,
and this is totally different and you know what I mean?
Like, you, you cannot stop this.
Well, and I mean, more to the point,
I'm not sure it would legally be allowed because now with
things like the WTO and various other trade deals that we've had
internationally,
uh, you could probably make a very strong argument that this is like, uh,
essentially they're trying to do an end, run an end, run around tariffs and taxes,
you know, by requiring, like, legal blah, blah, blah for Wi Fi enabled devices when,
you know, they never did this before and they're not doing it for these other things.
That
would be
interesting.
I mean, I, I, if I, you know, if I, if I was the guy in China trying to get around this,
that I would look at, you know, arguments around that because,
you know,
then it goes to like that wonky
WTO arbitration which bypasses national governments.
So
I'm not sure we're even at a point
where we could legally regulate this stuff anymore,
even if we had like, the strength of will to do so politically and, and there isn't,
I mean, we, yeah, I don't think any
will be
in the garbage dump in five years.
Right.
Well, not only that everything changes so fast by the time you have a regulation.
It is, it's going to be irrelevant.
I mean, this would be like
writing regulations about the internet via dial up
and it's like no one does that anymore.
Guys. This, this doesn't matter.
See, and my one concern here is, uh,
so the average age of a car in the US car fleet is I believe 11 years.
That's what I hear.
So, you know, somebody was talking about, um,
essentially, you know,
if we phase out like TLS 101112 and we move everything to 1.3 which is great.
Kind of, when do we actually have to do that in cars to make sure, say 10 years from now,
90% of them have TLS 1.3.
And the answer is like we have to get it done in the next two years
because of the cycles because the thing to remember
too is the cycles for creating these devices.
You know,
this dishwasher company isn't going to, you know,
be spending like an obscene amount of money on the software.
They're gonna do like the bare minimum. Of
course, you know, pull something off the shelf, get it working and boom, we're done,
you know, and unless there's like a Showstopper bug where the thing catches fire
even then, man.
Yeah. You know,
so I, I, I'm at the point where I, I don't think regulations will work. I think what
I think the only thing that can possibly even stand a
chance of making things slightly better is the consumer style reports.
A thing where
we have to kind of get things so bad where people actually do start, you know,
when they buy cars, they pay attention to what the consumer reports,
safety crash rating is.
Uh, maybe it, it could also something like underwriter labs
when you, I mean, well, you, I forget what the Canadian organization is called,
but in the US, we have UL and obviously
you're, you're not supposed to sell
electrical equipment without the UL logo.
Well, and my understanding of the deal is there is like a lot of insurance and stuff.
Well, you know,
if you buy non UL approved stuff and plug it
into your house and it burns your house down,
it's kind of like, well,
we're sorry you did that, we're not gonna cover it, you know,
um,
or if you like, rewire your house yourself and don't get, uh, you know,
a licensed electrician to do it.
They're like, yeah, that
you shouldn't have done that,
which takes,
you know, it makes sense. Right, because you can't have people randomly
messing around with this stuff and, you know,
expect it to not end in tears at least once in a while.
Um,
so, yeah, I think really the only way it's going to happen is that sort of
because insurance is a really insurance is a big industry and they understand,
you know, risk assessment, like that's their entire lifeblood
and
they do occasionally get it horribly wrong
and, you know, they suffer for it and then they typically tend to, you know,
change how they operate.
So a great example being, you know, is, is these insurers used to,
uh,
you know, take on risk insurance and,
you know, but occasionally you'd have a s, a
really catastrophic event
but they actually had to cover, you know, with, without being, you know,
like an act of God or an act of war.
And so these insurers would just get clobbered, right and lose a ton of money.
And now, you know, they have this concept of reinsurance. So,
you know, I as an insurance company will say,
insure like $10 billion of property in where hurricanes happen,
I will then take that $10 billion of, you know,
insurance kind of load and split it up into say 100 packets
and sell that to 100 different companies, right? So that
they, you know, when there is a catastrophic event,
you know, that, that,
that damage essentially is spread out among multiple companies
rather than just one big company taking the hit.
Sure.
Um And I suspect the same will have to happen
for anything to change because
yeah, politically it's not gonna happen technologically,
it's not gonna happen because there's no economic incentive to spend
money on being secure when you're pushing out dishwashers that,
you know, people are going to throw it in five years anyways.
Well, we've discussed this before.
I mean, if, if you went to the store and dishwasher A said
with added security and it cost $50 more. Dishwasher. B was like, regular security.
I would probably buy dishwasher. B,
yeah.
Yeah, me too. I mean,
it's not like, I mean, the reality is, I,
I don't know what added security means and even if they put in, like, you know,
I don't know, whatever version of TLS it supports, I mean,
unless they put in something really specific, like, you know,
this thing will get guaranteed security updates
for, say, five years
and here's how we define security updates and here's how, you know,
the response time and everything.
But at that point, we're getting into an area that, like, literally nobody does
and
I'm gonna save $50 and go buy a new game for my Nintendo switch.
That's
basically what would happen.
Yeah, exactly.
Um, so,
yeah. No, it's,
again, we're doomed.
It's $5 dishwashers, sorry, $5 rebates for installing flash on your dishwasher.
Oh, man. Flash in your dishwasher. I love it.
So, and, well, and you know, and speaking of safety and security, right?
There's like that recent, like,
laptop slash ipad ban on like Middle Eastern carriers.
Um, so for those of you that haven't heard, apparently, uh, the US government
sent out something basically saying, you know,
you cannot take anything bigger than, like, a cell phone onto
an airplane for a certain subset of Middle Eastern comp uh countries and flights.
And so, you know, the internet is,
of course abuzz with rumors and it really seems to boil down to either a,
there's like some plot by terrorists to, like,
fill an ipad full of explosives and blow up an airplane.
Uh, b this is some sort of, um,
punitive measure again to do an end, run around like, you know,
treaties and stuff and to basically punish certain Middle Eastern carriers.
Uh because, you know,
the reality is like business travelers are not going to get
on a flight where they can't have their laptop or ipad,
you know, I, I would be hesitant to,
it would, it would be a and that those are long flights.
These are like super crazy long flights. Now,
if you look though
Schneer
did some writing on this and he has some inside information,
it sounds like we're basically,
this is not politically motivated that there's actually some sort of intelligence
decision behind this where they're using this to mitigate a real threat.
Well, and then there's that third sort of thought process on this where it's like,
well, maybe,
you know, by separating travelers from their laptops and ipads,
you can now, you know, stick in USB key, turn it on and, you know,
compromise their devices
and it is conceivable
that something like that is part of this because
that, that isn't necessarily politically motivated
in that respect. And, and that's actually the first thing I thought of is
I would be hesitant to let my laptop
o off of my person in this manner
because
I mean, you always hear these stories about the baggage handlers essentially,
you know, like, like rifling through bags and taking things and all that.
Oh, yeah.
Well, there was that case recently, that guy that, you know,
got done up after stealing dozens of laptops.
Right.
I mean, and I know for myself, I've had those, those Ts,
a inspection pamphlets or whatever you call them, the little piece of paper saying,
you know, your bag was inspected by the TS A,
uh, for whatever reason
and, you know, and they smashed the heck out of that, um, tablet, you know,
you got me like they just, oh,
the poor thing was just destroyed.
Um,
yeah.
So, I mean, I, I, yeah, I've on multiple occasions had my checked luggage, you know,
rifled through because quite honestly, like,
I'll typically have like a big pile of wires in there,
you know. And so
it keeps mine checked all the time is I use a safety razor
when I shave and I will put safety razor blades in my check bag.
And every time I've had safety razor blades in the bag it gets checked.
I get one of the little tags regardless of country, even
like I've had this happen in Europe and in the us. Yep. Yep.
So, whatever.
That's how it is.
This,
I don't know, man. It, it's so crazy.
It's such a bizarre story and I guess here's part of the problem and this,
we'll, we'll try to tie everything back up into this is
it comes down to transparency
when you tell people to do something and you don't give them a good reason to do it.
They don't like that.
Well, when you tell them to do something inconvenient to themselves,
that's ok.
That, that's, yeah,
that's a very good point because the inconvenience is a huge part of that.
Like in the case of Symantec versus Google,
Google is being very transparent here.
And so Symantec obviously has to be defensive.
Whereas if Symantec somehow could become more transparent,
Google would end up being defensive.
In this case, you've got
the government and this is, this is typical of intelligence, just it's how it is.
They're not telling you why
and they won't tell you why because that secrecy is part of their secret sauce.
But because of that now people are saying
what's going on is this politically motivated?
Is this,
you know, are they stealing computers? Are they cutting data off computers?
Are they, does this even make sense?
Yeah.
I mean, the problem is they can't say, well,
we have a real world threat of people trying to pack explosives into ipads, you know,
and we spotted it last Thursday and everybody like, oh, ok.
But obviously they can't do that, to be honest with you.
I bet it's not even that because
this, the way they did this makes that the logical outcome,
which tells me that isn't the reason they're doing it.
It's something else
because
the intelligence people are smart enough to understand what logical outcomes
are when they make decisions and they make sure that's not,
they, they, they make sure the logical outcome isn't the one they're looking for.
So it's, it's craziness, man. It's all crazy.
Yeah, I mean, my fear is honestly if that, if that policy spreads globally, I mean,
that's gonna make flying just a pain in the ass.
I don't even want to think about it, you know, like I don't want to get on a, like
I don't want to get on a flight with my kids without their ipads.
Oh my goodness. I can't imagine.
Like
hopefully
please just let the Nintendo switch on.
Yeah.
Well, and that's what's interesting is I know for a fact, like they're always like,
you have to open, what is it?
You have to like,
open your laptop and turn it on and make sure
and show them it's working unless it's a Mac device.
I guess the theory being, you know,
mac devices have like no space in them to hide contraband or, you know,
other shenanigans,
you know, same thing with um
because my, my Apple Air, right, my little uh laptop
I have um like a nice gel sticker on the front of it.
And,
you know,
I've had them not recognize it as an Apple device and then I open it and they're, and
they're like, 00, it's an Apple. Yeah, you don't have to turn it on. Right.
I've never had that happen to me and hopefully I never will.
Yeah. And so, and same thing with tablets. Right.
You don't have to turn tablets on to prove that they work, you know.
Um
But I mean, and the ugly truth though is that, you know,
with increasing battery capacity,
we're we're approaching the point where batteries
have the energy density of explosives.
So like
legitimately what happens then when somebody can like,
you know, stab or
essentially compromise the battery,
you're gonna get us put on a list, I think
it's time to bring it home.
We get ourselves into trouble.
Thank you, everyone for listening.
It has been a most enjoyable episode.
If you want the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com.
We have links there to things like Twitter and a Facebook group.
You are welcome to interact with us. And
if you have any information on any of these scary stories, by all means, let us know.
I
Yeah, Kurt, you have a fantastic day and until next time.
Yeah. Uh please remember to use the hashtag Os S podcast. Ah Yes, that's true.
The Os S podcast. Hashtag Very good, very good. All right folks.
Thanks for listening. Until next time. Bye bye.
Happy Spring, everybody.