Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 127
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
-- What's
-- new man?
We've had beautiful snow and the skiing is great.
Yeah, that's fair
because you live way up north. So we,
yeah, where, where I live, which I'm obviously fairly far north in the US.
We've had some ice and that's pretty much it. We've had no real snow at all.
So it's just rotten out.
We had ice last week. We actually had freezing rain on Friday
and that was not super awesome.
But now we've had about three inches of just delightfully fluffy snow.
And like I said, the skiing is just
my son actually fell because he caught an edge
because he's never skied on proper snow before.
He's only ever skied on like machine groomed,
you know. So it's like skiing on a Teflon frying pan, right?
Which, you know, better than nothing. But
yeah.
So he was taking a turn and caught an edge and spun around and he was like,
just the look of confusion on his face.
Right.
We had a little talk about powder.
So, yeah, for those. Anyways. Um,
so the other thing that's come up in a couple of things is the, um,
Mozilla has been removing some extensions.
-- Yeah, I saw that you sent me that story. That's wild
-- and not for the usual reason.
Like they're malicious and terrible in stealing people's banking details,
which I'm ok when they remove those extensions, like that's
fine.
You know,
you can, you can throw plaguy people off the boat. That's cool.
You know.
Right.
-- I think, I think you're a witch. Right. Let's
-- just
see
if
you are a witch and if you drowned. Well,
you a
good death.
Oh, well,
sorry about that.
Right.
But, uh, no, they, they have removed apparently a whole bunch of paywall bypasses.
So we should all right. So, first of all, I guess, uh, what is a paywall bypass?
Let's, let's start there.
So a paywall is essentially a website that says, uh, you want to look at our content,
you got to pay.
There's a wall literally of you having to pay to look at the content.
So there's a bunch of newspapers and stuff that do this
and a paywall bypass is something that makes your web browser look different.
Um, so for example, it like makes you look like a Google search spot or, you know,
other things that these websites will allow to scrape their
website and look at their website without paying or,
-- you know,
-- it's really
sad. And some of them even is, I've seen some of those paywall bypasses.
They just, there's
so they load the article and then they load javascript that opens
up the paywall box and they just don't load the javascript.
And it's like,
that is insane. That is the dumbest way to do that.
Yeah.
When I'm on like a slow link where, yeah, the web page pops up and I'm like, oh, sweet.
-- And that gets covered by something. And I'm like,
-- oh,
-- I know, I hate that. So
-- yeah, you could easily block that with no script or something.
But you know,
you'd have to hunt around the interface
figuring out which element to actually block.
Whereas with these paywall blockers, they,
you know, like ad blockers, they've, they've found the quote on whatever it is.
I don't want to call it bad stuff, but they found the paywall stuff and blocked it
or, you know, they pretend to be a Google search bot
or they sometimes they can monkey with the refer header or whatever.
And so they blocked these things
and it's not
100% clear as to
why apparently one of the community reviewers removed it from
the store claiming it violated the terms of service,
which doesn't sound very legit, to be honest.
Uh Maybe, I mean, so look, I, I think you can easily say that
a paywall remover is potentially,
it might not be legal, but it's definitely ethically questionable. We'll say
yes, and no, I mean,
so having said that there's,
I would say part of it depends on how you're bypassing the paywall blocker, right?
For example, if you're using stolen credentials,
you know, and,
and accessing somebody's else account who is
allowed to access the paywall blocker.
-- Well, that, that's illegal.
-- That, yeah, exactly.
I was gonna say like so on the scale of from black to white that, that's black.
But for example, the paywall is like you said,
say a javascript box that pops up and blocks your
visual field of view.
Well, what if I'm running a web browser that has javascript disabled,
like completely disabled?
Like I'm running E links for the sake of argument.
You know, I'm on a text session just for the sake of argument. We 10 years back in the f
well, 20 years back in the future,
am I doing something unethical by running a
web browser that maybe doesn't even support javascript,
right? How am I supposed to even know that there's a paywall blocker there?
You know,
or somebody's running no script with the default
of having it disabled javascript everywhere and they
selectively enable it on their bank and some other sites they need to use it.
Are they doing something ethical and immoral?
Yeah, I would, it's, it's super gray, right? I, I would, I would say no, probably
to me at that point it's like walking out of the room when a commercial plays on TV.
Right. Exactly. Which I think someone tried to say it was illegal once,
-- which is crazy.
-- Well, illegal or moral or whatever. And it's like, yeah, no, too bad.
I get to control goes on my eyeballs to some degree.
So I think we can definitely agree. There's on, it's, it,
there's details, sometimes the details matter,
but let's just say generally speaking,
it's
not illegal behavior
usually.
Uh,
and it's typically not also completely clean
because typically these people kind of,
you know,
it's like when you tell a little line, you kind of giggle internally, right?
You know, you're doing something naughty,
but
on the scale of naughtiness, it's,
I would say it's not as bad as say, using your, you know,
phone while making a left hand turn and eating a sandwich.
Sure.
And, and I would, I would view it as it's,
it's maybe somewhat comparable to fast forwarding through commercials
when you're watching your DV. I Right. It's definitely
extremely minor,
-- but the problem is when you automate it and make it easily available and
-- that's
fair.
That's, you know, because the thing, it's like, it's like ad blocking,
if only like 1/10 of a percent of people are doing ad blockers,
whatever we can live with that.
But, you know, for example, what if somebody,
oh OK, let's say for the sake of argument,
let's say Microsoft starts shipping all copies of windows
with built with a built in ad blocker,
didn't Apple talk about doing this
-- with
-- Safari.
They sort of have they, with the tracking and the,
some other stuff to make sort of the,
it's more the malicious behaviors of some of these ads that are being blocked.
So, like the legitimate stuff is still ok.
Right. But regardless, let's just say for the sake of argument that,
well, let's say for the sake of argument, Microsoft
Apple and Google. Right. Those are the three people with
and let's say Mozilla as well.
Those are the basically between those four web browsers,
you're like 99% of the market,
you know, outside of China.
And let's say, by default, they all start blocking ads.
Well, for example,
Google has to hire a bunch of lawyers to
sue everybody because they're going to go bankrupt,
right? Like something like 90% of Google's revenue is from ads.
Uh
-- Yeah, it's huge, it's huge.
-- So if that revenue goes to zero,
you know, they're going to get a little grouchy.
So
that's part of the problem is, is where this becomes easily available.
You know, it's like the difference between,
remember when people were trading MP threes via use net versus Napster, right?
Everybody could use Napster, your mom could use Napster,
right? And that's when the music industry came down on it like a sack of hammers.
If you really do want to put up a paywall, then put up a paywall that works and isn't
trivially bypassed by for example,
blocking javascript because I have a hard time
feeling a lot of sympathy for somebody who
kind of puts up, uh,
they want to accomplish something and they use a very weak technical measure.
Like,
you know, it's like all those pictures of, um,
where they have like a locked gate with no fence
around it and people just walk around the gate.
Yes,
-- that's, that's fantastic.
-- It chews up the grass and it's not good for the grass.
But at the same time, I have a hard time.
Any sympathy for the guy that owns that gate is like,
ok, so I, I guess let's do this.
I,
I think we can Hammon haw over the ethical implications of removing a paywall with,
with a script, bypassing the pay
and that's fair, bypassing it. So let, let's go up a level though and talk about
the,
the concept of a walled garden where Mozilla
essentially gets to decide what is in or out
of there. I, I would, I can we even call it an app store?
-- I don, I don't know what you'd call it necessarily. Well,
-- it's a free app store.
-- Yeah, I guess we should, we could call it an app store. That's
-- fair.
There's free apps on the Google Play store in the Apple store.
So, yeah, I, so, ok, let's
ok. So first of all, what is a walled garden in this context?
In, in, well, in really any context?
I think that the fundamental concept of a walled garden.
And we'll, we'll pick,
I'm going to pick on apple because I think they have the largest and most famous
when you buy an I device, iphone, ipad. I think that might be it. Um Anyway, I buy this.
I,
yes,
those did not have wall gardens.
But anyway, I've got my iphone.
-- I can only install apps. No,
-- by default on the mac.
Now, you cannot install apps from 30 party developers.
Remember you have to go into your settings, security settings and a lot of
apps from unknown,
a little more difficult and that's fair. But that's, that's, we'll get to that.
That's I think if we had a sliding scale of no app store to app store,
the, the imac or the imac, what have you done to me?
The,
the ipad and the iphone are on the very far end where you can only install the apps in
the Apple app store and that is it Apple gets to decide what goes in what doesn't go in
and all of that,
they completely control their walled garden.
And I guess also it should be pointed out the, the, the term walled garden
comes from way back in the day
in, in Europe. They will say uh not poor people.
They, they lived generally with houses that would have like a garden in the middle
and they made sure nobody could get in unless you live there
because they didn't want to have to congregate with the common folk.
Right? And so the basic idea with this is
Apple only gets to let in the people it wants
into its magic little garden and the rest of you
-- screw off. You don't belong here is the idea.
-- Yeah.
Well, and you have a curated garden. It's nice. It's clean.
People aren't stomping all over it and, like putting weeds in there.
Part of me says that's ok because like, how,
how much malware do you hear about on iphones and ipads?
Well, exactly. Very, very little.
-- There. There's almost none. There
-- are malicious apps.
Uh,
my favorite being a new scam where basically it's
like a calorie counter or some sort of app
that convinces you that you need to hold your
thumb onto the fingerprint scanner for like 10 seconds.
So they can like, calibrate your calorie
sweat counter or whatever thing.
And of course, then it pops up an in app purchase for like 100 $200.
And if you're holding your, your finger, you know, a finger that's registered to,
you know, activate the device then and you have the, um,
and I think by default that you, you do allow when you have in app purchases,
you can use your thumbprint to activate it by default.
Bam you just bought, you know, one or 200 bucks worth of, well, garbage
in app purchases. Right.
-- Yeah.
-- But I assume you can
get your money back. Right.
-- Oh, yeah.
-- Well, but, you know, that's assuming you even notice this happened.
Well, and that's true.
These guys only, you know,
need a couple dozen people to not notice and they're swimming in gravy.
Let's think about our,
our sliding scale now and let's move down a little
bit and let's talk about the Android App store,
which I think is a little bit more wild west.
It's similar to the way the Macbooks work. Now,
-- the problem is there's more than one Android
-- App
store.
No, we're just going to focus on the real one. None of this stupid garbage.
All right, we're going to say Google, when you're running an Android phone, you're,
you're using the Google App Store
and by default, you can only install applications from Google, however you can go in
or I shouldn't say from Google, from the Google App Store, we'll say right.
And again, Google has a very similar model to Apple where they control what's in,
they control what's out and, and you got to play by their rules.
However, on Android phones,
you have the ability to go into the
settings and say allow applications from unknown sources.
And that then lets me install the app application.
And the best example of this on Android is Fortnite,
which is an insanely popular first person shooter and a lot of fun, by the way,
I just looked
and 25 million Fortnite players globally up to 8 million concurrently.
-- Yeah,
-- that's crazy. Right.
But anyway,
you can install the Fortnite app in Android,
but you have to get it from them because they don't want to pay Google
the because obviously, like for example, the Fortnite app in the Apple app store,
Apple takes like a what?
20% cut, I think or something
there.
That's a lot of money,
right?
And so Epic is a company that makes Fortnite and Epic basically said on Android,
we don't want to pay Google.
So here are the instructions to essentially,
you know, turn on untrusted apps and install our app on your phone, which
like
Fortnite from Epic Games on the app store is free in app purchases.
Well, yeah, the app is free.
But then you buy your loot boxes and skins and all that other crap.
-- Oh, so the gambling part,
-- basically gambling. Yes, essentially. And,
and of course, like my freaking kids, man,
they spent a small fortune on this garbage and like I play and I,
I
forget they have a name they give to people who just use a default skin.
And I said like I don't even care what I look like it literally from, from,
but you think when we grew up playing video games,
you didn't get to change what you looked like.
So I don't, I don't even care.
Right? But to them like you have to look cool when you're playing this game or you suck
and for me it's like
-- whatever,
-- one thing that's always sold is personalization. Right? Anything cars.
There's that Sketcher. Uh, what is it?
I forget which, uh,
Converse store I think in San Francisco where you can get a custom pair made,
like in the afternoon.
Right. You get to choose everything.
It's not cheap but customization of your stuff.
That's always, that's been a, you know, that is a hell of a valid business model.
That's fair.
Well, I guess I could pick on my laptop,
like my laptop looks like a NASCAR car full of stickers.
And I only put on the companies I like or the projects I like.
So. But anyway, anyway,
so the point is an Android, it is a, it is,
we'll say a walled garden but anyone inside can open the gate, right?
Well, we kind of put it that way
you can with a device, it's easy to enable side loading,
right? Like loading from whatever you want
and yeah, and on and on iphones and I devices
theoretically you can sort of enable sideloading using, you know, for example,
the developer stuff where you can build an app and have up to 100 people install it,
you know, whatever.
-- But yeah, it's, it's super nontrivial and
-- the bar is amazingly high.
I would say it is not attainable for normal people,
-- whereas Android has made it possible for normal people,
-- right?
I looked into it and I can't even be bothered I'm like I could do this.
-- But, oh, man, it potentially I might screw my phone up completely.
-- Right. Exactly.
Yes. Now you own a brick, well done. Ok.
So we'll keep moving on our scale and now we'll get to, we'll say kind of
the Windows World, which it's a little better, but basically
-- there's not really an app store they do. It sucks. What
-- do you mean? Not really an app?
Have you used Windows? 10?
It comes with apps installed by default that when you click on them, it's like,
oh,
you have this thing sort of installed but you need to like pony
up a credit card number if you actually want to use it.
-- I try really hard not to use it to be fair.
-- I
like as much as I hate on Microsoft sometimes
the experience of Microsoft office 365 now, you know,
I needed to do some powerpoint slides for RSA a year or two ago and like
they were screwed up in every app.
So I went and bought, you know, powerpoint or office or whatever.
It was like 100 bucks for a five user license for
one year with a terabyte of storage on Microsoft Onedrive.
So not a bad deal.
But the beauty is literally you just download the app, install it and it's like, hi,
I'm in demo model.
Do you want to use me or do you want to like, buy me and to buy me, like,
you just activate it and it's like, oh, if you've already, you know,
if you basically own a copy, just log in with your Microsoft account.
So I log in, you know, with my
email and password and it's like, ok, cool. You're legit now. Like that's it. Boom.
The full version. It is so painless and easy.
And do you remember what buying software used to be like?
-- And I'm not even counting like where you had to go to a store and get C
-- DS.
It's still like that in a lot of cases though where like fundamentally
in the Windows world,
I think there's still very much an expectation of you download
something off the internet or God forbid you buy a CD,
but you acquire an executable, you run it and it installs itself.
And really this is why the Microsoft world was just a cesspool of viruses for so long
because that is how it worked. And,
-- and the thing is like, you look at
-- run dancing hamster dot A
XC,
totally not a virus dot exe Exactly.
So, and here's the thing though, you look at
the apple ecosystem versus the the Old Windows ecosystem.
I'll say then like a good example is the surface that you can buy a surface.
Now that's like totally locked down and that's awesome, right?
-- I Totally
-- Windows 10 by default.
Now defaults to only allowing stuff from the Microsoft
App store and you can unlock it easily.
Right. It's too easy to unlock. But I think they know if they made it too,
-- people would like revolt.
-- Well, it's not that they would revolt.
-- They would incur support costs, which would be annoying.
-- Right. Right.
And, and so anyway, the point is when you have that, that ecosystem, I think you,
you have to make some considerations.
Do we want to make, our users will say more safe?
And I'm sure I'm going to get arguments against that.
But, but we'll say more safe versus more empowered.
I wouldn't say it's making them more safe.
I would say it's, let's maybe take away some of the sharp edges,
let's take away some of the potentially dangerous behaviors by default.
See, and originally, remember we were maybe going to have like a devil's advocate,
walled versus non walled gardens.
And the thing I sort of keep coming back to is
I think by default, it's
good to take away some of the sharp edges,
especially because there's a lot of people out there.
But my favorite is every time I go to the
apple store to get something fixed because it's really broken.
Like the speaker on my phone broke and I ended up having to, you know,
replace it like with a refurb because they couldn't even,
they replace the part and it still didn't work.
But I was sitting at this table and these people were fetching and complaining
number one, they hadn't made an appointment at the Apple store that don't do that,
don't go to the Apple store and then say, like, I'm here and I have a broken device
and they'll be like, great. We'll see you in like six days or hours or whatever.
Number two.
It was funny because the guy, you know, of course, when he's like, oh, you know, we,
we can do a phone refurb and I'm like, yeah, sweet, let's do that.
And he's like, oh, have you, have you backed up all your data?
And I'm like, yeah, of course,
I bloody well have and I factory wiped it before I brought it in here because like I
did. Exactly. And this lady sitting at my table looked at me and she's like,
you can back up your phone
and I'm like, oh, sweet Jiminy.
And the guy looks at me and looks at her and he's like, yeah, yeah,
you can back up your phone and she's like, how do you do it?
And I'm like,
you log into it
and then she looks at me
and I'm like,
yeah, I don't think there's a step two is there and I look at the guy and he's like, no,
no, I'm not by default.
Right? That's it. You just, you log into it.
But here, here's the thing,
I guess that that is another consideration here
is when you're in that apple like universe.
And I would also lump, we'll put game consoles in here as well.
You basically have one supplier of all this stuff
and they have like an insane amount of control.
And so basically you do it their way or screw you,
you lose like there's absolutely no options.
Right. Whereas then you look at kind of the Microsoft way and now you have
uh a bit of a commodity environment, it is less expensive, but as we've seen,
it comes with
a certain amount of risk as well.
But you also have large companies doing dumb stuff like installing spyware
and
on the laptops that they're selling by default.
I think that's one area where I really appreciate what Google is trying to do,
which is Google is from what I've seen trying to get
as many manufacturers as possible, sort of onto a stock Android
that will actually get updates, not some customized, you know, version of like, uh,
I don't even know if LG makes their own Android os.
But for the sake of argument, you know, like LG Android,
which is like slightly modified or whatever.
-- Yeah, I mean, they're, they're,
-- well, for example, I bought a Verizon,
uh Android phone that was unlocked for 100 bucks, you know,
so my son can start having a phone.
Uh, and it's, it's, you know, it's running some really ancient version of Android.
It's um, like two or three versions old and it, I, I can't update that
fully
and it's got like an NFL app.
And some other stuff installed on it that I cannot remove.
You can't, you can't remove them. I know it. It's super annoying.
Like I don't know if they're running
a
custom Android Os or just they're running an Android Os that's been locked down.
Don't know, don't care. It's a garbage experience.
So, so the way it works is in,
in the carrier world and this is where I give Apple a lot of credit,
but I think only Apple can do this.
So like for example, you want Verizon to sell your phone.
Verizon says great, we'll do it.
But you've got to put all this crap on it before we sell it and then they cave in and
do it. You end up with all this trash. Whereas Apple was like,
no, if you're selling the iphone, you're selling our iphone.
If you want something else to F
-- and B like you're doing it
-- our way. That's fundamentally. Apple is a luxury brand.
I, I, I do agree.
You know, they, they had their brief experimentation with their iphone five C,
you know, the cheap color ones and you'll notice that they, they just,
I want one so bad.
They don't do that anymore.
-- Well, that's what I like.
-- My phone is like,
I,
I bought a pixel. No. Well, no. Right.
No, but the se sucks because they haven't updated it in like six years,
whatever it works, it's got a thumbprint scanner. That's all I care about.
So my kid doesn't shoulder surf my pin.
-- I,
I want an se that is fast because all like
every phone on the market today is a monstrosity.
I hate them all. And I bought a pixel
and it's way too big. But like after doing more research than I want to pretend I did
uh basically for, for price size and what you get inside,
like the pixel is basically the, the nexus point of all those things today,
but it's still way bigger than I want
or no a pixel pixel, not nexus,
they call it a pixel. I don't
know. I said, I said the word nexus
used to be called the nexus.
It's also the nexus of all those points of interaction that you want.
Right. Right. So anyway, anyway, so here's the question though.
So is what Mozilla did and,
and now that we've kind of laid some of the
foundation behind the concept of walled garden and Mozilla is currently
more towards apple if we think about walled gardens than towards Microsoft.
And it used to be a little different because it used to be,
you could just install like random garbage as add ons anytime you wanted.
And and that's been done away with a little bit because obviously
that is dangerous because people were installing garbage that was dangerous,
right.
So, so the question becomes, is it OK for Mozilla an open source project
to, to kind of have this. Trust us. Wink, wink attitude.
I, I think so because one aspect of this is by definition, the people,
these people who install these garbage
add-ons tend to then blame the sort of underlying operating system or, or,
or software like Mozilla for when things go
wrong because they're not sophisticated enough to understand.
No, you install some,
like random junk off of some random website that that's what broke your,
your machine.
And again, this kind of goes back to that whole removing sharp edges.
I'm basically, I'm ok with sort of removing the sharp edges from stuff.
As long as you still allow
the more sophisticated people a way to then go in and be like, no, no, no.
I really do want to take the safety guard off this thing because, you know,
then we can run it 10 times faster and if you use a hockey stick to push the wooden
and not your hand, you'll be fine.
Right.
You know what I mean? Like, no, seriously. Right.
How many people remove the blade guard from their table?
Saw the answer is everybody does
much
more than
that
sucks, dude.
My latest, my current table saw, like,
literally I got it and they gave me like all the little do
you have to screw on and stuff? And like, I just threw the blade guard away.
-- I didn't even open the bag it came in.
-- Well, that's what I love.
-- The blade guard doesn't even come attached. They know like.
-- Right.
Yeah, they know. Seriously. Here's my argument though, with that. Right. And,
and we can relate this to the APP store thing is
the blade guard on a table saw makes using a table saw
significantly worse
and while it, it, it,
I won't say it provides no safety,
I think the amount of safety it provides is fairly minimal.
It ideally encourages you to keep your hand away from it.
Maybe it makes you a little more conscious of it.
But um yeah, I agree. So maybe, but backing away from that.
So basically what it boils down to for me is
software is kind of like power tools and that,
yeah, I mean,
you can definitely do things to power tools to make them work a lot more efficiently.
But holy cow, like
you better be careful. You know, like my favorite is always industrial lats. They,
they, you know, the, like on the one hand, I've seen the ones where, you know,
they're, they're completely computer controlled,
the housing comes down locks and then it will run and you cannot reach it and touch it
very appropriate
in some cases.
But in other cases, you know, you have the older ones where, you know,
you have a human being doing stuff to it.
And
so you have some guy like working with a piece of metal that's spinning it.
Like how many ever 1000 R PM
can things go horribly wrong? Oh, absolutely.
Do not Google for like, LA
accidents
don't, I would never do that.
It would be, you, you, you bring this up and I just watched a guy
turn. He, like, uh, there was, I think he's in Australia.
They, they drained like, uh, uh, there was a dam.
I don't know what you call the lake behind a dam. But anyway, they drained it
and then he went in and he reclaimed a bunch
of wood that was over water for like 60 years,
right?
But he, he had like this root ball from a tree and he put it on his freaking lathe.
And the thing is like vibrating like crazy.
I'm thinking you're going to lose a finger.
-- I mean, in your recording
-- the best case scenario
and the thing is like, and also it worked and the bowl he made was was awesome.
But at the same time, I'm thinking
the amount of risk you took on to make this bowl is totally not worth it.
Like that was crazy town. What you just did?
Well, it's like when people do ice sculpture carving, right?
And they're working with a chainsaw
and of course my son wants to stick his face in there and take a look and I'm like, no,
the circle of blood like get away.
We give him at least
arm's length plus the chainsaw plus another meter
in case he trips,
you know.
But so I think for me part of it.
I think there is definitely value in taking some of the sharp edges away from people.
But at the same time,
if they want to,
you know,
work with the professional tools and have the
really sharp knives that work really well,
then you allow them. But maybe, and, and this is part of what I was thinking about is,
you know, if you make it a little bit harder to install
it, maybe forces them to learn a little bit. And thus
they then
are able to actually make a better sort of risk assessment and understand
what they're doing because they have to learn a little bit about it.
You know, and I kind of wonder, you know,
sometimes with programming languages and frameworks, I think some of the time
that's part of the challenge here is, is, you know,
I've seen web devs that don't know what SQL or XSS is
and that's fine as long as they're using the appropriate framework.
But at some point then they do something where they run
into this and they have no idea what they're doing.
Whereas all the old timey developers, you know, they,
they had to write their own SQL statements and prepare them and, and, you know,
do all that
so they understand this.
And so
I think there is
maybe value in sort of having that on ramp to, OK.
Well, you want to work with the real sharp power tools.
Yeah, you can but
by definition to get to them, you have to kind of learn what is a blade garden, you know
how to remove it before we let you remove it, right?
Versus just, you know, here's a bunch of random sharp objects. Good luck with that.
So like on android, I mean, let me put it this way, you know, for,
for me to find that setting in the android settings.
It was like what setting security uh allow third party developer apps,
you know, click, yes.
Like if you can't find and get that setting to work,
then you really probably shouldn't be installing third party apps.
I, I think fundamentally you're right, but here's where
I struggle in my mind
is and I'm going to pick on Fortnite again.
So lots of people want to play Fortnite and
I would say a, a substantial number of them
don't have a freaking clue how anything works.
And when I say anything, I mean, like anything computer related, right?
Fortnite gives you the instructions to disable
the security essentially and then install the Fortnite app.
And so
in that context, I feel like they are encouraging negative behavior
because you, you, you didn't, you basically said, OK, person, uh
before you can cut our wood, we need you to take off the, the, the uh the blade guard.
Here's how you take off the blade guard and they're like, what the
F's the blade guard, right? It's like holy cow. Don't do that.
Yeah, I'm just looking at this.
So to get started,
please visit fortnite.com/android on an Android device or scan the QR code below.
I don't have an Android device so I can't,
I was actually wanted to see if I could walk
through this quickly and see if they actually kind of explain
because, you know, I've seen instructions where it's like do this dangerous thing
and here's why it's dangerous and here's the consequences of if it goes wrong
and you absolutely need to do this to accomplish this.
But, you know, we're also going to give you the downside and the risk
information
and, and then I'm a little bit more ok with it.
I haven't looked in the instructions in a
while but they did not say anything like that
when I looked some time ago because in fact, it was,
uh, my, my kids were interested in it for their android devices.
And basically I looked at it and said, well, first of all,
none of your stuff could run this.
So I don't care. But secondly, uh don't do any of this.
And then,
uh they, in fact, they, they put it on their, their ipads and it sucks on tablets.
So they just never use it.
So, whatever.
Right. Right.
So, anyway, anyway,
we are, are basically out of time. So I guess let's, let's recap all of this.
I think fundamentally,
I am not opposed to walled gardens,
but I I do feel like
as an open source fan
there is it, it, it can be a slippery slope if you lock people down too much. Right?
And I guess actually one thing we didn't even address is like
your Linux distribution is essentially a wall.
Like when you install a package from Fedora or Debian or
ubuntu or whatever, like somebody decided
-- that goes in and somebody decided
-- those other, what really gets me is for example,
with
YBE stuff and well, Debian as well.
You know, when I add a third party repo because I want, for example, the latest
whatever,
no jazz for the sake of argument
that third party repo can now install anything on my system,
right? There's no way to have that.
This is one thing that's
always bugged me about
A
and R PM and all these things is what I want is I want a repo
where I can say, for example, I'm only going to, you know,
get package X from repo and you can sort of do that in the configure,
you can say exclude or you can say include or whatever.
-- But even then, you know, it's, it's still, you can't really,
-- it's pretty dodgy,
definitely.
Well, it's installing us root. So like it,
you know, here's,
here's the newest package of No Js and we also shoved a new Linux kernel in there,
right? And I can't stop that.
And this is one thing I love about containers where I, you know, I want the latest,
no Js, I just get the latest, no jazz container.
Right.
And it's got a really well defined interface and doesn't cramp all over my system.
Yeah.
No,
I agree with that 100% because I know I've enabled some third party repos in the past.
-- That did horrible things to my system.
-- Oh, yeah.
No, I ended up getting a new version of G lip C once
-- that did not go well, I don't want to talk about it.
-- II, I love that.
Actually, I, man, I remember reading there was a guy in Irc one time,
this was like many, many years ago.
But anyway, for some reason, he decided like his version of G
Lipsy was broken and we're like,
no, you can't touch that. He's like, I'm going to uninstall it.
We said if you uninstall this, like your computer literally breaks.
I'm going to do it. I think this is bad.
And like,
and a few seconds later he dropped out
there like
we,
we won't be seeing him for a while
just
because I was kind of curious because I know
Amazon tends to have a really strong walled garden.
Uh I just turned on my Kindle fire eight thing of a jigger.
You click settings, you click security and privacy, you click. Uh
Yeah, you can install third party app.
Yeah.
It's just uh apps from unknown sources,
allow installation of applications that are not from the app store.
-- So that, to me is the perfect example.
-- Funny enough.
If you do a Google search,
-- you can find instructions for installing the Google Play store on your Amazon
-- fire.
Yeah, I saw that,
uh,
just
saying I did try and
because I wanted, what did I want to get?
Oh, I think it was a VPN client.
Oh, no, it was the last pass. I wanted to put last pass on this thing.
But then I realized this thing doesn't have a thumbprint scanner. So, nope.
-- Yeah. Right. I'm not
-- typing in my
passcode, typing
in my 700 character password is
not ok. Actually, that's funny because
uh the other day my phone forgot the, the,
every now and then last pass decides like I need
to type my password in again on my phone.
And I'm like, well,
I'm not using this for a while until I could
find my USB my Bluetooth keyboard because like I,
I, it, it takes so many tries and I screwed up so much when I type it in.
Oh, that's why I had to simplify my Wi Fi password was things like all my apple TV.
S and the Google chromecast and all that junk,
you know.
And what I really appreciate now is all the devices where you, the device does Wi Fi,
you connect to the device via Wi Fi
and then like your phone in the app on your phone, shares the wi fi settings to it.
-- And I'm
-- like, oh my
God, which is awesome.
Yeah.
So, anyway, anyway, so I guess back to the closing remarks,
walled gardens are ok if you have a door to get out.
And sometimes I think, I mean, I'll ii, I think
in, in most instances, a door is acceptable and good
and
I think the, the other side of it is
how hostile is it to us?
Right? Where I'll pick on like Nintendo
for this one is Nintendo is notoriously anti.
And so for example,
they end up like shutting down a lot of homebrew scenes on their gear
and, and I love
some of that Homebrew stuff,
but at the same time, I also understand they're losing some of their sales to piracy,
but I don't know if it's enough to matter.
Well, I remember there were stores here, you know,
in Edmonton's Chinatown district where it was like open,
you know, an open secret that for like 50 bucks, they would mod your,
your console
with the chip to, you know, do everything.
And then for like another couple of bucks they'd give you like
whatever game, you know, copies of CD,
like they would burn C DS of whatever you wanted
and that's hundreds of dollars of piracy. Bam right there. Right. So I get it.
Why they, when you look at Nintendo's like hardware security, right?
There's some really good write ups on this stuff. Like we're talking you know,
this is like nuclear missile pal code interlock levels of security where
like even with physical access to the device in like six months and
you know, to monkey with it,
getting it to like side load a game is still a nightmare which,
and as we discussed the T two security chip, like
that's where Apple's headed
potentially if they want.
Uh yeah, I do think they're kind of going there. So,
So I guess,
man, I always get torn, but I guess, yes, I'll agree with you that at the end of the day,
I want my escape hatch.
Well, I want to be able to do that weird thing that I need to do for my job or for my hobby
that involves taking the blade guard off my table. So,
-- and I will accept the risk.
-- Yeah, I think that's fair.
So, all right, I guess in summary,
the issue is complex and strange and hard to
understand and even harder to explain in many instances.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag to find us on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.