Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 129 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
-- What's
-- new Man?
-- Uh
-- It's Christmas. It's the New Year.
It, it is the new year.
But thanks to the magic of podcasting,
this is going to come out like in the middle of January.
So that's fun.
I thought you were gonna say the middle of the year.
I could do that though. If you really wanted to,
we could just start releasing episodes in random order.
Like a,
I don't know,
I don't know that they really have an order per se.
Uh They have numbers that have been increasing in value for the most part.
And then that's something I think about sometimes is like,
does this really have a purpose?
But I guess the one good thing I think of is
I have podcasts.
I listen to that don't have like numbers associated with the episodes and sometimes
I want to listen to like three or four at a time because like,
I've lost track or whatever.
There's a million reasons
and putting them in the right order is a pain in my butt.
So, the numbers are helpful in that regard, which is why I've kept them to date.
Well,
I guess there's a reason ISBN barcodes and CV E numbers and
all those numbers exist because we humans do like sequential numbers.
Right.
Even, even, yeah, I mean, in the case of CV, E sequential,
-- sequential. Well, no,
-- it doesn't matter but having an identifying number.
Yeah. Totally. Absolutely. Yep. Yep.
So, so anyway, the topic today is the EU bug bounty, which is,
I think a super interesting topic.
-- I, I wrote a blog post about it which I hope you've read if you haven't shame
-- on you.
No,
I was sleeping
shame on you. Uh, no, it's a great topic though.
So, why don't you give us the background and then we'll dive right here.
So, uh, the EU is a major government thing
and one of the
things,
-- yeah.
-- Uh,
one of the things they do is this free and open source software auditing
project
quite simply put,
it's an effort to audit free and open source
software for security flaws and get them fixed.
Um, and this is software
that the EU
government has decided that they essentially rely upon heavily.
And one thing that really impressed me is that they actually
managed to identify the open source projects that they care about.
And if you look at the list for the bug bounty, it's actually
like, it makes sense. It's, it's stuff that's like
public facing or that is accepting weird files from random people that you,
you kind of have to open as part of your job function.
Right.
Well, the list is a little weird but, I mean, fundamentally I think it's, it's over,
I think the list is entirely rational and,
and I was actually looking through it trying to figure out
what all these things are because half of these things,
I, well, not half a quarter of these things I'd never heard of.
But when I hunted them down, it was like, wow,
that actually really like having a bug bounty for this piece of software makes
a lot of sense.
Yeah. No, I won't disagree. It's
what, 14
project I believe
and funny story.
But I can't open the website that talks about it a lot
right now because it's not available today on I PV four.
And I guess I need to go set up I PV six. Finally.
Luckily I live in the future.
So I have the website and, and I'll quickly read the list that's, that's put here.
So there's file Zilla
Apache,
Kafka notepad plus plus, which made me laugh out loud.
I love that
on windows.
Uh
-- OK.
-- That's,
I kind of wish they would just buy it and integrate it.
So I didn't have to go install it. Uh
VLC media player, something called flux TL. I don't know what that is.
-- Flux
-- transport layer. It's for the fisheries data platform,
-- uh
-- fishery, like people fishing,
-- like literally boats catching fish,
-- giant boats going out in fishing.
We'll talk about that one a lot. Actually, that's one, that one is interesting.
Fishing means something else to us.
As I said, seven zip
digital signature services. I don't know that one.
Drupal
GC Library, Glips CPHP Symphony. I don't know that. Really. Apache tomcat wso two.
No idea what that is and midpoint
and that is the current list.
So most of these, we've heard of like file Zilla Great FTP S FTP client, right?
I love it.
You know, same thing Apache
Kafka, you know,
it's uh message bus, message bus with transformations on the data,
-- right?
-- Yep. Yep. It's used heavily, especially like in the elastic universe
because
elastic search, I should say because obviously people bring data in,
they do stuff and they need to put it somewhere
and, and so it's a cool tool
and notepad plus plus.
I mean, if you don't,
if you use windows and you don't know what notepad plus plus is like,
go find out what it is. It's, it's a great little text editor.
Uh same thing for Putty, right? Well, uh
having you know a command line SSH S FTP
client on Windows who knew that could be useful.
I mean, VLC media player, if, if you don't know what VLC media player is,
how do you even compute?
No, like seriously,
because that thing is installed on every single one of my Windows Macs,
it's even installed on my kids like ipads because
-- it's the only player that will play all the files.
-- Right. It's, it's on my fire TV.
Yeah,
you're right. It plays all the files
and nothing else will.
Uh, we'll skip Flux TL for a sec because we'll keep to the simple stuff.
So, key pass, key
-- pass is, um, it's a password keeper.
-- It's an offline password
essentially.
And it's not
sort of the best one,
but it's one of the most widely used ones and it sort of decides the format
of the file.
So it's kind of the parent password file program.
There's, there's a uh I guess clones maybe is the word I would use.
There's some clones of it that are actually a bit better,
but they're not as widely useful.
They,
they basically rely on key pass to define the password file format,
uh seven zip to put it bluntly if you need to open weirdly compressed files
and you don't know how to use the command line,
-- then probably seven zip is your best bet
-- even if you do actually.
So, so funny enough on, on Linux,
there is a seven zip command that I, I assume is related to this,
that's command line only.
And, and fun fact is the zip command
doesn't do the, the encryption.
It does sucks, but the seven zip one does proper zip encryption.
So if you actually need to like ever ever encrypt a zip file
to send it to someone use the seven zip command line tool.
Don't use the zip tool
because seven zip does it right.
So yeah, like seven zip, I can totally get behind and,
and the seven zip compression for like the seven zip format is freaking awesome.
Yeah,
see I'm just used to like beating myself with tools like be zip and XZ and GP G
which are,
which are fine for me to use.
But when I want to, yeah, then when I send the file to somebody,
it's kind of like uh how do you open it?
-- Great. I don't,
-- what is this thing?
Exactly.
Actually,
I remember we would do that when I was younger when
we wanted to troll someone who asked for a file,
we would send them a TGZ.
They're like, I don't know what to do with this.
We're like, oh, you just need to
G zip it and then un tar it. They're like, yeah, you didn't help me at all.
It's like we know by click
which not quite that anymore.
Well, you've, you've become a kinder person. Uh
No, I, I just don't send people things
and even if I did send them a tar ball, like everything can deal with them now,
it's nothing like it used to be and seven zip deals with them.
It's weird how the built in tools for Windows and Mac for so long languished
moving on
digital signature services is exactly what it sounds like. It is
a digital signature services, open source software library
uh for doing signature creation and validation.
But
that's,
that's pretty important.
Well, when you're, when you're doing electronic documents,
uh
knowing where it came from and so on, uh Drew Paul, Drew Paul is Drew Paul
the, the content management system
because it's,
everyone uses it.
-- A lot of stuff sits on top of it.
-- It's everywhere and
it's, like, always on fire.
Yeah.
Well, it's interesting if you look at it,
Putty and Drew Paul got the two highest bug bounty dollar amounts for this project.
Yeah, I was, I was just looking at that actually, but I would also, I have a suspicion.
-- They're probably the two riskiest of the whole list.
-- Putty shouldn't be that risky.
But Putty is one of those things where it's like a high value. If you compromise.
I'm just trying to think if you can somehow compromise Putty,
there's a lot of windows users using Putty to log into a lot of sensitive systems.
Well, and not only that, I also have a suspicion, Putty.
The finding the security issues in.
Putty is going to be, I guess Putty and Drupal have opposite problems.
Drupal is really easy to find security issues in but I bet Putty is really hard.
Well, Putty is also, it's a small command line client, like it's only several,
you know, it's a couple 100 K
it's,
yeah, it's not a monstrosity whereas Dr Paul. Yeah, it's the opposite or?
Well, it's like
Gipsy, like g lipsy is so big.
It's enormous. Yeah, like it, it is literally all the things
PHP Symphony. Similar problem. It's all the things. It's, it's basically
no Js type thing. It's, it's all your PHP libraries pulling them in automatically.
-- Got you. Yeah, that's pretty serious. So,
-- dependency management. Skipping
a well. Ok. A patchy Tomcat is Apache Tomcat, right? You run your Java
three
tier layer cake application,
right. Right. And I remember man, Tomcat was like the only game in town for a long time
when if you wanted to run Java on the web like
that was that or pay so
-- like a dump truck of money. Yeah,
-- for glass fish or whatever,
right?
I don't even remember the name of it. Exactly.
There's WSO two which is a API management when you deploy services and API S
obviously those API S are probably going to change a little bit over time.
So this is doing things, you know,
management of those API S inversion so that you
don't break all your clients or all your services
because you did an update.
Um and then midpoint, I forgot to look at midpoint.
That's what
I
funny enough for some reason I expected you to say that. So I looked it up.
It's an identity management platform.
Oh, interesting.
Yeah. And identity management, you know,
kind of a big deal.
So,
going up now here's what's the most interesting
to me because pretty much all of these,
all of these I knew except for Flux TL, the DS S and the WSO Two and midpoint.
But, you know, when you look up the digital signature service, it's like, well,
that's exactly what it is.
Ok.
Right. Easy WSO two API Management. Ok.
You know, it's a little esoteric but it's, it's like Red Hat bought that.
Uh what was it called three scale company that does API management.
-- So
-- yeah, API S are a big deal man.
Yeah.
Uh midpoint. OK. Identity management.
Yeah. Identity management, right?
Like again, lots of companies have identity management products kind of a common.
-- Everyone
-- has identity.
Yes. OK.
That's fair. But everyone needs it, right?
Like if you have more than two users, you probably need identity management.
So then that really that left us with like what the heck is Flux TL? And I'm like, OK.
Flux TL is the current transport layer of choice for a
family of applications under the integrated fisheries data management program.
And I'm like, wait, what, how did we end up in the fisheries?
Right?
Because all of a sudden we go from like
all of this stuff is normal desktop server type,
whatever to like fisheries.
And so I did a bunch of digging,
read a bunch of interesting PDF S uh learned a lot about uh sustainable
fishing and the eu challenges with that and fish stock management and whatnot.
But basically the too long didn't read of it is
you're in Iceland, you're a fishing boat registered out of Holland,
going to a piece of ocean owned by some other country or not even owned by a country,
but, you know, controlled by
some international agreement.
And you want to go catch a bunch of herring.
Are you allowed to do that? What kind of permitting do you need and so on and so forth.
And this is an electronic system to handle all of that.
That's pretty cool.
And so thinking about this, number one, this is like all the countries, right,
all the countries with fishing boats, all the countries that control ocean,
all the countries that are part of
groups that control international parts of the ocean
that are, you know, covered by fishing treaties,
which is like all of it at this point because,
well, the tragedy of the commons literally, right,
we tend to over fish things because the fish are very tasty.
And so
this is things like the permitting reporting your catches,
you know,
because we can only allow people to haul so many thousands or millions of tons
of fish out of that part of the ocean before we have to like,
tell them to stop for the year.
And I was thinking about this, I've always kind of wondered with boats and well,
not submarines, but that, that's more of a military problem.
But with boats, you know, they typically don't have great internet connectivity.
Uh Right.
Also, let's say you do
great internet connectivity.
Let, let's assume for a moment, like let's, we'll do an episode on Spacex's,
you know, future internet satellite plans.
But let's assume for a moment, like every part of the planet is covered in,
what was it like?
10 megabit or gigabit internet
magic?
Well,
even then you still don't necessarily want like the mechanic on the
boat upgrading a computer system out in the middle of the ocean.
Because if it fails,
then like, how do you like get a tech out there to fix it?
You know, helicopter, some guy out
at a cost of
something in the four digits per hour.
So obviously with fishing boats,
I assume there's a lot of hesitancy to upgrade or
change systems at random in the middle of the ocean.
And this is, of course,
assuming everything is going well and you're not in
the middle of a storm trying to catch fish.
Do they catch fish during storms? That seems like a foolish thing to do.
I would assume that they work as much as they can because I mean, you,
you've seen a last, what was that fishing boat show out of Alaska? The crabbing one,
-- uh, dangerous catch,
-- maybe
dangerous. They were fishing in some pretty horrible weather because
they only had a certain, like, what one or two weeks for the season?
It always amazed me. Like, more people didn't fly off the boat and die. I
know
every time those guys were stepping in the
ropes when the traps were going overboard,
I was just like, like, you know,
that cartoon character thing where the rope titans around
their ankle and drapes them down and they're dead.
And it just always gave me the heebie Jeebies.
I, I agree.
I, I would make,
I am not a boat person and I would be a very
bad fisherman and I guarantee I would be dead on day three.
Like no questions asked.
Like I'm not even going to pretend I have the ability to, to work that job.
Yeah, I know.
I don't think physically we could do it let alone like
safety wise, not die.
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
This is, this is a great example of, not only is it a very complicated it system,
I mean,
we've got data flowing backwards and forwards
and being shared with multiple governments,
they've got these centralized data nodes, they've, you know,
there's stuff flowing in over satellite, over radio links over the internet.
You
have it platforms literally in the middle of the ocean,
possibly with no or very limited internet connectivity.
Definitely nobody with like computer certification aboard on a lot of these boats,
you know, some of these boats are only 12 m long or less, right.
Like they, they break up the fishing by, it was like 0 to 12 m 12 to 24 and 24 plus.
You know, and I'm guessing like a 24 m plus boat. Yeah, it'll,
that's a pretty big boat
but
some little crabbing boat,
you know, you're in the middle of fishing season.
Uh, let me just reboot this for an update and you're going to get smacked.
That, that does make sense.
And then, so this system is taking data in from the Lord only knows where. Right.
And it's taking in data that I'm with latencies.
So I there's just, it's a lot of complicated problems essentially.
Right. The, the, the use case is very complicated. It's not like,
you know,
my computer can just talk to everything
on the internet with 50 millisecond latency.
-- No problem.
-- Right. Right.
And, and that's, that's awesome. Right.
I love seeing open source projects that affect an entire industry because
obviously in an instance like this,
everyone can help and everyone can make it
better depending upon what they need to do.
Now, the, the place I want to talk about with this bug bounty though.
And this is this is where the conversation has kind of ended up a little bit is
the bug bounty is a great idea
and I'd love it.
But there are a nontrivial number of people who are saying,
but what about the projects? Why are we paying bug bounties to researchers?
Why aren't we paying the projects? And I actually know what the answer is.
And this is what my blog post is about.
But I would love to hear your thoughts before we kind of dive into what's going on.
So, my thoughts are two folds. Number one, I agree that in some ways the bug bounty
is sort of the crowning achievement for a software project, security
response
because quite frankly,
and especially a bug bounty with this, there's quite a bit of money involved in this.
-- It was, what was it? €851,000 in total in bounty
-- just under a million euros.
So probably a million dollars
or pretty close, we'll say, using
whatever sort of
American dollars
or some dollars from somewhere. Right.
So, so number one, I would say, you know, yeah,
bug bounty is definitely sort of the crowning achievement because essentially,
you know, if a tree falls in the forest and lands on your head,
that's not very helpful, you need to be able to dodge it.
So, you know, if these projects can't fix these security flaws,
then the bug bounty is literally wasted money
on the flip side. However,
bug bounties can sort of let you know how bad things are
and maybe you do
need to justify funding for that project because,
uh, ok,
I'm going to pick on Putty because it's pretty blameless
and it's actually got a pretty good track record.
But let's say, for the sake of argument, this bug bounty for Putty comes out
and some guy finds like 20 bugs in it, like really bad ones.
Well, then we know maybe, you know,
uh,
we need to invest some money in actually improving Putty and maybe funding
the developer or funding another developer to help that guy with it or,
or whatever.
So it kind of reminds me of, um, of penetration testing, right?
A lot of people like, oh, penetration testing is done.
They always get in and I'm like, yeah, exactly.
And then you use that to scare your executives into giving you more money.
So here's the, I, I agree with you, but here's the real problem.
The eu can't pay putty, they have no way to legally pay putty.
And here's so here's let me kind of let me set out the, the, the landscape here.
And this is something I wrote about.
In fact, someone from the EU replied to me basically saying, yes, you're right.
Good job.
This is the lady that,
whose website I couldn't load the talks about all
the stuff that we've been using as our resource.
Yes. Perfect. OK. Good. Yeah.
So, so anyway, here's basically the problem.
So the EU has money, that's their resource, right?
They don't have developers necessarily, they don't, you know, and, and
yes, I know there are developers.
Uh No, no, no, even worse, worse, they have government developers.
Right. Exactly.
And so like,
oftentimes like their ability to contribute to open source is going to be
limited fundamentally to money and I know there's some asterisks on that,
but we're going to ignore all the weird details for the moment.
So their resource is money,
right?
What is the only thing
they can do with that money today
that has the ability to directly affect a project?
And the answer is a bug bounty because these bug bounties exist and,
and like they're not paying the,
like the, the researchers, they're working with people like hacker one,
for example, for these bug bounties,
which is important because these bug bounty organizations,
they have the legal entities and the frameworks in
place to take money in and pay researchers.
Right?
So the eu can cut a check to hacker one and say,
here's a pile of money for bug bounties on these projects.
Like make it work,
right?
So the eu can do that.
The eu can't go to Putty and say, here's a bunch of money, like, make it better.
They're like, what the, what the f do I do with this?
You know, he, I'm assuming has a day job or something and he,
he may not even be able to take that money
even if they were able to give it to him.
-- Right.
-- Exactly.
And they probably can't because like, is this guy a European citizen?
-- Where does he live? Like, how does that work?
-- Well, he's in Cambridge.
He's a British guy.
Uh, ok, great. Well,
not an EU citizen for long
burn.
-- But anyway, anyway. Anyway, I can't, I can't wait. We finally
-- covered breast
and that's it, folks. That's
-- all you're getting.
-- We'll never talk about it again.
Uh But anyway, so here's the thing.
So
for now they're doing the only thing they can and if this is the only way it is,
if we never get past the ability to pay like projects and it's only ever bug mommies,
this is
going to fizzle out and die because eventually someone from the EU is going to
look at this and say like the return on this investment kind of sucks.
And the projects are getting mad at us because
we're just reporting bugs and not helping them.
Like what do we do next?
Right. So this is where there's an organization called Tide Lift that
I know I've tweeted about them a lot.
But basically, it's a bunch of ex red hat people started a company
that has the ability to basically pay open source projects is
what it fundamentally comes down to where companies pay Tide Lift,
tide Lift, pay some projects.
And, and this,
that's the sort of framework you need because the eu can't pay projects.
So you need like some sort of intermediary that the
Eu can give a bunch of money to and say,
I want you to fund these projects.
And now when I say fund, I don't just mean writing checks
because some projects want money
but not all of them, right?
You're going to have projects that want pizza,
you're going to have projects that will say like I need hosting in,
in this data center over whatever they're like a million things, right?
And that's the thing, the eu can't do that. Like the eu literally has a check
and they need to give a check to somebody and they have a whole
bunch of crazy rules that say how they can and can't spend money.
When I was thinking my partner works for the government and they were,
she was talking about, yeah, how they spend money and it's,
oh boy, the regulations. Wow.
Yeah. Right. Exactly.
It's like crazy town for these people.
Well, but it's, it's, you know, the road to hell is paved with good intentions,
right?
Because all of these regulations came from, well, somebody abused this.
Like I remember specifically to not to mention Red Hat yet again,
but I remember specifically at Red Hat, the travel,
uh the Red Hat travel guide specifically stated that I think it
was that anybody under director level cannot charter a helicopter or a boat
and that got added in at some point.
And it's like, well, pretty clearly somebody did that and so they went, nope,
we're not allowing that again.
And so they, they put in an explicit rule saying, you know,
unless you're a director or above or whatever,
you can't charter boats and helicopters.
That's fantastic in every possible way and, and right,
the rule is there because someone did it.
Yeah. And got away with it.
No, you're right thinking about it.
Like, because I remember I worked for the government for six months once when I was,
like, 20
yeah. No, it's, um, a lot of people work for the government.
They have good intentions.
But, yeah, they're, they're literally
bureaucracy is holding
back what they want to do. So, what they do end up doing
from the outside looks insane.
But if you, if you look at the bureaucracy and what the rules are,
that's literally all they can do
and, and not just that.
So in, in this context, we're obviously talking about the eu as a government,
but even large companies have similar problems.
Well, and the EU is a government, but it's, it's like a meta government too.
So it's even messier
uh Right. That, that's a very good point.
So I,
I have a great story actually about this and I don't
feel bad because like most of the people involved are,
are long, the company is gone.
So a long time ago, I worked for a company called uh Progeny Linux Systems
and Red Hat
stopped supporting Red Hat Linux 71728 and nine, I think,
way back in
the,
I remember those.
Yeah,
basically at the same time because they were
obviously focusing on Red Hat enterprise Linux.
And like I was at Progeny,
I was doing security updates for our Linux distribution that, like,
nobody bought at the time.
And I remember I went to my boss and I'm like, hey, Red Hats,
discontinuing this stuff.
Like I'm already doing this work. Why we could just start, you know,
selling updates for Red Hat Linux.
And they were like, well, that sounds neat. Right.
And we went from like very few customers to like a bazillion customers overnight.
Right.
And I remember we talked about
that
stuff.
Well, of course not. Then what happened was
we were like, well, well, how much are we charge for this?
And someone like said, 0 $5 a machine. We're like, great. That sounds neat.
It was super cheap, whatever. It doesn't matter. This is a million years ago.
Kurt, it's too late now.
Right. So it's very inexpensive.
And I remember we had like, some fortune 500 companies that were like, we have like,
you know, 100 machines.
We're like, oh, that's $500 a month.
They're like,
we can't pay you $500 like we need, it has to cost more.
We're like, well, it's $500. So, like,
here's my personal credit card. Like I'll figure it out. Right.
That happened more often than not because, like, these companies just,
they couldn't spend a small amount of money.
-- Right. They had, it had to be an enormous bill
-- or it looks like fraud. Right.
Right.
And, and this is the same problem with, like,
open source projects is a large company.
Can't say, like, here's 100 bucks putty, go fix my buck. Right.
They need some way to pay some, like, legitimate organization
-- and then that money has to go somewhere else.
-- Well, and it's even worse than that.
Right. For large companies, things
can't be one offs. They have to be part of a process. They have to be part of
an ongoing,
recurring, quarterly, yearly, whatever billing cycle.
Right. Right.
So these people who say, oh, just give some money to the project like it's hard,
it's not something you can do.
-- So
-- anyone, they're not legally allowed to in a lot of cases,
you can't just disperse money to an individual without the auditors going.
-- Like what
-- now?
Wink, wink in the memo. Right? Like
this is
so anyway.
Right.
But, but I guess here's the thing and,
and this is kind of the way I would sum all of this up is
I give the eu tons of credit for doing this.
And I think there's a lot of people that want to stand up and say, oh, no, no.
But what about the projects? What about the Children, blah, blah, blah, blah.
It's like no,
look,
the eu is taking the first step now, if, if we never take a second step, then yes,
your criticism is 100% valid.
But the,
the thing is instead of just whining and
complaining like an annoying internet gas bag,
which is of course, what a lot of people like to do,
but now we need to go to the next place and,
and the thing to think about is how do we make it?
So, in a large organization or a government or somebody
can somehow get money to a project
to make sure the thing they want done gets done.
Because like, obviously one of the things I think about in my head a lot
is think of like a reverse bug bounty
where instead of paying people for finding bugs,
you pay people for fixing bugs where you say like, hey,
I want this feature that's been tried.
It, it, it never worked.
And, but again, we didn't have like the frameworks to actually do this.
Well, there were a couple of companies that did build that, but it's just,
-- it, I suspect part of it is for a lot of,
-- I think it was premature. Right?
I mean, I think open source is way more popular, I think.
Yeah, I think part of it at the market wasn't ready
and I think part of it too is a lot of the people who can fix
these bugs are not doing it for the money and when you start paying them,
they, they go and they look at their time and they're like, well,
this actually isn't really worth my time,
you know, if you do something. Some of that is true.
Well, there's been multiple studies done where you know,
something was a volunteer action and then they
started paying the volunteers and it dried up.
Yes. Yes. And, and I'll post a link. Actually, there's a really nice video.
One of those animated videos, it might have been a TED talk. Even
where they talk about kind of rewards and money in
effect. Open source is a huge part of the talk.
-- And, and anyway, I, I'll link it in the show notes.
-- Well, I agree.
Like, if, if people paid me to do CV E, I'd be like, great.
My professional rate is this three digit number,
-- right? Like a gazillion dollars.
-- I'm not doing it for five bucks an hour.
-- And
-- that's fair.
I, I think that's,
but again, again, this is where I kind of come back to
resources don't have to be money, right?
It could be as simple as saying, you fix my bug,
here's a pizza
or you fix my bug, like here's a free ipad, whatever.
There's a million things you can do here and, and it, it, if,
if we just obsess over sending money to a project,
I think we end up in the exact trap you're talking about.
And so this is, this is, again, this is part of step two, is figuring out
how do we actually
fund these projects in ways that is acceptable and increases
the,
the output they have because a lot of
these projects like you mentioned earlier are like,
it's literally a guy
and they do it on the weekend for fun.
And what do you do with that person? Right.
How do we make sure they stay motivated and
they feel like what they're doing is worthwhile?
-- So,
-- one thing I was just thinking, well, two things.
Number one, you say, how do we fund these projects? I would say
more generally, how do we allocate resources to them that they need?
And number two
would be um the, the second thing that always drives me nuts is every time I run into,
well, this is not so much now, but back in the day, especially,
I'd run into people that, you know, were like, wow, I started using open source.
It's great,
you know, I'd love to give back. How can I get back?
And I'm like, have you ever encountered like a bug with it?
They're like, yeah, and I'm like, did you report it?
Right? Like seriously just reporting the bugs reporting them.
Well, would honestly,
that's what a lot of these developers do want is good bug reports.
Yeah,
I mean, again,
debt potentially is a resource
you can help fund these, these developers with or
I know there's a lot of projects that would like, they'd be in heaven
if someone just went through their bug trackers and was like, this is a valid bug.
This isn't a valid bug, right? Or, or fixing do, right?
Documentation is another big one like there's so much
that these projects need and every project's different.
And so you can't just say, like, throw money at them. It's not that easy.
Well, the problem here is then you have a company.
It's like, ok, we're going to pay an intern or we're gonna pay some guy to do this
unless you kind of like wink, wink, nudge, nudge, 10% of your time thing, you know,
and it, it just, again,
it gets very messy for these large companies that are driven by process and by
rules because
they're ultimately trying not to be driven by people who make mistakes and,
or if they do make mistakes, they want the mistakes catalog, you know,
the iso 9000 process where like everything is documented.
So if it goes wrong
while we in theory, can go update the documentation and stop doing it wrong. Sure.
So it's, but I agree it's a very complicated problem of, you know,
yeah, a fortune 500 company might be quite happy to,
you know,
allocate some sort of resources to some open source they're using.
But how do they actually do that?
Especially if they're financially or legally constrained
with what they're allowed to do.
Yep. Yep. Exactly.
So, I, yeah, I mean, I, I guess we'll see where we go next all in all.
Like I said, I think what the eu is doing is awesome.
Well,
this also presupposes that people are actually going
to look at this bug bounty and participate.
Right. Bug bounty is the demand side of. We want to pay for bugs.
You still need a supply of bugs. You need some,
you go find, you need to go
for the
supply
-- of bugs but
-- people willing to sell them. And I,
I, I think, I think it'll be ok.
There are a nontrivial number of people who basically are now making a living.
I mean, think of like the gig economy where they're,
they're literally making their living on bug bunnies.
And if you're good at it,
-- you can do quite well. Well,
-- especially if you live in a cheaper part of the world.
Yeah. $10,000 payday.
That's a good chunk of money.
And computers and internet are not that expensive. And open source by definition is
well, and that's the beauty too, is like all the fuzzing tools and most of the pretty,
what I would say are the really good security tools for doing this
kind of bug bounty fuzzing and stuff. With one or two exceptions. They are all free.
-- Yeah,
-- for the most part. So I have a suspicion this is going to be successful.
The, the one worry I have
that, that I think is a legitimate worry. That isn't step two is my concern.
Is some of these bug bounties might be too successful and overwhelm the projects
and that would be equally bad
because now you have projects that are like,
I have 1000 bugs and I don't have time to fix them.
I don't think they're going to end up with 1000 bugs.
Now. I don't think they will either. I'm just saying like it is conceivable.
Even a dozen bugs would be a pain in the. Right.
So, anyway, but again, this is where we need step two. Right. We need some way
to, to go to the next level and, and it doesn't even have to be security focused.
I know obviously bug bounties are very security focused, but
there's no reason
that you can't fund features that have nothing to do with security, right? It's just
again, bug bounties are the only mechanism they have like
the, the E U's hammer is money
and that's the only nail they could find
like for real.
-- Yeah.
-- No, that makes sense.
So, any closing thoughts on this one,
-- if
-- you do find security flaws, please,
and you're going through a bug bamy, please,
please please have them request a CV number.
-- Yeah,
-- that's fair.
And I guess on that note also,
and I put this in my blog post and I'll reiterate it again.
Here is if you are a project
and whether you're part of this EU list or not,
and you need help with security things like dealing with security reports,
dealing with advisory CD ES whatever, like feel free to get in touch with me.
My Twitter D MS are open and I will help you because I know what this is like
and kind of the, the, the closing statement on my blog was something like, you know,
the only thing worse than,
than being part of running an open source
project is running security for an open source project
because it's like, it's, you think that's thankless, right?
Like come to my world sometime, but, but for real, it's tricky to do.
It's not simple and it's something like I,
I both of us have been doing longer than we can possibly remember.
So by all means, ask for help and, and
it's kind of like the, the Harry Potter thing, right?
Anyone who asked for help at Hogwarts would get it.
No, it's, it's definitely,
-- it's a nontrivial type of work.
-- Yep. Yep. Totally. All right, sweet.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show
notes. You can use the pound. Oh, it says podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
and yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye
the