Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and not discussing all the truly
terrible things that we know are happening in the world.
But you can get your coverage for that elsewhere.
Like say the Australian surveillance bill that got
shoved through in less than 24 hours.
Uh We're gonna kind of keep it light and happy and talk about all the bad stuff in
infosec. That's right. I will, I have a personal complaint.
I will, I will put out there for all.
So I get up every morning and I take a bike ride, right?
And
I always get on to the,
I guess in the world and I figure out which direction is
the wind blowing because I like to bike into the wind.
So my way home is generally the easier like of the world
float down.
That's right.
So I bike into the wind
for about half an hour.
I turn around
and
no law.
Yes, it literally changed 100 and 80 degrees. And I'm like, how did this happen? Like
I felt like I was in a video game and someone was like, ha ha.
And they, like, turn the knob and it's like, oh, my goodness.
And that is basically summed up my day so far
anyway.
-- Yeah. Sorry. I don't mean to laugh at your plight but
-- it's ok.
It's, it,
it is something you can laugh at and I will take no offense because it's a bike ride.
My legs are slightly more tired than normal
and it was probably good for me.
Yeah.
Yeah, I gotta start doing more cardio.
Actually, I have one other funny story. I'll tell you about my bike ride. So. Right.
We got
an enormous amount of rain, like a ridiculous amount of rain.
And there's this trail near the river,
I like to bike on that is probably lower than it should be, we'll say.
And there's this one spot that often will get a little bit of water on it. Right.
So I ride my bike up to it and it's
usually a little bit of water a couple centimeters max.
Right.
I,
I pull up and the water is extremely dirty because obviously it was very heavy rain.
So a lot of dirt in the water.
And I'm like, oh, look at that and I start biking through it. It was
enough water that my, like,
bike was significantly submerged as I was riding through.
And by the time I made it there, it's like, well, I'm halfway in,
I'm just going to keep going.
I was
very muddy and wet.
OK.
I, I'm going to say this for everybody.
If you cannot see the bottom of the water don't go in. It's
no straight up because I've seen, I've seen far too well. And
the other thing to remember is I think it's four inches
of fast moving water can basically take a concrete mixer.
Yes.
Now, I,
I want to clarify one important point of this particular poor decision on my part
is
the water where I was at was completely still. And it was like a
weird big puddle thing.
There was no way
that there could be current to carry me off.
-- But yes, never, ever, ever cross moving water.
-- And you're not in like a mud
bog situation.
But I've also seen those mud bog videos where, you know,
somebody steps into what they think is a puddle and just,
-- it's,
-- you know,
this is, this is a paved trail. I had asphalt beneath me
and I knew where it was. I've ridden this a million times.
I did not exit the asphalt at any time.
This is a
perfect infosec
allegory because yes, it was a paved trail.
But if there's moving water under that trail,
like in a culvert or something that doesn't work quite right
all of a sudden.
But there wasn't,
I
-- know, but I'm just saying
-- I assessed my risks
and while I won't say I made the right decision necessarily, I will say it was,
I did, I lived to tell the tale
anyway. Anyway,
we
survivor bias. So it must be safe to do that again. It's
-- not
-- making me look like an idiot.
Well, I mean, speaking of looking like an idiot,
I kind of liked clipping in the sense of like clipping was a horrible idea.
Wait a minute. How does that relate to being an idiot?
-- Is clipping an idiot or are you idiot for liking clipping or I'm getting
-- there?
So I like the idea of clipping in that
Microsoft was,
remember there was that phase of trying to personalize
and humanize and make computing less scary like Microsoft,
Bob and Microsoft clipping and those things, right?
Those things failed miserably because I think a lot of it is uncanny valley related.
But anyways, but now we've got
github
Copilot,
which is one of those things where
I heard about it. And I'm like,
OK,
so basically they're automating the whole search stack overflow for code snippets
and cut and paste it into your code to make stuff work.
That's, that's basically what Copilot is,
right?
It's, it's a,
it's an A IML engine that learns about code and
then when you're typing code it's auto suggest blah,
blah blah,
right? There's a reason
coding is seen as hard.
Uh And that's because it is
right. You're, you're trying to describe
a problem
at such a fundamentally low
deconstructed level that something as stupid as a computer can then execute it and,
and do it correctly.
Are you comparing
copilot to clip?
Well, it's the same idea. Fundamentally.
Hi. I see. You're trying to write a resume.
Would you like to put that in Comic Sans to make it more cheerful?
-- Yes,
-- everything should be in comic sense
the best.
So
the, the problem is,
well, I think we should build tools that make it easier to do stuff.
I'm not sure that this is the right kind of tool to be building.
Because for example, there's a big difference between having a nice sharp chisel
and having a supposed tool that will recommend
on how to actually build a table correctly.
That requires a lot of mastery and expertise
and it requires the system to really kind of understand what your actual goal is.
I I think you've put the cart before the horse a little bit here.
So let's, let's back it up. There was a report that came out
-- sometime before now,
-- not a report, an academic paper.
OK, an academic paper, whatever report in my mind, that's all reports.
But this is based on evidence, not anecdotal
that does have evidence. That's true.
It's not made of crap,
which is why I do love academic papers because
nothing angers me more than made up crap.
Anyway,
this paper comes out
and these researchers basically took copilot
and they
put it in some will say precarious situations.
They purposely tried to make it, help them write code
that they knew
was going to be likely to,
we'll say, trigger security vulnerabilities and it did 40% of the time. Yeah.
Well, and, and
you don't have to try real hard to make something
precarious from a security point of view.
Anytime there's say logic flow about whether or not something is allowed to happen.
Right.
Any time there's a network operation. Right. There's, there's a million
things in code that if they're a little bit wrong
all of a sudden are a security issue.
Now, now here's what I took away from this and this. I did not see this in the paper.
I admit I did not read it as closely as I would like due to time constraints.
But
my takeaway from this is 40% of the code in use
has we'll say horrible security problems of of I should say
potentially security sensitive code because
they also purposely created an environment
where it was more likely to have to make hard decisions,
right?
Because it should be noted. Copilot is not smart is doing basic pattern matching
and saying I've seen similar code to this before. Here's what someone else did.
Let me shove it in place here.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, it is straight up
essentially automating the task of searching stack
overflow for code snippets that work.
Um to the point of remember there was also the licensing issues where
it was grabbing code that was licensed in a way where you,
you're not supposed to just grab the code and say not include
-- the license or whatever
-- or it was funny when it was adding
credentials like tokens from other projects,
which was awesome.
Yeah,
I guess ironically as well explains why the new github
token format is so obviously a token,
that way they can't accidentally include them.
We're going to go there because that's something I've
been thinking about because I've actually been dealing with this
a bit because remember I used to have to deal
with it when I was putting emails into github.
And these token scanners were true
on the message I DS because it was like a long random string of text and realistically
the a string of text past a certain point of entropy
probably should not be code unless it's like pearl.
It's, you know, if, if a string of text has that much entropy, it,
it probably is an access token or a password or some sort of secret.
And so
there was a really good thread about these
API tokens and, and
revocation of them because apparently there's some projects, you know,
like Amazon and github
where they're scanning github now and
automatically revoking,
say Amazon web services tokens in seconds of showing up because
people use those tokens to go grab a whole bunch of computer resources and do stuff.
And somebody in hacker news pointed out
rather, I think intelligently
tokens should be self
-- revoking.
-- What do you, what do you mean by self provoking.
-- So
-- the idea is why can't tokens be something like
revoked.sendgrid.com/token and literally by going to that end point,
that revokes the token.
So if somebody sees that token,
instead of me having to figure out how to report it and go oh my God,
somebody's token got exposed.
I literally can just
fire that token off as a your request and poof,
it's no longer available because anybody
fly
well.
But the thing is anybody who legitimately has that token won't do that.
And I personally would love that because it
would make revoking tokens super quick and easy
and rotating them actually a bit simpler.
Um And I, I suspect that that is where we're headed is,
is these kind of big tokens like Amazon or, you know,
I don't think we're headed there at all. Look, here's, here's how this works.
They're already sticking identifiers on it.
-- Yeah,
-- they're sticking identifiers on it and they should,
and I agree with that because that's what github
is doing, but they're never going to be self revoking because what happens is
there's so much automated
stuff in our environments now that follows URL S
and looks at things that you're just going to
have some system accidentally revoking all of your tokens
and then it's going to take some poor schmuck,
you know,
six days to regenerate the 4000 tokens you're running in your environment.
It's just that, that, that, that wouldn't work.
Well, that's why you don't put like http or whatever in, in the token,
you just have a string of text,
-- whatever this is never gonna happen. I don't want to talk
-- about it.
I'm not sure it will happen. But the point is,
I think it's,
I,
I think it's this kind of thinking that actually
might make things
different
-- better.
-- Here's what I want to stop you at right now.
Insecurity. We have a terrible track record of thinking something makes sense
and then pretending it does without doing any
research saying whether it does or doesn't,
I will agree with you when you show me a paper that says this is a good idea.
Until then I'm going to say no.
So here's the problem. You
have gone to the end though of saying if you do this, here's what will happen,
an automated system will do this.
-- So by definition you're making,
-- that was my mistake.
OK? I scratched that from the record. Show me any research
that says this is true.
Well, but the same thing with Copilot, right is where I,
I understand that they're trying to build a system that quote unquote,
makes it easier to code.
And again, I, I am for that, like I, I just put in a new outlet on the side of my house
and because I have access to power tools, it did not take long, right?
Because I had to cut through some pretty thick wood, you know,
and doing it by hand with a chisel or whatever would have taken forever.
But with a power drill and a Sawzall,
I
basically made a rectangle hole in the side of my house in like five minutes.
Right.
You know, it was lovely and it was the right size and I, you know,
I had to use a chisel for a bit of it and basically
the chisel removed 5% of the material and took half an hour,
you know, to get it nice and clean. But the point is I, I'm for tools
that
help people.
But the problem is we're now getting into that a IML space of,
you know, rather than like lane assist where, oh you,
you seem to be drifting outside your lane.
You know, I'm gonna beep at you.
It's like, no, no, you can just fall asleep. I'm gonna keep the road.
Uh I'm gonna keep on the road until we get to Calgary and it'll be fine, take a nap.
And, and that's kind of my fear where Copilot is.
I thought about this actually.
And, and I, I don't, I think you're wrong
and
here's what I was, I was thinking about this exact thing actually, not,
not two hours ago while I was reading some, some documentation on this.
And I think here's the trick is,
let's say I wrote a tool that could
identify security vulnerabilities while you are typing,
right? While developers are developing,
is that valuable?
I don't know it, it it is
but not, not super valuable.
But now I build the tool that I can say your developers can
write three times as much code in the same amount of time.
Is that valuable? Yes, hugely valuable. So if you look at the economics of this
writing a tool that does secure stuff at the moment
is less valuable than writing a tool that
appears to increase productivity by several magnitudes.
One comment,
I love that appears to increase productivity because
here's my other thought is I'm not,
no,
no, exactly I'm saying appears to increase because you know,
you get more lines of code out of your developers.
That's progress, right? But here's my concern with copilot is
that people are having codes suggested to them,
how many of them actually will take the time to
truly understand the code that is being suggested to them?
I I would assume not very many.
And in all seriousness, I think with a tool like this, the expectation should exist
of, I don't need to pay attention. The tool should do the right thing.
-- It doesn't, but it should
-- spell check is a perfect example of this.
How many people use spell check but get which, which is which incorrect.
-- It
-- doesn't matter. We figure
out
there's my favorite. Yeah, I
mean
like that's a great example though. OK. So let's let's look at spell check, right?
When we were young,
we would use Microsoft Word on our computers and we had like six floppy disks because
-- you had to keep lots of backups because there was no version anything in these
-- files.
If you turn your computer off, that file was gone,
-- it was
-- gone
and we had a spell checker and it was dumb and it screwed up a lot.
But whatever,
it was still better than whatever the nonsensical
English that comes out of my fingers was.
Now, if we look at something like Google Docs today,
Google Docs now has a suggester that looks at the grammar you're using
and you can catch things like the wrong there.
And I think this is kind of a similar thing is it is a
the first step in a long road of progress that,
that I think will get us there eventually.
But this is where we have to start.
For example,
I've started using grammarly and while it is
significantly better than say Google's or Microsoft's stuff,
I mean, I would hope so.
It's still kind of
comically, some bad English is coming out of it.
Like some of the suggestions it's making are I'm looking at this and
I'm not sure I'm pretty sure that's not correct.
But the difference being and you know, I tweeted about this,
humans are fantastically fuzzy.
Can parse English wrong order of Jedi,
Jedi,
nonsensical santa words and still sense to understand
what I was trying to get across,
right?
That like that pile of word soup is understandable to people.
Whereas if you type that into your code editor,
your compiler is going to barf on it or you miss a
or a semicolon or an equal sign.
So I think fundamentally the auto suggesting code, see,
here's the thing that kind of drives me nuts is we actually have a well
established way of suggesting people use code and
don't write it themselves and it's libraries.
-- No, that's not comparable. No, no,
-- no.
The majority of programming nowadays is basically
gluing a bunch of stuff together for most
us, a lot of it is. I agree.
Well, and look, the end state of this is going to be where I say hello, computer.
I need an application that lets someone type in their personal
information and then stores it inside of a SQL database.
So that's already happening.
It's getting, I know,
I know there's certain things that do it and we're not talking about that today.
But like that's obviously the end state of this
because
I don't think copilot to the best of my knowledge understands intent yet.
-- But it is no doubt on that path. Again,
-- we're there's natural language to contract
software for smart contracts where you literally can express
a contract in Natural English and then it converts it into
chain code.
-- Yeah, but that's like that's like asking a genie for a wish, right. Pretty
-- much.
Yeah.
And, and ironically,
it's actually a slightly more constrained problem space than other types of code.
But
I
think my concern is, is I keep coming back to sort of the self driving car issue of
if you're in a partly self driving car
and something starts to go wrong.
Number one, you have to realize something starts to go wrong and then deal with it.
But because you're in a partly self driving car, you're, you're,
you're reading a book or something,
not paying attention to the fact that you're about to slam into
a bridge abutment or the back of a stopped fire truck.
And I can't help but feel that that's going
to be sort of the similar dynamic with this github
copilot of these people are going to kind of get used to it, like spell check
and they're going to be using correctly spelled words,
but the wrong words
maybe, I mean, look, and here is part of the difficulty in that argument is
a lot of people are going to write the code
and they're never going to touch it again because they
get a new job or they're a contractor or whatever.
-- You don't
-- have to leave a place to never touch your code again.
Uh Sometimes, you know what I mean?
Like, so there's an aspect of that, but here's the thing, even if you
are in the same job for five years,
you might write something and never touch it again.
No one might ever touch it again. You know, because you just might not find bugs in it.
It depends who's looking and where it is and, and how it works. And
so, like,
that's going to be one of the challenges is
even if it's output gar like is generated code
that works but is crap and is full of security issues,
but no one knows it's there and no one finds it
is, you know, that, that this is the typical if a tree falls in the forest question,
right.
I fundamentally I I want them to make the effort to build these tools,
but I do wonder that we're sort of
letting people use these tools with a false,
like there's no disclaimer on this tool
saying, you know,
this tool has the following side effects, you know, may cause dizziness, nausea,
heartburn, indigestion.
Well, that's because nobody dies if so, who cares?
So maybe that's what we need is warning labels on technology
to actually describe accurately what the technology is capable of.
But I don't care if it doesn't kill me, do I care?
I mean, that's how, that's how it works.
-- I
-- mean, people are going to use this to crank out way more lines of code faster. And
yeah, that's for a lot of people that's kind of their metric.
-- Right. Right. Exactly.
-- Churning out stuff
and finding security vulnerabilities. Like like now I will say there is a lot of
interesting happenings in the space of standard code analysis,
composition analysis library use copy and paste all of that stuff.
So
I think this all goes hand in hand.
But then you also need some sort of checker to make
sure that copilot and the human aren't going off the rails,
but we're not quite there.
-- Everything is too new to be working together in tandem correctly.
-- What did I find?
Really fascinating is
how much software do you think
is essentially being
written as a result of not invented here syndrome?
Like essentially how much software is being written
for which there is a perfectly good, probably even open source free
solution that
will get you 90% or even 100% of the way there.
See, this is what I always wonder about is I see, like
I looked at the skater industry a while ago,
I was trying to figure out how big is the skate industry.
And as far as I can tell,
there's over 1000 companies globally writing skater products
and the pattern seems to be is a company will start out small,
have one or two big customers that kind of keep
them afloat and they'll grow to a couple 100 people.
And then, you know,
essentially move from sort of a consulting to the more software side of things
and boom, there's, you know,
a big pile of software running a couple of
oil refineries or beer breweries or factories or whatever.
And then typically, once they get big enough, they get acquired by a,
like a Honeywell because,
well, how else is Honeywell going to grow their customer base? Right?
Like SK a software, you know, is a lead time of a decade.
You know, you don't just decide, hey,
we're going to upgrade our oil refinery software because you just don't,
that's not how that works.
-- Just do it on Saturday.
-- It'll be fine. Yeah,
just when nobody's in
and like,
while I do want millions of people to
be programming and coding and having cool ideas,
right?
Like we come from the open source world, that's how this happened.
You know, let 1000 flowers bloom.
I do wonder though sometimes how much of this stuff is just being
reinvented and rewritten poorly.
Well, some of it, I mean, look, you can look at like N PM, right?
There's what 18 million N PM modules. Now,
how many of those are duplicates? I bet a lot of them are.
And does it matter? I mean, I don't know, I, I wonder this a lot because
you can make the argument that everyone should be trying to reuse everything
and I
think that's reasonable in a lot of ways. But then you also get the argument of OK.
So I'm using this left shift library from N PM and then the
developer got mad and deleted it and now everything I have broke,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
Well, and in theory,
you should be using tools and build systems that are OK with say something
disappearing for whatever reason.
That's another story. Like we talked about that with Dan
-- last week. Was it last week? I feel like it was two years ago
-- but
the perception of time
is,
oh, I
know, I know.
But, but right, I mean, these are, these are,
I feel like so here's kind of how I will bring us home on this one is
I think all of these things we keep talking but all of the open source supply chain,
all of the dependency stuff, all of the autopilot stuff,
all of the code scanning everything.
I feel like we are approaching this nexus point where we're starting to recognize
these are all the same problem. They just don't look like it.
This,
this feels like in in physics how when Einstein managed to like
bring all of physics together into one coherent thing and everyone's like,
oh I get it now.
They're all the same. Like I feel like
software development is is doing this
where everything is, is starting to come together.
I don't know where it's going to end,
but I feel like it's coming,
I keep coming back to all these economic incentives where when I,
when I look at stuff through the lens of what are the incentives.
It's like, oh,
this suddenly makes sense and all the
human behavior is explicable and predictable,
right?
And see that's the thing I love about science.
Not only do I explain what's currently going on.
I can then make predictions about the future and see if they're correct or not
and then adjust right,
and being able to make predictions about the future kind of a useful thing.
So
I, I feel like
the reality is
everything is software.
That's it. Right. That, that's a done deal.
And so that means we need to write lots and lots of software.
What does that look like? How does that happen?
And, and I think that's where like right now there's tons of companies reproducing
things poorly
and
well, the, the market is big enough to absorb that right now.
But I just,
I sometimes wonder what things would look like if there was a more
open source usage and acceptance rather than writing all this junk internally.
Everyone's using open source for like everything.
I don't know, open source usage and acceptance could be any higher than it is today,
but there's still a lot of not invented here syndrome.
Right.
That's never going to go away. I mean, I've known people acting like that.
Well, exactly. And, and so my question is why,
well, because of humans, man, I mean,
I know people that have acted like that in literally every industry,
every place I've ever been,
every club, everyone
where there are people who just have this attitude of,
there's no way someone else could do this as good as me.
And that's what it really comes down to I mean,
I remember suffering from this greatly when I was young,
that perception of control.
-- Well,
-- I don't even think that man, I mean,
I remember being surrounded by people that were like, oh, we're smarter than them.
Let's do it
the right way.
And in hindsight, it's like no, like by definition,
if you say that you've proven you're not,
but when you're young, you're like, yeah,
I can do this better and the reality was
-- no, he couldn't.
-- Well, that speaks to Dunning Kruger, right?
That generally speaking, the smarter and more people actually know about a topic.
The more that they say, I don't know
everything about this topic because they
-- understand how big the topic is.
-- My, my other favorite one is where it's like, oh,
I can write that software and I'll make it better.
Ignoring the fact that these people spent five years working on features
and bugs and I'm going to do it in two weeks.
No, I'm not.
I've always loved the people who are like, I can,
I can rewrite that entire thing in a weekend
-- and get the basics up and running. And it's like, no,
-- you can't.
I mean, I used to think like that. I remember when I was young.
I would be like, oh, I can do this in a week
and it's like, no,
you can't.
But do we need a university level course on this?
Similar to how, for example,
geologists have a course that teaches them how to
think about time in geological time scales which,
like I've looked at that and I, I,
I fundamentally get that. I don't get it.
Like I cannot think in terms of millions or billions of years and what that means.
Right.
Whereas geologists have to learn that as part of their thing and
maybe that's something we need to start teaching
people is the scale of software because again,
the scale is a big thing too, right?
How many people,
you know, you can write a very simplistic web server and oh, what was that?
The person was going?
Oh, it only, oh, it was the DNS resolver in, I think Alpine Linux, whatever.
It only supports
uh UDP, not TCP. So it can't handle large responses that have to be sent as TCP.
And it's kind of like,
yeah, I mean, if I could write a DNS resolver that doesn't do TCP/IP.
Yeah, I could probably crank one out relatively quickly.
But, oh, you want me to support all the bits of DNS,
including DNS sec.
I know enough about this to know that the answer is no, Kurt can't do that.
Well, in, in DNS is probably what, like 30 RFC S you have to read. At
least
I think it's around 100 now.
-- That could
-- be all right.
So you mentioned a university course and there's a good comparison to this I think.
And I would say it's uh physics versus engineering
where
physicists deal with, we'll say the, the theory and concepts of the universe,
engineers have to actually deal with the
constraints and realities of the universe.
It's like spherical cows and the old jokes, right? And
I think computer science is kind of similar where
if you go to college for computer science,
you, you don't learn how to build software,
you learn about like the weird fundamentals of things like algorithm design.
I mean, I remember taking computer science courses when I was at university and
I'm like, I don't care about big O notation. Like, I, it doesn't matter. Right.
And the professor of course, would get very upset.
But it's like in my world it didn't matter because I just
used a library that had a short function built into it.
Right.
But when you're a computer scientist, that's a great thing to think about and solve.
Well, I think it's one of those things where it doesn't matter until it does matter.
But
the
people. Exactly. And that's the,
that's smart,
you know, and it's like my car,
my car has a whole bunch of parts in it that I can't even begin to understand.
Cool.
I just order them online and, you know, the mechanic shoves them in when they break.
Right. Pretty much. I don't know.
I think definitely people having maybe an
appreciation for the complexity and difficulty and
the design trade offs and decisions that
were made and maybe making those more public
might help.
Well, I think a lot of software, especially in open source, you can,
you can make these as you can figure this out by
looking at commit history and bugs and things like that.
I mean,
I think what you just said though, applies to a copilot is, it's a magic box.
Like here's something in that in the paper that will obviously be in the show notes.
So
they basically tried to get whole pilot to complete a function,
then they waited a little while and they did it again and
the code was different and they gave it the same inputs,
which I mean,
this is how A I and ML work for anyone who understands how models grow and evolve.
-- But like think about
-- that well and also as systems get updated,
right? Because it's updating itself on new code and everything.
-- But
-- the point is this is a magic black box that I have no idea what's going on.
Well, but I would also point out if it spat out the same code consistently,
then that means the system is not improving or evolving because
it's definitely not got the right answer the first time around.
I'm not saying there's a problem with it, spitting out different code.
I'm going to hope the second code was better than the first.
I, I don't know because I haven't tried this particular experiment.
But the point is though
it's completely magic and why did it change? Is it better?
Is it work like, you know what I mean?
This is what makes a system like this just so terrifying
is the fact that we have no idea what's going on.
I mean, here,
here's a thought experiment that's completely not out
of the question is what if a company
that has a, a solution that has say a free library that you can then
pay to upgrade
into some commercial features
and they go to github
and they're like, here's a couple of million bucks.
We want you to make sure you suggest our library
when people try to solve this problem.
Well,
I'm assuming that there's going to be organic se search engine optimization
style attempts at this kind of thing because there's money there,
honestly.
Yes, I hadn't even thought of that. But yes, absolutely.
Well, there's money there. So there's an incentive for people to do this.
So I'm going to make a prediction that when
you incentivize people to do stuff with money,
they go and do it.
-- That's not a prediction. That's reality. Well,
-- and yet we have so many
things where people are like, why do people do that?
It's like because they get paid to
like all that Russian trolling online. Why? Well, because
the government pays those people to troll us and
you know, take sheep de
wormer.
Yeah, I hadn't even thought of that, but you're right there, there,
there are going to be ways
to trick. I don't know if trick is the right word, but we'll say coerce
A to like autopilot. I mean, it is a black box. We have no idea how it works.
But I mean, think about Google, right.
We technically don't know how their algorithm works yet.
There's an awful lot of seo companies that seem to do pretty good, you know,
you can do black box testing, right?
And the beauty is with something like the Google search engine optimization.
You have very clear output metrics of more or less search results.
You know what I mean? You, you find out pretty quickly if it works or not.
And so you just, yeah, you just plug away at it and, and
keep trying
totally.
I, I think these are, I, I like the idea of technology moving forwards,
but I think for me,
the biggest thing is I come back to this kind of auto uh self driving car concept of
it
needs to maybe be very explicit and clear of what it is
and is not capable of so that people use it correctly.
And the reality is having said that I know that 99% of people
don't read the ingredients list on the food they eat.
Of course not. Why would I So,
yeah.
Anyway.
All right. II, I feel like once again
I know less than I did
before we started this conversation.
Oh, I guess we'll, we'll have to wait and see. All right, I'm calling it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for ever for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up, brush your notes, UZ Pound
Oss
podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.