December 19th. We're almost done. This feels like a slog.
It is, but it'll be over soon, just like this year.
-- That's
-- assuming anyone's still listening at this point
and they haven't all unsubscribed from the podcast.
I wonder if anybody is going to binge watch these and I hope not.
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry if you do.
All right.
TLS.
-- Yeah. TLS. Certificate. Trust. What
-- does that mean?
You wrote this one down?
So, what is it?
I don't know.
No.
Ok. So
we talked about public key cryptography. It feels like yesterday.
But
I
swear
it's almost over.
It's almost over.
But anyway, so I thought this is an important topic because
the internet runs on TLS.
Trust.
What does that mean? Right. Where do we get it from?
And so I would sum this up as we
get it from a website where we paid for it with our credit card
right
-- now.
-- And when you say that out loud, it doesn't sound very good.
-- Does
-- it, I mean, it, whatever,
what it,
what it basically comes down to is having a
certificate on the internet means that you proved you.
Are you
in some way?
Proved you have control of the aspects of yourself, which fundamentally
proving control of something is tantamount.
If you do enough of it to proving that you are that something
because that's just how it works. You know, if I can provide a DNA sample, that
is your DNA and I can provide a voice print, that is your voice print,
then effectively I can so effectively spoof you that I am. You
-- are, are ev certificates still a thing. Are those dead now? Absolutely.
-- Yes.
There's a couple of banks and stuff using them.
But more to the point,
there's a lot of organizations that specifically do not use them.
So my favorite example being Amazon, right, Amazon,
I think does a bit of online commerce
and they don't use EV cert and I think outside of banks, I haven't seen an EV Cert
in,
you know, forever.
Right. Right.
Well, and they're, they look weird. That's the biggest thing. Right.
They look weird because you get that big green thing in your title bar.
-- I don't know if it's still there even because I haven't
-- seen one in.
-- No, I don't remember it. I
-- suspect it probably caused people to freak out.
-- So anyway,
-- the point is the point of certificate trust
is that
the internet to use encryption, to use public key cryptography.
You need a way to basically say that I'm talking to
my bank and I'm not talking to a server cart owns.
-- Right.
-- Fundamentally Well, you're talking to
food.com and hopefully food.com is your bank
and let's assume it is because let's not,
let's not worry about all the weird corner cases because there's a million of them.
Well, the perfect example is just, you know, somebody registers your bank name.
Dash for real.com, you know, and then they get a certificate for it and,
and if you're not paying attention, you click on it and it looks like your bank,
they scrape the page and
well, to put it bluntly, that's why you need a password manager. But,
and,
and two factor off
the problem with TLS trust is TLS trust is about the
domain name or the proof of the thing that they controlled,
maybe an email address, but it's not who that entity is.
And that's in theory what extended validation and
organizational ov or organizational validation does where,
you know, they check your dunn's business number and blah, blah, blah.
But even that is,
you know, it's not perfect.
No. And there, there were many, many ways around it.
It was definitely security theater.
-- What is Burger King called in Australia? I
-- don't know. Is it Burger?
No, it's got a different name because isn't Burger King owned by some, like
some guy
it was
hungry Jack's
in Australia because some Australian
opened up a restaurant that serve burgers and called it Burger King,
which is a pretty reasonable thing to do.
And he beat Burger King to it. So tough.
I mean, yeah, it's, I'm not, it's not a unique name.
Yeah.
And,
but, but now at the same time, obviously, if you go to Burger king.com,
what the purpose of TLS does is it,
it doesn't even necessarily say you're connecting
to the Burger King organization.
It's saying that there's a level of trust
that can be traced back to another, a third party
that says the site you are going to
is the site you think it is, right?
And I think that is what it doesn't say anything about ownership.
It says nothing about trust.
Interestingly, Burger king.com dot au, redirects to hungry jacks.com dot au.
-- So they did buy the domain name.
-- Interesting.
So they bought the domain. Well, good for them.
But no, you're right. It's,
and fundamentally that's a
we need, I need to know that I'm ending up at cnn.com because, you know,
I want to get my news or I'm at my td.com for my bank or
whatever.
And because that's a, that's a thing in the physical real world.
When you go to a store,
it's usually whatever that storefront says, right?
People don't set up fake storefronts, take your money and run.
I mean, it kind of happens once in a while, but it's super rare.
-- Whereas online it's pretty common. We're,
-- we're basically out of time,
but I will tell you that the one answer to this question is now let's encrypt.
Yes.
Absolutely.
-- And not
-- just
-- let's
-- encrypt. Not just because,
because let's encrypt forces you to automate it and this stuff should be automated.
So,
it doesn't expire someday and break all your stuff
and their certificates have a very short lifetime.
So, even if an evildoer gets a hold of one,
it's not good for 10 years.
Yeah. And that again, speaks to automation.
Let's encrypt.
We're almost there.
They pick a
good domain name
and project name. Let's encrypt.
-- Time
-- to go.