Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
Oh, man, you keep saying crime. I'm used to thought crime. Anyway, I'm ecstatic.
Today. We have, we have a guest.
We have someone who I've recently become acquainted with.
His name is Travis Murdoch. He's the executive vice president at R
FIN and Travis is, I guess, what, what would you describe your job as Travis?
I don't wanna, I guess upend you on this.
Well, I help people tell their stories and to tell them.
Well, my job is a storyteller. How's that?
That's a lovely description.
So, so the actual topic we're, we're talking about is is functionally,
I guess public relations would be maybe the old way of saying it.
But I, I really like the storytelling answer. That's, that's phenomenal.
So why don't you tell us who you are? Travis kind of why, why are you here?
Well, I,
I do pr for a living and a lot of the place
where I focus is in helping people understand and talk about the technology
and also very often around security.
There's a lot to inform both the public and the informed public, which I might call,
say developers and, and security professionals themselves.
And I love to talk about that.
So I think we're going to talk a little bit about that today.
Well, we'll see, we might end up talking about plumbing or something.
You never know.
There is no topic.
I just, I just love how initially like my first reaction is like,
uh pr but then I'm like, no, we like,
infosec needs this because when I think about all the times I've seen people
tell me something and I'm like, why is it important? They're like, be because it is.
And I'm like, that's not really convincing, as I said, so, well,
that's their backup plan usually.
Yes. Is why won't you listen to me? I'm the expert.
Yeah. Yeah.
-- And, and you and I both used to be that person. Ok.
-- Ok. So let's
before we, we dive into the weeds, I guess.
And this is, this is why I wanted Travis to come talk to us because
I've, I've been interacting with Travis in, in day job.
And
I realized quickly that, you know, your stuff from the pr perspective,
but also from the security perspective,
which is not something I'd experienced in the past.
And I guess I will start the conversation with the joke.
I always tell everyone in the security world,
there are two kinds of people, there are people who won't talk to reporters
and people who shouldn't talk to reporters and I guess let's take it from there.
Why, why does this matter? Why should we care?
And, and I guess what is the advantage to all of this Travis?
Yeah.
I mean, of course, people skills as we've learned from office space are important
but,
but commune
but communicating particularly to reporters is,
is really important because they're your conduit
to, to creating change. You know, security is very often
about changing of behaviors.
A lot of security incidents, a lot of security problems occur because the user,
the end user is making a mis a very common mistake or even sometimes the developer is,
is making a mistake
that communication because the, the, you know,
the media buy ink and barrels gives them the ability to
communicate to large groups of people and to change behavior.
And,
you know, without them,
we're in a situation where we have to communicate one on one and,
and we know that doesn't,
doesn't work or at least it's much harder and much more expensive.
And a security person who can speak regular talk is so valuable to a
reporter is so valuable because they don't sit in this stuff all day long.
They need someone that helps them translate it and
it makes a big difference for their job.
Right. Right.
And, and so you hit on,
I think a really important point and this
is something as very technical oriented people,
we forget about sometimes is that reporters and, and just everyone in general,
they're not steeped in this world.
And so they don't understand all of the
nuance and just silliness that sometimes comes with it
and, and I wouldn't say worse, but they also,
they don't necessarily have the time for this.
Like, they already have a job.
No. Seriously. Right.
Like, because I've, I've literally encountered technical people that are like,
why can't everybody just learn how to like
safely click links in their email and like identify
the link in the address bar and stuff.
And then it's like, no,
no, like these, like,
because I remember doing tech support once and I
was doing tech support a doctor and I'm like,
clearly this doctor's not stupid because they're a doctor, right?
Like, they generally don't let dumb people be doctors.
And that's kind of that was, I remember when I was about 19 or 20
that was my first moment where I realized the doctor's not the problem.
Maybe I'm part of the problem, but I think the technology is the problem, right? And
I, I didn't have a good way to explain it to the doctor. So it didn't go very well.
But I, I think a lot of us technical people think,
why can't everybody just learn that it's easy, right?
-- Like riding a bike upside down,
-- you know,
I'll also say that I've learned over time that there are
people who have what I would call a systems oriented mind.
So, you know, A then B then C and there's others who just don't. Now
we're all, we're all valuable people. And
so those who can explain those processes to others
are quite valuable.
Another thing about reporters is that
especially with the pressure today on media, they're writing
very often two or three stories a day.
And even if they're afforded, you know, maybe writing just one story a day,
that's a lot of writing. And so they're just not going to have time
to dig into the details. They're not going to have time to understand,
you know,
kind of the upside and the downside of what you're telling them and
your ability to communicate that to them
clearly and quickly is extremely valuable.
I mean, once they know that you're a good source, I mean,
for those who want to promote their own company,
once they know that you're a good source
that you'll provide them with clear information,
they're going to come back to you time and time again.
-- So
-- actually,
that also leads on to one of the other
things that I've been thinking about lately is there,
is there's a security
journalist that I follow and I remember he,
he put a thing up on Twitter,
probably it's been two or three weeks where basically he said I am tired
of companies trying to use me as a wing of their marketing department.
And so
I'm, I'm curious if you have thoughts. And like obviously, if, if I'm speaking
to a reporter, on behalf of my company,
there is a fine line right between marketing
and and helping the reporter write a story,
you know, be a real source.
So add value to that report, don't be just trying to extract it.
A true relationship is, is two way with reporters that I work with,
you know,
I will pitch them a story and of course I have clients that
I work with and I am trying to help sell their product,
but I'm not just interacting with that reporter at that moment. At
that pitch, I am sending them,
hey, I know you write about this.
Have you thought about this that has nothing to do with me or my self interest?
And I'm giving them information.
So I think that's, that's a key thing. If you want to build a relationship, build it,
you're not going to build relationships with 100 and 50 reporters,
you're going to build a relationship with five, pick the five,
find the ones that write about the things that you're interested in
and then read what they write
and then deliver value.
You know, maybe one other thing is, is that man do. They really hate
when you send them pitches that have nothing to do with them
and they get this all day long, they get hundreds of email messages.
As a reporter, you get hundreds a day and 90% of those are,
it's like that's not a beat I cover.
Why are you sending this to me?
This is, you know, this is just like, has nothing to do with me and,
and that is so frustrating for
Border. So being careful, just, just read what they've written
is what I'm sharing with them.
Is it relevant to what they've written in the past?
Because if it's not,
it's, it's not interesting for them now either.
-- Yeah,
-- that makes a lot of sense. That's, yeah. Yeah, I can, I can relate to that. And
I mean, obviously as people on a podcast,
we get the pitches every now and then and yeah, sometimes it's like you clearly,
you clearly have never even opened our website
you
sent
us.
But yeah, yeah, that, that's fair. That's fair. I like that. Ok,
so we,
I, I want, I want to move the conversation a little bit as well.
So obviously we've discussed
what, what it means to kind of connect with reporters,
but I also feel like actually talking to these people
is
an art in itself where
I don't think most reporters are looking to, to catch you
necessarily.
But I think there's also some,
I find people get confused about like the off the record on the record.
Can I say this? Can I say that?
You know, what does it mean to talk to a member of the press?
Yeah, I mean, I have lots of reporters who are my friends.
So I don't want this to sound wrong but,
but the reporters are not your friends, you know, they are,
you need to be
conscious and careful to know that when you're speaking to them
that it is on record, right?
What you're telling them is something that they're
legally and professionally obligated to report on.
So be very careful with that and,
and think about what you're going to say ahead of time.
I mean, this, this part is extremely basic, but, you know,
compose yourself into three bullets of key messages, you know,
what are you going to say?
So that
so that you can get it to them clearly and so that they can understand it quickly,
know that you're gonna speak to a reporter if you're lucky for 20 minutes.
Now,
every once in a while when they see something of a
lot of interest or you're delivering a lot of value,
you'll get a little bit more time out of them, but that's what you're going to get.
And if for some reason,
you're in a situation where you really are giving information
that you don't want the reporter to use your name.
You need to be extremely explicit about that
before you shared anything
and you need to get the reporter to agree to that you need to say to them.
I, you know, I want this to be confidential and I don't want you to,
to share my name and if they agree to that then, ok.
But if they don't agree to that ahead of time, know that you can't tell them at the end.
Oh, this is all confidential. That's not, that's not how they work. Right.
You know, it's, it's, it has to be before.
I would just tell you quite honestly,
if you're engaging in that kind of a conversation with a reporter
that you really do need somebody who helps
who is with you that understands what you're doing
and can help guide you a little bit because that's tricky.
That's tricky waters to be in.
Yeah,
two questions I have.
So like, for example,
would that be finding somebody like just a marketing person
at your company that can help you with this,
that kind of has that skill set?
Like basically like let's say a reporter wants to talk to me. And I'm kind of like, uh
you know, like, yeah, where do I find my adult friend to help me out?
Well, I would, I would actually find somebody that has media relations experience.
So somebody who, who does pr I, I do this very often for,
for people that I've worked at where they get into another
company and they just need a 20 minute free consulting advice
for my own marketing. I have to say that I have told everyone that I work with that.
Hey, look,
you have free pr advice for life and it's been really helpful to me personally
and people will call and say, hey, look, we feel like we need to share this story.
How do we share it?
And it is very often on,
they're tr they're thinking that they can be like deep throat here and they can,
you know, give a secret
something to a reporter
and I'll tell you,
you really got to do that the right way and it's very tricky most of the time,
99% of the time.
That's not the right way. You either say it and it's public or you don't say it
-- and it's not public.
-- Well, I actually have a second question, like,
as part of it, I've also seen, you know,
people who rely on talking points on the one
head and it annoys me because they tend to,
like, bang on about the same two or three things.
But on the flip side,
I've noticed that they do tend to at least get two or three out clearly, you know,
versus
like when I've tried to think off the top of my head and it's kind of like da, da,
da,
-- you know, it's verbal mishmash,
-- diarrhea. We call that a podcast.
Yes.
Right.
Yeah.
You know,
and, uh, well, I mean, funnily enough,
me and Josh did discuss at one point about maybe
sort of scripting the podcast and then we're both,
like, not too much work, not doing it.
I don't really come up with talking points for the podcast, but I do try to, you know,
pre think a little bit so I'm not thinking on my feet constantly and I
was just wondering what your thoughts or comments were sort of around that whole,
like, talking points.
Yeah, I, I would definitely do it, you know,
every time you're speaking to a reporter or you're having even, you're,
you're speaking on a panel on a stage, make sure that you have those three points,
one because it organizes your thoughts in front of others.
And, and, and second of all,
it helps you to just think through how do I say this or where could
I get gummed up and secretly all executives
are media trained and they're taught to repeat
these, you know, three key messages.
And so that's why you hear that people get stuck
on that is because they've been trained to do it.
I would say though that
obviously maybe they were overtrained, you know, you need to,
you have to sound like a human. You have to engage with people.
You know, reporters are humans too.
I said they're not your friends but they, they're still humans and they're,
and they respond to warmth and in particular, if you're in a conversation, right?
It's like, are you a robot
or are you giving me real advice? One thing I always advise
my executives on is that your primary goal of this
interview of this discussion is to build a relationship of trust
with that reporter,
that relationship of trust.
Yes, it might get us the story right now.
But maybe so much more importantly,
it'll make that person come back to you time and time and time again.
So whatever you need to do to bridge the gap, do that,
-- to build that relationship of trust,
-- I think that's really powerful and I feel like
a lot of people I've interacted with over the course of my career
view, they don't understand always that, that human element to all of this. And
if you view the press is just your dumping ground for your talking points,
you're never going to build those connections.
Yeah, I mean, wow, like going back to that comment, I'm not your marketing tool.
It's like, that's exactly right.
If you're just dumping
press releases on them and saying, why didn't you cover me?
It's like that is that is not going to work in the short or long term, you know,
it just isn't.
I, I used to many, many, many moons ago.
This was, this was before I even worked at Red Hat,
which any listener of the podcast is well aware that Kurt and I have,
we both worked at Red Hat for a long time.
But, but prior to that even I remember I was at a company that
would produce press releases,
dump them out into the world.
And then the,
the CEO would get very angry when the press when no one was calling him to talk to him.
And
I remember everyone was like, I don't know a lot about the press,
but I'm pretty sure this isn't how it works.
Well, unless you're like, the press releases is beyond amazing.
-- Like, hey, we just cured cancer.
-- They, they weren't
like
it was, that company didn't make it a real long time. We'll say it was a dot Release.
It was, this was.com,
-- you know.
-- Oh, yeah,
I remember,
I remember like,
just remember the flood of press releases from these.com companies.
Like it was
hysterically bad,
you know, synergize the markets and delivering pet food to your door.
I tell you guys a quick negative story about me. Oh, definitely.
So I worked for a company and I wrote this press release.
They asked me to write this press release and, you know,
I wrote it in about four hours or so
and I sent it over to the CEO and, and it came back and it was, you know,
he just redlined the whole thing and every
single adjective or adverb he had replaced with,
you know, at least a three syllable
word.
And I was so I,
I wrote it and over the week I spent more
than 40 hours writing this press release going back and forth
because it was, he,
he was cramming more and more and more into it and I was
trying to pull it out and I was early in my career.
So I didn't really have the ability to, you know,
kind of like explain why this didn't make sense.
So
end of the week happened, the release went out
and
I pitched it out and then I got an email from the Wall
Street Journal from the number one person that we were trying to influence.
So this is the most important person on the planet for this company at this moment.
And he said, Travis, I,
I'd like to congratulate you on winning the Buzzy Award for this week.
Uh
All the business reporters and every single top business publication,
they had this little pool where they got
together and they had an algorithm that scored
$100 words inside of this press release.
And ours had won the, you know, essentially the worst press release of the week.
So now remember every single top business publication
reporter
has now read my press release and has said that it was awful.
I didn't even know what to say, right?
Because of course, my name is on the press release. They assume I've written it
and I forwarded it to the CEO and I said here this is it. Wow. So as a,
I do have to say as a consolation prize.
A few weeks later, the reporter wrote a literally a two inch story two inches.
That's it. That's how big the story was that was buried.
Like on page 18 of the Wall Street Journal that mentioned my company,
he did that kind of as, as a joke, consolation prize for me.
But it was really, I mean, like those when you do stuff like that,
it has negative consequences and that was fairly negative.
So I think this is one thing in general
with any career is that learning to say no. Right?
Because I've seen a lot of tech, people are asked to implement something
and they don't say no or like this is a really bad idea that could get us in jail.
And especially with the press, I've seen a lot of yeah,
people try to manipulate the press and it's kind of like,
well that's like trying to manipulate like a used car sales guy because they
sell like 10 cars a day and you do this once every two years,
you know you're going to lose.
Yeah. And it's, it's funny how today I now use that story to say look man,
like there's real negative consequences. I know how to say no now. Right.
Well, I mean, in all seriousness sometimes
see sometimes something bad has to happen to make to let something good happen.
So I, I assume you made lemonade from your lemons.
I mean, you seem to be doing all right. You know, I
-- I
-- did
-- continue, I persisted,
it did work. I did learn,
I did not have to fight with that CEO ever again when I told him
-- that his press release did not make sense. All of us learned well after that.
-- Nice.
Ok. Ok.
We are, we are approaching the, the end of the show in a little bit, but I,
I have one more topic I really want to touch on as well since we have you is.
So let's assume
I've discovered
an amazing
thing
and
let's,
I don't know, let's say the new, the new heart bleed, right.
The new terrible security vulnerability.
What, what I guess what, what do you do next? Right.
Because obviously the intent is going to be to properly
inform and get the information out into the universe.
So as a professional other than like just, you know,
like posting garbage on Twitter,
what would be the right thing to do as a researcher to deal with,
you know, some sort of sensitive and important?
Well, I'm definitely an advocate for responsible disclosure.
So, you know,
making sure that you do this in the right order I think is really important.
First thing I would do is I would make sure that you write it down from,
from a both technical and not maybe less technical perspective,
short paper blog post that explains
what it is. This is before you've taken it to anyone
think through
what the problem is, what its impacts are
and you know, the technical exploits on it.
And the reason why that's important is that you're
going to need to pass this along to many people
and they're going to need to pass it to people.
So the kind of the short email I found a breach here at this point,
it isn't really helpful.
We all document bugs, right? But, but, but use words here to document this right?
In, in a blog post, like format. Second step is
I really advocate
that you don't just,
you're not just when you're doing responsible
disclosure and you're not sending it to,
you know, just at security at whoever.com
that you really take the time to figure out
real email addresses and really who you should speak to.
It doesn't take long.
I'm gonna, I would push back there a little bit. Shouldn't these companies?
To me it's a signal.
If they actually care about security,
they're going to make it relatively easy to report a security flaw, you know,
having security at company name.com or having, you know,
company name.com/security or, you know,
something on their web page under contact us.
And the reason I say that is because I,
I have dealt with this where I try to chase
down somebody responsible to contact and it proves impossible.
And what that's always resulted in is this company doesn't really care, you know,
like, if they can't make it easy to report an issue,
then they're probably not going to have the
capability of fixing and dealing with that issue.
Well, I certainly agree that lots of companies don't do this. Right.
I guess I would just say that
it's not that hard to find the CEO S email address these days.
And if, if, if, as a, as a final thing, you know, you have to do that.
Of course, we don't want to dump stuff out into the world. And also
I think that
when you go to report this later because later it will be public,
I think it, I think it makes you look as more,
much more of a responsible security researcher
when you do that.
Yeah,
but the next step, as you decide that it's time to disclose, you know, publicly,
you've worked with the company, you, you know,
when you're going to disclose and it's time to disclose,
you should pull up the reporters
that cover this and send them an email that says
I found this, this is when we're, you know,
going out with it and here's the details and I'm available to
speak to you on the phone and give them the times
when you're available and I suspect many of them will call,
you know,
if this is a decent sized problem by bringing that
to them and now you have that blog post,
right?
That explains the whole thing to them.
Now, they can read that and say, ok,
I don't just have to trust this guy that I don't know.
I'm reading this. I see that it's big. I see that it's important
and also this person knows how to communicate with
me and then listen you can get a lot.
There's a few researchers out there today who are gaining
lots of notoriety.
They don't have a super technical background
but they have learned how to communicate.
They've learned how to tell reporters
what's going on
and that allows them to get the credit that they deserve
-- for the thing that they found.
-- Yeah, I, I think that's huge and I'm,
I will admit I'm guilty of this on a
regular basis where I often treat the human skills,
those soft skills as less important than the technical skills.
And in many ways, I think they are more important
than the technical skills because being able to concisely communicate any of
this is not only insanely difficult but insanely valuable as well.
You know, just simple things like, like I said,
having a blog post where it's written down
so that it's
available to everybody at the same time and then just giving
reporters the times when you're available to speak to them,
you know, ahead of time. So that because their schedule is packed,
you make it quick and easy for them
and understand that, you know, they are competing for clicks.
So if you give everyone the news at the same time,
you're gonna get a lot more people interested in talking to
you about it than if you dole it out to one person
and then wait 48 hours and give it to everyone else.
You know, it's like it's old
So, so, so you've lost it.
If you're, if you, if your interest is in getting more people to know,
you know about this thing you found,
do it at the same time. Now, I would caution you that
to never give this information to reporters before the
agreed time when you're going to release it.
And, and the reason is,
is that asking them to hold an embargo unless you've agreed to an embargo,
that's not how it works.
They have to agree to the embargo before you tell them that information.
And I, I just don't think it doesn't work very well with security exploits.
-- It just doesn't work
-- to
-- be
-- blunt.
Josh and I have been on the receiving end of many,
many totally screwed up embargoed issues where
it just went all the way sideways and
unnecessarily painful and not like anything terrible happened.
But just,
wow. Did it ever make things painful?
The stories we can tell?
So I want to end with a fun question,
branded security vulnerabilities like heartbleed and shell shock
and meltdown and ghost and pick one.
What do you think are, is branding security issues a good idea or a bad idea?
Oh, I love that. You asked this question.
I thought it was so hokey when it first came out and I just was like, this is so so silly,
but I realized that as a storyteller
that
it has an
extreme amount of value, every single one of those words that you just said,
I know what you're talking about. Right?
And if you would have used some numbering system,
right.
So long,
I would not have known what you're talking about and I would have had to go look it up.
That's the way our brains work. We are. We have to have a name because
can't remember something unless it has a name and we can put it in the box right.
Once it's in that box, then we can
put all the other things in with it. So I'm I'm gonna vote for these names.
-- Yeah, I think we should keep using them. Yeah,
-- I mean, I, I do agree.
I feel like at the beginning I, I found them to be silly also, but you're right.
I don't know
the CV E for heartbleed off the top of my head,
but obviously I know what heartbleed is and I can say
lead to you and you know exactly what I'm talking about, which is, that's cool.
-- Right. That's really cool.
-- I just looked it up. I didn't remember it either.
-- What is it?
2014? 10160
0160 back when CB still like I feel like we run out of the zero,
the leading zero by what?
Middle of January these days?
-- Well,
-- you know, it's funny because the only CV I know off by heart is CV 2009 35
also known as El Diablo because it affected so many vendors.
It was the,
one of the first TS protocol ones that it actually broke our
reporting system because you could only update a report 100 times and
that's it.
And we actually did that and then it broke and then
some poor guy had to retype the entire thing from scratch
so we could keep it right. Like, keep updating it and it's
no, no, it wasn't. OK.
But like
I just know that because this is like one of the first things
that was just, it's over 100 vendor references. Like it's a monster.
And so it's, it's just, it's like the Titanic of CV. S for me, right? That's
one.
And it's the only number I remember and, and I'm a CV guy.
So like, clearly these CV numbers don't work for humans.
That's true. Right? We're, we're buried in them
-- all, all Travis. You get the last word before we wrap up.
-- If you are
eager to tell your story,
think about it ahead of time, write it down, use those key points
and add value to reporters, meaning build a relationship early.
Think about how you can give them things that are of value and make their life easier.
And then when you have something that you want to share with them,
they'll be very happy to, to listen to you.
That's, that's fabulous. I, I love,
I love the concept of the storyteller that's,
I mean, that's what we are, right.
We're super intelligent monkeys that love to tell stories and that's
fundamentally what it all comes down to. Awesome. Ok, cool. Thank you so much.
This has been so much fun. I am, I am just giddy. I I, you have no idea how happy I am.
You came, came and talked to us today. So, so thank you so, so, so much and
we'll almost definitely have to have you back someday to tell more stories,
which is super wonderful, so cool.
So, thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you Travis.
You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up our show notes.
I'll have links to Travis and some other things there for everyone.
And if I remember the CV, we just talked about,
maybe I'll put those in there and you can use I
Podos as podcast.
Hashtag You've hit us up on social media,
-- Kurt and Travis have fantastic rest of your
-- days.
-- Thanks
-- everybody.
-- Thank
-- you,
marvelous. Thank you all so much. All right, bye bye.