Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurtz Fried and my partner in not recording
journalists and breaking into their phones illegally,
Josh Bresser.
-- I mean,
-- we've recorded journalists.
-- We, we're, we're technically journalists,
-- not illegally. We had consent,
-- they
-- had to dial in.
-- That's
-- true. They followed a link and they, there's
a,
there's a big thing that says we're recording on the screen
and you have to like pick your microphone and pick your speakers
pretty sure the spyware doesn't do that,
I suppose not. So, what are we talking about?
We're talking about the NSO and what, and, and let's just get any bias out of the way.
I personally think the NSO
is
a horrifically ill behaved company that is
probably doing things that are illegal and
we're going to basically throw them under the train.
They're the bad guys in this story. Let's face it.
I'm not sure they can be the good guys ever.
So basically, the NSO group is this
Israeli company.
And again, normally I wouldn't care what country they're from,
but apparently the NSO group gives the Israeli government
the list of the people that they're targeting Right.
So they essentially share intelligence with the government.
Which sort of sounds like one of those things where,
well, it's like the Russian ransomware gangs,
they're doing things that are illegal, probably illegal in Russia.
But, you know, the Russian authorities don't care.
One of the latest ransomware that tore through the world
was specifically looking for computers that had Russian language as
-- a default language and they weren't ransoming those
-- computers.
That's a common thing now. Yeah.
So I suspect in general the rule of law is
stronger in a country like Israel than say Russia.
Yes point is,
it seems to me like this is one of those things where
we want to do something that may or may not be legal.
But you know, if we give the government this information, they might keep,
let us stick around.
Well, there's also the aspect of, I mean,
a great example is there are companies that make missiles for the military.
If I go to them and say I want to buy a missile, they're going to be like no.
And
so, and I would imagine buying,
selling and possessing missiles is probably illegal.
Well, it's under itar and it's a destructive device under us federal law.
-- So
-- the idea is that there are
companies that provide goods and services to
governments and the idea is the government will say you can do this thing,
but you can only work with the people we like.
And the current evidence with the NSO group is suggesting
that
-- that is probably not true. Yeah.
-- Well, I mean, there's, there's,
I feel like it's like, you know, that Webber and Mitchell, are we the baddies skit?
Yes.
And so, and then the other thing is like, you look at the Guardian and, well,
and it's the Guardian of the New York Times, the Washington Post, you know, not, not
that they're reasonably respectable papers.
I mean, they're pretty much the only ones left
and you look at the list of people
that are getting targeted by this
product and it's journalists,
it's the editor at the Financial Times, like, come on
the editor at the financial Times,
like I'm pretty sure she is not involved in anything too shady.
Well, no, no, I mean, so the reason they're doing this actually is
by targeting journalists, they're not
actively going after journalists, journalists talk to people
they want,
right?
And some of these and, and when you cast a wide net,
you're going to get people on every side
of this argument because, like, for example,
whenever you hear about an anonymous source, that could be someone working for the,
the government that says, oh, this thing is happening.
I mean, Edward Snowden is the easiest whistleblower of all time of, I mean,
functionally he, he leaked a ton of stuff but everyone knew who he was.
Like, there was no escaping that, but there's
people who leak little bits and pieces
to journalists all the time.
And so now a government could say to the NSO group, uh, who leaked this
and if they have access to that reporter's phone, they can probably figure it out.
And I
-- really don't like that argument. Oh, it's
-- terrible. I agree. I'm not saying it's ok.
I'm saying that's what they're doing.
-- Well,
-- and the other thing that even if you ignore all this and let's,
let's just go with the whole lawful government authorized whatever.
Literally, if you Google, you know,
surveillance program later found to be unlawful space country name,
like you plug in the word Canada.
And we get an article from like May where, you know, our version of the NSA was
essentially paddled by a judge and the judge straight up said your,
your warrant process is so weak that you may be doing things that are illegal.
Right. Right.
You know, and this is Canada, we have pretty strong rule of law and whatnot here.
Like if Canada can't get it right.
-- I mean,
-- come on, there are always there, there's this constant back and forth.
And one of my favorite examples is
where we get new technology and then
the law and judges have to catch up with new technology
and,
and I mean, this is,
this is constant where there might be like the FBI might do some sort
of surveillance and then you go to court and the courts will say,
ok, this is new we don't know what to do and sometimes they get it wrong a lot,
but sometimes they get it right.
There's this thing called the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act in
the US that says I can't break into your phone.
Well, you can't,
but, but
a group working on behalf of the government could.
-- But here's the thing,
-- are they working on behalf of the government though?
Because it's also sounds like private clients,
not just that you have to work on behalf of the
government and you have to have a warrant for example,
to do this because if say the FBI put spyware on my phone
and they don't have a warrant to do it,
then that is almost definitely a violation
of.
I, I think the fourth amendment, I think the fourth amendment, yeah,
fourth amendment, which we talked about what, a couple of episodes ago with Chris.
But you know what I mean? It's that surveillance state
and I have a strong suspicion.
Everything going on here is, well, well,
outside of the realm of even discussing in polite circles
and, and this is part of what goes through this whole, well, you know,
maybe it's a necessary evil.
Well,
is it
like, have there actually been
e essentially, has this program, the negatives been outweighed by the positives?
Well, and the classic argument is like, oh,
we can't talk about the positives because they're so super secret.
I, I don't, I don't agree with that, let's, let's break this apart.
There's a lot, there's a lot to unpack here. I want to start with just
the,
the, the technical exploit
-- given what we know at this moment. So
-- it's, it's multiple exploits.
They essentially have like a stable of exploits that they use at scale.
And, you know, so once in a while, one or two of them get caught and they go on to the next
one.
and apparently one thing they've done is they've really upped their
game with their command and control and reporting back services because,
well, hold on, hold on.
You're, you're too far, you're too far. You've jumped to like step seven.
Let's start with how they're getting into these phones.
So what we understand at this point is obviously people have cell phones,
cell phones have security vulnerabilities.
These groups have stables of vulnerabilities. And so what they do is
they have a payload,
but they have to use a vulnerability to get the payload onto the phone.
And I know there is just recently been a fix for,
for iphones that it sounds like there was a what they call zero click
exploit for iMessage and zero click means a human doesn't have to do anything.
There are exploits that human might have to hit, ok?
Or a human might have to read the message or whatever.
And in this case, it was just send a message hack phone.
That's it. Right. Wait till the person goes to sleep.
-- They don't even know anything happened.
-- Well, and that's the beauty, right?
By definition, traditional tax where I send you an email, you have to open the email,
it's not parsed until you.
I have to get you to browse to a web page that explodes your browser
and oh my God, what a pain. That is. What if I could just send you a text message or an
iMessage? Right? And that's the thing to remember.
There's text messages, s MS text messages
and then there's
iMessage and
iMessage is all sorts of black magic on the back end with, you know,
Apple's systems and whatnot.
But the point is basically I send you an
iMessage
and whether you like it or not, your phone's parsing it.
That's
right.
And so
obviously, from an attacker's point of view,
Hazza,
right? I just fire off an
-- iMessage at you. And then 30 seconds later, I have a payload running on
-- your phone.
And now it should be noted that this is not a problem restricted just to
iMessage literally anything that processes
almost any kind of data
is going to be subject to this.
It's these push messages, apps like say whatsapp or signal or
you know, anything that accepts a message from a remote party.
I think 11 aspect being is a lot of these programs don't allow
random people to text you or to message you as easily as say,
iMessage does. So Yeah. So they basically, they push
an exploit towards you, your phone parses in and it hijacks your phone.
And what's really interesting to me is two things they've changed.
They, they no longer
appear to be getting persistence like they're
no longer compromising your system and modifying it
because here's the thing, if you reboot your phone or get a newer phone
while still gonna have probably an operating system with that
exploit and they just push the text message out again.
Sure. Right. So,
you know,
and this is one thing I always kind of thought about is
why do Attackers spend so much time getting persistence on a system
when, if the, if the system isn't patched to fix that flaw,
like if they reboot it or something,
you can just fire the attack again.
Well, that's assuming they don't update it. I mean, I, I think the, the issue being
that
every time you use an exploit,
you risk burning it because the right person might be paying attention
at the right time and all of a sudden you're done.
And so, I mean,
that's something you have to keep in mind if
you're doing some sort of co ordinated attack.
Yeah.
Well, and ironically, of course,
not getting persistence helps with that
because there's less to forensically examine.
I mean, potentially in this case, it sounds like they're dropping malware
and they don't have to
-- re exploit the device.
-- No, no.
If you, if you reboot if you turn your phone off and on it, kicks them out,
but they can just send the attack again.
Ok.
So, so
they're not modifying the system in any way, shape or form,
like on dis as it were in old.
I know which
-- I assuming
-- whatever, same thing,
chips,
chips all the way down.
-- I call them discs. And
-- what's interesting is,
well, that's the thing, right?
Is, is in past, like,
computers generally don't accept a message from
an untrusted source and fully parse it.
And this is a new,
like this is now a common use case because what
I I need to message with people and talk to them
like that's kind of the point of a phone originally was you remember
back in the olden days when we used phones to talk to people?
I, I remember that you'd use your voice. That was
lame.
Yeah. Uh
maybe we should convert this podcast to, to an emoji text stream.
It would just be poop
emojis
pretty much thousands of poop emojis.
So,
and then the next thing. So, OK, you've got a payload on a person's phone.
Now you gotta, we'll get some data out of there
to where you can go look at it. Traditionally, this was kind of noisy.
Apparently they were using, for example, among other things,
Amazon's cloudfront services because
everything talks to cloudfront at some point like games are using it, you know,
all sorts of apps use cloudfront for, for content delivery because, well, yeah,
I mean, you're gonna use cloudfront,
my
cloud flare, right. You're going to use one of those people.
And, uh, the good news is apparently Amazon kicked, uh,
NSO group off of their infrastructure.
That's what I hear.
Yeah, there's a big article about it,
but part of the problem is the NSO group has become
somewhat more sophisticated with using things like port knocking
and using other tricks to hide their command and
control services and to make them harder to detect
and conversely in doing that. Obviously,
if you do find it, it's, it's guaranteed that it's that, you know, nso group thing,
like there's no way somebody accidentally
created this wonky looking domain with this
like weird where you do a DNS request that opens a port,
you talk to the port, it opens another, you know what I mean?
Like this whole thing, it's
you,
you basically know that you found something malicious when you run across that,
I mean, sure. And so the good news there is is
possibly and hopefully, you know,
this results in fingerprints that the good guys can use to detect
when their systems are compromised and and then go deal with it,
right?
-- Well,
-- in, in. But ok,
so this is part of where I think the story becomes more interesting is
yes,
exactly that where the good guys can start looking for indicators of compromise,
be it on the device, be it, network traffic, whatever.
But the problem is just given the nature of this game,
the defenders always have to wait for the attacker to
make a move before they can react to it.
And so now we've reached the point where the pendulum
is swinging back towards the defenders in this case.
But that's it. It's unfortunate. Well, I guess it's not unfortunate.
It's just reality.
Yeah. And it always has to be like this.
And I mean,
the good news is Apple has done some sandbox around
iMessage using their blast door thing and that's the future.
There's, there is no way to build a piece of software
that parses a rich multitude of text and images and video
-- and have it be secure.
-- That's a, that's a,
there's so many layers here. It's so wild.
But the good news is
what I love Apple had a full dress panic. Right. That's what we want.
Like they pushed out a security update.
And do you remember what the update notes said? I didn't even look.
They basically, they said there's an update, install it. That's it.
We don't have time to write stuff down.
They probably didn't even exactly know what they were going to write.
I know how this works
and there's probably lawyers that want to approve things.
But so, ok,
I want to focus on what you said a bit ago,
which is that we're never going to
write secure software and these mitigating technologies are
kind of the future and I think that's a hugely important point and not something
that gets enough attention because these exploits come
out and we obsess over the exploit.
And then people are like, oh, this image library is garbage.
-- Oh, Apple is so dumb for using it this way. Well,
-- yeah, they all are.
What else are they
gonna use?
Exactly. All of the image libraries are terrible. It's just,
all of the libraries are terrible.
That's fair.
But anyway, the point is
there, there's always going to be an exploit in any software written by humans.
Like that's just the, the truth. Yeah.
And you can use memory safe languages like Rust and, and that'll help,
you'll get a lot of the loaf for Hanging Fruit.
It takes away buffer over
flows, it doesn't take away the million other security vulnerabilities. Exactly.
And so what happens is we know we can't fix the software and I
think we spent a long time obsessing over trying to fix the software.
And I think we've mostly given up. I think we still do.
Well, there's a lot of people who do, but I think generally speaking,
I think it's become hip to acknowledge this is just true. We cannot fix this.
So now it means we have to find another way to solve these problems.
And this is where some of these like sand boxing style technologies,
I think become a huge deal because Apple has this thing they've called blast door.
And unfortunately, so this is madness on I os
iMessage.
It's the equivalent of running his root is my understanding or it used to at least.
And so if you could basically hack into
iMessage, you own the.
And so they created this thing called Blast Star that was meant to sandbox
iMessage.
And my understanding is they don't have it like they
don't have the dial turned all the way on.
There's certain things, but which allowed this particular exploit to get through.
-- Hopefully they turn the dial way up.
-- Now,
you don't want to start twiddling those dials and breaking
-- iMessage for a half a billion people or a billion people.
-- I mean,
-- that
-- would
-- be a problem.
I know I'm not gonna, I'm not going to get into that discussion. There's I,
I'm sensitive to that discussion from every possible side of it
and it is not an easy answer. So anyway, the point is though they can't fix
iMessage. Let's just say that. So now you have to find a way to make
iMessage. Let's say somebody sends a malicious message.
You want to make sure
iMessage can't cause any damage.
And that is kind of where we're at
in the world of computers. Now.
Sandbox,
there's a second option too, which is
if you can detect something malicious happened
and either
deal with it or warn the user.
It's not ideal. Right.
I, I'm not saying that's what we want, but it's better than nothing. We're seeing
things where people log things because maybe they
can't prevent an attacker from getting in.
But, you know, Zhou shouldn't be doing this activity at 3 a.m. from China
and you can boot them out.
You know, you can prevent terabytes of data from being infiltrated or something.
-- You know, because an attacker broken, even if
-- they steal the data,
just knowing what happened
is
enormously valuable.
-- Knowing that something happened, you can warn your contacts. Right.
-- Yes, exactly.
Because I mean, there have been
one of my favorite examples of this is I remember back in, I mean,
this was probably 2004 or something.
There was some,
some like website, this is before github
even existed.
There was some website that was hosting a bunch of open source projects.
They got p
and they're like, we don't know what happened.
We don't know if anyone inserted malicious code
and it was like hundreds of projects.
It was, we're talking like,
I probably hundreds of thousands or millions of lines of code
and it kind of turned into like, uh
there's literally nothing anyone can do about this.
I, I guess we're all just going to go home now.
And it was terrifying to me of like,
I want to do something here, but there's nothing we can reasonably do.
I mean, this was before, like, because back in the day, well, back in the day,
we used to have this source management system called CV S and, like, now with get,
you do a, get checkout and there's hashes and everything.
And so, like, modifying a repo is actually really hard to do with CV S.
It was not hard to do it all. It only checked out the latest version.
And so, like, if someone modified it, there's no way you'd know it was wild.
Yeah. Well, I mean,
a,
yeah,
there's,
yeah.
Right. Right.
And I mean,
that's what happens is when you have an attack and you have
no logging or the attacker knows how to circumvent your logging.
You can be like, I think someone stole our data.
I have no idea if they did.
And now you have, you have that ethical decision of, do I, do I say,
do I assume the attacker has taken everything or
do I assume the attacker has taken nothing?
And I think it's, it's really easy to be like,
I don't think they took anything even though you have no evidence,
either way.
-- Well,
-- or worse. Did the attacker modify anything?
-- Yeah,
-- that's true.
I mean, that's less of a problem for a journalist. Cell phones.
Well, no, actually because for example,
they could change your contact phone number
so that when they phone that contact they're
actually phoning a proxy pass through service.
So I take that statement back. Yeah.
No, that modifying somebody's phone data could be horrifically damaging.
Yeah. Yeah. There's, I mean, who knows?
And,
and when you're talking about these sort
of well funded organizations like running a
proxy service that literally has someone on hand 24 7 to answer the phone.
Totally not out of the question.
I'm not sure that we need this kind of
technology because one of the other things is traditional.
A
lot of technology tends to be dual use like fire. I can use fire to make hamburgers,
which are delicious
And we can also use fire to burn down all the forests and cover the city in smoke,
which is less awesome.
Yeah, that's not delicious at all. Luckily it rained here last night.
So the air is actually kind of,
yeah, it's,
-- yeah, we've got about another what two months of smoke ahead of us, at
-- least,
-- maybe
-- more.
So
this is not a dual use technology, right?
This this technology has one use which is to spy on people
and now the problem becomes, it becomes an intent issue of, well,
hopefully they only use it to spy on the
-- right people
-- and that's such a dicey question.
I mean, so, ok, I want to start out by saying
that that spying on journalists I think is is ethically wrong under almost I don't
care if the journalist is is literally talking to the worst person on the planet.
It
is not right to spy on journalists,
like journalists are doing their job and sometimes
the journalist jobs to talk to bad people.
That doesn't make the journalist bad.
It doesn't mean you should get to spy on the journalist.
They are doing a valuable work
and by spying on them, you are destroying trust everywhere.
Well, the fifth estate, the press is one of the most important pillars of democracy.
Absolutely. Like, as we've learned from Facebook news,
I know
we need proper journalists who do research and verify sources
and don't, you know, republish Uncle Buck's memes as the truth.
Right. Right. Exactly.
Yeah, I, I just part of the frustration here is I read these stories and
there's really nothing you or I can do, even, even a group like citizen labs that,
you know, they have a lot of technology, a
lot of smart people
and it's super nontrivial.
Well, no, they're doing what they can, they're, they're,
they're explaining what's going on and,
and the knowledge of these events has immense value
from the aspect of now,
Apple can say this is a bigger deal than we thought
it was and people normal people can start to say,
ok,
this is something I need to be concerned with, especially if you are a journalist,
you understand that it is extremely likely that your phone cannot be trusted.
Not that I think anything can be necessarily if you're a target, but it's,
it's something you can keep in the back of your mind.
Well, I think my concern is that it's easy to monetize
spying.
Right. You just sell it to governments.
It's really hard to monetize security and privacy at this level.
Right. Because there's
like, there's billionaires who will pay for this kind of privacy. Like,
you know,
the, uh, well remember Obama's blackberry phone, right. That was a huge deal.
Right. Because they didn't want him to have a
blackberry. They, they
weren't sure that they could secure it properly
and no offense,
every blackberry user I've ever known.
Yeah. Trying to get that phone out of their hands. You're going to get hurt.
Like we call them crack berries for a reason.
Well,
there's also some other weirdness to the president having
a phone because every single thing the president writes
down in the United States goes into an archive
and then someday that archive gets opened up,
you supposed to is probably a big, big, big thing.
But you know what I mean? And so one of the concerns Obama staff had was that
him using a blackberry, he's going to write whatever they need to then log
everything he writes, collect it and then store it
and maybe we don't want everything he writes and in that case,
it was just easy to be like, just don't do this
and, and, and, and
honestly sometimes
just don't write this down
is exactly the right answer.
I feel like a lot of criminal lawyers spent a lot of time saying that
that seems to be the case from any time I watch anything a lawyer talks about
some sort of trial or case or whatever. It's like,
don't talk about this, don't write it down.
Like,
-- don't do this on the phone
-- just because you deleted your email and your
text messages doesn't mean they're not still on some server or the person's phone or
still on your phone.
Uh
But yeah, II,
I do worry because this obviously also has a chilling effect of, you know,
whistleblowers may not come forward to talk to journalists now because
right, if I was a whistleblower today, I would be horrified of,
of what could come next just because did they spy on the person I talked to,
do they know who I am?
Do they know what's going on?
And
I mean,
yeah, it would be,
it would be terrifying, you know.
Yeah,
I mean, the good news is, uh for example, the CBC
and this is in 2016. So they've been doing this for a while.
They adopted secure drop to allow for anonymous leaks.
Like it's getting to the point where news
organizations are having to adopt operational security that,
you know, was cold war levels of paranoia.
-- I mean,
-- kind of,
and again, if this kind of Pegasus spyware stuff was being used on, you know,
real major crimes, you know, real major world incidents
maybe, but we're talking things that are not major crimes or major incidents,
you know, we're talking environmental protests and human rights protests.
I
mean,
these aren't the criminals,
you know, if you're afraid of human rights people then maybe,
maybe you're the baddie.
Oh, my goodness. Yes.
You know what I always think of is, have you ever seen the LEGO movie?
I love the scene when they track
the, the lego people back to, what do they call it? Cloud cuckoo
land? I think it's called
and they, they bust through in bad cops. Like, it's the bad guys,
I think of that.
Like, some of these groups, like,
is that what it's like working there where it's just,
they know,
-- I, I don't know, I
-- wonder, I mean,
I live in Alberta and our premier spent $30 million on a provincial war room to combat
essentially falsehoods about the oil and gas industry.
Well,
did he spend it or did the oil
-- taxpayers
-- spent the money? And it's a private arm's length entity.
So it's, it's not subject to foia and all those other, you know,
freedom of information
act and all that other stuff. So,
and, you know, they, they, again,
they were doing things that target journalists and
environmental groups
and
I kind of feel like if they had access to this Pegasus stuff, they,
they might
use it.
-- I mean, I, I'd be shocked if they wouldn't.
-- Yeah.
Yeah. I don't know.
I just, part of the frustration is as a person,
I feel like there's not really anything I can do
other than, like,
literally I've been considering buying
a Guardian subscription to support because
they seem to do a lot of really good investigative reporting.
They, they do everyone who can afford to please support good honest journalism.
Any way you can be. It, lo local journalism is hugely important.
Like the Guardian is a great one to support.
There's, there's so many and the journalists are under such attack right now.
It's, it's difficult being a journalist for sure. I know many who have
left the field because they just, they burnt out and, and that's a shame.
Well, or they just can't make a living doing it.
Like I literally, there's an Albertan who's doing amazing online journalism
as far as I understand it privately, you know,
and I hope he's making ends meet with like Patreon.
Yeah,
I guess maybe the moral of the story is don't just donate to the
eff and the ac lu and whatever your local version of that entity is.
But yeah, find a reputable news source and buy a subscription.
I mean, that's part of the story for sure. But now more than that,
I, I think one of the questions.
So I've seen a lot of things online where people
are saying there's nothing you can do about this.
Like just go hide in the corner and cry
and
there is some truth to that. Like there is no way
that if the nso group wanted to target you or I,
that we could fundamentally stop them
when you are in a position
of say, a journalist
reporting on, let's say
drug dealers, your job is to talk to these bad guys, right? And, and
then we'll use the word bad guy loosely in some cases. But you know what I mean?
Like we, we'll say generally speaking,
you're going to be talking to people who are on the wrong side
of the law, whether you think the law is just or not.
Now,
when you enter a position where law enforcement uses
you as a stepping stone to get through,
they're putting you in danger, right?
Because that person's friends are going to come get you because did you,
did you tell them
or did they hack your stuff and steal it? Like they don't care?
Yeah,
-- I don't think they're going to be too concerned about the details
-- and like
that's one of those instances where you can talk about operational security and,
and segmenting services and using multiple devices or whatever.
But I mean, the reality is the vast majority of people lack the expertise to do that.
And I think honestly, even
if you did it, if you had a well funded knowledgeable attacker,
-- it really isn't going to
-- matter the time and resources to do this properly.
-- Like
-- I don't want to say that it's all doom and gloom and there's no way out of this.
I think the correct answer,
especially for people listening to this
particular podcast because the people listening are
going to generally have connections and skills that will say normal people do not
is we are now at a time when the
defenders are better understanding the layout of the game
and we now need to do things like better monitoring.
We need to have the ability to sandbox the
crap out of everything going on on these phones.
Like it's not a question of, are the bad guys doing this stuff like yes,
they absolutely are.
They're taking advantage of every single service running on your phone
and they're going to abuse it any way they can.
We need to sandbox everything, we need to segment all services.
And now the bad part of this
is the things I'm saying are going to take years to implement.
This is not something that oh, next week we could sandbox.
No, no, I'm talking about years of effort.
We're going to have to invent technologies.
We're going to have to invent process that doesn't exist today.
-- None of that is quick and
-- more so than that even mindset.
Like one thing I keep coming back to is this farm to fork idea for data,
you know that we're using for the universal vulnerability identifier thing,
not so much for security, but so so we can simply say we made a statement about X Well,
why did we do that?
Oh,
because of this data over here that we downloaded
from this web page at this date and time.
Ah.
Oh, and that's changed? Ok. It's wrong now.
You know.
And I think that's going to become increasingly important also,
the new style of ransomware attacks where, ok.
Health provider,
we've altered 20 patient records and for a couple of Bitcoin
we'll tell you which ones and what we did to them.
Yeah. That's right.
So, it's not just
we, we need a changing mindset of,
we,
we can't just keep applying more patches to our
image libraries that's not going to make us secure.
But I think things like blast
door and one thing I'm really intrigued by is these low power budget arm CP us.
You know,
if you can start running stuff on a dedicated CPU where there's no side channels
and for example, you pass them to the CPU,
you know, data, a package to be rendered
and it passes something back out.
You know,
you maybe don't have to care what happened in there as long as
what comes out is like a validly formed J peg or something.
I mean, maybe things like that.
I I think that but,
but that kind of stuff just was not possible like 10 years ago if you
said K like I want you to dedicate ac pu to processing an image,
I'd be like, no, that's stupid,
you know, but now with arm CP US and you have half a dozen or more CP US.
Yeah, things like this will be possible and,
and I suspect this is kind of where we have to go is to this
massively sandboxed, well-defined inputs and outputs
because what's happening in the sandbox is going to be a train wreck always.
Well, you should assume it's literally malicious and, and I mean,
that's one of the things that really can change your mind and,
and we should probably just do a whole new show on this at
some point because I don't want to get into all the details today,
but like when you literally have in your brain, all right,
let's assume
that an attacker can literally run whatever they want in this environment.
What now?
And it really, it, and if you assume that of every function call,
of every service call of everything you do is saying when I call this library,
I'm going to assume an attacker has full control
and they get to decide what comes back to me what is
now now that's going to change the way you think about it.
But anyway, uh this holy crap,
I feel like I feel like I just got punched in the face after talking about this one.
It's just it, it's so infuriating and so upsetting and so obnoxious.
-- It's,
-- I
just keep coming back to the fact that every time we go through this,
we have a huge pile of court decisions saying that yes, they did the wrong thing,
-- but then they just keep doing it and
-- they're going to keep doing it.
I mean,
look that the intelligence services have been doing acting like this forever.
They're never going to change.
It is the job of the courts and the
citizenry to remain and the press to remain vigilant
and kind of try keeping the, the stuff reined in.
And of course, that the fact that they're directly targeted the press,
I think makes the job even harder now for a variety of reasons.
But, I mean, fundamentally, I guess no, this is the thing we can do.
There is something we can do.
What we can do is we can
make sure our elected representatives understand what's going
on and we can make sure that we hold them accountable and say this is wrong
while we can't fix the technology today,
we can at least hopefully fix some of the things going on in the government.
And that's easier said than done
because
it is going to be extremely difficult,
I think to convince many of these people that this is something they
-- should even think about still
-- can't get half of everybody to vote.
-- I know, I know also vote. Voting is another great thing you can do today. Please
-- vote.
Yeah. And even if you just spoil your ballot, you know, at least you vote.
You made a statement, you were counted,
just pick the one who's less of a horrible person. Maybe like, I don't know, there's,
that's what I feel like voting is like,
I'm going to pick the person who I feel like would only be a minor evildoer in the,
in the story, not the main evildoer.
Like, oh my goodness. Anyway,
this is, this is a lot, man. This is, this one's heavy.
I don't,
I'm sorry,
everyone who had
to listen
to us.
Oh, and I think this really speaks to keep your devices up to date.
I mean that too. But that's, yeah, that's just good advice no matter what.
All right.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com.
We'll put a bunch of stuff in the show notes, C A
Podos podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt
have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the