Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurtz Siefried and my partner and just discussing all sorts of things.
-- Josh Presser. That's literally what
-- we do.
-- Well, we just came up with two shows before the show. We
-- did.
-- I know and we got into a marvelous argument. I would say
-- an argument.
-- It's a classical argument.
-- I consider every one of our discussions an argument
a
classical,
which is great because like both of us end up changing our mind or more often than not.
-- Oh, this is actually worse than we thought. Yeah,
-- that's the sad truth sometimes.
But that complexity is the thing, right?
Like a lot of people don't want to embrace or understand
complexity. They're just like, why can't this be simple?
Well, because it's not, it's like,
it's like every time I see an economics discussion and I'm like,
economics is hard. Like people are complicated,
money supply M two M one, I don't know,
we can't just simplify this.
It's complicated because there's so many people involved.
And which is a perfect example.
Today we're gonna talk about passwords and passwords
are horrifically complicated to get even remotely,
right.
-- In
-- a very specific context
and even that is complicated.
The 23 and me story has been bananas to say the least. But I think the most interesting
point of discussion from it all
is the 23 and me leadership are saying
all the people who got hacked had terrible passwords, it's not our fault.
And then you read stories that were written about this and
there are security people saying 23 and me are a bunch of idiots. Absolutely not.
And there's other people that are like,
-- yeah, how do you defend against crap
-- passwords? So the answer is 23 three and me
is completely correct
and
-- 23 and me is also completely wrong.
-- Well, thanks for coming everyone.
You're welcome.
So here's the beauty. It again, this is complicated. So,
well, let's start with a bit of disclaimer. So I am a 23 and me customer from ages ago.
So I'm your information has been stolen. No, it has not because
this is a perfect example.
I'm a security privacy minded jerk who doesn't like sharing,
right? So I don't, for example, share my genetic profile.
You didn't click the button. I see.
Are you insane?
But that's the thing.
People do click that button because they do want to share and they do want to like, oh,
you have that gene for the asparagus thing or for the diabetes thing.
And you're my second cousin removed. And oh, you also did perfect example,
there's a genetic health problem in my family that like
I had to go get a camera up my butt.
-- Me,
-- everyone our age has to do that. That's
not at the age of 4050
-- you know,
-- it's
45 for colonoscopies here now.
Well, it's,
you know, it was anyways.
But the point is like this can actually be really useful
information to know that can save your life because for example,
my mom is still alive because she got prompt treatment.
You know, it is nice. I would miss her.
So this is the complexity of. So here's the problem. Fundamentally,
passwords can be very weak. You can choose a weak password like 1234,
right?
You can also reuse a password which is then exposed and not only
do I know your password potentially through the breach at another site,
but I know that email associated with it.
So now I'm gonna try, you know Joshua
press
net
and the password of whatever your dog's name is
plus your kid's birthday because you posted that on social media.
-- For example,
-- my dog's name is Atlas. So there you go. Now everyone can do
-- me on all the sudden.
-- The problem is passwords can be very weak
and here is where things get complicated.
You can
make them very strong
from both the user's perspective and the provider's perspective that right.
So the user, for example,
can use a password manager and generate a very strong random password for each site.
So even if it gets breached, no big deal, it's just that one
password, right? It should be used anywhere else.
So that is on the user to then be secure that
there's degrees of this.
So for example, when you cross the road,
you need to look both ways and if you don't look both ways that's on you.
But using a password manager and unique passwords,
that's a little bit more sophisticated and complicated and it,
it's very sophisticated for normal people.
I, I feel like that is outside of the
realm of possibility for at least 80% of the population.
And in fairness,
companies like Apple are trying to make it easier like in on an Apple mobile device.
Now it will suggest
do you want to use a strong password and then it will generate one in store it.
And really like, what more can we do?
We can't really force people to use password managers.
Well, we, we can't use passwords like obviously,
-- but
-- I was about to say again, it's complicated in that.
Yeah, actually we can force people to use password managers
because for example, the provider,
the site could assign you such a horrifically long, complicated password,
but you can't remember it and that you're forced to write it down,
-- but they
-- won't do that because that's going to create a cost
for the provider because people aren't going to write it down or
run into one or two that do that. And I was pretty impressed.
So, again, this talks to the complexity of it. So, let's assume. Ok.
So basically what the user can do is strong password hygiene,
use a password manager.
And like we agree that that's,
that's like people who use their turn signals, it's not going to be everybody.
No, I'm serious. Right.
We can't even get people to use their damn turn signals. I know for sure.
Please turn your headlights on at night and by night, I mean,
anything past 430 here where I live in winter.
No, I'm serious. Like I
know
-- it was brutal last night it was snowing and it was dark and it
-- was no,
no headlights are a great example.
Right? Because how many times have you started driving?
And someone flashed their lights at you and you're like, oh crap,
I forgot to turn my headlights on.
Literally never because part of my checklist for getting in my car is making sure the
knob is turned all the way to automatic and making sure the lights are on.
It happens. It's happened more than once. Not a lot, but it's happened.
Everyone does this, right.
This is a really good comparison I think because my suspicion is the vast majority of
people without headlights on at night did not
intend to not turn their headlights on.
They just forgot because the kid yelled at them or whatever. Right.
There's a million things that can happen.
And I think it's the same story with passwords
is no one wants to use a crappy password.
They just don't know better or they forgot or they accidentally did something or,
-- or they're not able to, they have a bad memory. Sure.
-- Sure. There's
reasons.
-- Right. I,
-- I have a son with autism. He
can't really remember passwords. I thank God for biometrics.
-- Right.
And, you
know,
there
is man, I feel like blaming users in this context is ridiculous.
I would agree because
there is not only I would say the obligation for the provider,
especially a provider handling your genetic data,
which is kind of, I think we'll all agree a little bit sensitive,
especially if you ever want to get insurance because I would agree.
For example, in the US,
there's a specific law saying an insurance
carrier cannot deny you coverage based on genetic
testing.
I don't have that law in Canada.
I'm shocked usually Canada is way ahead of us, but
-- I don't have to worry about health insurance.
-- That's
so that's a good
point.
If anything,
your genetic data being in the hands of the the medical system is a benefit,
-- not a negative,
-- right.
I would say not only does 23 me sort of have
a moral and ethical obligation to keep customers data safe.
Are simple technical controls to do so.
And I'm gonna read them because this is in my mind if you are going to support
user names and passwords, number one, what is the data for?
Like if it's like, let's say it's the circle platform at the CS A,
it's our social media platform for intersect discussion.
Yeah, that's not super sensitive. It's all public anyways, right?
Like, so if somebody breaks in your account like, yeah,
it's gonna be kind of annoying but like they're not gonna get you genetic data,
right?
So the first thing is kind of what are the, what is the risk level like if it is it,
is it a crypto brokerage or your genetic data or is it like, you know,
for?
So number one, I think we can all agree that 23 me is handling sensitive data.
-- It's pretty high on the, I don't want this out
-- list. Exactly.
That's the first thing is what is the risk level and it's high,
very high like damn near 10 out of 10.
So this means that I think they have an obligation to do everything possible.
And the thing is there are some very reasonable
and simple things you can do as a provider.
So number one
is they should support single sign on and pass
keys
and
I
passwords and email are an option but should be discouraged.
And, and I also want to point out that
23 and me isn't like some five
person start up,
right? This is a real big company.
-- This is a high
-- tech company that does fast genetic sequencing. Like
-- come
-- on.
Even even that honestly, like it's so easy to use single sign on now.
Even if you're a five person start up, you can make it happen.
It's not like it's not like five or 10 years ago where you needed like a
-- team of 10 people to get sso to work
-- and going back to what's complicated.
I would also say on the flip side, if you are a major provider that provides some
sign in,
you should also be obligated to provide email and password login because
some people do not want to or cannot use single sign on.
So
moving along
number two, if you're providing passwords,
you should also support two fa and I mean strong
two fa not S MS but like hardware tokens,
Fido
all that stuff.
Number three, if you are still then providing user passwords and user names,
and we're going to assume the user is not sophisticated.
So they're not doing single sign on, they're not doing pas keys,
they're not doing a hardware token, they're not doing two factors
authentication.
Then any time a user sets a password,
you need to check it against the have I've been PS list and if it's in there,
you don't get to use it.
I, I would agree with that.
Let me ask, did you, did you make this list up or did you get this from somewhere?
I made this list up
this is a topic I've actually been thinking about off and on for a very long time
because I wrote that pas
keys paper and I've spent a lot of time
thinking also about the social implications of authentication.
Because
to put it bluntly, if you make authentication truly secure, you're going to lock out
a lot of vulnerable people are not gonna be able to use your service for sure.
Full stop.
So again, it's these degrees. So
if you're gonna offer just a pure user name and password,
you need to
check how I've been ped
-- and not let them set that password
-- probably.
-- Yeah, I'm ok with that
-- if it's a high security application.
So a perfect example, Shake pay just got also breached. I use Shake pay. Lucky me.
I'm just hitting everybody today
is Shake.
Shake is a crypto exchange in Canada.
I'm pretty sure it's you guys in Toronto in an apartment building or condo
maybe three. They seem legit
ish.
Uh
Anyway, this is not obviously this is not like an endorsement of their product,
the
opposite. So they got breached
oopsy doodle.
But here's the thing when I log into shake pay,
I enter my user name and password.
And then I get a thing saying, oh, you know, I don't recognize this IP address,
go check your email
and I have to go check my email for a four digit code
and then plug that in.
So,
yeah,
so,
um, if you are using just pure password and email. Then
in a high security application,
I think you have an obligation to send an email saying
like you're trying to log in from a new IP.
Is this you? Yes, cool. If it's not, you
either ignore this or maybe click this button so that we can like,
panic a little bit on your behalf.
Uh Yeah. You know what's funny about that? So I like once a week
I get
uh a Facebook reset
uh email and they do have a button that says this wasn't me on the bottom,
-- which I appreciate because because
-- now we know that IP address is a bad actor
and that, I mean, that's not foolproof because for example,
I was actually trying to browse the web on a web blog on
my phone and it said basically you're using a VP on your block.
And I'm like, well, yeah, I'm on my mobile phone.
So obviously I'm coming from one IP address
that represents like essentially everybody in Alberta,
you know, using tell us which is like
a lot of us. So crap. I got to go on my desktop.
But I would say these are the minimum things you need to do.
And now having said that if you check the, have I been pulling password,
people will basically be forced
to pick a
stronger password that by definition has not really
been seen in a public breach yet,
which is I mean, there's billions of passwords in there.
So it's going to be pretty good.
And I would say a further thing that I didn't write down on the list is that
you should
offer people an instructional page on
how to use
the password managers that are built into their devices and software.
So for example,
a
link to here's Apple,
here's the link to the Apple page talking about how to use Apple password storage.
Here's a link to the chrome one,
here's a link to the whatever like because I'll be blunt,
how hard is it to do user agent detection and be like, oh,
you're coming from a mobile Apple device.
If you want to learn more about saving your
passwords securely go to the Apple website here.
And so I'm saying that the,
the the the provider of that service does not tell the customer what to do.
They simply say to the customer look, you appear to be using an Apple device,
go to Apple and learn about this if you want to.
I I think there is somewhat of an obligation to start trying to educate people and to,
I don't know about that one. I don't know about that one.
I, I think you run into two problems there that companies aren't going to want.
First of all,
you have the issue of endorsement where if you send people to Apple there,
it's gonna be claimed you're endorsing Apple as like
-- coming
-- from an Apple device. I mean,
you're not wrong.
I'm just saying like this is a legal
concern.
No.
And then I think the other piece of this is by encouraging password manager
use in people who may have never heard of a password manager before.
You're going to, without question,
increase the number of support requests you
get for password resets because people aren't
going to understand what they're doing and
they're going to accidentally lose that password.
Yeah.
And, and
that,
but, but from
that
-- to some degree,
-- well,
it'll probably be higher and companies don't want to spend money on this.
So the business people are going to be like, don't do this.
It's going to cost us more money.
And so what's interesting to me is looking at all this,
I would also pause it. There's a, there's 1/4 thing.
Now, I, again having said this, I say this very carefully.
I think we have an obligation
to,
I don't want to say force.
I, I don't want to use the word force but to strongly,
strongly encourage people to use pass keys
with the proviso
that we still need to support emails and
passwords because not everybody can use past keys.
I don't want to walk people
-- out just because, you know, they don't have an up to date phone or whatever.
-- Right.
Right.
I, I won't disagree with that.
I mean, I think past keys are really cool and they solve a lot of problems.
But unfortunately, I bet if we did a poll of, like,
randomly selected humans on the planet and ask them how many have heard of pass Keys.
It's probably less than 5%.
I would go with 0.05%.
No, I'm serious. Like, it would be less than 100,000.
And here's the other thing,
this all ignores the reality and the reality is
the people most likely to have chosen a bad password
and be in a breach and so on have bad passwords.
They're use, they're reusing that password everywhere.
And these are the kind of people that are going to be
least amenable to change because if they were amenable to change,
they
would have. And so this
now comes incumbent on 23
for example, to detect credential stuff.
So these are called credential stuffing attacks where I get a breach.
I got a list of emails, I got a list of passwords they used elsewhere.
I'm literally just gonna try stuffing them into 23 and me and see what happens.
And here's where I would say 23 and me is really gonna struggle
is that they could have detected that and could have dealt with it
and they did not.
And you want an example of a site that actually dealt with this really well,
Bricklin.
So Bricklin is a Lego, it's like it's like an online
exchange for selling and buying LEGO,
buy the piece or buy the pound or whatever specific pieces, you know,
you can search by country or shipping and cost
Lego actually bought
Bricklin, uh, about a year
and
I was terrified because I'm like, God, I love Bricklin
and like, when I need those pieces, you know, for the thing
and they haven't screwed it up, they've actually made it better
yet.
Well, it's been a year and a half, like,
you know,
but the point is Brick link sent me an email one
day saying we apologize but we've locked all the accounts.
Ok. That's it basically.
And then three days later they sent an email saying,
ok,
here's what happened. Credential stuffing basically. So we locked everything
and we did a bunch of forensics and everything and you're not affected.
Hold on when you mean everything. You mean like every customer they have, they
understand they
walk my account, my account password is
strong because like they locked, yeah, they just locked everything.
I mean, that's
I applaud the
will
to do that.
Yeah,
-- so that's the thing, I'm sorry. But if a lego exchange can do this properly, I
-- mean,
for sure. And look,
the reality is if you're a proper company handling sensitive
data and even if you're not handling sensitive data,
like you should be doing these things,
there are a ton of technologies that exist today you can use
to watch for credential stuffing and data scraping and all of this sort
of activity they should have lit up a dashboard like a Christmas tree.
And let's, and, and
you're gonna be really impressed with it. This is from the Bricklin email.
There is no evidence to suggest that your Bricklin account has been compromised.
However, as a precaution, we're asking you to update your password.
Please go to the Bricklin site and start the process
of resetting your password by following the prompts during login.
Awesome. Make sure you use a unique password which you don't use on other sites.
We're sorry for the inconvenience and disruption caused by the site being down.
We're taking this incident very seriously
and want to assure you that we're committed to doing
all that we can to ensure this doesn't happen again.
Like to put it bluntly. Oh and yeah, it gets better.
We've taken steps to further strengthen our
security and we'll continue to investigate and take
a step to tighten how we monitor and respond to unusual activity like I'm sorry,
but Bricklin handled this perfectly 100%
like straight up. Perfect. Like this is Olympic gold medal levels of infosec. Yep.
Yep.
So come on 23. Me,
I mean, you could
sort lots of companies like,
yeah, but like for 23 and me not just to handle this poorly but to then go with, hey,
you know what?
Let's try blame the user
because they don't want a class action lawsuit and even better
when I haven't logged in yet intentionally because now when you log in,
you're being asked to agree to the new terms of service,
which it's got a weird little arbitration clause
at 23 and me.
-- Yeah, they changed
-- their
course
and most companies are trying to move
away from arbitration because it's expensive.
But arbitration is probably less expensive when you do have
-- the very real potential of a class action lawsuit.
-- Arbitration is funny
because didn't, was it
Uber or someone where the drivers abused arbitration to
actually cost them like an insane amount of money?
It's expensive because Uber has to pay for it.
So a lot of them are trying to move away from it and be like, you have to file in like the,
you know, the, the Sioux County lower Court of blah, blah,
blah and some middle of the nowhere place
that's like closed except for Tuesdays between two and three in the morning
and they, they bought off the judge. So
there's nothing to worry about.
-- Like,
-- I'm sorry, but here's the thing, like if this was some hypothetical or some,
like in a vacuum thing, like, ok, 20
need to handle this wall. But no, this is not some hypothetical. This is a well known,
like,
have I been
ped, has been around for what, 10 years now?
Five years?
It's older than that.
-- Well, I
-- mean, with the service where you can actually check passwords and stuff.
Yeah. Oh, the check password service? That's a couple of years at moment. So
this is, this is not like, oh, like this is not an Apple zero day where like they spent,
you know, how much money researching a zero day chain.
This is like kid in the basement level attack.
Yeah,
that's exactly what this is.
And,
and then conversely
there are sites that
handle this really well, like Bricklin
look like.
So I'm sorry, but like there's, this isn't some,
like this isn't some hypothetical gold standard of
information security where it's like hard to achieve.
No, if Bricklin can do this
23 and me can do this, they can spend a bit of money.
I don't think that's the argument I would use in this context.
-- Well, it's one of the arguments, I
-- mean, sure. But look, I think
what this reminds me of when we kind of lay
it all out and obviously people blaming people and,
and whatever is
when you are a business,
you have to make a decision to spend money
on
reducing the level of risk you have. And this is across your entire business, right?
This isn't just like it and, and information
-- and
-- actually managing
risk. Sure. Right.
Like locks on the doors,
like where are we renting buildings if you rent your
office in the most crime ridden part of town,
like yes,
you're going to have a different set of problems and if you rent
an office in the very expensive part of town that does zero crime.
You know, there's like there's all these pieces to this.
And so what I mean, what fundamentally happened here is 23 and me
pretty clearly has cheaped out on security is what I'd say.
And now they have to try to pick up the pieces
that, to be blunt is assuming that they have any security.
-- That's a good point
-- because no, we've, we don't know that they have a security team.
-- We know nothing about the internal security at 23 and me,
-- it could be a guy.
-- It might be, I don't know.
-- And that's the thing.
And this is the part of the problem with security is like, uh, I'm going to pick on me.
Cloud security lines basically is one kind of security.
It, operations person mostly, which is me
and, well, but that's kind of cheating because I'm a Donk. Right.
Like I have been doing this for a long time and I get free rein to, like,
everything goes by in Cloud Flare.
What is a Donk
from the, the movie Crocodile Dundee? This sounds like a dirty word.
So the, the, the Colombian drug dealers go to Australia to assassinate Crocodile
D,
right.
And they go up to that, you know, the little guy drinking beer on the beach
and the guy's like, I've got a gun and the little guy's like, yeah, cool.
I've got a Donk and the guy's like,
what's a Donk and a Donk is a 6 ft five guy who bashes you in the head and knocks you out.
-- I don't remember
-- this.
Right.
-- The guy's name is Donk. Are you sure
-- this is Crocodile Dundee.
Yeah,
it's the second, uh, the first one, right?
Because they is, it, I don't remember anymore anyways. But,
but that's the thing, right? A lot of places have a Donk
and have shockingly good security based on one or two or a small team of people.
And then there's large companies where it's like,
how on earth have you? Not like a, how did you get your pants on this morning?
-- I'm not clear on that, but b how would you not burnt the building down
-- yet?
I mean, look, there's also many aspects of this.
Like I have,
I have seen instances where like internal security
was just blatantly lying to upper management.
Right. There's,
there's a lot of challenges in this space and
you have instances where you get a third party office
and if people know how to work the auditor, you can get by with terrible security.
Like there's, there's so many dials on this machine
and like, we don't know what 23 and me story,
they're never gonna tell us because they're gonna get sued no
-- matter what we
-- do know for sure that they have bad security
because they didn't
agree
with that.
That
is reasonable.
They did not detect and block the attack.
They did not use the, have I been P password
thing.
The only thing you need to know about this attack is they blamed the users,
which means the lawyers wrote that release not the security team
because every time lawyers write something,
the sole intent of that communication is reducing
our risk and pushing it somewhere else.
That is like the job of a lawyer
in that context.
Like that's the famous Supreme Court decision
here in Canada where saying I'm sorry,
does is not an admission of guilt.
That's right. That's right. Which I love.
Yeah,
very Canadian.
It is.
Well, I mean, what I love is, for example,
I remember one time I bumped into a cop at a coffee shop,
like we were both sort of backing up and we both said sorry at the same moment.
Nice.
Well, anyway, so sorry, I just logged into 23 and me
and uh they now, for example, are saying,
like I just clicked on single sign on to see what happens.
I actually use user name, password.
But it says basically, do you want to sign in with Google or I'll keep my password?
I'm gonna keep my password.
So I'm gonna click and sign in with my
Oh, here we go.
As an added security measure,
we're requiring that all customers choose a new
password to unique 23 and me to proceed,
please reset your password.
So they are forcing a password reset, which to me says
I would do that no matter what, in this particular instance?
-- Well,
-- but they didn't get into 23 and me's database or anything they got into
user accounts. I
know.
But this is a good,
I think it is a good behavior for an organization like
23 and me to do because I think it helps signal.
We're taking this seriously.
We're making everyone change their passwords because we don't know for sure
who has a crap password.
Of course, it doesn't mean people are going to set good passwords.
-- But
-- actually, let's see if I can choose a bad password.
-- One second, I don't know, set of crap
-- password set like password. 123, four.
Ok.
It said
this password is too short. It must contain at least 12 characters.
This password is too common. Ok, let's try password. Uh, hang on a sec.
Let me just cut and paste because I'm tired of typing.
I, I tried password 123 and it didn't let me do that nice.
So pass. Let's try capital P word,
123 and 123. So capital password. 123 with shift and then 123.
Oh,
it took that. It'll take bad passwords.
They are definitely not using,
make sure you change that back now.
Yeah, I'm gonna actually hang on a sec reset password.
But yeah, it'll let you pick a very poor password.
It's just, it has to be more than 12 characters long.
Uh,
hang on one second. Let me see if I can pick something truly terrible.
-- This email confirms that you've changed your Oh, yeah. Yeah. Ok.
-- That's,
-- that's nice. Here's
-- the new reset link. Ok. I'm gonna try
just password password.
Let me set a password of password, password with capital PS
in, in both PS.
Yeah,
that's like the worst password ever. Well done.
So, I'm sorry. 23 me fails.
No. Come on, this is
I'm very glad
they don't have any of my data.
I mean, look, none of this surprises me
because no, no, no, I just want to try my email as my password.
Oh, that's a good one.
Because if they let me set my email as my password, then we know that they, that's true
is what that is.
The password is too similar to the email address. Ok, let's try
fried one
with the number one.
No, it didn't let me do that. Ok.
So it will not let me set my email address as a password,
-- but it
-- will accept
password password.
I mean, look, it is clear that
23 and me has some security issues internally. So none of this surprises me.
-- Oh, wait,
-- I need 12 characters.
Ok. So
123, basically 1234567890123.
And that, that work. This password is entirely numeric is too common. Ok, let's try
pass.
We have,
we're not going to sit here while you try
every combination of passwords you can think of.
-- We know their password form, accepts crap password.
-- It took password 1234567
-- with
-- a lowercase.
Well done,
well done.
Hats off to you, sir. Ok.
Let me just actually set my password to something good now,
so you don't log into my account because,
or somebody else logs into my account because that's a pretty
good password.
I love it
also.
There's no apparently limitation on me resetting my
password multiple times in a few minutes.
Oh,
except now I'm not getting the reset link.
no, I didn't. Ok.
I
see.
But in my opinion,
if somebody resets their password like four or five times in a minute
-- that should flag something.
-- I mean, I would think so. It's often not
clearly
affected behavior.
They're testing something or they're a bad guy maybe. But,
ok, anyway, anyway,
I want us to kind of bring this one home and we're going to stop listening to you,
-- change your
-- password.
Ok. There, I changed something secure.
I feel like
this is
just the universe we live in now
where organizations have to deal with this kind of crap because
even if you're a company that does genetic testing,
like you're in the information security business now, that's it.
There's, there's no other option.
-- Bosch
-- makes nice tools and dryers and washers and stuff, that drill thing,
the torque drills that are uh IOT devices essentially So, for example,
you can remotely set and calibrate and measure
all these screws were torqued correctly, which that's important for a lot of stuff.
Like if you over to
something,
well, if you over to
something, you can break it.
If you under torque it,
-- the screw falls out
-- as we have seen with an airplane incident recently say
somebody found like, what was it? 27 vulnerabilities in these things.
So you could remotely compromise it.
And for example,
reset the torque value so that you're not torquing stuff tight or too tight.
So it breaks early.
And that's the other thing is there is a lot of
health and human safety and sensitive data that is online now.
And yeah, these companies need to do better
and the fact is
it's not that
I'm sorry, but like
Apple is dealing with crazy zero days with people who have millions of dollars
23 and me is failing when people set their password to password 1234567.
And I think that's it.
That's all I have to say.
Well, look, here's ok. I think the Bosch example fits in nicely with this.
The reality is,
let's say five or 10, maybe 20 years ago, you could be a product company
and not need to know anything about information security or it in general, right?
That was fine. You could exist like that. That is not the world we live in today.
Everything's connected
you can make the argument
that it's not right that every company has to be a security
wise company
to exist in the universe. And I won't disagree with that.
I think it's too easy to screw this stuff up and that's a different conversation.
But the reality is where we exist today. If you are a company
with,
we just say a product and I'll use the
term product loosely to denote like things or services.
You have to be security aware because if you're not, this is going to happen to you.
But now here's the other piece of this to think about.
-- So Bosch and 23 and me had security incidents
-- and Bosch seems to be handling a, well,
Bosch is committed to updates by the end of
the month which for a software company that's ok
regardless
at the end of the day,
if they, if, if, when you look at the math,
if doing nothing about security and just paying the fines or,
or whatever was cheaper than actually having good security,
they're gonna say that was a good business decision.
And so that's part of the problem is today,
that is a conversation a company can have
because there are often little to no negative
outcomes for them
when this stuff happens because maybe 23 and me will get sued.
Maybe they won't, maybe they'll get fined, maybe they won't,
I don't know how this is gonna happen,
but a good security team is expensive. Right? How expensive is crappy security.
We don't know yet.
-- And
-- actually I would say it's more subtle now, it's not just if you produce a product,
but if you use stuff to produce a product, for example,
you might be producing an entirely mechanical device like AAA wood plane.
And if you're using those Bosch
internet capable torture wrenches,
you could be over tightening screws and like damaging products.
So it all fails earlier or the screws fall out and people get hurt or whatever.
And then an extreme case would be like, yeah,
if you're using these things to install door plugs in airlines,
then getting the torque wrong on those screws
has very significant downside potentially.
And that's the other thing is it's,
it's not just enough. If you're producing a product,
it's if you're, now, if your supply chain
uses any of these things, if you're using them directly.
And this is,
I mean,
essentially this is everybody that's like everybody
has an IP capable H VAC system because
like, well, that's just how they are nowadays
and that's how Home Depot got broken into, for example, right.
They got into the H VAC system at Home Depot and
then into the Home Depot Network and the credit card stuff.
And so I think the reality is
basically everybody has to have an information security team now or
they really need to start like,
outsourcing this stuff to somebody who's trustworthy.
Like I don't do. Well, I'm not going to build a system to manage my cash.
I keep it in a bank. I pay a bit of money for it.
That's just like, and that's what most businesses do. Most businesses even casinos
avoid handling cash as much as they can because it's such a pain.
But now we're going,
now this opens a conversation about how do you find enough people?
You know who's like, how do you tell if the MS sp is competent or like a bunch of morons
-- and
-- you can't outsource your drills like you need to have on premises drills
and yeah. Does an MSP P manage them or something like? Right.
It's complicated.
That's a conversation for another day.
I suspect I want to call this one because I don't want to drag on too long,
but like 23 and me failed.
That's it. And they continue to fail.
That's what really upsets me
the fact that they let me set those poor passwords. That's it is sad.
Like if you're a lawyer
just email me and Josh,
we'll explain why this is so terrible in terms that the jury can understand.
I'm staying out of this.
Yeah, but like straight up, this is just like, I'm sorry, Bricklin gold star,
gold medal
23 and me,
you continue to disappoint him.
What is it? My, my disappointment is immeasurable and my day is ruined.
Check how he's doing.
Steve was just eating 100 plus year old crackers and
they were edible because it was just flour and water.
There was no shortening.
I got a couple of tins of World War One biscuits
-- and they were edible.
-- I don't think I want to watch that.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to
security podcast.com hit.
The sh
T
Podos
says podcast hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.
Ok.