-- Security podcast with myself, started talking
-- too late.
Which is ironic actually because it's unlucky 13th, December 13th.
I do love how that's such a strong thing in, in our culture that, like,
I don't think I've ever seen a building with 1/13 floor
-- outside.
-- I saw one once actually and I forget where I was.
It may have been Europe. Yeah, I,
I do recall
pointing it out and being like,
I have never seen a button 13 on an elevator before and then I of course,
did not go there
anyway. So, what are we talking
about?
There was this thing about the, the world's most,
like, unluckiest man.
And he's been, uh, in a train crash, a plane crash in a car crash, just a whole pile of,
you know, bizarre, terrible thing.
-- I mean,
-- is that unlucky or is
-- I
-- was kind of thinking about that,
you know,
car crashes? Ok. That happens plane accidents. Well, they're,
but not, you know, the, the miracle over the Hudson. Right.
There's a, you know, these things do happen and people survive them.
Right. But it just got me thinking of all the people.
Well,
the only reason we know he's the unluckiest man in
the world is because so far he survived everything.
He's not dead.
And it just got me thinking about, you know, how many people,
like fell out of a tree and just whack their head the wrong way.
And that's it.
I, I know someone that happened.
He was an elderly gentleman, trimming a tree and fell out of the tree
-- and that was all you're
-- supposed to use a ladder or hire
an arborist if it's more than 20 ft off the ground.
-- Look,
-- I'm old enough. I'm not climbing in a tree to cut it like,
yeah,
just honestly just don't because the professionals have safety equipment
and they're not going to fall out of the tree,
-- like
-- for real.
And if they follow the tree,
it's them falling out of the tree and they usually wear a helmet.
No, seriously, that's what always got me right. They're tied to the tree.
But also like, what, what always gets me is, you know, as a child,
we never wore helmets, skiing and snowboarding.
Only the ski race team wore helmets, you know,
and nowadays it's under 18 is required to wear a helmet at the ski hill.
But under 18 is required, adults are not required to wear a helmet at the ski hill. So,
well,
it's like you see people riding bikes with their
kids and they make their kids wear a helmet,
but the adults aren't wearing a helmet
All right. Let's, let's warp this into a
survivorship bias conversation because I think that's what it is.
Tell us what survivorship bias is. Yeah.
-- So
-- survivor, survivorship bias is the simple fact that,
well, the people who survive, get to tell their story
by a,
-- I,
-- I didn't wear a helmet when I was a kid and I was just fine
except for all those kids who aren't just fine because they got run over by a car.
And that's what I mean. It's interesting to me. I,
I had a broken bone as a kid. Pretty much everybody I knew as a kid had a broken bone
and now that's super rare.
Like my kids have never broken a bone and I, I never broke a bone.
But you probably knew somebody who did.
-- I knew many people who broke bones.
-- It was just, it was normal, right?
It was part of being a child. You broke a bone somewhere
and now it's, I'm trying to think like I,
I literally haven't met a kid with a broken arm or leg and
ages.
That's true. Actually, I haven't seen one
and, and signing cast was like the big thing
that was,
and I remember when I was a kid, I was like,
I wish I had a broken leg so I could get my cast signed,
which in hindsight is an idiotic thing to think.
-- But at the time,
-- well,
but if you don't know how much it hurts and how itchy it gets in there.
-- Like,
-- and that's the thing, right?
Like, I'm certain it was an unpleasant experience in every way.
Honestly, it wasn't that bad because I broke my, I chipped my thumb, I broke wrist.
And so, like, honestly, the thumb thing was just, it was a cast. It was a little itchy.
No big deal. And that's the other thing too. As a young kid, you heal fast.
You know, my kids get the sniffles and if I get the sniffles from them,
I'm out for like, two or three days.
-- Whereas they're just like snotty for two or three days. Yeah,
-- I know how that goes.
All right.
So, I guess the other half of it though is something else I always think about when I,
when I hear about lucky or unlucky is I often feel like I am not a lucky
person where I know people who seem like
they're always winning contests and things like that.
And I feel like that is not me. Now, granted I'm not dead.
So, I've got that going for me.
I would say you're well fed, you have food and shelter and heat. You have a nice house.
-- You're doing a lot better than most
-- well fed is just a nice way to call me fat, isn't
it?
Yeah, we're both pretty well fed, I think.
Well, I mean, and that's, that's part of the privilege I have is like,
I'm trying to eat less food.
I know. Right. Exactly.
For most people over the history of humanity,
that statement would have got me punched in the face.
Yeah.
So, I mean,
my suspicion is most people listening to this podcast aren't actually unlucky.
So,
I mean, yeah, I don't know. I don't know what the moral of the story is here.
I guess survivorship bias is a real thing and we see it in security.
Right where it's like, 00, absolutely.
I didn't have to care about that problem. It's like, uh, not yet. We give it time.
They'll come get you.
So, anyway,
stay safe, everybody and try not to fall out of a tree.
Just don't climb trees. It's December. All right. See you on December 14th.