Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in embracing the future Josh Pressers.
Actually, I did embrace the future.
This weekend,
I have a fun story I was going to talk about because
even though I had a very busy and tiring weekend in general,
I added a bed leveling sensor to my 3D printer.
It didn't come with one. No, it is amazing. Ok. So, no. Ok.
I've, I've explained this on the podcast several times.
-- You obviously don't remember. I have the worst 3D printer
-- in the world. That's true.
-- Yours is a couple of years old at this point,
-- not just old. It's more than a couple.
It's probably almost five years old now.
But more importantly,
it was a very cheap Chinese knockoff of a Prus I three. It's called an Anne A eight.
I mean, this was like a burn your house down 3D printer, right?
And I've since upgraded it and added numerous safety
features so it won't burn my house down.
And the one thing it didn't have was auto bed level. Yeah, I mean, for real, like
this is one of the reasons I didn't get a 3D printer five years ago because I'm, like,
these things are not safe, like,
straight up they might catch fire and with a
big spool of filament that could be a problem.
Yeah.
Oh, there's plenty of pictures of 3d printers, like,
literally bursting into flames
anyway.
And, like, this printer didn't have any thermal runaway protection.
So, if, like, the heat,
the sensor fails, that detects the temperature of your extruder,
it'll just heat forever.
Right.
You know,
like the new firmware have like thermal runaway protection where it's like if the,
if, if the temperature is reading zero, it's like something might be wrong.
Maybe I should
stop heating. Maybe off scale high is a problem.
Anyway. I, I buy this 3D printer. It's called the BL Touch
and
I hook it all up.
I wire it in, I had to rebuild my firmware many times because I kept, like,
missing little bits and pieces and, and whatever
and I get it working and like this feels like cheating.
It used to take 20 minutes to level the printer bed
and I don't have to, I just hit print and like,
it figures it all out and it's magic and it prints perfect every time.
And I'm like,
I don't even know what to say.
This is as I feel like I'm living in the future,
like 1000 years in the future with how easy this has become.
And that's the thing. Right.
Like just like as we've seen with open source,
like I'm looking to buy a 3D printer in the next few months and,
and they all have bed leveling by default or a perfect example is
I am sitting next to a little machine here.
This little machine is a Ryzen 7 5800 with 80 gigs of ra M
210 terabyte hard drives and raid one for the media content.
A 10 terabyte hard drive for youtube downloads.
Like because I have four terabytes of youtube video and a two terabyte M two
drive hooked into a PC I four X slot to run on my virtual machines.
So that I don't have to hear the hard drives going,
you know, whenever something happens.
And like you would agree
10 years ago,
that's a pretty monster server
and 20 years ago, unimaginable.
And now it's just my little media box.
You know what you just reminded me of
is I was thinking about a project over the weekend. I was thinking it would be funny to
build a thing.
So,
you know how like on the hard drive light still
turns on in your computer when it reads your hard drive
thing is now
it would
amuse me to build a little thing that made
fake hard drive noises every time the light turned on
it wouldn't,
I would love that because
I won't lie.
There was a certain,
just comfort
in hearing the noises and knowing something was happening.
Like
anyway,
we have a real topic to talk about as much fun as it
would be to go on and on about our old person tech problems.
So, open A I
and
-- we're not going to talk about.
-- No one knows what that is. Chad GP, T
GP.
Who
knows what Chad GP T is?
-- Well,
-- chat GP,
T is the model that open A I built and you can access chat GP T either through open
a.com or through bing or through a third party
service that essentially is buying access to the API.
That's right
to be clear. I am a chat GP T fan boy. I love it. I'm using it a ton
but
-- I'm not so sure about open A I the company,
-- I'm not even a little surprised. OK.
So here's the,
the, the quick TLDR open
A I had a security incident
-- and
-- a pretty bad one too.
-- Like it was, it was uh
-- it was leaking other people's data. And
I mean, that's
-- remember cloud bleed
-- from
-- their
-- perspective. That's critical. I agree.
But basically
they blamed the open source library
instead of themselves.
Initially, I will say that the initial tweet
they sent out was very this open source library broke our stuff
and then they wrote a blog post where I
feel like it was definitely less blaming open source.
Uh
Did you see the responses to his tweet?
Like,
yeah, the the community was pretty clear on what they thought of his tweet.
Yeah. And, and that's fair and, and I think the blog post is toned much better.
It still could be a little nicer. But again, I mean,
so who knew like tweets could be problematic for getting yourself in trouble.
How could we
possibly
no
one, no one knew, no one knew that
no one knew.
But
it, I
don't think the open A I aspect of this is necessarily super
important because I think you're gonna find people who view open A I
in a multitude of directions.
Like my favorite example is you get a lot of complaints because when they started,
they were what, like a nonprofit foundation or something?
-- They are still a nonprofit.
-- Are they technically still a nonprofit?
The most profitable nonprofit?
So,
and that's part of what people complain about is it's
a nonprofit that now has transitioned to a for profit,
right?
No, that's what I mean. They, they, you are a for profit corporation now, right?
Or not?
Well, ok, in 2019,
open A I transitioned from nonprofit to capped for profit
with a profit capped at 101 100 times any investment.
Ok.
So essentially whatever somebody invests into open A I,
they can only get up to 100 times back.
And then my understanding is open A I, I gets to keep the rest
anyway. It doesn't matter, doesn't matter. I don't want to dwell on it.
The point is
they have a product,
there was definitely a bug in an open source library because
I'll put the bug in the show notes like it,
I, I it's there
and
they decided to blame the open source library,
I think in an attempt to make themselves look better.
Right. That's, that's always the intent of blaming someone else.
We took Chat GP T offline earlier this week due to a bug in an open
source library which allowed some users to see
titles from another active user chat history.
But we
built a thing that
yeah,
like come on it. True.
That's true. That's as, that's as under the bus as you can go.
And now here's the topic. I think that is interesting in all of this.
And this is
going back to our Red Hat days. Red Hat had this saying inside the company.
I, I imagine they still do
but it was, if we ship it, we support it.
Well, it's kind of the whole point of the company.
I mean, one would think, but
-- like that's what people are paying for it.
-- That feels simple when you talk about it.
But remember this was a time
when
even then
there were other groups that would use open
source software and they would say that is not my software,
open source did that. I'm not responsible.
And Red Hat purposely said
if it is in our product, if it is going out our door,
we will support it no matter what that means.
But I think part one of the challenges Red Hat was always
an open
source company.
Now, I know that there were,
there were technically a few close source things like
there was a Red hat enterprise virtualization version one,
had an,
had a binary component that they got rid of in version two.
And there were some binary components in
manage iqevm that was acquired and like they
got rid of them as soon as they could within a year or so.
But so the point is red hat was always either pure open
source or very close in trying to be pure open source.
Whereas somebody like IBM or so
back in the day.
Yeah, not even a little bit.
Oh, no, no, for sure. Absolutely not.
And, and so anyway,
this amuses me
because it's just part of my DNA in a way I can't escape.
I mean, I, I say this at work all the time where someone will be like, oh,
we're shipping this.
I'm like, if we ship it, we support it
then they're like, oh yeah, I guess you're right.
Well, you know, it reminds me of as a car manufacturer,
a car manufacturer can't be like,
oh, you know, we got some bad screws like
go yell at the screw guys like
you
sold me this car and said it was fit for purpose and like
wouldn't like the engine wouldn't fall out on the highway.
That's right.
Well, was it, there was, uh,
there was a court case, I think about this.
-- I feel like
-- it's been more than a few court cases.
No, no, no, no, no. There was a very specific court case about this.
I will try to look it up, but I'm trying, I think I remember this correctly.
This was a talk I saw at a Bide Las Vegas
from
her name is Wendy. Wendy CK is what she went up as on Twitter.
I, I don't know if she's on Masteron. It's been so long. But anyway,
uh
there was a court case at when the car industry was becoming a thing
where basically, like someone got hurt because the tires on the car were bad
and the car manufacturer basically said not our problem. It's the tire guy
and the courts were like, it's totally your problem because you sold the car.
You don't get to blame the tire people.
You can't
use a bad component
but
pass the blame.
No, no. We,
you say that as if it makes perfect sense,
but I don't think it always does. And especially this is where human nature kicks in
because how many times have you made a mistake?
And the first thing you did was try to figure out who can I blame? How is this?
Not my fault?
We've all done it. Don't pretend you have.
But I also caught over quickly because my favorite was
always staring at the blue screen of death that said,
please contact your sister administrator for more help.
And I'm like, that's me.
Damn it.
Right. So I got over that at a very, I think early age because
nine times out of 10, I built the system that failed.
Uh
Yeah, it's me. But, but it's just human nature.
I think it's human nature to try to get out
of getting in trouble when you make a mistake.
I still experience this all the time
where
there will be like a security vulnerability in a thing I'm responsible for.
And the first thing I'm like is, can I prove this doesn't affect us?
That's literally the first thing I say immediately,
it depends on your, like, that's my, that's what I want.
I want to say this doesn't affect me.
But I think the difference here is,
is you're going to go see if you are affected or not.
And if you are affected, then you're going to immediately do the right thing.
That's a massive difference.
It's also my job
in
the
sense
of
being
-- vague,
-- but in the sense of like, I remember with Jackson data bind and satellite,
you know, constant XML. Um, the, uh,
the, the, the stream processing which satellite didn't use.
And so
deer,
yeah, object deser.
There you go.
And so I immediately would be like, I would check,
I would like every time I would double check grip for the function
Yeah, we're not vulnerable, we're not fixed,
but it's coming from the space of like
that's part of the fix to it is are we actually vulnerable or not?
And if, then we are vulnerable then Kurt has to go
try and get people to fix it and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
But,
but that is very different than
immediately seeing.
Can we, we like, can we weasel our way out of the blame
right there? That's a very different intent than
are we actually affected or not? Oh, we're not affected.
Thank goodness or oh, we are affected. Let's fix it.
That's
fair.
And
I think that's where a lot of people get this thing confused.
That's fair. And I think
the other thing I'm grateful for that red hat instilled into my bones
is when you are an open source company, you basically have to tell the truth.
There's no way you can weasel out of a lot of
this stuff because it's just all out in the open.
There was more than one time I was in meetings where we were basically saying,
how can we not look like idiots?
And at the end, we're like, we have to look like idiots.
We have no way we can do this because the source
code and the patches are all going to be available.
What also really astounds me is so many people I think are and not just people,
but companies are
really overly afraid of bad news.
And I get that sometimes it's legitimate because they've
done something truly terrible that will make the national news
and get them, like, in front of Congress, you know, hearings,
congressional hearings, like the tiktok thing.
If you haven't seen
the tiktok ceo, giving extremely evasive answers to Congress,
it's a thing,
especially with a lot of the software that people buy.
Number one,
they probably did a lot of research and ended up buying
that one is like the least worst choice that they could make
and they're stuck with it. Like
you can't just
like, I don't care how angry I get at Mac Os or Windows. I can't not use it.
Yeah, you can, you just won't.
Well, it just, I get certain other things and benefits and you know
that it's just,
yeah, I can't, you know,
I,
I don't like the fossil fuel industry but I'm gonna
have to go guess on my car this week.
That's fair.
What, what frustrates me here is,
I think open A I could have been a lot more forthright
and said like, yeah, we used an open source library.
We built a caching system.
See,
here's fundamentally where some of this really
frustrates me is multi-tenant systems are hard,
especially if you want them to be efficient, right?
Because I've seen multi-tenant systems where you essentially stand up at
a new instance for each tenant and they're very separate.
Like in the sense of like they have their own VM, their own database,
-- running their own V
-- M.
That's not multi-tenant, that's called single tenant cloud. Well, exactly.
But they refer to it as multi-tenant because, you know,
there's multiple tenants on the system anyways.
The point is,
and then there's, you know, like shared databases.
Well, but databases have pretty good security. Right.
We've been doing that for a while now. I mean, it took them 20 years
and this is one of the reasons my SQL and PHP took off,
right is my SQL had really pretty good solid multi user access.
For example,
time nobody used that crap back in the early days of my I SQL
everyone just had like one user
and
-- you just created a new database for everything you did. And if you got
-- into a
new table, everybody got their own table
-- or a
-- new table.
If you got into a my sequel instance, you almost always had complete rain over it.
It was hilarious.
This is actually why Post Chris was better
because Post Chris had really good fine grain access
-- nobody
-- could use because it was complicated.
It was too complicated. I agree.
But that's why that's why my sequel won, right? It was easy.
It was, it was worse and so it won.
But going back to this, I think they've been more forthright and said, look, we built
a really multi-tenant system that's very efficient and has this
caching layer that
oops. Yeah, everybody went like oh OK. That happens, right?
Like clouded are great, like not clouded.
But there's many examples where people have built caching layers where like, yeah,
you got somebody else cash result back.
Oops, that's
really bad.
But it happens like because
caching layers are like anybody who's like oh caching is easy. I can do that. Yeah.
Go ray curl. I think they could have been very forthright.
The reason I'm very concerned about this is open A I is at a very
delicate point
where building trust with people is very important
and I have to say
my impression of them.
Uh It's funny because I'm actually just in the middle
of reading one of the major security papers about chat GP
T and about how they really spent a lot of
time and effort trying to make it safe and not,
you know, answer questions like,
what's the, you know,
what's the easiest way I can kill the most amount of people for $1?
And it, like, spits out some answer like, do this
or, you know, how do I make like nerve gas at home music,
like common household ingredients because like, it,
it,
it can sort of answer those questions.
It totally can.
So what frustrates me is they're at a point where they need to
really be building trust with people about the safety of their system.
And
I look at this and it's just like
I'm reading the security paper,
they did a lot of work but then I see how they
actually handled a security incident and it's like they handled it.
Ok. But it took a, like, one thing that also concerned me is there was talk of this
people getting other people's results for a while before they shut it down.
You know,
I mean, they're not going to shut it down unless they have to, let's face it.
Well, no, but they, they only shut down the threat
history. They didn't shut down the whole system and you can live without that.
Like, it's, it's awkward and annoying not to have
your history,
but
the product still works.
Ah, gotcha.
That's fair. Ok. So, look, here's what I would say to what you're talking about.
Being concerned about the trust in. Open
A
I as a company
open
A, I's DNA
doesn't contain
that critical response, emergency
aspect that comes with security
but
-- they don't have time.
-- They
don't,
they don't, it doesn't matter what you say,
they don't have it and they're not going to have it and here's what's going to happen.
How many companies have you seen
that when it was crisis communications time?
They let the lawyers run it
-- but a lot,
-- they actually delayed chat. GP t to give it some time to make it safer.
They actually looked
at the,
what I'm talking about.
I
understand, but just let me finish
different.
But
the concern I have is that
they don't have a lot of time and space and runway to grow up and mature.
No, they're out, it's done. It's too late.
And
the other thing is to put it bluntly like they're tightly entwined with Microsoft
and Microsoft knows how to do this and does do it quite well.
-- And
-- that's the thing if Microsoft bought them,
it would solve a lot of these problems.
Microsoft can't buy them.
They,
Microsoft did invest in them but it's structured
so that they can't be taken over easily.
But so the Microsoft and opening I
extend partnership was announced, you know, a month ago, blah, blah, blah,
but dumb.
-- So
-- this is, I mean,
this could be a serious problem that if you have an organization
that essentially can't be acquired by someone more competent and capable,
you could potentially have a serious issue because they
obviously aren't prepared for dealing with a crisis.
And why would they be, this is not the sort of
behavior or skill you, you, you learn, you don't learn this on the fly.
And so what's gonna happen is lawyers are going to take over
and they're going to start dealing with risk, but in the lawyer way,
which is often just risk, aversion, not actually dealing with risk.
And what I'm saying is they should have been prepared for this.
They should have been,
-- this is not some little start up.
-- Why would they be, why would they know this?
-- But why would they know this because
-- they
built a hugely complicated system that by definition,
they even like looked at how
those are different things.
-- But the point
-- is building a complicated system is not the skill set of crisis,
communications.
They could have asked chat GP t how to do crisis communications maybe.
Well, no,
but this is a perfect example of they should have
anticipated this happening and built the capability before they needed it
because
you, you anticipate this. You
have a major
-- in.
-- No,
they don't. No one, no one knows they're gonna have a major incident.
No one, no, Kurt, I have built
enough product, security teams.
I'm telling you, I'm going to Dunning Kruger.
You right now when you start at any organization or open source project or anything,
people are unprepared and unaware of the pending need
of security crisis, communications.
You don't think Microsoft talked to them about this or somebody like
I don't, this is
a,
this is a company now valued in the tens of billions of dollars building.
Arguably one of the most amazing hottest
things that by definition people are gonna try and abuse and beat up and compromise.
They're learning now.
But I'm telling you this is not something normal people think about. We are freaks
because we do this.
Well,
ok, I don't have the paper handy but the thing, no, seriously, please listen,
the paper, for example,
talks how they actually engaged with and hired dozens of a I
safety experts to red team it and to beat it up,
of course they did.
And I'm saying like, how did they manage to do that? But
-- not this, this is, I'm sorry, like
-- let's let,
let me rewind this to a whole different place.
Ok. I sadly have been on this wild ride more times than I want to be
and I'm on it again at a start up. So I'm, it's all happening once again,
the thing is
why would someone who is an expert in A I
-- safety or security or whatever you want to call it?
-- No, no, I'm not saying them.
I'm saying the company had the foresight to hire these A I security experts
and to deal with this and to try and yes,
because they're A I people but to try and head these crises
off for them to not have built a good robust response process.
That's
what I'm
-- saying. There's
-- no reason,
no, there is no reason they would, there is absolutely no reason.
A competent A I
researcher
would imagine this will ever be a problem because it is so far.
-- It's, it's what's the old Rumsfeld quote, the unknowns, unknowns
-- to imagine.
There's no flaw in your security, open source
stack. I mean,
we're freaks. Kurt, we live in a world. No one else does
like, ok, let me give you a good example. Right?
I finally, after months of brow beating
the kids on that robotics team I help with,
I have them all using password managers.
Now, this took me like six months of basically constant harassment
right
now that they're using password managers.
They're talking about how complex their passwords are.
And I'm like, whoa, no, complex passwords are bad.
You want a very long password and you're like, wait, what?
Then I'm like, ok,
let's talk about this and I explained like how we got to where we are, how the
guidance was wrong because they actually made it up
and once you sit down and explain to them, they're like, oh, ok. That makes sense.
Why would a high school kid
understand that pass phrases are better than passwords that
have like a million weird characters in them.
There's no way they would understand that because they
don't have anywhere to even begin discovering that knowledge.
And that is what we are talking about.
An A I researcher
doesn't know that security events are even
going to happen because they've probably never been
involved in them because they've been living in academia for the last 10 years.
The thing is their,
their safety and security paper explicitly mentions a lot of concerns.
They have like,
open A I being attacked and made to do bad things.
And it's different. I'm saying, like, I'm sorry,
but here's the thing you're saying. Oh, how could they possibly imagine?
Oh, it's too hard. Well, I'm sorry.
But you, like, when I imagine a house I don't get to just write the plans for it.
I hire an architect who hires an engineer
that builds me a foundation that doesn't
immediately fall down because Kurt's like,
what's the foundation?
I just want to build a house. Why do I need a foundation?
And that's what I'm saying is we're at this
point where they need to build trust and show
well that they're trustworthy
and
no, they do. They absolutely do.
But they just found out now
that they have to do this.
I I'm telling you
beyond a reasonable doubt when they sent that tweet,
they probably thought like this is the get out of jail free card.
Everyone will be like, oh cool, cool.
It was open source everything fine now and that is not what happened and
anyone in our place would have looked at that tweet and been like,
you can't send that at at all.
Like, no, that is the worst thing.
Like if we were going to rank all of the things you could say
that is probably the absolute bottom of the list. Unquestionably
again,
this is a skill set people don't have
and you can't learn it on the fly. Well, you learn things on the fly
but like
-- it's hard.
-- But see, here's the thing,
the start up you work for managed to find you.
You're saying open the eye with tens of billions of
-- dollars can't find one of us
-- if they will.
Now, I think they know about it now.
But, but here's the thing,
here's the thing you got to remember the start up I work for came to get me
because I worked with some of them at Red Hot. And so they were aware this is a problem.
I bet you most of the people at open a I spent a long time in academia,
they probably never ventured out into the scary world of product.
And so they didn't even realize this was going to happen
in, in the world of academia.
You could totally go to your department head and say, oh, we use this open
source library and it screwed everything up and,
and so it's totally open source library's fault,
but we'll fix it later and it'll be cool.
-- OK? And you'd be like, all right, good job.
-- Right. I don't know. Like I said, I just
either they do have a security team and this is the result of it,
which is not encouraging.
I, I don't think they do or they don't have this capability,
which is also very worrying.
So either way it's, I'm not,
I'm a little bit worried
this conversation ended up in a place that I, I didn't expect at all in
any universe.
But I,
I think here's the important part and I want to bring us
back to the thing I was actually hoping that we would talk about
and we didn't,
but it's basically
we exist in this open source universe now where
everyone is using open source in everything they have.
And there is definitely
a,
I think simplistic view that says when one of the packages I'm using
has a bug or a security vulnerability or something wrong with it,
it's not my problem. It's the problem with the open source
and
you'll see this.
If you look at some of the the bugs filed against open source packages,
we only have people being like you need to fix this. This is breaking my product.
It's like, no, we don't like why don't you fix it and send us the patch.
It is really interesting to me that people have a lot of people, not all people,
but a lot of people have formed this,
I get to use this and
I get to use this for free and I get the benefit of being able to ship it
and I get the benefit of being able to
charge money for either shipping it or supporting it.
And somehow they get to make demands of the open source people,
which again goes back to, you know, Tomas, I'm not a supplier thing.
And
yeah, I just, it's wild to me that like,
yeah, it's just, it's such a, it's an obviously pervasive
like it's a very common mindset
and maybe it's because for example, people drive on roads and complain about,
you know, the quality of the roads of the roads are like jammed up.
We need more roads because I pay taxes, you know, I pay your salary,
you know,
and maybe it's part of that. But
how do I put this nicely?
Like, when it comes to negotiating with an open source project?
I think what people forget is by definition,
if you're negotiating or making demands of an open source project,
you're in a position of weakness because
to be, well,
if you were involved in it, you'd be like, hey, everybody, we found this bug and hm,
I don't know how to fix it, but like,
you know, you, you're the subsystem owner. Can you, can you take a look at it, please?
And thank you or, you know, we have a proposed patch
and
that would be a much easier discussion to have than like, yeah,
I need you to fix this patch now so I can show my product
that
all
the time
and, and,
and, and I think that's,
I think a lot of companies are gonna be up for rude awakenings. But,
and what's kind of funny to me is I don't think it's
actually gonna be that bad for most companies because most open source
is
shockingly robust and secure.
Like when you consider that somebody wrote it in their spare time
to scratch an itch and
yeah.
No, it is. I think for if you compare these security bugs per lines of code of open
source, destroys most of the competition in terms of quality,
we'll never know will.
We like, that's the thing, right?
We can say whatever we want about closed
source because they'll never release that stuff.
That's a good point unless they like,
do a massive code cleaning effort and then release it.
Definitely not.
Anyway. All right, I've got one last point before we end.
This one is, I just looked up so the guy who tweeted that, that open A I tweet
gaming gratis,
that guy's the CEO.
Oh, sorry, I should have mentioned that.
-- I didn't know that. I don't know anything about open
-- A I Yeah.
No, he's the CEO like this is not some Rando.
You think
if the CEO is sending out a tweet like that they have a security team, like come on,
-- that's all I'm saying.
-- So good news is they have a bug bounty.
-- Bad news is no rewards that
-- they don't have a bug bunny.
Well, no, no, no worse.
What they've said to the community is if you find a bug
and you wanna get rewarded for it, go to the bad guys.
No, that's what they're saying.
If Apple did this, would anybody cut Apple any slack? No.
And they shouldn't.
They'd be like Apple, you have to pay money,
you have to pay money for these phones to fix our phones to keep us safe.
And I'm Yeah,
that's right again, I'm a huge fan of chat GP D I think it's world changing.
You know, I'm looking like my, my one son is using it already and loving it,
uh,
for historical research purposes
and like, yeah, I, yeah. No, they, they need to, they need to get better at this.
Like now they don't have a year or
I agree. And that's what scares me. I'm not afraid of chat. GP.
T I'm afraid of open a, I,
because I'm not convinced
they have the mental fortitude
to deal with everything coming.
Well, the good news is,
is they are tightly twined with Microsoft who can hopefully
be the adult to help them achieve this quickly.
I hope so because uh like I
look at their coordinate vulnerability disclosure policy.
Like, and, and basically they expect you to
essentially they expect to be treated like an open source project
except
they're not, they're, they're a multibillion dollar entity,
right?
Like
-- I'm sorry,
-- poor little open A I don't be picking on us.
-- We're just a poor little billion dollar company.
-- This isn't, you know,
Daniel doing consulting work for curl. Like
no, this is they have resources
-- if they choose to big
-- curl pushing their agenda. Like anyway.
All right, I'm, I'm calling this one.
What a conversation, Kurt, I don't even know what to say
-- anyway. Thank you, Kurt.
-- We should have chat GP T analyze this conversation.
No, I don't think we should. It'll probably tell us things we know it's true.
We don't want to admit. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to open
social security podcast.com. Hit the show notes. Easy
Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your
-- day. You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye.