Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
I am so excited. We have two guests today, both from Sisig.
We are joined with
Loris de
Joani, founder of Sisig
and Dan Papandrea, the director of open source community and ecosystem.
Gentlemen,
I, I love Sisig. I'm so excited. You're here. Welcome.
Thank you. Thanks for having us
all. We should clarify. That is Lori
who just spoke and Dan, why don't you say hi. So everyone knows who we are.
Hello, everyone. This is Dan Pop,
Andrea.
People call me pop.
I just realized we've never had two guests before. So this is like this is a new thing.
I have to make sure we understand who's saying what? Anyway. Anyway, welcome,
Loris. Why don't you tell us what is, what is Sig
sig
is the security ops company.
We are in a leader in visibility and security for modern infrastructures,
especially the ones based on containers, Coor
natives and cloud. We offer a product
that covers the life cycle of modern
software applications starting from the bill phase,
run and run time security and then respond in terms of forensics
and
-- we've been around for quite a bit and we are still having fun.
-- That's, that's so cool.
And so, Dan, why don't you tell us what, what do you do at sig
What is, what is the director of open source and community?
I just write loss coattails for the majority of the time is what I do.
No, but seriously. So I
work with the community ecosystem with some of our open source projects.
Some of them you might know of one's called Falco,
which is AC NCF based project for runtime Behavioral analysis,
outputs rules engine, that type of thing.
And it's the basis for, for a lot of our,
a lot of our open sources is the basis for our larger commercial products.
But also like we have a large vibrant community that's contributing, you know,
integrations to various things.
And there's something called Falco sidekick, for instance,
allows you to output to many different sources like a slack
page of duty, you know, those types of things.
So really cool ecosystem, very vibrant
for runtime security.
And uh you know, it's, it's awesome being like, you know,
something like a very much like a de facto runtime engine for K
Benetti.
I wanna, I wanna clarify first because I don't, if anyone hasn't heard of Falco, it is
like magic.
The thing is freaking amazing and, and I will, let's see if I get this right.
Just because I, I enjoy
making sure I, I maybe still have the skills we'll say in the industry.
So Falco
is essentially a tool that uses EB PF the,
what is E is it enhanced Berkeley packet filter?
Is that what the E stands for? OK. I don't, I don't remember anymore.
But anyway, it's basically EB PF to watch containers running on a host and then Falco
has the ability to watch for behavior and then, I mean,
functionally just like shut the container down and
the state and then you can obviously do inspection on
that later and make sure like nothing bad is happening.
Yes. When describing Falco, typically, I
compare it to
something like a security camera
for your containerized infrastructures.
So Falco, you deploy Falco on a host, the host can run
one
or 1000 containers, it doesn't matter. Falco
thanks to the EVPF that you are describing
is deployed in a safe way
in in the kernel of the operating system because Eebpf allows you to essentially
add functionality in terms of safe scripts to the kernel of the operating system.
At the point, Falco is able to see
what happens inside any of the containers as a set of rules and policies
that are essentially created by the community to let you know when something
is not right?
To give you an example, somebody is spawning a share in your red container
or somebody is trying to
exfiltrate a file or somebody is trying to modify a system binary.
These are examples of things that Falco is able
to automatically detect and then Falco can either inform you
or take action and help you essentially rectify the problem.
-- It's
-- so cool.
It's, I got to say this one thing coming from the history of, you know,
25 years of Linux security
trying to watch a system for bad behavior was always
to put it bluntly a nightmare.
And what always kind of annoyed me is the one thing all attacks have in common since,
well, the last 30 years is
the network,
right?
Because like if you pop a system,
then you have to do something on the network
either for command and control that filtrate data.
And I was always so frustrated that yeah, there,
there were generally not great tools to handle this.
Think about that at scale with multiple nodes, right? Think about taking that,
you know, single cluster, then you do multi cluster, right?
And so like again that finite thing that's there is that is the kernel, right?
Being able to reverse those things. And you're looking at this person,
Loris who's been doing this for X amount of years, he's the he is the god of,
I'm going to call it right now of,
you know,
kernel level introspection. I told you I was a side
player. That's what I do on these things.
That's all
actually K
since we are talking about the network, let's do it 30 seconds of Easter
Falco, as we just mentioned, is based on collecting system calls, uh actually Falco
uh and also open
source,
the tool that gave the name to our company
are inspired by the fact that
I spent the 1st 15 years of my career, just dealing with network packets,
including my phd thesis was about high speed packet capture.
And what we do with Falco and with CD is we apply
essentially the same techniques that you use to use with network packets.
But to system calls, why?
Because system calls are closer to the application are richer.
They of course, when you capture a system call, you see all of the socket activity.
So you see the network traffic exactly like you were describing
but much more follow your user activity, inter process communication,
all this kind of stuff.
At the same time,
Falco has been inspired by network intrusion detection tools like snort
or
surat
who remembers nor you know, where you could create policies on the network traffic,
you know, and essentially with snort, what what you are doing is you are capturing,
you still are you are capturing packets.
And there are rules that are saying,
I don't know if the packet is an IP address is coming from, I have no idea Afghanistan
and and the payload contains a PDF but then matches a PERL
script, then send me an alert, you know,
Falco can do the same but on a much broader data set because it uses
system calls and it's able to tap inside the kernel of the operating system.
But the philosophy is the same.
So this comes from my days, you know, working,
working with network packets and trying to apply, you know,
the same techniques to more modern cloud based container based infrastructure.
But the philosophy is the same.
Well, it's funny you mention that because I remember, you know,
when networks were 10 megabit 100 megabit gigabit, 10 gigabit
and just the ridiculous amount of engineering effort.
And I I actually knew the snort team back in the day
and like the amount of effort they put into supporting gigabit was insane.
But you know, it's funny,
I've never really given it much thought about system calls and system
calls are easily firing off at higher rates than that potentially.
Yes, because you are not, again,
you are seeing potentially all of the network traffic
because each network transfer generates some activity on a, on a,
on a socket related system called but imagine
file
a
yo you know, on a on a busy database. You know, you can really have a ton of
IOPS and each of these operations on this.
The beauty is that with the like the B PE BPF kind of system that we have,
you can see all of them.
So you can really see and reconstruct, for example, what somebody saved
to this
maybe after a container is gone, which is beautiful, you know, and very powerful.
At the same time, it's a ton of traffic.
So I'm sure we cannot,
we don't have a chance to go into the technical
details of what we do essentially to make this,
you know, digestible and bearable for a tool like Falco.
But there's a lot of engineering
that is going on to make sure that
you can capture this information at these rates without
impacting the system to watch because they are supposed to
operate at one time, right?
A lot of these is actually inspired by the work that myself and the team
have done in the past in terms of capturing on gigabit 10 gigabit 40 gigabit
gigabit. So
E software
in a way that is optimized and it still works,
think about the trajectory of like containers and
pods and all those things that have,
these are black boxes, they're literally,
there's no way to really get that introspection. Then you confound that by
like we talked about earlier, multiple clusters,
you know, clusters that have, you know, different like, you know,
deployment mechanisms, all of those things.
What you one thing that's always been the standard
underneath all of that is it always has to be a
kernel or some type of OS that's running those system calls,
that's allowing you
to create rules to be able to do those things. And so
with the, you know, the technology that, you know, that lori
you know, that Lori had obviously a huge hand in kind of, you know, putting together,
helps to, you know,
mitigate some of those runtime security risks and all those types of things.
So again, we've seen it from the, you know, the community,
folks kind of adhering to it.
We've just did a major, major contribution to the C NCF of these driving Libs.
So folks can, you know,
utilize this because we totally believe that the future security
open, we want to make sure that we can, you know,
attack those things and people to address them.
Let's talk about what you guys just donated to the C
NCF because this feels enormous when I read your press release,
essentially this technology that we just described
to capture system calls at high speed.
This this is more or less if we summarize what we donated. So initially
Falco was contributed
to the CNCF as the engine, which is a really powerful and substantial piece of work.
It's essentially what notification part and the engine part of the,
of the flight recording.
But
the actual data capture, we weren't
able yet to contribute to the
NCF because there were there were other open source tools, for example,
like open sources,
which is more like the T CPD for system
calls that were also depending on this library.
So we managed to essentially separate properly these components
so that now the libraries can be independently located.
And then since these libraries are a super powerful and high performance tool
to build
a
any kind of, you know, security and invisibility software that, that needs to, to,
to support containers and microservices.
We decided why not making the real step and contributing them to the community,
to the CCNCF community where they can really, first of all, have a neutral
governance,
uh they can be owned by everybody
and then can and they can be really the base
of many future tools because as them was saying,
the future of security in our opinion is, is open and this is
the way for us to put our money where our mouth is.
And then yeah, you were talking about this.
Sure, you have something to add on the future of security is open.
-- So
-- in general, the way that we look at it, if you think of internal or external actors,
right, like, you know, there's been, you know,
vulnerabilities or CVE based on like pseudo for instance,
having a community in the world contributing right back to be able to, you know,
address those things, be able to detect those things.
It's been huge, think about things like Miter
attack framework.
I'll give you a good example, a very large investment bank for instance,
wanted to create these rule sets based on the Miter Attack framework.
There was nothing out there to be able to do that
at the time.
And so using like, you know, a very simple rule syntax that we have within, within,
within Falco to be able to detect those things.
They were able to create like 26 sets,
26 specific rules in a matter of like a week and a half's time.
So that tells you, you know, again, where and then those things were contributed to,
you know, other folks in the, in the industry or in our community, then would,
you know, add more to that.
So think about this instead of having something where you have a bunch of, you know,
a single set of researchers looking for
something you have multiple companies versus researchers
being able to, to detect things.
Uh
and, and in the past, like you said, if he's a vulnerability,
you'd have to send it to the,
to
Linux's
mailing glass to be able to dress this with
things like EBPF and those types of things.
It's like, wow,
it's
that, is that the spirit of that is beautiful and that's what I think, you know,
community is based.
And if you look at like, you
know, Kernes or some of the other CNCF projects,
I think security has to play a very large part in, in, in, in community based things.
And if we open that
open the kimono, so to speak, if that's even said,
it's the only way to really have true security. So I'm, I'm curious, do you know
what your percentage of like
cystic
generated rules versus community generated rules is,
it's hard to measure because
cystic behaves
from this point of view, like,
like any other member of the community that's very important Falco,
you know, even the, I don't know, the security researchers inside CD
that maybe then
as part of what they do sometimes create Falco
rules, these are still trying to do it in a way that is,
that involves participating to the community.
And that means that pretty much all of the Falco
rules that are around
you,
you get them, you know, as a community.
But I would say that nowadays is like the majority
of, of the activity in
Falco including including rules.
It's coming from community members and not and
not and not from the company specifically.
-- That
-- is so
cool.
Well, and it's just because for myself, you know, being cloud native,
one of the things I find really interesting is, you know,
we're making that shift from
hardware to V MS to containers now to serverless.
And what I'm seeing the majority of security solutions fail
miserably in a serverless environment because they make assumptions like
I have a system to live on and well, now they don't.
And what's interesting my understanding is because
I was reading through the press release.
Can you tell us about pet?
Yeah. So this is an effort that we undertook during 2020.
The another beautiful side of security being open source is that
you can work together with the cloud providers, right?
Because the cloud providers are incentivized to
have this powerful open source solutions,
especially in security, you know,
when security is so important and covering the basis
even in this new place and a completely open
community driven engine like Falco
is suitable essentially for them to include in their solution. So what happened is
an environment like for example, Fargate where there's,
I mean there still is an operating system underneath
but the instrument, the instrumentation is not exposed to that,
you need to find essentially alternative ways to collect this.
And what happened is Amazon worked on enabling a technology called
prays,
which is essentially the same technology that is used.
It is in the Linux kernel and it is used to implement both
rays and G DB and they enabled it on far gate so that it's
possible essentially to go and introspect applications in a way that is still safe.
Pray
is much less a performance than EB PF.
In fact, you know, tools like strays are famously extremely slow.
So these require to do quite a bit of creative work essentially to
bring it to a performance level that is acceptable to have deep instrumentation
and still have the performance being
in the overhead being
contained.
And this is what we did essentially together with the community during 2020.
And now you can essentially run
Falco
on, on Fargate and magically it works and the performance is acceptable.
And we are also working
at the same time on further optimizations to make the
performance pretty much almost indistinguishable
from the original Falco performance.
I think we took our time because we want to ensure the end users and customers, right,
don't have performance issues because there's, you know, look serverless as a,
as a paradigm, right is basically like I run my program and I get out
now if you run your program and there's no, you know,
the security is adding a ton of overhead to that,
then what's the benefit of it? Right.
Then go back to V and container where it's where it looks,
we again took our time with the,
with the functionality of P trades to make this optimal.
And we'll continue to do that hearing feedback from the community.
That's really cool because
I think history shows, if the security tool
hurts, performance,
performance went right. Like, just turn it off.
Look how fast it is now, this is way better.
Like
just take an
antivirus.
Yeah.
You know, like in the past on your, on your machine, it's like, oh, well,
if this is impacting the fact that I can't play, you know,
World of Warcraft for God's sakes, why do I disable it?
Right.
I had a coworker call me and, uh, his, uh, brother-in-law or whatever has a computer
but, and I quote, his son
turned off the antivirus and installed a bunch of cheat programs and
now it runs really slow and has problems and I'm like,
yep.
It probably does.
It's like, what should we do? And I'm like,
-- it has internet syphilis. I don't know what you can do.
-- Buy a new computer.
That's how you saw
Run and Hide
because, I mean, well, and that's, and the
well ignoring performance, like, if
you try and tell, like,
a bunch of devs to spend a month adding this security
thing and make it work and it doesn't want to work.
You know, that's what I ran into with Ac Linux, right?
Trying to sell Se Linux to vendors and they're like,
so you want me to like break it and then we'll spend like a month trying to make it work.
-- That is not a winning strategy in
-- terms of the Se Linux part. That's a great point.
It's like, look, you can have, you know,
set of Se Linux set in force to zero which the majority of us do, right?
But I'm just saying in general,
if you're adhering to good Se Linux kind of etiquette where you have a, you know,
default set of profile that you've set up, that's exactly what we've done with,
with, with Falcon rule sets.
We have this default set that's going to, you know,
give you kind of the best of the best and then
you can extend that and say for my own use cases,
my own use. This is what needs to be addressed.
If you think about any tool that's out there is going to have,
you have a lot of false positives,
right?
You're going to get a bunch of rule violations because you
have to tweak said rules for your environment or your,
you know, capabilities, your applications,
your serverless technology and all of those types of things,
you have the capability in your falco and
even our commercial tool extends it even further.
So there's a ui behind it, there's capabilities for, you know,
extent abilities for vulnerability management,
incident response and all of those types of things.
But you know, again,
it's all based on that kind of rules engine that's very similar
to Lake and Se Linux where you can basically say here's my
line
and if I need to customize it, I can do it by creating profiles or rules.
So this is really interesting, you say that.
So in the past when I would turn Falco on you, you,
you turn it on and it works, right?
And I feel like in the past when I turned E Linux on,
things would just explode and I'd give up.
And I think that's a huge difference, right?
Because if I'm a new user and I turn it on and it explodes well, screw that I'm done.
-- You know, that's huge.
-- That was actually by design.
There are things that you can do even just in the,
in the design of the tool or just how you
approach essentially the problem that can reduce essentially these issues
when I when I was, for example,
describing Falco before I was comparing it more to a flight recorder.
Of course, Falco is the option, you know,
to then enforce and block stuff and integrate, you know,
with admission controllers and that kind of stuff.
But it's important that
that is left as a feature
for advanced users.
It's not the default behavior because you don't know which system
you, you, you, you go into, you know, as a tool. And if the trade of insecurity is,
of course, it's important to,
to insecurity to, you know, shoot before,
before you let somebody talk because because that's the essence of security.
But if you do it too much and if you are too aggressive,
then you run the risk of shooting a random person on the street, you know,
and so philosophically starting with a simple rule set that is extremely curated,
starting with detection and only going with
prevention with people that really understand it and
want to do it having a mechanism by which the user can start with a,
with a rule set that is a little bit safer even if maybe a little bit less complete,
but it's good to go and then gradually and turn stuff
on and see what happens if they desire to do that.
They were all choices that we, that we designed that way to, yeah, reduce
if possible a little bit.
The Sc Linux kind of fatigue, you know, that people clearly were showing.
I love that. I think that makes perfect sense. We got all types of love for Sc Linux.
Don't think we're, you know, v
it's great. Oh, it's all right. We make fun of Sc Linux all the time. You're fine.
We love it. But,
yeah, I, I think, yeah. And just to be clear, me and Josh don't hate,
uh, se Linux. Uh, it's just,
I think we're both frustrated by it because it shows
so much potential and it has so much potential,
not just for security related issues, but for,
you know, reporting and whatnot and,
and it just the interface and the tools for it are just
non existent for sure.
C
was
indeed a big inspiration for us, uh you know, the Falco community
and, and Falco developers.
So we need to also give credit, you know, not only, not only complain about it, but
uh
uh definitely one thing I've been in the industry now for, for quite a bit.
And one thing that I learned is that you never invent stuff.
If you, if you think you are inventing stuff, it's because you are uh you know, not,
not good enough at remembering
and, and, and, and taking inspiration and just trying to
improve the previous generation is really the best way innovation
in
software. And as I was mentioning, you know, Falco,
you can really see it as Sc Linux
plus snort open source is big.
It is more like A
T
CPD
and the
clin looks together, you know. So it's like T CPD
for system calls and for system events, frustrating tools.
But we, we would not be here without them,
you know, 100%. That's, that's a very good way to put it.
OK. OK.
We are, we, we, we're running ourselves out of time, which always seems to happen.
I have so much more I want to ask, but
I actually have one thing I'm really curious about is is on your website,
you have an infographic and let me, let me look at the title a bit quick.
I could pull it up in a tab,
a container security and usage snapshot. This blew my mind.
You guys said like half of containers live for, what is it? Five minutes or less?
That's bananas.
-- Yeah,
-- that, that's a high percentage that lasts for less than 10 seconds, you know.
So, yeah, a lot of churn
because from what I've seen, basically, there's,
there's really two types of people using containers.
There's the people who use it
as a virtual machine replacement.
And then there's the people who use it properly and the people who use it properly,
of course, are going to skew the numbers because they're going to
like they're gonna like Netflix, they're gonna be,
they're using it at scale properly, right. Whereas
little people like us, like I have containers that were running for way too long.
I'm just going to say
world record
and I ran Foodora once in production for four years,
the same
-- everything
-- is fine, you know,
it was behind the firewall
when when describing containers especially, you know, to,
to people that maybe are not part of this industry, I typically extend the
metaphor of a pet versus cattle,
right? You remember that one to
describe cloud cloud computing in modern cloud instances, people compare them
to cattle while the traditional monolithic servers were pets
that you were really treating individually and really you cared about them.
Now, the cloud instances are behind a lot of balancers and you treat them as a group.
And if you lose one,
it it it it's not a huge deal because they behave more like a group of entities, right?
Well, containers to me are are like going from kettle to locust to a swarm of locust,
you know, they are tiny,
they are very fast, they are everywhere.
It's very hard if impossible to keep track of them individually.
And if you are not careful about what to do, they do a lot of them,
you know.
So,
so we're in the locust era and this infographic essentially
-- proves that
-- if you think about DEV ops functions get
ops functions, right? I mean, the speed and resiliency that that's happening.
I mean, looking at an infographic,
it completely makes sense as you see people shifting their
workloads to more of this very quick resilient deployment mechanism.
So your CD processes and get
s and all of those whatever buzz terms you're hearing and what have you,
those are things they're going to, they're going to be much more like shorter term,
you know, containers or pods or those types of things.
You're always going to have, you know, state full applications that may, you know,
that, that, you know, stays in from a data store perspective.
But think about again is I'm doing releases constantly.
And also you need protection from that perspective. You need as laws
talked about in the beginning. You need
the build, you need the the the run,
you need the post mortem for those like things that are happening at a millisecond.
And again, it is our belief, strong belief
that the only place you are able to get to that like low, low level from like a cus
perspective, from
a
perspective is in the kernel.
And that's what we do with not only our open source tool but our commercial platform,
which I mean,
the thing that really blows my brain here more than anything is that
a lot of your antivirus and various anti malware tools,
they take more than 10 seconds to start like the
container's gone before they even know what's going on.
And you cannot replay those commands that were happening
during those periods to say what that caused this.
Laura said this once again, Godfather.
So basically like the he said this, that the kernel doesn't lie.
System calls do not lie.
And it's, and I've said this in countless end user and customer meetings.
I've said this. It is one of the greatest quotes ever because it's completely true.
There's no other place that's going to give you those short term
and long term detail that the system calls mcconnell will give you.
That sounds like it could be famous last words if
someone like Tavis Ormandy gets a hold of it.
So,
but, but anyway, anyway,
OK. OK. So I guess we've not talked, what is your commercial offering?
You know, let's end the show on that.
Like I honestly don't even know cause I've only ever
interacted with Falco from kind of the community perspective.
So I'm curious like what is sig
actually doing?
Like how are you,
-- how are you feeding your family
-- our commercial offering builds
on top of the technology that we've just described.
So collecting
the best data
kernel of the operating system,
open source engines like the CD one and the Falco one and so on.
But, but what we offer is a platform,
we mentioned a couple of times build runner response.
What does it mean
in the build phase? You need to be able to essentially do shift left security
scanning the images validating configurations, all of this kind of stuff.
So our commercial tool does that by
employing
an open source engine, the anchor
engine and being able to plug it in the different areas of the CIC
pipeline of people building modern applications.
Then on runtime, there's a, there's a big focus on Falco but we offer workflows,
user interfaces, orchestration of the agent poly secure,
all of this kind of stuff on top of the Falco engine.
And then at the response phase, we are able like every time, for example, Falco,
the flight recorder gives you
uh a uh an an alert that something has happened.
We are able to take action, we are able to collect the data.
We are able to take captures similar to water
shark captures to allow you to do
the forensics and retrospective and threat hunting,
right?
So how do you understand an attack for a container that last five seconds,
the way you do it is you are able to take a full capture of the full activity,
every file iy every connection, all of this kind of stuff.
The moment before and after the container is gone
and everything in the middle and we store it
somewhere and then we give you a essentially forensics
tools that you can use to go and investigate.
That's how you solve the problem.
That's the only way, you know,
because you cannot take a sage into the container anymore,
you're guaranteed it's gone.
So this old workflow that starts from the ship left and goes to the forensics.
It's part of a unified workflows in our commercial
tool that is the source of puts everything together
and there's
a bunch of enterprise features so that the biggest
organizations in the world are able to take advantage of this functionality.
I'll add a couple of points too, right?
And look anybody off the shelf can do some of the capabilities.
You know, again, you have this, this whole rules engine, you know,
core engine and you have outputs that you can, you know, use Falco with
you add vulnerability management as
you add incident response,
you add all of those capabilities but also an enter like an
enterprise S A to be able to support that for you.
So you don't, you can concentrate on building your applications, right?
That to me is, is a benefit not having to support a just a security system,
be able to just support your applications that are
running inside clouds and all those types of things.
So again, as the open source lead, I want to see people contribute because again,
the commercial tool
and Falco all use that underlying
same beating heart,
right? It's using that same kernel canal functionality that's there.
And and so having the the capability for somebody just
to be able to say look off the shelf,
I just need to do you know runtime capability.
That's great. Go ahead and use Falco.
But if you need a full platform,
the way you do a security platform from a
runtime perspective from the build from the post mortem,
then you go with a commercial tool that's on as SASS,
you don't have to worry about managing a back end or
any of that thing that is the compelling event for wanting,
you know, a commercial tool.
But again, you have a far,
far high set of capabilities with Falco that
you can utilize from a runtime security perspective.
We have run ourselves out of time,
but this was
a lovely conversation. So I want to thank you both for joining us.
Thank you.
I will put links to everything we've talked about in
the show notes for anyone who's looking for it.
So I guess yes,
you can go to open source security podcast.com and find those show notes.
You can use the
Podos podcast. Hashtag
-- hit us up on social media. Dan and Loris have marvelous rest of your days. You
-- too.
And thank you.
-- Thanks for having us.
-- Thanks everybody.
Wonderful. Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the