Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and hopefully not making things worse.
Josh Pressers.
I mean, I try not to make things categorically worse, but I,
I make no guarantees of that fact.
Well,
and I think the other thing is we're
open to correction when somebody points out that like
you did this thing, you probably thought you, we're doing the right thing, but
it resulted in this other negative outcome that were you even aware of.
And it's like,
like those one hour shows we started with for, again, we apologize.
We did well in the audio quality was bad and, and lots of things.
But so for anyone who doesn't know what K
just said back in the early days of the podcast and please,
please don't go back and look,
we, we, our shows were like an hour long.
Why, why did we do that because we didn't know any better.
But so in all seriousness at that point in time,
I would say virtually all podcasts were an hour long.
That's true. I think that's why we did it.
It was very, very common and then someone,
someone at one point I don't even remember who it was, was.
I, I was actually at an event with them and they were like,
I love your podcast but it's too long.
I was like, what do you mean? He's like,
my commute to work is 40 minutes
and I don't want to listen to part of a podcast on the way home. And I'm like, oh,
and then it also occurred to me like,
30 minutes does a nicer job. I think of focusing the mind.
I mean, I do this with meetings at work and stuff is
brevity. I always schedule 30 minute meetings or less
because I feel like if you know, you have 30 minutes, well,
I shouldn't say that no matter how long you schedule a meeting for,
you will fill that time,
-- whether you should or not. It's
-- like a plate of food.
That's a portion. Like,
no, like it's like a bag of chips unless it's like family size.
I'm sorry, that's not three servings of chips.
That's a bag of chips and I'm eating it.
You know,
like those Pepsi my favorite now is where
you buy something and it's like 1.5 servings
if you read the serving guide in size. And I'm like, that's some BS like, come on.
I remember that
for sure.
Like, I totally get something that's two servings or three servings,
but you can't say it's like 1.6
-- clearly just gaming it to make it come out as like 100 calories. Right.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. That's exactly what,
-- and actually that's exactly the topic for today.
I don't, I wouldn't call it gaming it
well, but, you know,
trying to squish things for,
I suspect largely for the sake of squishing them.
Not because they actually need squishing.
Well, I want, I want to reframe it a little differently.
So there is a blog post,
a link to the hacker news discussion because there's
some interesting comments and then there's a blog post and
the blog post is titled How I Reduced the size
of my very first published Docker image by 40%.
A lesson in Docker
shell scripts.
And
this caught my attention immediately when I read it
because
when you talk about security,
one of the topics that comes up all the
time is something called a tax surface reduction.
The idea being
the less stuff you have like be it API N points or third party dependencies or,
or whatever or even your container size,
the less stuff you have, the more secure you'll be in theory, right?
I mean, no one's gonna argue that.
And ironically that's part of the reason for
containerizing stuff is so that the stuff is
in a container and not like you're not running a Python script on your local machine.
Yeah.
Yeah. For sure. For sure. Right. Right.
Which I do all the time and I probably shouldn't but
whatever, it's fine
and, well, I mean, I, I remember too, like, on that note
back in the good old days when we would, like,
have systems and we were system administrators, for example,
you would do, like,
1000 random things you didn't even keep track of to make something run.
And so trying to, like,
reproduce and install another computer would be impossible.
How about just trying to fix it? Well, yeah, that's true. Like,
like my favorite was always, you know, you'd reboot the system and like,
the service wouldn't come up.
And that's one of the arguments
and that's one of the arguments I always made for people are like,
how often do you reboot?
And I'm like, I reboot on a forced monthly schedule
to make sure things work because I would make tweaks to the system,
-- but forget to put them in the configuration file.
-- I have a funny story about that. I
logged into my file server in the basement. Uh, I was over the weekend
and because, uh, what was it? Like? There's a new,
oh, I, I haven't, I'm, I'm running a bunch of Debbie and 11 and Debbie and 12 is out now.
And so I was thinking, oh, maybe I'll upgrade some of these systems to Debbie and 12.
Not that, I mean, le
still supported. So there's nothing wrong with it.
But I looked at my file server and the up time was 287 days and I'm, like, nope,
not touching this,
that
we're going to let the universe schedule my downtime on this one.
Yeah,
I know. It isn't going to reboot. Right.
-- There's almost certainly going to be something wrong or
-- worse. It will reboot.
But is everything working fine?
I'm not even
gonna
find out
and it's not like you have a test suite to make sure. Like
that's one reason I actually intentionally keep my plex server very simple.
And I don't have a lot of weird stuff on it because
like my kids need to be able to watch their shows.
I upgrade my plex server like probably once a week, I bet.
Um Anyway, OK. OK. So we were talking about attack surface reduction.
So anyway,
I read this article by this person who wrote a
blog post and it's a very well written post.
Like I think they did a really nice job.
They broke it down into all their attempts and they talk heavily about what they did.
But fundamentally at the end of the day,
what they end up doing is they take a container,
-- an alpine image which is like
-- four megabytes or something.
This person needed to install some things in the container, which is normal, right?
Like almost no one runs just a container.
-- You always need other stuff in your base
-- image.
It's like the open BS D open BS D secure by default. What does it do? You can ssh into it.
And then what? And that's it.
Yeah. Right. Then you start installing stuff and it falls apart anyway.
So,
but what they end up doing is they're like, oh,
I want to make my container as small as possible, which is a cool thing to do.
I have no issues with this.
I think it's a good skill to have, but not necessarily a good skill to use.
And I think that's like a lot of skills
-- it
-- has value to a point.
And let's say there's it's like the old you can
underflow an integer back around to from negative to positive,
for example, right?
This is like a security underflow is what I would kind of use this as is my
very
clever description. But anyway,
they instead of using like alpine, they basically end up taking one container,
installing everything they need
and then copying it all into a scratch image.
Now in the container will the scratch image is literally an empty container.
You can start with a scratch image and then just copy
stuff in it like a lot of go applications do this.
I used to do this with V MS all the time,
right?
Like I would install a VM, do all this, install, install,
install and then like RM hyphen R fa whole
like all the man pages, all the everything
and think of this as the opposite though, right?
Where you start from nothing and you only copy in the things you absolutely need.
And so you can end up with a functional Linux system by doing this. Right.
No surprise.
Now,
-- here's
-- the,
it's
shocking how little you need to get a log and pro
is
-- amazing, in fact.
-- But the thing is we used to run computers off of like,
like single
-- digit megabyte storage devices.
-- A floppy disk. Exactly.
So, and, you know, that's the other thing to keep in mind,
right is you actually don't need a lot of stuff to stand
-- a computer up and get it on the internet to
-- run.
We
run in here. I'm making air codes
-- minimum to run TCP/IP stack and an SSH N A shell,
-- you don't even need SSH. But
-- anyway,
-- you do, if you want to remotely connect to it, no,
don't remote into your containers, don't
SSH in your containers,
you
whatever, whatever, stop it.
Ok.
And here's the thing that like really tripped me when I read this
is at the very end,
the person mentions
I ran Docker Scout on the image and it found like no vulnerabilities and I was like,
of course, it didn't.
You removed everything Docker Scout looks for.
And so this,
this especially amused me because Docker Scout uses
sift underneath sift is the S bomb scanner.
The company I work for Encor
created.
And so here's where I, I like this,
like instantly lit up my mind when I read this whole article and I got to the end,
I'm like, holy cow.
This is like you went too far and you're less secure now.
And so let me explain why this is. So
we exist in a universe now where an enormous amount
of our security is derived from having the ability to update
and having the ability to kind of inspect the
system and get an understanding for what's going on.
Now, when the vast majority of tools like SBO
tools, for example, inspect a system,
they look at things like the alpine database or the R PM database or the Python.
What it,
what is it the
Oh the pie project dot Tomel
is the new one, right? For like
understanding. Well, it's the the dot lock file but whatever, right?
-- Understanding what's installed.
-- Well, essentially,
I think I can simplify it even better
if you actually look at every single binary and every
single finer file and have a hash and identify it.
Yes, that's how we used to do things.
There's too many files and things now we can't do it that way.
And now like Sift will look for certain binaries in certain places.
Like for example, Busy Box is a good one, right?
Like lots of containers have just Busy Box in them
and there's no like
distro database or anything else to look at.
So Busy Box is one of those examples where
Sift will like inspect the binary and look for known
strings in the binary to be like, yes,
this is Busy Box and I can identify this version of Busy Box, right?
Makes sense. That's obvious.
But it doesn't do this for everything because you have kind of two problems.
-- The one you said where there's just too many binaries
-- and
too many people building them from scratch and getting weird.
-- Like, it would
-- also take a bazillion years to actually parse all this data.
-- Like that's the other half of
-- like how many
Linux distributions are there now that are widely used.
-- I think it's over 100 it's
-- a lot, a lot,
-- a
-- lot, right?
I mean, it's really just three but
like they're all based on each other.
But anyway, you get the point.
And so this the the reason this like lit me up
is because it's like, ok, yes,
Doctor Scout is reporting nothing because Doctor Scout can find
nothing because you've taken out everything Doctor Scout looks for.
And so now by your the the journey to the smallest container possible
is going to result in worse security because Doctor
Scout is always going to report zero vulnerabilities.
I mean, granted this thing is doing very little so it not like it's going to have a ton,
but you get the idea, right?
Like
you can no longer use modern tools to like inspect and maintain this container.
Well, this is exactly like back in the olden days where, you know,
Apache would say hi, I'm Apache version 1.1 0.2 or send mail, you know,
you could request hello version and it would say I'm send mail 3.6 0.9 or whatever.
And then you disable that because people are like, oh,
it's leaking information and Attackers will use that.
And I always argued that like,
well, or they just try all the attacks and see which one works.
They don't care what version it is. But the point is removing the version string
again,
made you less secure over time.
Because legitimate tools like n map and stuff
that could use a fingerprinting and say,
hey, look, you're running this old version of Apache, you should update it
don't work anymore.
So I remember this was always funny because this
would come up when I worked at elastic is
elastic search
was notorious for reporting it like literally in the,
in the string like the hello string or whatever
it
is. And that's exactly what it was for. And Cabana would do the same thing, right?
Where the Cabana server would be like, I'm Cabana, this version
and all of these like p tester types would freak out
like, oh my goodness, what are we doing? And it's like
if you can't figure out the version from like all the other features and,
and libraries included, you can just look at like you're an idiot.
This version string is meaningless
but more to the point Attackers don't care. They just try all the attacks.
And the first thing they putting is stand up a Webster put it online.
Oh, yeah. And you will still see front page exploits hitting it. And I'm like,
-- that's been gone for 20 years, hasn't it? Well, I
-- guess
now here's, but here's, here's where I want to bring this conversation.
Like, all the way
is
I feel like there's this, like, cargo,
cult security that has been pervasive for a long time Now
that focuses on this like minim
attitude but almost to the point of making certain things worse.
Like one of my favorite examples right now is the obsession with zero CV ES
where you keep people would be like, oh, I just scanned your container.
It is 10 CV ES in, in the red hat base image. And I'm like, who cares?
Red Hat said they're not fixing it.
What's fascinating to me is also that shows a lack of maturity.
-- Oh, yeah. Yeah,
-- in the security process.
But no, no, no,
a very subtle lack of maturity that I think a lot of people
don't think about which is binary thinking versus actual risk is a scale,
right?
Because they go, we have to have, we have to have zero CV S not,
we have to have an acceptable risk of CV S
and that's a subtle but very important distinction
because if your organization has that binary thinking,
eventually a
it's going to be more expensive in the long term than having subtle thinking
-- and it's going to break at some point, it
-- will break,
-- it'll break 100%
-- because log for J doesn't care, log for J is everywhere.
The better example always is
the cobra effect, right? Which is the
like the legendary story where what it, what it was the the British in India
decided they were going to pay people to bring them dead cobras.
And in theory, this sounds like a good idea right?
Where we have too many cobras, let's pay people to kill them and bring them to us.
Except the Indians being like the brilliant business people, they are,
they started breeding cobras.
And so now the problem was infinitely worse.
And then when the British were like, holy crap, they're breeding cobras.
This is nuts.
They were like, well, we're done here, like open the doors, let them out.
We're, we're ok. And then the problem was like 10 times worse when they were done.
But I think this is what make security such a mind
boggling pain in the butt is there are so many
things that feel like this is a good idea,
like complex passwords fall in this bucket.
But when you actually sit down and you like, put all the pieces together and,
and you look at it like correctly, which is very hard to do.
But you end up in these situations where it's
like holy cow doing this actually made it worse.
It didn't make it better at all.
Well, and I think there again is a subtle thing is a lot of security
strategies and controls are effective up to a point and
then there's diminishing returns and to the point where it
can make things actually
us
worse for users so that they like drive around the fence. And the second thing is
security is always context dependent.
Like I just read about those attacks where you can like with physical access,
uh you and a Raspberry pi and a bunch of other shenanigans.
You can basically bypass windows, bit locker and
oh, you can extract the key. Yes, that was a very clever attack.
And my, my take on that is like, yes,
there are some people that have to worry about that.
I'm not one of them and people are like, what do you mean? I'm like
because they will just take me and my laptop and they will say Kurt,
I'm going to give you a nice choice here.
You can either unlock your laptop and tell us your
bit locker key or we can burn your house down.
-- Uh
-- It's the old XK CD comic, right? Like take this Wrench and hit them until they
-- tell you the password
-- and I will happily give them the bit lock.
Well, not happily, I will give them the bit lock key
rather than have my house burned down.
-- Well,
-- you don't know the bit locker key,
-- you know the password that unlocks the bit
-- locker key.
Well, actually I know where the bit locker key is printed out.
That's,
I have one
of those too
because I do
my computer. So, like, it craps. It's like Bit Locker
and it's like,
oh, yeah. Yeah, that's true too. Yeah, changing your hardware.
I ran into that when I upgraded video cards. And I was like, oh,
-- thank goodness, I have this printed out. Well,
-- it might be a different computer.
We don't know.
So
that's the thing though is there's like, so many things.
Oh, my perfect Canadian thing is those, you know, in Canada and, well,
you're in America in a cold part.
So you, if it's going to snow,
you typically raise your windshield wipers so that they don't get frozen
to the window and then when you scrape the ice off,
you damage your wiper blades.
And my favorite thing is people posting pictures of cars in,
like indoor heated arcades with their wipers up.
Yep. Yep. Right.
And I mean, maybe one could argue that it's like short, it's like,
just do it every time you park your car in winter.
So it's a habit
and that's a good argument.
And there's not a lot of downside to it because, you know,
you sit in the car and you'll be like, oh, my windshield wipers up, get out,
put them down, go on your day.
But there is a lot of security where people are, like,
like the password rotation thing where n said it was a good idea
and it
kind of sort of maybe was back in the day a little bit, but not really.
And then it turns out to have been a really bad idea with, you know,
it turns out Attackers don't guess, passwords, they just go credential stuffing.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
Now, here's, I think the piece of that that becomes more difficult.
There are a lot of things we all do just because someone
said we should do it and we don't necessarily understand the why
-- this is, I mean security
-- or the how the mechanism.
Well, it's all part of the same, same thing, right?
And I think this is where security is extra weird
because we don't have a lot of like good resources where people
can go and understand why we might do a certain thing.
It's really hard to find this information.
Like a good example is so I want to use a small container base image, right? I agree.
There's, it's a good idea.
You don't want a container image that's like gigabytes in size and it's completely
chocked full of crap, right? Small images. Good idea.
But
why like what does that actually accomplish and what are the actual advantages
other than these people like running around screaming zero CD ES which is nuts.
And now at the same time, like here's one of my favorite examples.
So at work, we use red hats base images for a bunch of stuff.
Red hats ba images are really big
and this has been like a perpetual problem Red Hat
has had is how do we shrink our base images?
-- And we'll say they've struggled to solve this problem.
-- Stupid question.
But why bother
because like, no offense.
But the kind of stuff people install on Red Hat tends to be chunky software.
It often is and, and the stuff we're using is pretty chunky too. So,
and again, this is part of that situation.
Like I'm going to say this, I'm gonna make this bet.
The average person using a Red hat container is not
at all like the average person using an alpine container.
Yes, I agree with that. But here's, here's,
that's the thing I always talk about is every now and then it works.
Someone's like, oh, we should switch to alpine and I'm like, I'm not going to say no,
but we have to understand that that comes with the large engineering burden.
And more importantly,
here's the thing people whine and complain about the findings in a redhead image.
But at the same time,
Red Hat has more security people and a lot of companies have people.
This is true. So there is, there is something in that where every time
there is a security, I mean, Kurt and I were part of this, we,
we have intimate knowledge of this process,
but every time there's a security vulnerability,
a
bunch of people are literally investigating it to
understand exactly how it affects red hats,
containers and operating systems and products.
Well, I mean,
this is why I feel comfortable using a lot of large cloud
providers for very complicated stuff that I just 100% all sorts of
source the risk to them
because yeah, they have a bigger security team than my organization
has people for sure, for sure.
And like, I don't want to, I don't have time to deal with this.
But now at the
same time
there's, there's this other side to that coin,
there are cloud,
there are companies.
Well, I won't say cloud companies,
I'll say there are companies that will say you are exporting your risk to
that don't have a security team at all.
0 100%. I've, I've dealt with them.
I've looked at them
and, you know, since we do things like I'm,
I was actually just looking at one vendor we use um I'll name them prompt.
Perfect. They optimize your A I prompt and feed it into the A I.
No privacy policy. No GDPR. No,
nothing.
-- Yeah,
-- it's probably like three dudes in a garage. I bet.
-- Like maybe two,
-- maybe two,
one
is
like,
so we'll just use it in a way that is air, quote safe, you know,
um to optimize prompts and then we, you know,
if it's sort of something you're doing at scale or with pi I, you know,
I'll probably because we're working on our A I policy,
the CS A and it's funny because it's going to be, I think,
a bit more complicated than usual because I've actually been
using this stuff and doing this stuff and there's,
there's a lot of subtlety and a lot of complicated stuff.
Like, does this thing record your data for training sets? Yes or no.
Um, or can it be configured or, you know, like
how does it cash stuff, blah, blah, blah, all sorts of complicated things.
And especially when you start layering them,
like if I have a Zapper that uses a proper, that uses an open A I Yeah.
-- Now I have three moving parts interacting with us.
-- That's
right.
That's right.
But the, but again, this is where security becomes this like weird behemoth
and, and I I compare it to
like it, it's the hydro, right? You cut off one head and two new heads grow.
And what I mean by that is it's quite common in the security
universe where you have like one obvious problem you're trying to address,
let's say large, like too much crap in my container base image. OK?
So we're gonna use a small image.
But now I have two new problems because now I've got like an image that
the typical security tools don't know what to do with
and
it's maintained by a very,
very small group of people that can't actually properly maintain it.
But then the third problem is I have no idea they can't
maintain it because I don't even know what to look for.
And so this is where it gets nuts.
Well, and this is so like,
and this is some of the back of the envelope sort of calculations I do is I'll look,
I'll look at a github
repo and be like, when was the last commit?
How many kind of old stale issues are there to just get a feel for
it?
And I and I wish there were tools that kind of collected
all these metrics and globed them all together into a usable actual.
Like here's the outcome.
So here's the inputs which ones matter and don't because I actually,
there's a lot of software I use that is old and stale and
that's OK because it's old and stale, like it's just, it's complete.
-- So
-- here's one of my favorites, right?
Is it's becoming hip these days in the security tooling universe to try to
assign some sort of like goodness score to the open source you're using.
There's things like, I mean, we did a whole episode, an open SSF scorecard,
I'll dig it up and put it in the show notes,
but like needless to say we weren't super kind to it because fundamentally the the
point of the episode is basically like this seems clever but does it like does,
does any of this data matter?
And the answer is we don't know,
we have no idea if a high score from the open SSF scorecard means more secure.
We have absolutely no idea. High score could mean less secure. We don't know now,
but here's the fun of it. Right.
So there's all these people trying to assign
like these goodness scores and things like that.
And at the end of the day, let's say you run the score tool against your project
and you see one of your dependencies scored to zero.
What are you going to do? The answer is nothing.
Yeah.
Well, and that's, and then that leads the second thing is,
is any of this actually actionable
and you know, replacing a two or three deep dependency is so much work that no,
you literally can't,
let's say if it's a first cause and this is part of the difficulty, right?
Where you have transitive dependencies being
I installed dependency, A dependency, A installed dependency B,
dependency B installed dependency C
let's say I have a scanning tool that says, hey,
dependency C has a score of negative 12 out of a
total score of a possible score of 0 to 10.
So it's obviously terrible. You should replace it,
but I can't replace dependency A
I I, how do, what do I do? Right?
-- The answer is you're going to do nothing
-- unless you're Google
size and you essentially fork it and bring it in house,
right?
No, that's, that's literally,
and there's like seven companies that can do that.
It's pretty tough for sure. And sorry. Speaking of, sorry, back to the Red Hat days.
The red hat box is still broken if you search for my email address
because it returns too many,
too many bugs.
The list of search results is too long for Bugzilla to display the next pre first,
last buttons on.
Oh, it's actually returning a web page now.
It's been running for a minute or 20,
it's only 2500 entries. That's not as many as I thought.
-- But then
-- we got to kind of start thinking about wrapping this one up a little bit.
Well, I think part of it is
because I do this a lot of the CS A where people are like, hey,
we should do security X and I'm like,
probably, maybe we should let me think about that for a minute and come back to you.
And then sort of my first thought is always, is like,
will this sort of immediately actually make things better and work followed by?
Ok. But like, what if we
do, like, can we do too much of this? Can it become a problem?
Yes,
and followed by like, or is there maybe a better or simpler control?
And so like an example I always go back to is, you know,
the CS A had to take payments for things like the CCS K exam
and right off the bat. I'm like, yeah, we're using like paypal IP N instant payment
notification. So like
you go to our website, you click pay, you get booted over to paypal, you deal with them
and then paypal tells us if you paid the amount or not.
And I'm like,
because I, I just don't want their data, I don't want to deal with this.
That was how,
that was the correct way to secure our payment infrastructure was to
it to paypal.
And then you, you, if you did it yourself,
you have to be PC I compliant and there's like tons of stuff you have to do and it's,
you don't have to be PC I compliant to run a payment system.
No, I mean they check, they,
-- they do check on that like you have to put up a good show if you're
-- not
every major credit card breach happened at the PC I compliant vendor.
-- Look
-- PC I compliance
-- is II I say this about sock two as well.
-- This is the best cargo cult example.
No, it's not a cargo cult. This is the I wash my hands after I use the toilet.
Like it is a very baseline minimum. It doesn't guarantee any security. It just,
it, it makes it. So you verify like the company accepting credit cards
will say like
they, they have,
they have a door on the house, right?
It could still be full of crackheads or something, but at least there is a door
and so it's, it's not necessarily saying you are secure.
It's just saying you meet this very low bar which a lot of places can't.
I mean, I'm just looking at this, the top five PC I compliance breaches. This one was
big.
This 40 million, 15 million.
Look,
I'm not gonna say it's perfect and I'm not gonna
say it's necessarily some like great solution to any problem.
Well, I always wonder like if we did not have PC I would,
things actually be measurably worse
for sure. Kurt, I remember back in the early two thousands,
I worked for this ISP and they had a customer that was basically like, they,
they wanted to accept payments for
buying some. It was like figurines or something.
And this is like back in the early days of like internet shopping, right?
You built them a web form that you typed in all your information.
You like, pick the thing you wanted from the drop down
and we just store the credit card information in a SQL database. Like no encryption.
No nothing.
If someone broke into that database,
they would have had hundreds of credit card
numbers they could have just gone wild with.
And I guarantee without PC I compliance that would be rampant everywhere
and the problems would be magnitudes worse than they are today.
So you would think about how bad it is now
and how I bet it could be.
Well,
it absolutely was because like I dealt with an ISP
where they had a guy with three credit card terminals,
physically punching numbers into them, spitting out a little receipt.
And I'm like,
-- he's like, this is how we do our credit cards. And I'm like,
-- in
fact,
the ISP I worked for, we did the same thing.
We kept credit card numbers in a spreadsheet when people sent them to us.
And then the, the person at the front desk that was,
that was their job on the last day of the month was to
go to the credit card machine and type in all the numbers.
Yes,
I'm familiar with this.
So I, I guess what we're saying is things could be worse.
I mean, everything
-- slowly get better ish.
-- I mean, look, I think if you, ok,
here's how I'm going to end this because I feel like
as humans,
it's very easy to have doom and gloom
about everything and especially as security people,
it's easy to have doom and gloom about everything.
Where if you, in fact, I,
I got an argument about this with someone just the other day where they
were talking about how like everything is broken and nothing can ever be fixed.
And I'm like, do you bank online?
-- I was actually gonna go with like, have you experienced humanity?
-- But
here's
the
thing,
traffic, if you look at like every measurable data point of society in humans,
they're all fundamentally going up into the right
and it's easy to get hung up on the bad and the dumb and the terrible,
especially if you're a security nerd, which goodness knows we are.
But at the end of the day,
things are better than they were a decade ago.
And I'm mostly confident
we'll see after the next election.
But I'm mostly confident
that 10 years from now it will be even better.
And like, yes, there are difficulties and there are challenges
but
this is just, this is how it works being like a squishy bag of meat that smells funny.
Like this is, this is humans, you know.
Well, just, you know, as bad as traffic is, it's, it works,
it does work. It does. I know
-- most
-- of the
world, I know
most of the world.
I,
I don't.
That's it. That's all I have to say.
Mhm. I'll let, I'll let you close this one out.
-- Then I
-- just, I, I keep coming back to when I'm doing things.
I, I try to sometimes look at like, why am I doing this?
What do I actually want it to accomplish? And does it do that?
That's a good point because I've also noticed a lot of people,
I'll, I'll notice a behavior security wise.
And I'm like, like, what are you trying to do? Like accomplish
and they're like
security.
I'm like, no, you gotta be more specific and, and you know,
and sometimes it is in line with what they
actually want to accomplish and other times I'm like,
how about we do this completely other thing, like,
just outsource this and they're like,
oh, yeah.
Yeah, that would fair.
That's fair. I would argue with that. I do think, like, security is not an end state.
No, it's like, it's like being healthy.
-- Yeah,
-- we forget that sometimes. Like, the
security, like, we're not the most important group in the company
and, like, security isn't a solution.
It
is just part of the journey.
Well, my favorite thing is like, uh a good example is nuclear weapon security.
Something the US takes very seriously and has for a long time, like for example,
permissive action links, which,
you know, we're gonna put codes on all the nukes so that
somebody can't go rogue with them. But can't,
we do want
people to be able to use them. So we'll set them all to zero.
So the P
code was 00000 for the longest time now. They actually have real numbers. But,
uh, like a great thing is look at like a convoy of, uh,
of them moving up a missile on American highways and it is bonkers,
like there's helicopters, there's multiple vehicles and everything
and
like
this is, it's not like the,
like the US spends tens of billions of dollars a year on this.
Yeah, that's just how this works.
Like you want security, you gotta,
you gotta keep exercising and eating your vegetables
and security is the same way.
And also you can't just keep doing the same thing
either because the Attackers evolve and the systems evolve.
Like
two years ago, we didn't have to worry about A I security.
No, like, seriously, like two years ago, prompt injection wasn't even,
hadn't been coined as a term.
-- It was coined like, what, 18 months ago,
-- prompt injection is the best.
I love it anyway. All right, I'm cutting you off
it. We'll talk about prompt injection some other day because it's a marvelous,
ignore all previous instructions and do what I say.
No, I'm ending the podcast. That's what I'm doing. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go up. It's our Security podcast.com U
Pounds S podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon.
Kurt. Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks, everyone. Bye bye.