Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
-- Kurt Siefried and my unwilling life coach partner, Josh
-- Pressers.
Oh, you actually used it. I didn't think you do that.
Yes.
-- Yes. And
-- we're talking about potholes today
and no, we are not talking, oh my goodness, not potholes. Well, you're in a pothole
pothole.
I will, I will preface this by saying it is July 10th when we are recording this.
So basically one full week before the show is going out and PP just sent
the email to the top 1% Python projects saying you have to enable to vector
off. And there has been
an enormous amount of discussion about this particular issue.
And our favorite co-host,
Kurt found himself embroiled and we'll say an annoying argument.
I wouldn't say it was annoying.
Ok. Well, it wasn't totally annoying.
You were accused of something that wasn't your intent, we'll say,
and it's because you could have worded it better,
but
we will not dwell on this point. We will just stress the fact
that
sometimes Twitter is a bad place to have discussions.
Part of the challenge is it is 100 and 80 100 and 60 characters and
it's like 240 now,
whatever. It's still short.
And,
yeah, I know
that, like, Totp doesn't need your phone number. I
-- was talking about like S MS two fa or
-- I understand that in general,
if you're going to ship something to somebody,
you generally need to know where to ship it.
-- And I know that you don't plug your address into your hardware key.
-- I know.
Anyway, anyway, doesn't matter.
I don't,
I do want to talk about Python though because I think
what pipe is doing is fascinating for a number of reasons.
OK. So basically they are requiring two fa for the top 1% of packages.
And I assume by top 1% they mean like by
-- uh download popularity
-- by bi weekly downloads,
that's how they're measuring it right now.
It's in, it's in their blog post.
-- OK?
-- I got, I got to go write a script then and get in there,
right.
So just target the top 2% now and you're fine.
They're basically mandating two fa for this top 1%.
And let's preface the show by saying I support two factor authentication.
Look, I'm going to preface it with saying I support what pa
pa is doing.
Yes, I was about to go there.
-- I
-- just think there's larger discussions around it and
what I
was getting to is I also support the idea of two
fa for things that matter.
And also for things that don't matter that much because in general two
fa good not to fa bad
and to be even more clear hardware, two of a best
software. Two fa on your phone. It's ok. It's not great. It's not bad.
I mean, the one advantage is you can back it up and
that's hard to do with hardware tokens unless you have multiple tokens and
keep them off site, blah, blah, blah.
So
to be clear, I I want do we did the show on N PM?
What was the other one that was forcibly doing two fa was it?
So anyways, and we like, we agree with this,
but it's clear that the, the how is uh we need to work on that?
Well, OK, look. So I think there's a couple of pieces to this
and,
and there's the angle of the logistics and difficulty of developers using
two fact Roth because there have been a number of developers,
some high profile developers who basically came out and said, OK,
so you're making me do this. I don't really want to
um someone deleted what one of a very popular package as a
at all my crew, right?
And but in fairness, he also said that like you shouldn't be using it,
you should be using, there's like two system built ins now that do a better job.
And he was like, and also he didn't mean to actually delete it.
He's like, I wanted to archive it or whatever and it like the,
like
in fairness,
stuff like archiving it or removing your package.
-- Most people don't do that very often before you died
-- down this rattle.
So
there's the just logistics of dealing with the developers, right.
And that's its own conversation. I think
there's the question of
what are the attacks this will solve because there's a lot of people,
especially like on Twitter.
-- So,
-- what's the benefit?
-- Well,
-- well, basically, yes, they're, they're decrying this
as a pans.
And it's like this really only solves one very narrow
-- set of attacks.
-- It actually solves two attacks on the same thing which is quasi
three if they choose a really bad password. But basically it solves
account takeovers via bad passwords or revealed passwords.
So that means uh number one brute forcing or stuffing the password. So, like
they reuse a password or something or
1234, don't do that.
Number two, they somehow reveal or leak the password, for example,
through phishing.
And number three, just good old brew forcing,
which if you're choosing even a remotely same password is not a problem nowadays.
Right. Right.
And, and
many of the, uh, well, some of the stories in recent, we'll say months
have revolved around account takeovers.
Some, we know some we don't,
but like one was a researcher that found
all these N PM packages with expired domains.
But if you have a, an account recovery process for two factor
off which piye does. If you take over the account,
you just recover the two factor codes like it, it doesn't fix that.
So,
and that leads to something I've been talking about a
lot and I actually have previous threat models on.
So for example, at the CS A, we allow
you to uh well, when you, when you
start working here,
we have to email you your like user name and password so you can log in and do your job.
So we obviously need your personal email and password.
And we allow
people to link that to their CS A account for
recovery and also to apply their own phone number for recovery
because it's less work for me. So I like it.
Um, but it actually turns out that that is, that is basically the biggest
threat that we have is
somebody attacks the person's personal account and then uses it to do
account recovery because otherwise the CS A is super locked down.
But there's like this back door that
has to be there for account recovery.
And, and that's the thing is, I don't care how good your security is.
If you have an account recovery mechanism that is weak
and they are all weak because they rely on
an email address.
That's
like it's
99% of these account recovery systems boil down to.
We have your email address,
we send you an email with a link or some secret or whatever, but it boils down to, if you
have access to that email address,
you can do a recovery of whatever is using that email address.
U usually the only ones going kind of beyond that are one of my
favorite stories is with Instagram where like you will basically hold up a picture
with like a number written on it because they have
like a pile of photos of you so they can like
make sure it's you.
Facebook is doing the thing with the social
graph where it's like you can nominate like,
OK, three of these five people
can be allowed to, you know,
so like
look,
identity is super hard and I don't want this to turn into an identity discussion.
-- Let's just say it's really hard.
-- So the reality is recovery is
a massively weak link. But yeah, two of a doesn't do crap or,
and that ignores the fact that also normal people
don't register domains and run the rain email.
A lot of devs do
weirdly who knew,
right? It, it is true. I both of us have our own domains.
I'm sure many of our listeners do as well.
My domain is old enough to drink.
I
registered mine in 2001. 0, wow. Mine is 21. Wow.
-- Anyway,
-- well, a great example of this is, I mean, yeah, like you said,
somebody went through the note data and found how many domains that were expired,
linked to packages
-- it
-- was thousands
like like bit rod is real.
Like I'm just going through the CV data and there are now 25 CV S that
link to the GSD because I registered some domain names and pointed them at the GSD.
You know, there's,
there's a ton of dead domains or non working domains and CV like that,
that's just a thing like this data is 5, 1020 years old.
It happens, right? The other challenge is two fa
definitely prevent things like fishing. But
we've seen cases where, you know, somebody hijacks the developer's workstation.
-- I don't
-- want to get into all the attacks.
There, there's one other really important piece of this though.
Kurt, you haven't, we haven't gotten to yet
and we're, we're going to run ourselves out of time.
I think the attack thing we need to do a little more work on and
we should discuss that because I don't think we know all the attacks and I think
there are,
I, I feel like we need something like, you know,
there's like the miter attack framework, we need that for the supply chain.
And I don't know if someone knows of this.
-- Like, please let me know
-- technically it should fall under attack.
-- But yeah, it's, it's, I think
-- it's, I don't know if it does.
I think supply chain is important enough and special enough to be its own thing.
I agree. I agree. I think it should have its own
and, and the third thing is one of uh there was a developer,
um I think an alpine dove basically said,
what, what, what comes next and it's, it's that concern of
like this dial only goes one way. So it's two factor off today.
What is the next thing
that everyone's gonna say
I should do as an open source developer. Is it signing things? Is it SIG store? Is it?
You know what I mean?
Well, like are we gonna,
are we gonna force to have store an endpoint control
software to make sure they have up to date antivirus?
Exactly this, like where does it stop?
And I think that's also a very legitimate concern
because it's easy to say, oh, you're just fear mongering.
-- But like this again, this dial goes one way for the most part to
-- me.
Two fa is a natural extension of passwords and I think passwords are
kind of well established that we have to do that.
Like whether we like it or not because
people will try and access other people's accounts and
they didn't learn the lesson in kindergarten of
don't touch other people's stuff without permission.
But on the other hand, yeah, I mean, do we get to a point where they require devs,
they were talking about how some projects now require your
background checks for new developers of kind of core things.
And I mean,
Josh and I are old enough that we come
from a world where you just started submitting patches.
-- That's, that's how you got in.
-- That's still how it works in most projects.
-- I mean, that's just the reality of it.
-- Almost no projects can go that far. They just
like, if let's be real, if you send me a high res scan of your US passport. Cool.
Like, I guess it looks like one,
like how, how
I think they're blue,
like, right. I don't know how to validate a passport from America.
And so that's the other challenges even if a project
has the capability and has the resources to do this,
like or not the capability but has the wherewithal to do this.
They now have to have the capability to do this.
And what do you do if one of your developers is in
like Kazakhstan or some random place and doesn't have a passport?
Like he's going to send you in his Costco card.
I, I've literally seen people use their Costco card as ID because it has a photo on it.
It's grainy but it's there. Oh, interesting.
The chances of somebody having a fake Costco card are like pretty slim.
-- Like it's
-- probably pretty low. I agree with that.
And that's part of the challenge here is it's,
it's we need to reel you beckon because you went too far and this is what you do
fly, I'm here saying endpoint, whatever like in I DS, they ignore that.
Let's just say it's multi factor off.
But in a year, you're gonna have N PM and pipe say, OK,
developers now you have to sign everything with SIG star,
right?
And that is going to happen. I I guarantee it.
And so now developers are like now I have to do more work
or even simpler. Hey, you know, your github
-- repos, they have to require, you know, signed
-- commits.
Uh And, and that will, that might happen too. Actually, we, we tried to do that at
Acor and it didn't go well. So we turn that off.
It worked with a DEV team of five people.
Let me put it that way, like with five people, you can do it.
But that was one thing with five people like doing this across.
Well, the top 1% of Python like
that.
Yeah, that's probably not going to fly with a few percent.
And that's the other problem is this is dealing with large numbers, like we say,
1% of Python.
Like it's like what seven things, I mean, how much, really,
how many packages could there be?
But 1% of pie, pie is, how many
-- is it? Thousands or tens of thousands of
-- packages,
-- 350,000 packages in pi
-- pie. So 3500 packages,
that's
times more than one dev often per package especially.
Well, by definition, from popular stuff. They actually have
groups,
you know, same thing with note what 2 million packages, some of them have,
they're over 2 million now.
Jeez.
Wow.
And that's the thing, right. This is
3500 packages times. I don't know how many devs I'd have to look, I'm guessing 5 to 10
ish. I'm, you know,
that sounds about right.
-- No,
-- no,
-- no. Yeah,
-- exactly. I'm making stuff up.
I have a graph somewhere.
The V,
like half, half of these, half of those have one development.
I'm not surprised. So, I mean, you gotta keep that in mind. So 1500
developers plus
whatever the multiples are after that. And of course, there's some overlap.
But let's say, let's say 3000 developers, let's say 2000 developers.
It doesn't matter.
That's a lot of freaking people.
Well, and probably 1% of them are on vacation right now.
Hopefully more actually now that I say that,
I mean, we've talked about this on previous shows but it just,
these are large numbers, these are people.
It's complicated
here.
We, we're proving our point
because
there's a lot of moving pieces in this. There's a lot of complexity.
Some people are going to see two factor, I should be everywhere, no questions asked.
Some people are going to say, I don't want this crap, take it away. I I don't want it.
And then you've got people in the middle that are like,
what's actually going on here?
Like what does this, what is the problem we're trying to solve?
How does this solve it?
And what are the new problems it creates when we do this?
See, and that's the thing that came up on Twitter is people are like, well,
but shouldn't more security be.
It's a
good enough argument and it's like, well,
you could glue your doors shut and that would be more secure. But
that's a dumb argument. I have a better one.
So, in my city I think I've told this story on the podcast before.
So if you've heard it, I apologize.
We in my city we have a what we call the large item drop off where like if you have a big,
like a couch or something,
you need to throw away you and bring it to the city
and they have the big dumpster and you throw it in,
right?
And it used to just be, you could drive up and chuck stuff in and leave no big deal.
And then people were complaining
that
individuals who didn't live in the city who weren't citizens were
coming and dumping their stuff off. And so
the solution
was they now you can only drop stuff off two
days a week and they have a person sitting there
that's checking I DS.
And so the question becomes,
is the price of like employing and paying
this person larger than the additional garbage.
You know what I mean?
Like,
I don't know the answer to this and I asked them
-- and they won't tell me
-- and some people would argue,
you know, there's the moral aspect, the ethical aspect.
And also it's a,
it's a slippery slope like you let one guy dump a couch from out of state and it's like,
oh, pretty soon you're like, knee deep and
finding tractors or whatever people are dropping off.
Like, from my perspective,
I really only care about the cost, whichever one is cheaper. Do that one.
Well, and also the convenience.
Like it sounds like when you just had a big dumpster that you went through stuff in.
That's true. It is inconvenient.
Now,
we have sort of these micro eco stations locally where it's
like 40 or 50 dumpsters that take like paper box,
cardboard, blah, blah, blah.
And there's lots of signs saying this,
you know, it's video monitor, no dumping, blah, blah, blah.
And it's great because I
it's less work to just because I happen to live really close to one.
It's way less work to throw my cardboard in the trunk of my car
and throw it in there than it is like try and cut it or fold it up and,
you know, stuff it up.
The
same thing
we have, we have the same thing.
We have a place I can bring my cardboard and yeah,
my cardboard all goes there because it's a pain in the butt otherwise.
So, but back to this, like part of it too is I think people are conflating.
Prevention is often better than the cure and if we can prevent things,
bad things from happening, that's,
well, that's good.
Yeah, I don't want a ton of account takeovers in us having to clean up
ungodly messes where, you know,
somebody slips a back door into a popular package and it gets deployed to 1000.
Right.
Different things that depend on it and all your,
basically all of our IOT light bulbs try to kill us on Thursday
part of it is there's a difference between a black swan event and
should we build a fence to keep out the black Swans?
Because for example, one argument uh I was
looking at is
we know that there are account takeovers that is through password shenanigans.
Let's call it.
There's definitely
for the sake of argument,
let's say there's at least one documented case per major ecosystem like pi pi node,
whatever, right?
Github,
whatever.
But there's not many, there's like literally,
it's a very
small and I was thinking about this and I'm like, well, OK, number one,
couldn't you then argue that like they're doing a
pretty good job keeping the bad guys out,
right? Like, I mean, if there's only like one, then
apparently we're not doing that terrible of a job.
But number two is I was then I was like thinking, OK, well, incentive wise like
is pi pie?
Are there account takeovers happening that we don't know about?
Well,
maybe
are there account takeovers happening that we,
but the security PP, people know about
that. They're not telling us and I find that really improbable.
-- I mean, I, I would hope that they'd be proud of that and talk about it.
-- Exactly. And,
and, and it's, you can't hide this stuff. Like
when, when somebody puts in, you know,
a thing in the code that says infinite loop back door, it's kind of,
it's kind of obvious, you know, when somebody takes out the authentication,
it's like that's not, these attacks are not
quiet. It's not like
what like solar winds like what?
Like it blows my mind that solar winds looked at this and like, oh whatever,
just like smash that install button and ignore the signature being all screwed up.
These are not quite attacks,
not, not in the open source world. I think the vast majority of
attacks like this that have happened have been caught very quickly open source.
-- And I think it's one of the superpowers open source has
-- we've talked
about three or four of them on the show over the years.
Yeah.
And I mean, I'll, I'll,
I'll take that message to the grave is just like the
open source has a superpower and this is it because people,
people notice this stuff.
Well, not that they, you can notice it and,
and there are generally channels to shout about it.
Channels, Twitter,
I mean
it
but
right, I, I agree. I agree. Well, although github
is now going to include malware
in their advisories,
which is great.
I, I love that. CV just categorically refuses to cover backdoors in Malware.
-- It's like cool
-- because no, we're not talking about that today.
That could be another episode.
That could probably be a series of 700 episodes, but don't do that.
So, ok, now here's, here's what it comes down to, I think and, and, and
I don't wanna, I feel like we've been all over the place on this show.
But I think at the end of the day,
the question is really what, what is pi po developers? And what is PPO users? Right?
Because you can make the argument
that
not enforcing multi factor
off is doing a disservice to the users.
You can make the argument,
enforcing multi factor off is a disservice to the developers.
But at the end of the day, the way I see it,
Pie Pie is an open source project that gets to do what they want to do.
And if you don't like it,
like go build your own pie pie.
You know,
-- you
-- and I come from the world before Pie Pie. I remember when I first ran into C pan
-- the Comprehensive Pearl Archive Network.
-- Oh
-- my
-- goodness. C
is so
so good.
-- Like if I wanted something, I went and found a tar ball and you know,
-- that's right. C
A was magic when C
A came out, I was like,
do you remember there was a whole
Riley book just on C
A.
Yeah.
Well,
I remember installing Paarl dependencies manually and
upgrading them manually and managing them manually
and using that tar wrapper program that would basically like look at your system,
you would install something
and it would look at your system again and then
build a tar ball of like those installed binaries.
So the
poor man's binary packager,
you know, like the challenge is,
and I think the one developer wrote a really good blog post.
And basically because I've had this happen,
I remember handling security vulnerability with somebody who started out
making documentation fixes and then basically six months later,
ended up as the primary developer of this package.
Yes,
I recall this, this poor person,
there was like a remote code execution flaw in this library
and
they're like 20 years old, 21 years old
and they're panicking. They're like, am I going to get sued? Am I going to get like
killed?
I'm like, I'm freaking out man and I'm like, it's OK. Breathe, it'll be OK.
Trust me, it's Thursday. This happens all the time
and this person didn't start out to
be in charge of a critical package.
And, and this other developer pointed out, you know, I wrote some software
like it's my fault, people like it and use it everywhere.
And now I'm supposed to be held to some
higher, like the same standard as Microsoft for Windows.
It's
like, really?
Have you ever seen some of the letters that open
source develop posted after log the log for shell an open
source project got a letter from like a, a bank that was like,
please provide answers to these questions.
They were like
no,
which, but you know,
I that's the thing is this is again where the knob only turns one way.
So Popeye says you have to use two factor off.
Then Popeye says you have to,
you have to sign your packages and Popeye says you have to sign your commits and
you know what I mean? It's gonna,
it, it, it adds up and, and as an open source developer at one point or you're like,
screw it, I'm just sick of all this crap.
I don't want to do this anymore.
I wanted to write a library and it was fun and now I'm doing freaking maintenance on
-- stuff. Pipe tells me I need to do well.
-- And this leads to two big things that
I haven't seen people talking about, which is number one is like,
could we do this better?
That's not what it is. And number two,
what about the companies? Well, no, no, I'm getting there.
I'm gonna throw them under the bus in a second.
So the first thing is like, could we do this better?
And could we talk to the developers and engage with
them and find out a better way to do this?
And here's the, the sad truth.
The answer is no, because there's like a kaji developers,
even if you sampled a statistically relevant
sample size of like 51 or 2%. That's,
that's thousands of people.
I, I have a great example of this. I want you to get 20 people in a room
and get everyone to agree where to eat.
Well, no, no, you don't have to get them to agree what to eat.
Get those 20 people to actually clearly describe what
kind of food they like and don't like.
Oh, there you go. That's fair.
Then you get to find three options to present to the group.
-- Ah,
-- that sounds exciting. And then not get beaten to death with chairs.
So,
and that's the thing, right.
And then, and the second thing is like, are there other ways to do this,
are there other ways to accomplish these goals?
I don't know.
And that involves a whole pile of threat modeling and sophistication and
-- stuff we don't have as a community.
-- I want to add one really important point.
Here is the poor pai pai people are on the, they're on the worst end of this stick in
every possible direction. And they're,
they are doing the best they can with the tools they have. And so by all means,
-- they're doing a fabulous job. No one pick on
-- them. I use pi pie daily like it.
It's great.
-- Yeah, it's amazing.
-- And then this leads to
none of this matters for
two simple reasons. One
companies like free stuff.
Right. They, they, they look like I can write a web server. I can use a free one. Great,
which has a corollary of
what they don't have a choice. They can't write a web server anymore.
Like they have to go download flask or Apache or engine X or whatever.
This assumes that they're coming into this. No, they're not. They're already here.
They, they can't leave. That's the second thing like they're
like, they're in too deep,
you know, they owe
$57,000 and the vig is due on Thursday and it's 75%
like they're stuck.
Well, and, and look, here's,
here's part of the thing that I think about on this all
the time is there's all these companies using all this open source
and
they're the ones demanding this kind of stuff
like open
source nerds aren't demanding multi factor
A,
it's, it's functionally companies that are worried about their supply chain.
That's one thing I was kind of wondering about because
here's the reality.
If, if this two fa was so awesome and so wonderful, Popeye could just say, hey,
we giving away free two fa tokens.
So the top 1% you know,
-- like here's
-- the form they literally are giving away free two fa tokens.
No, but what I'm saying is make it voluntary, not mandatory. That's the
D and because if this was so awesome, they would go do it
seven people would sign up if you did it
-- maybe less.
-- Exactly.
So clearly this doesn't make their lives better and less hassle and,
ok, whatever. That's a, that's a fair point. But I do think
this is one of those examples of, I'm comfortable forcing two factor oath on people
just because we can,
and it's not worse, but I also recognize it's, it's a hard thing to do.
What's ironic is the, the situation where the developer, you know,
gets fed up and leaves
is an existing problem we have to deal with,
like with the colors dot Js with the um what was the other one?
The guy nuked anyways.
So where these developers, you know,
either
put a back door in or, or more commonly just like,
don't maintain it because they have a life,
you know,
that was someone I think Tide Lift did a survey
of open source developers and it was like half of open
source developers basically said, like I'm becoming
incredibly frustrated managing my project and I want to quit.
I will never do an open
source project. Like I will never do an open source software project ever again.
Or rather I will, I, I do do open
source project. Like I have open source software that I release, but
I, I'm just absolutely done caring about what people want.
Like I, I really
sent
her the A PL two. Good luck.
Like, unless that bug fix affects me, I'm not fixing it, you can fork it.
I'm
not
like I will never be nice again. I'm just done.
No,
I,
I've seen too much abuse of these people.
I've seen too many people burn out and I've seen too many people just
like, come on. We worked at Red Hat.
We, we saw what some of these developers went through. It was,
I, I see it all the time now when you're, when you're dealing with, I mean,
there are projects where the developers are
very overworked and they're very underappreciated.
I mean, one of my, one of my favorite examples of that was
uh the guy who does Jackson data bin and
Tau,
he, he, he's, I don't know what he's doing now,
but I remember talking to him at one point
and he was just like, I don't have time. I'm busy, I'm burnt out.
Like I really don't care about this.
And it was, I mean,
I was trying to help is what I was doing in that particular instance,
but like I totally get it.
And that's, I mean, Jackson data bind is used in everything.
Well, if it's Java and it's moving data around, it's
how is he going to do it?
And so anyway,
I think that's one of the angles of this that I'm not seeing anyone discuss is
adding
responsibility to open source maintainers.
It is a very lopsided agreement because you're saying you
should do this extra work that you're already doing for free
and you get no benefits from doing it.
-- Well,
-- the problem is responsibilities, create obligations,
right? Like
I want two fa so you have to do two fa
I've now created an obligation. I've created a work for you.
I've created something new for you to do.
And that's the challenge here is the security. Things are not simply
somehow just
there, but they don't impact the end developers. They do impact the end developers.
Everybody's like, oh, it's not that bad.
You just have to load like a piece of software on your phone, your
phone,
get a free two fa key. OK? Cool. Except, oh, wait, now I got to back up my phone.
So I have my two fa
well, but I got, I wanted the hardware keys because they're more secure. But
like what if my house burns down? Well,
so they, the pi pie fact they will send you two hard work
-- for that reason.
-- Actually. Fun fact.
That's how Google Titan works. The Google Titan keys come in a pair
full stop because Google's like they're engineers and they're like,
everybody needs two keys.
I bought one Titan
key when I went to buy it, they only sold them in pairs.
You got the, you get the, the, the like the big one and the little one.
-- No, when I bought it, I just got the white one that plugs into the USB
-- C
part.
I have one
in my case. I have a UB key at the bank.
I have a UB key on my key chain and I have a Titan key at
-- my desk
-- and I actually,
I have a calendar entry where I need to go get my safety deposit box, go into it,
get the UB key,
come back home, register it with a bunch of new services
and then schlep it back to the bank and
that is,
that's like an hour or two of my time.
Oh,
I bet it's more than that. But no, I, I agree. I hear you. It's, it's not free.
And I, I always think about uh
there was a time I was working with a developer on some TLS stuff
and we were discussing generating certificates.
They were like, I don't understand why people say this is so hard.
You just run a couple of commands and open SSL and you're done.
-- And I'm like, oh my goodness. No, that is so not what happens here.
-- Like
you gotta edit your Openness cell
con figure
-- first
-- you have to search stack overflow for how to generate a
certificate and then you copy and paste exactly what's in stack over
and then it fails because you're open as a cell.com wants the state and not the,
I forget what I always had to edit back in the day. And,
and, and this is similar, this is not as simple as people make it out to be.
It's simple for us because we're security nerds. We do this all the freaking time.
-- It's one of those
-- classic, it's easy. If you know how to do it,
it's still not easy.
Well, if you know how to do it,
you know what keywords to plug into Google to get the stack
over food
or you know what,
you know, what else is going to happen.
There are going to be people who only
publish their Python package once or twice a year
and they're going to completely forget how to do all this stuff.
You have to remem
where they kept the U BC. And
that
was my,
that was my biggest argument against requiring open source to become
like AC NA A CV numbering authority to do CV.
S because
a lot of these projects do like
one security vulnerability a quarter.
Like, unless you're doing something at least weekly, you're gonna forget
every year.
I have to kind of relearn how to mow my lawn because it's been six months and it's like,
uh,
you know, did I go around and then back and forth? Did I go and like, uh,
what
was the best way? And then I hit the tree root and I'm like, oh, that's right.
I go this way to avoid the stupid tree root,
you know.
Right. Oh, it makes a horrible noise when the blade of the mower hits it
-- that you just keep doing it. And eventually it is I
-- that, but the tree is growing.
-- Uh
-- not if you keep hitting it.
So,
and that's the thing, right is,
that's a great example of you,
you're requiring an additional action maybe once a
quarter or once a month from people.
And now that actually they have to look up how to do it, they have to blah, blah, blah.
And now, you know, something that
if you know how to do it, it's super easy and takes 30 seconds.
Now it's 5, 1020 minutes,
I'll do it after dinner if I get around to it.
And then I, I've done that. Oh, I forget, I've got some project
that
I forgot how to
cut a release or something on. And I just like, kind of quit because
I don't remember how to do it.
That was it.
But ok, so I wanna, I wanna wrap this one up because we've been all over the place.
But I think fundamentally at the end of the day, what,
what I think all of this really comes down to
is
if this is what PP wants to do and I applaud
them for taking initiative in this specific area because I think
like security is hard
and there's a lot of things we can do.
I do think we also need to obviously keep, keep tabs on like, what is this
like, how many attacks is it stopping? What does it look like?
Are the attacks getting better or worse or whatever?
But that, that's another conversation.
-- So
-- like some sort of global security,
database of things that are security related in a database, something like that.
But, but anyway, the point is like
pipe pie can do this.
And that's great. Like, and if you don't like it
either, start your own, get involved in pi pie and help them.
But here's a problem or failure to know is so when a Dev refuses to do this,
what happens to the package?
Do they forcibly
revoke ownership of it?
And
that's a great question
and, and it'll probably happen with the 3000 developers like
it'll happen more than once
and and not only that, here's the thing like,
so what happens if you have 3000 developers and let's say 1% of them 300
every month
or 30 not 300
but let's say 30 a month have to reset their two factor
off
and right now you open an issue.
So I mean, that's one of the other things you have to think of at the at the scale.
Yeah, that's how pipe pye is doing.
-- You open an issue with them to reset your two factor
-- odd.
-- So they do like a manual reset.
-- It's
-- probably
-- human. It's very human. It looks like
which is safer than automated because you can potentially weed out.
That's like saying because if we have humans do the code reviews,
they'll review the code.
No, they hit that like, yeah, looks fine button.
Well, and that's fair.
Well,
-- probably
-- we use a password manager at the CS A and every
time a new person signs in or does an account reset,
I get an email saying, like,
so and so wanted to set up their count or do a password reset.
And I'm like, ok, like, I don't talk to them and hunt them down and be like,
did you really mean to do that?
No, I just, that
I
-- don't have time to
-- actually that, that, that could be fair.
I don't know what their process will be. I hope it's not just click. Ok.
-- But it might be, which is obviously bad. But
-- what are they gonna do? Like,
like,
like the government send me a pin number in the mail
to make sure I still live there and then I plug that
into the
website anyway.
And to be clear, I'm not accusing pipe pye of collecting people's addresses.
-- Oh my God.
-- Stop
that. Why do you keep doing this?
This is, see, you're not allowed to talk about that anymore. That's your problem.
Just stop talking about that particular point and you'll be fine.
So the, the point is, but that's the point, right?
If you do account, recover properly,
-- it's a inexpensive, heavy process.
-- Yeah, that's true. That's true. And so anyway,
the point is the point of all this,
like,
I will be interested to see what this all looks like in a year or two.
Once I think it's maybe more scaled out than we're seeing because
we
as security people love to talk about like the incredible benefits of two factor.
Often there are many places that has great benefits. But I think
too much of what we do is what I call smart people. That think something is a good idea,
-- like
-- password rotation
if we do this. Right. And that's, that's exactly it right
where a smart person thought that was a good idea.
And once research was done and we had data, we can say no, this was a terrible idea.
And I think everything we're doing now,
it concerns me because there's way too much smart people think this is a good idea
and not enough, let's actually treat this as a scientific problem
and look at it using reason and research and the
-- scientific method and we are not doing that
-- well.
And it's actually harder than that because there's 2nd and 3rd order effects
that will only show up at scale. Because if something is,
for example, if something is one in a million, OK, that's two in the note ecosystem.
And maybe it doesn't matter.
And,
but maybe it does because those two packages are like left pad or shift or whatever,
right. And that's the problem is
part of this has to be sort of this experimental
like throw it at the wall and see what sticks.
But again, maybe we can do it a little more
gently. Like I, I perfect example,
I look at this and I'm like, why didn't they just make this voluntary?
-- And, and see if like, just see if did seven people sign up or 700 it is
-- voluntary today.
Well, it's voluntary in the sense if you don't do it, we kick you out.
Well, ok, that is not voluntary.
But I'm saying like today you can turn on two factor off in your Pi Pye account
and like, I have a pipe Pye account and I haven't done it because it's, I,
I can't be bothered.
-- Like,
-- I, I think github
did it in a good way, for example, where you can apply
to fa at the organization level and at an organization level,
that's kind of
like more of a dunbar number of people where it's not so horrifying.
Maybe, I don't know.
And I think
maybe
I feel like part of the challenge here too is when you,
it's like, Sweden, when they went from uh right hand to left hand driving,
right.
And it was like, they had a massive plan, you know, at three in the morning,
all the traffic stopped and
stuff and like, you know, they had like, you had like 30 or 40 minutes to like,
basically do a u-turn with all your cars and like, and,
but you weren't allowed to drive, like,
you're allowed to basically do a u-turn point the other way, get everything ready
and then at like four o'clock or whatever in the morning traffic recommences.
And I feel like
that's,
it's not going to work real well or gracefully or painlessly.
And I think we need to find better ways to kind
of roll out these new security solutions to people because,
huh. Fun fact. One time.
Oh, my, this is, this is one of the things I will forever be shameful of.
We're getting a whole bunch of email phishing at the CS A, especially Office Docs.
So I had a bright idea. And what was that? Do you think?
-- You, did you block the office Docs? No,
-- I'm not that stupid.
I proposed that we block the office Docs.
And then
did you work for the CS A? I'm sorry. It's on the record.
I've apologized via email and in Slack it was a bad idea. Ok.
And yeah, like, luckily I wasn't dumb enough to just go block it.
I, I actually kind of floated the idea and how did it get slapped down hard fast?
I can imagine
they were right, because the, the solution would have,
the cure would have been way worse than the disease,
you know?
And that's what I worry here
is that I don't think they're going to do irreparable damage.
But does this solve a problem? Is this the best way to do it?
Well, it does solve a problem.
But is the, the question isn't that we know it solves a problem? Is the,
is the pain and suffering of implementing this.
-- When your data set is one that doesn't,
-- there
-- are
-- not a lot of these attacks. I agree.
I think things like uh uh type of squatting is vastly more dangerous, but also
we literally don't know how to fix that. Today.
I actually had a thought about that and it was simple
when you register a corporate name in most jurisdictions,
they check for similar sounding or spelled names and and stop it.
And the flip side is that doesn't work across jurisdictions.
So for example,
there is a standard General here in Alberta
that is like a massive company that does paving
and there's like a Scheer
contractor out in eastern Canada that registered that name in his province.
And people think it's
like the same company because what's the standard general? Right? I got you.
And it's not, it's like some total Scheer
guy who's totally ripped off people,
but we don't have that problem. We have a single jurisdiction.
It's pipe.org like you want to live in that name space, you play by their rules.
And so for example,
they could implement rules that say things like, ok,
we're gonna deal with cosmic bit flips so
we're gonna generate every possible like off by one
name for your package
and that's not allowed anymore. Like that's now reserved.
We could, for example, like do the Scrabble thing of like, you know,
these letters look too much alike,
man. This is, this is a hard problem. We're out of time.
I'm not, I'm not willing to say it is. I think you're done in Kruger
this, well, I'm pointing out that it's not impossible to solve.
I don't know that this would solve it. But
again, unless we sort of talk about it and try it in a
hypothetical situation, we don't know.
I think this is why we need a tech because we need the ability to
look at this
-- more holistically I think.
-- Well, here's a good example. No, no example
is
very simple. What if Pi Pie
actually logged all the requests for packages that
don't exist and published that data set?
That would be very interesting to be honest with you.
Number one Attackers would be like he,
-- yeah. Now I know it's a typo squat,
-- right?
But number two, we could actually see like how common or
-- problematic is this
-- typos
anyway. All right. I'm calling this one man. This was, this was fun.
We were all over the place, but it was fun. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to open
source security podcast.com. Head up the show, not, it's Susy Pound
Ss Podcast. Hashtag hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye,
the