Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner joining me in
four minutes of hate towards selected software.
Josh Bresser.
-- Wait,
-- we get a four minutes hate. I thought it was, was it two minutes? Hate?
-- No, it was four minutes of hate in 19. Was it four minutes?
-- I don't remember
-- too long. I thought it
-- was four minutes. Two minutes of hate? Oh, I stand corrected.
-- Ok. It was
-- two minutes. I thought so. All right.
-- So, for anyone who's never read it, go read the book 1984 or
-- watch the movie,
it is actually pretty.
Yeah, I've never seen the movie.
It's depressing. I'm
-- not gonna lie.
-- It
is
really quite depressing. I think it's just called, like modern documentaries now.
I think so. It's fine.
Thanks, man.
-- Yeah. Anyway, what are we hating on? Exactly. I, I thought this was about
-- apps.
The Canadian government is hating on wechat and Kaspersky on government devices.
They also banned tiktok, like six months ago or so. I think
it's, it's in the article, the,
yeah, the article you sent me
from Reuters. It just search for tiktok. It's tumbled down by the bottom.
Oh, yeah. That's right. I forgot about that.
Yeah, the Treasury board president, they announced on Monday that,
that back in February.
Oh, so, uh, to explain
in Canada for the federal government, the Treasury board don't ask
is the one that basically sets it policy
and strategy for the whole federal government.
I'm assuming it's probably because they were like
the first department to have a computer.
-- No. Seriously.
-- Right. Like, straight off
we probably not.
And then, so they do the policy side and then the um the,
the Canadian signals establishment CS E it's our
version of the NSA with the offensive thing.
Not so much the deep. Well, the
sort anyway, basically the NSA light,
they do the offensive side of cybersecurity and
the treasury board does the defensive side.
Ok. So that's why if I'm talking about the Treasury board,
everybody's going to be like, why
talking about like the Department of Treasury in Canada, like,
what have they got to do with this?
And
they said it policy,
nothing in government makes sense ever. So that's fine.
So, yeah,
so they basically looked at the risks involved with like wechat
and tiktok and Kaspersky and banned it on government devices,
which leads me to think and wonder,
well,
I mean, if my government is that worried from a national security point of view,
like,
shouldn't the rest of us probably not use it?
Ok. I spent
a lot of time thinking about this.
And I think here is the answer I will give,
I don't think the Chinese government is using these apps
to directly
spy on
or
we'll say infiltrate organizations because Persky may be different.
Hold on, hold on. I have an answer for that.
And this is where that fitness tracking app story comes into play, which was back in,
what is it 22,007 or something like that?
Ok.
There was a fitness tracking app that would show all of
the other users of the fitness tracking app on a map
and there was a place out in the middle of the desert,
-- it would show
-- your running routes and stuff.
Right. Right. Right. Would show where people were running or doing whatever.
And there was a location out in the desert in like Iraq or somewhere, one of the
Middle
East
Af
Afghanistan. Ok.
That had all these people going around in a circle and it's like, hm,
I wonder what that is
and
I think the,
the, the danger posed for governments and to a degree for the citizens.
But I think it's certainly less of a concern,
but the danger is the metadata these organizations
will collect that will inevitably fall into the hands
of the Chinese government or the Russian government.
And let's face it.
They're just the United States and Canada are
not friends with Russia and China right now.
And that's just the truth.
Well, and the other thing that comes to mind is OK.
So Kaspersky is an antivirus company
and I have alternatives.
I have North American alternatives,
wechat.
Yeah, basically I have alternatives. I have a
lot of alternatives
and then, but Tik Tok,
well tiktok is tiktok like you don't, I mean youtube,
I guess youtube shorts now exist
but it's kind of like Instagram or Facebook and that
if I'm
on that platform consuming that media,
I don't really have an alternative.
You don't.
Right. And so I think that kind of makes Tik Tok a little more interesting
to me banning Russian antivirus when you have alternatives of North Americans,
who
cares
who in the government needs tiktok to do their job.
Seriously.
Social media, peoples
managers,
-- the Canadian forces has a tiktok,
-- I'm sure some of them can get
exceptions.
I mean, for, for any government rule, there are ways to get waivers and exceptions,
but
-- there are countless people
-- official underscore Canadian underscore army
-- on
-- tiktok and, and I'm fine with that. I, I think
if you are a government organization,
you need to go to where the people are and the people are on tiktok.
-- Well, the young people,
-- but at the same time,
if I'm a government employee that's doing government work, be it, you know,
dealing with paperwork or whatever it, or, or security or something,
having
these apps on my device
or computer or whatever.
Yeah, that could be a potential problem because of the metadata.
Remember, metadata is my concern here,
not the app like hacking me or doing something like that.
-- So I think it's legit.
-- One thing that blows my mind is I've, I've spoken with and
so some people basically
this is a first hand account. Somebody was retiring from the government
and they wanted to keep their government cell phone number.
And I was like, what?
And it's because they canceled their personal phone number like 10 years ago.
And I like
the government
and I was like,
they use their government phone for all their personal stuff and she was like, yeah,
100%.
And I'm like,
I don't even know where to begin with that.
-- I am not even a little surprised that that would happen. I get
-- it.
Like,
because cell phones in Canada are pretty bloody expensive
and that's like 1000 bucks a year easily saved.
That's
the
cost of the phone.
So, like some people, man.
Right.
But I'm just like, I would not put my personal life on a government device.
Like no, but,
oh, for sure, like, well, I mean,
you hear these instances where people had, like,
they had their family photos on their work computer or
something and then they got laid off or fired or,
or
it
happens and then they're like, can I get my pictures back? And it's like,
no look, I've been, I've been there, we gave them the pictures back.
But like, at the same time. It's like,
don't ever do this again. Like, you're lucky we're nice
because other, it departments would have been like, ha ha
ha ha.
No.
See, my
normal experience of a lot of government it is that the stuff is
locked down and you have like a catalog of stuff you can get,
you know what I mean?
Like here's the list of things you're allowed to
grab or install or these ones cost money.
So you have to ask nicely like,
right,
and you don't just get the,
and I get that it's harder with mobile device because
you have to run the uh what are they called,
MS M or me?
What is the mobile management stuff called again?
MD M
MD M, I was getting there in the end.
Um you know, like it, you know,
you have to be somewhat competent to run all this stuff and have the anyways
and so a lot of places don't do that. And so
you kind of have to work on the honor system of like, please don't install this.
Uh Yeah,
yeah, you do get some of that,
-- you
-- know, to some degree,
but I,
I don't know
but look, ok, I wanna, I wanna clarify something before we get too far down this hole.
Hold on, hold on. So MD M like, I don't like MD M software because I don't like
arbitrary control over even employees hardware. However, I'm going to say
that
if an employee opening an
-- application on their computer.
-- Let's go with
device or a device or a device
results in your entire company getting hacked. Like you have garbage security.
Because who, who did that just happen to? There was some,
I can't,
was it was, it, was it Octa that the, the,
supposedly the developer opened Gmail on their work computer?
They, no, they had,
they were signed in on their personal account as well on their work computer.
Basically.
That's right. Which look if that, if that happens to you, your security sucks.
And like,
-- honestly,
-- the thing that always gets me is
what if you have a malicious insider,
right? Like
you can't
defend
it. We didn't, we, we did a photo
-- like a year ago basically
-- all this anti fishing and like, oh blah, blah, blah,
like what if you have even a remotely malicious insider?
Like,
yeah,
I bet you the fishing training creates more malicious insiders than anything else
related here on
-- fun
-- fact, I was looking at some stats
according to one fishing report, fishing is up over 1200%.
So, like that is what a factor of 13 times more fishing
since the release of chat.
54.
Oh, I totally believe that
because now you can make very convincing fishing mails versus the
garbage ones we've all been getting for years and years.
Yeah. The number of times my ceo has been in a Mexican jail needing uh gift cards is
itunes gift cards to post bail
to
pay
tax,
which I love revenue. Canada actually issued an official statement saying
we do not take payment from gift cards.
They have to
and also that they will never,
the thing I love about revenue. Canada is they straight up. We will never email you
with one exception of
if you get a message in the system, like if you have an account and you're registered,
they will email you a notification
with no link with no link to click.
And you should love,
I like that.
They will never phone you.
And that's actually not true. They will once in a while phone you.
But everything is sent via physical mail in these
or gray envelopes.
-- And I love that because
-- the government owns a post office. So,
yeah, I guess they get
a, a discount.
I wonder, I bet they don't get a discount.
Well, no, because they, they presort,
-- oh, they might. That's
-- fair.
That's
true.
That's probably true. But back to the sea.
So the thing I'm thinking is like number one,
if
hypothetically speaking, if the Chinese government were to go full on,
like we're gonna use Tik Tok in a way that everybody will end up hating it.
Like, so we're gonna ship uh an update with a security thing to
maliciously whatever
they would have. They have that capability because
to quote myself when the nice men with guns show up, you do what they
routing software,
I can address that as well though.
So I would compare it to the malicious packages in N PM, which in fact,
I just had a friend asked me about this literally hours before we started recording,
basically saying like
he sent me a link to it and there were more malicious MBM packages.
I'm like this is, this is normal now
and he's like, I don't get it.
And I said, look, people,
this is people love talking about this stuff because it's kind
of like I compared it to the poison candy problem where
people don't shut up about poison candy.
And Halloween when cars literally kill hundreds of Children,
every Halloween and poison candy kills zero kids.
-- Same thing with this stuff. So
-- it's not zero people. Sadly
what? For poison candy?
Sadly,
there's, but it's in the single digits.
I didn't realize that was even a thing
regardless. Cars are vastly more dangerous than Halloween. Ok.
Now,
I think using N PM packages is our example when there is a malicious M PM package,
it generally gets found pretty quickly because there's so many people,
there's people looking
and there's people who are going to be affected and it's detected by their
endpoint detection software or their security software
or they just have a clever developer,
whatever.
There's a million things, right?
And so generally speaking,
these malicious packages make it a day or two at the most and then they get found
and then they get dealt with.
And I think if tiktok
pushed out a malicious update from the Chinese government,
it's
going to be
found literally in minutes, most likely.
And then all of the app stores are going to push a button
that says remove tiktok from every single device it's on right now.
And now that now Bytedance is gone as a company.
But the argument would be is if that's something you're using, like
the Chinese government might not care about by dance. Right?
-- That's something to keep in mind. They're not
-- idiots.
I mean, this would be the dumbest thing you could do. Like if you're going to pa
-- you got to go in slow and low. Like, but
-- it's possible
and I would point out with Ukraine and Russia. Right. Not Petya.
We've seen it happen where they,
they broke into that accounting company that all the Ukrainian companies use
maliciously back door of the software.
And so
the thing to remember too is with like strong authoritarian governments.
They don't have the checks and balances that we have
stupid
-- things. But
-- at the same time,
they're not going to go after wechat or tiktok,
they're probably going to break into some
non
Chinese company
tell them
and that's what's going to get pushed to all the
government devices because they are already on them all.
Like maybe,
I don't know, a company called Solar Winds. Maybe,
for example, you know,
-- that's the thing.
-- Oh,
and I love the solar winds thing where everybody's freaking out about like,
oh the co and everything is being
potentially gonna go to jail for this. And it's like,
it's not what they did.
It's they lied about it to investors.
And if you know, if you lie to your investors,
the SEC will come down on you like a sack of hammers.
-- It wasn't
-- the investors, they lied to the SEC,
right?
Fundamentally to
the sec.
Like of all the organizations on the planet, the SEC is literally the like,
do not lie to these people more than any other organization.
-- Like for real, I
-- love how every time, you know, don't lie under oath.
What happens is these people made a gamble and said,
I think lying is less dangerous than the alternative
and sometimes it is and sometimes it isn't.
And my suspicion is in this case it was not.
Yeah,
but back to this. So I think if nothing else, I would ban
Kaspersky just because there are better alternatives like
that are not also from,
you know, a country like Russia.
Oh, yeah, for sure, for sure. Which,
yeah.
And, and my, you know, if you look at Kaspersky, it's not the nicest program ever.
I mean, maybe it's better now. I don't know.
But the last time I looked, it's weird that like a lot of people,
like use it.
Like I,
it seems like when I run into people randomly
using antivirus quite often they're using Kaspersky and I,
maybe it's because they have a free version and a aggressive UPS sale.
I don't know.
But
I
kind of like thinking about tiktok.
Like, I know some people that I, like, I used to have consume tiktok.
There was a couple of uh content creators on tiktok that I found amusing
and
much like Twitter, I decided.
No, I'm done with this and it was more about um the time usage than
security concerns. Right.
So, same thing with Twitter, I realized Twitter was just like,
had already turned into a pretty not great place and
then Elon Musk acquired it and I was like,
well,
this is probably not gonna go well and
-- it did not go well.
-- It did not go well.
-- Yeah,
-- they're worth what they say internally $19 billion from down from 44. So, like
another year and with any luck it's done.
I
mean,
it takes a long time for companies to die.
I think Twitter will probably outlive both of us. But
I mean
slash dot is still around and dig is still around, but they're not,
it,
it's not at all anything
like part of me kind of wants to always allow list and be like, here's like,
here's the suit.
Well, and we kind of do this at the CS A,
like here's the suite of apps and services and stuff we use and like,
here's the core stuff that
everybody gets by default, you know,
you all get one password and please please use it, you know,
we all go Google Microsoft 365 you know, the, the usual suspects and then
ok, if you need Adobe, yeah, we can buy Adobe for you. Like, uh, not
a
but what else are you gonna do? Right.
Like gotta use Adobe if you're like our graphic designer, like,
I don't want to use Adobe. I'm like, uh I get that
like
we'll pay for it.
Um
And then, but I've, I've not gone so far as to like,
well, I guess I've
sort of banned in the sense of like we use Defender 365
for antivirus and everything else is you're not supposed to use that,
right? You're supposed to use the, the one that we provide.
So I guess I've implicitly banned some of these.
But uh oh, it was when I was looking at the web browser in Google,
you can control what extensions are.
You can either block list or allow list extensions.
And I was like, well, I'm not,
I block listing them because like
that's a waste of my time.
And if I allow listed,
people are going to be constantly yelling at me for more extensions.
And so like,
I think web browsers are a good example of sort
of a similar threat profile mobile devices where it's like,
I just want to get like this little bit of useful code that does X
and like how many of these extensions are, like, always, like,
it will see your full browsing history and this and that.
-- I'm like,
-- all of them have like full control, web, web,
web browser extensions are almost certainly more dangerous than apps on phones.
I guarantee it.
And again, though, look, this comes back to that whole,
if your entire organization can be p
by someone, a malicious web browser extension,
your security is crap.
That's just the way it is.
-- And, and like, I mean, that sounds kind of mean, but it's
-- true.
Well, I mean, it's like saying, you know, like, like banks,
banks have lots of good controls now to prevent them from being ripped off
both by robbers and by internal people because that happened for 200 years.
You know,
like I remember the first time I saw the cash
machine, counter, vault box thing,
you know, where I basically,
I was withdrawing like $100 and normally they would like tap, tap, tap, tap, tap,
tap,
open up a little drawer and like,
you know, 2040 6080 whatever, 100 I'd be a bad bank teller, but she instead stood up,
turned, swiped her card on this thing, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap and then it's like,
you know, like little vault size things spat out some money
and I'm like, what the heck is that?
And she's like, oh, we don't have cash stores anymore. It's this thing
-- Oh, interesting. So, it's like an ATM.
-- Basically, it's, it's an internal ATM and
it will not give money unless there's an,
unless there's a transaction associated with it.
So, if you
drop
the bank, you have to, like, they'd have to do a transaction to withdraw it $20,000.
-- Do they have a, a ransom like account? They might, actually,
-- it's a
computer. So I'm, you could very easily have a panic button. You know.
That's very simple. Right.
I'm assuming there's like one of those blue buttons she was clicking on,
one of them is probably marked, like, you know,
with a little skull and crossbones or whatever.
Um, but it, it got me, you know, like, or when you, if you ever done a,
a large cash transaction at the bank, right.
Oh, I have to go get a sign off or even, oh, when I transfer money between accounts
I have to go get a sign off. It's more than $1000.
This is an example of having good internal security controls. Right.
-- That's why can't
-- we do it
in Infosec?
We can just a lot of people don't.
I mean, so, actually, ok, it's funny you say this now because
there is a new fed
ramp
standard
that came out fairly recently and I have spent
a lot of time last week. It's, it's Fed
Ramp Provision Five if you're looking forward to anyone.
And I spent a lot of time this week. Reading
fed ramp version five because there's things we need to do internally as a company,
there's things we need to do in the product
to, because while our product isn't fed
Ramp certified we,
it's used for others because we run on prem basically and in other, uh,
organizations and whatnot.
So anyway,
I've been reading this a ton
and
they cover a ton of these kind of controls about, you know,
limiting access to single users,
making sure you have to like off up to do activities, making sure.
Oh, so step up off. Yeah,
like all kinds of stuff like that. Right.
Making sure you don't have people running as admin when they're doing work.
And it's funny because you read this is like,
why do you even write this down?
And I'm like, oh, because lots of people do this, like that's why, well,
like we tried, you know, we
tried at various stages in the CS A to do least privilege and I'm like,
we're a public facing organization like we can't do that for our docs.
Like it would just,
and I think that's part of it is
people could implement these controls but it would
slow work down and cause so much overhead.
But here's the thing is the,
the cost of that more than the cost of the occasional security incident.
And the answer is for most security incidents,
you can just externalize the cost of like, oh, we're so sorry.
We lost your personal data. Here's like a
$17 credit for credit monitoring at Expedia or,
I mean,
that's a typical risk calculation, right? Where
when you're doing
actual, like,
I know a lot of security people use the word
risk a lot but they don't actually use it correctly.
There's a group called the, it's called the Fair Institute.
I think I'll put a link in the
show
but the Fair Institute has done a very nice job of
basically saying like here is how you quantify risk properly.
We're like,
and, and they use like these are lawyers doing this stuff, right?
These are like these people know what's up
and it's saying things like this is how much an
yeah, they they literally have
data,
-- they
-- have the receipts.
I remember the first time I looked at them like, oh
actuarial got
it. This is true data nerds.
But they're saying things like this,
this is how much an incident could cost.
This is how much you're going to spend to try to prevent this incident.
And there's like this calculation,
you used to basically say like spending a
million dollars to prevent $10,000 worth of damage.
That doesn't make sense, spending $5000 to prevent $10,000 worth of damage,
totally worth a good investment, right?
And this is an organization that it helps you do this kind of stuff
and I think that's part of it, right?
But however,
when you're dealing with something like fed ramp because
this is a federal government and they're going to,
like, they're going to tell you what to do.
There's no risk calculations like you do it their way or you don't do it.
That's just the way it is.
And the beauty is the federal government is one of the few, like,
and generally most federal governments, not just the US,
one are one of the few players that has enough buying power
and
it's not like they externalize this cost and it just goes away.
It's, they externalize this cost and then they pay for it.
Oh, yeah, they, they pay extra, they know they pay extra.
I mean, nearly every company on the planet has two price sheets.
-- They have a
-- government sales department,
one price sheet for everyone else and another price sheet for the government.
And,
yeah. Right.
And the government knows this.
But they also, they're like,
we're going to make ridiculous demands and we're
going to pay extra for our ridiculous demands.
It's like
we're all happy here.
It's funny because I was just,
I was just actually writing about A I safety and so
this term A I safety is being used a lot.
And it's interesting that everybody's using it, including us at the CS A and
there's, as I see it three levels,
there's the national security level where like they don't want the
A is to help people do bioterrorism or nuclear terrorism.
Or stuff, which is a legitimate concern.
I mean, that's fair.
That's fair.
So, anyway, so we'll have the national security side
kind of doing what they do
the next level then would be the criminal side, right. Obviously.
And like a lot of things, it's not so much that you have a tool.
It's when you use the tool illegally.
So, for example, Home Depot sells burglary tools,
also known as crowbars and hammers
And
I own a very complete set of these,
but I'm not wandering around at three in the morning with them and a black mask on.
So I'm fine. Right. No, seriously. Right.
Yes, there is.
And then the third level though is the business side where
it comes down to business risk because you can as a
business have an A I that is totally national security safe,
totally criminal
safe.
And you use the A I and you do something stupid with it,
like not checking the output and it hallucinates some
random garbage code that causes you a problem.
And so
that's kind of where the CS A fits in those. But thinking to this as this,
back to this, the Canadian government banning the software. Now it Twix my mind that
like, they have a different threat profile than we do. But more importantly, I think
they have a different,
I don't know what to call it. Like, not a use profile but a different,
like they have a different set of finances and a
different set of what they can and cannot externalize.
And to some degree, the Canadian government cannot externalize like,
like a private company can externalize stuff if the waste ends up three blocks over,
not their problem
from the Canadian government's point of view though,
that waste is still in Canada and we still have to pay for health care to deal with the
whatever problems it causes or whatever. Right.
And so the Canadian government can't
externalize stuff that a provincial or a local municipal or a company could.
And maybe that's part of what's happening here. Why
they always do things that don't make sense to us
is because they can't externalize things that we can.
I mean, that's probably fair.
Like lead gasoline,
right? Like lead gasoline is a perfect example.
Carmakers loved it because it reduced engine
knock and increased the engine lifespan.
But we ended up with a generation of criminals. Right.
That, that whole lead poisoning problem.
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, I don't know anyway.
And I guess that, that additionally comes back to the whole,
ironically you brought us back to the topic and I guess accidentally,
like,
this is the government banning these apps
and they get.
Right. That's right. That's right. Not for citizens, for themselves.
And that's like,
they, they can't externalize, they,
they're unwilling to and can't externalize the risk.
And so they're like, we just don't want to
deal with it and we're going to say you can't do it. And that's the way it is because
we said so. That's it.
-- That's funny. Well done. Coming back around.
-- It's always about the money.
-- I
-- mean, is it about money though?
-- These are free apps,
-- money as a measure of externalized,
internalized risk and cost?
Right? Because a lot of risk,
like I hate to say, but we even like there is the, the US government has that number.
Here's what a human life is worth.
Like, I remember my favorite thing when I went to work for the government,
uh provincial government, you know, have to sign a whole bunch of paperwork.
And one of them was like on the,
like you get kind of on the job insurance against injury.
Ok?
And I'm like, kind of laughing. I'm like, what?
Like, you know, I felt like a filing cabinet falls on me.
She's like, no, somebody cut all their toes off once. And I'm like, what?
Ok.
So this is when, you know, all, every time you're repairing a lawnmower,
you're supposed to like unhook the spark plug or unhook the
batteries or like disconnect stuff so it can't turn on.
Yeah, this guy didn't.
-- So he lost all his toes
-- and he was a government.
Well, back, this is a long time ago when like, landscaping
for the government was actually done by the government. Oh, fun fact
I had to learn about hedges and the Ontario government has
the most amazing 60 page manual on hedge landscaping and care.
One thing I learned is all my hedges were the wrong shape to handle snow load.
No, seriously, like in Canada, snow load
stuff is a concern, I guess.
Anyway, so the Ontario government has this lovely publication for like 1960.
Something about hedges.
Super.
But so anyways, but back to this, like,
Nist has peanut butter.
-- Yeah, it's like 1400 bucks a jar,
-- $1000 a pound. Yeah.
My favorite thing about Nist is,
you know what they use for their reference root beer.
I don't actually,
I can respect that. A, I love a and wr
here, like,
-- and, and in my mind I'm like, well, what else would it be?
-- I, I'm ok with that.
-- There's an A W down the street from my house. They're in
-- America.
-- I did not know that.
-- Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
They've been here forever as long as I can remember.
And there's one down the street from my house and I,
every time someone like my wife or kids will be like, oh,
we should go get a and w I'm like,
we have to go in because you get the frosted mug and then you
get the root beer you put in the frosted mug and it's just like,
it's unbeatable.
One thing I'm sad now is their floats use that like,
frozen puck of ice cream instead of a scoop.
I
got
a, I don't like, I don't like ice
-- cream
-- floats. They used to be
now
-- anyways,
-- I don't think they've ever been good.
-- But
-- I thinking of this, here's a question I have for our viewership. Hands
up.
They're listeners. Kurt, we don't have viewers because we both have faces or radio.
Yeah.
Yeah, we do.
Um, so anyways hands up
who here has actually done any sort of financial calculation around the cost
of security incidents and controls.
-- And I'm guessing, like, I know I've, I've never done it. No,
-- it's not a fair question.
And you're not going to because you don't work for a company that can do it.
So the reality is if you're doing that sort of calculation,
you probably have 30 or more people on
your security team is my guess from my experience
that level of security kicks in and somewhere around 30 to 50 people on
a security team because the reality is it's expensive and it's hard to do
and you need people whose only job is like collecting evidence
and collecting data and monitoring the data and logging the data.
And so a small organization isn't doing calculations like that.
It's, there was uh you know what this reminds me of,
there was a blog post from a long time ago
from like some start up where basically the start up was
some big company was saying, oh, we have this contract for you to sign and
they asked their dad like, what his dad was a lawyer or something.
They're like, what do we do? He's like, you sign it. Who cares what it says?
He's like what he's like.
Look, if you get, if you, if you get big enough that this matters,
we'll deal with it then.
But the reality is your company is probably gonna go under in the next year anyway.
So just sign the contract.
This is what gets me like,
like people are pooping on cloud floor right
now for having an outage and they're like,
oh the cloud flare, prioritized development of features over safety.
And it's like,
yeah,
like
that, that's why they're a successful company like
does that they added features that made people buy it?
I mean, this is why security, no one likes security.
It's like
you can listen to me or you could sell more product
because you have the features customers needed like pick one,
it's up to you.
So anyway,
so that, that is why your question I think is invalid and I don't think it's fair. Ok.
Well, let me rephrase it. How many people have ever even thought of
the cost? And the ro I and is it
worth it?
Not just in sense of security R I but will
this because there's been some people that like for example,
fishing training was suggested and I was like, no,
we're not doing fishing training because
a bunch of people fail it and
it not only will there be no Roy, security wise,
it'll just waste people's time and, and annoy them.
What's, what's the action that comes out of fishing training?
-- Yeah. Right.
-- Like
nothing.
I mean, if you're a regulated company and you're really big
you can use fishing training to justify spend or, or something like that.
But even then I still hate fishing training because I think it's,
it's deceitful and immoral.
-- And
-- my favorite thing is when people get the fishing training
and delete it or ignore it or report it and are like or filter it.
Like one guy,
there was that one story where the one guy just filtered
it for like the whole company because he was an admin,
right?
And he's like, is this not my job?
And he got in trouble for that because we're trying to do fishing training?
He's like, but
am I not supposed to block this?
I feel like that's a perfect example of fishing training. Gone well,
yeah,
like I, I just as a side note,
I actually a few weeks ago blocked a couple of swear words,
our email because I realize we'll never get a legit email with certain swear words.
And some can you send the naughty words or is it only if I send
word
only
incoming? So you can reply to me using inappropriate language? But I can't
maybe appropriate depending on what you did.
But anyways because somebody was being abusive to our support staff and I'm like,
I'm done
and it's, it's, and it's funny because the, the, you will get a message saying like
that language is inappropriate. Please be polite.
I like
that.
I think
my take was,
I think people should maybe take cues from what the government bans or doesn't ban,
kind of like California as a state banning all sorts of cancer.
Chemicals
-- might not be the worst thing.
-- Now, every single item in the world carries A
-- I this
-- the C 95 or whatever label
this has
been found to cause cancer in California or whatever,
or the best one is where people started
intentionally adding a little bit of sesame or
peanut or whatever to the product so that they didn't have to worry like they can say
we don't care about cross contamination.
It is contaminated so you can't eat it anymore.
Sorry.
Um
I think we should take their cues from them.
But I think now that I say this out loud like
that what they can and cannot externalize versus what we can and cannot externalize
and not to say ethically or morally what we should or should not externalize.
So I'm, I'm not even touching that
because, you know,
some people say ethically you should not externalize the cost of that software.
And I'm like, well,
I
would love to live in that world.
-- Where, where are you getting this software from?
-- Exactly.
And actually this is another show we need to do but the, um, the,
the whole FDA software thing and life reliance software that
they're saying people are starting to realize
it might need to be open source so
that people can't like repossess your kidney monitor or
your kidney monitors and just stop working in two
years when the company decides to stop supporting it
a
different one. But,
and that's, I think that's
so it's looking at what the government does
and trying to look at it through the lens of the government, not your lens
-- and it'll make a bit more sense.
-- Look, this is just part of the government's job, man.
Like the government says, don't put these chemicals in your stuff,
right? They, they, they can say like we think this software is dangerous.
We think this is the way you should deploy applications. This is, you know,
part of their job is having
people doing the boring actuarial work. No one else wants to do.
And then using the data they found to tell people like
this is a good idea to do it this way.
I remember the day I walked into King tire trying to buy a water bottle
and they were all gone
and that was the week they banned the BP A plastic,
right?
And I
was like,
because the lady was like all the water bottles are gone. I'm like, what?
-- Like all of them hockey,
-- everything.
Yeah, they were full of terrible chemicals for you
anyway. So, yeah. That was a fun lesson to learn.
-- So
-- anyway, all right, I'm gonna call this one. I think we're dragging it on.
But all in all
I feel like what did we come to a conclusion of like
-- good job government, bad job government? I don't know.
-- You know what?
I think a broader lesson would be,
pay attention to what other people do when they ban things,
but look at it through their lens because
it might,
it may or may not make sense for you to also then ban it or to block it or whatever.
For example,
don't ban books.
-- I
-- don't ban books,
look at it through the lens and be like, oh, they're fascists.
I am not a fascist. Therefore, I'm not going to ban it.
OK. That's true. Sometimes people are an anti
example. I actually had this conversation
with my Children the other day.
There are people we will experience in life who are
role models and there are people we experience in life
who are anti role models who like their job is to give you the example of what not to do
anyway. All right, I'm ending this show.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open our security podcast.com. Hit up the show. Not Susie Pounds
Podcast. Hashtag I'm Maon
-- Kurt. Have a marvelous rest of your day. You too,
-- I guess.
Don't try to be the anti example of today's lesson.
I mean, I don't, does anyone try to be the anti example,
Sam
Beman Fried.
Did he try?
He testified at his own trial? Which everybody agreed was a bad idea.
He is the anti example. But did he try to be an anti example or is he just a moron?
I think he's just a moron.
What does it,
what does it never attribute to malice or can be explained with stupidity?
I
think in
this case he doesn't sound like a nice person.
Thank you, everyone. Bye bye.