Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast on December the fifth.
This is myself,
Kurt Siefried with my co-host Josh Bresser and a special guest today, Michael
Gosman,
Michael. Say hello.
-- Hey, everybody. How's it going
-- going?
Good. So, uh
so I run a, a hacker conference in Wisconsin called Cipher Con
and uh
uh we're new as of 2016 and just wanted to, uh
you know,
let everybody become aware of our existence.
Um Wisconsin can be a quiet place and just trying to pull everybody together.
Indeed. Awesome.
And, and in fact, uh Mike, you and I met some time ago at a what, what's it called?
920 Security or something or other? It's a local meet up
and
yeah, so 920 sec.
Um so I'm a co founder of 920 sec and that is uh Green Bay Wisconsin Go Packers.
It's a really, really small community and we're trying to um
have a regional pull together. So, hence the uh area code 920,
-- yeah,
-- totally, totally. So
now, now for those folks listening who, who might not know you by the name, Mike,
you also go by
KGO on Irc
which, which I must ask uh what is the history behind Cargo?
How did you come up with that one?
Yeah, so that's a great question. Um
So I was probably in like middle school and uh I was sitting on Irc in, in the channels,
I sit in for like years, right?
And we started catching on to these other names
and some dude came into Irc and was obviously using an alias.
So like a one time alias didn't know who he was
and he's like cargo. I like you so much that I named my virus after you.
And I'm like, what?
And uh or, or I was under a different name, but he created this cargo
virus
and he put all my contact information in the code of the virus, right?
And released it out to the uh
the wild West. You know, let's jump around the air tubes of the internet
and I'm waiting for a knock on the door from the FBI or something cause like
he put all my contact information in there.
Uh You know, about a year later, I'm like, well, I guess I never got busted for that.
And this guy did a shout out to me on this coral
virus.
So uh I, I named my hacker name, my hacker tag to uh
to cargo kind of in honor of this anonymous figure
that tried to have the FBI knock on my door.
That's a great story. Holy cow.
I'm, I'm, I'm still half waiting for somebody to knock on my door and be like, dude,
like, what was up with that virus?
-- Do
-- you have a copy of it?
You need to get that and, and at least strings the thing right to, to show off.
Yeah. So if you google cargo
virus,
there's like tons of information on it.
Oh man, that is so cool.
Nice.
So a
warning to those that like hang out on the IRC far too long, you'll get,
get an hour named after you.
Only, only the lucky ones, man, only the lucky ones. It's
I love it.
Ok, so, so you run Cipher Con,
which is the real reason we asked you to talk to us because
conferences are crazy to run.
It's one of those things that people love to go
and complain about the management or what happened or whatever,
but
it, it's like insane
to run this, this sort of stuff.
So, so let me ask you this, what on earth possessed you to start and,
and even do it again, but of running a a hacker con.
So the reason why I started cipher Con was
there was a hacker space in Milwaukee called Bucket Works
due to financial reasons. It kind of went under
and what that did was
it scattered the attendees or, or you know,
the guys they used to hang out with uh all over the place into multiple groups, right?
You got your software people, your,
um, you know, your, your pen testers, your,
your hardware people and they all kind of went
into different little groups and different little pockets.
And I found myself going to like eight or 10 of these a month and it was just killing my,
uh,
productivity because I'm going to all these events
because I wanna see one or two different
friends of each of these groups as I went around these groups for about a year.
I'm like, hey, you know, we should, we should all, like, throw together this, like,
alumni group or whatever
and bring everybody together and everybody's like, yeah,
that's a really good idea.
But it never went anywhere.
So, finally I'm like, all right,
I'll like,
risk putting 80
the funding for like, 80 people together and we would do it at the safe house.
So people not familiar with the safe house
is a spy bar slash restaurant slash club,
um, with a Cold War theme and I thought it was very fitting.
Um,
not just a Cold War theme. Right? How do you get in?
Because that's, that's really the trick, isn't
it?
No, I, I, you can't discuss that. You gotta earn your wage.
Let's just say it, it, it's not obvious to get in. Right.
It, it's a bit of the, the old school, you know, knock the,
knock and say the password sort of stuff.
Right.
Yeah.
If you don't know the secret handshake,
you're not like you're not in until you earn it.
So, yeah, you know it's, it's been around for like 50 years.
Um it's, it's, it's a gem, a hidden gem of Milwaukee, right.
So I thought it was perfect. Uh spy theme a lot picking, you know, just screen hacker.
And um
so I, I did the down payment myself and I'm like, all right, you know,
I'm just gonna say everybody chipping 100 bucks
and uh almost immediately I sold out of the 80 tickets and I was like, wow, like this,
this is gonna,
this is gonna be an awesome party.
I'm gonna have some speakers, you know, we're gonna get some food cheese curd,
you know, the Wisconsin delicacy.
Um
And, and then all of a sudden I had people like sending me messages like you asshole
cargo. You didn't tell me anything about this.
Like I thought we were friends and I was like, oh crap. So I expanded the space
um up to 100 and 25
and I expanded the space again and again and again.
So eventually I expanded it six times
and it turned to a two day event
the second day being at the Fister Hotel, which is the Fanciest Hotel in Milwaukee.
So it was kind of eerie
like this, like a Renaissance art and Renaissance theme
and it's uh
it's really high end place and then everybody in their hacker black hoodies,
you know,
really awesome. Um
We ended up with 225 attendees for our first year. Um
And
I, I'm obviously biased but I thought it was an amazing event
that, that's crazy, man for a first year. Con
225 is solid. Well done.
Congrats.
-- So, so I
-- mean
that was planning, that was like 4 to 5 months of planning.
So I was like nervous that something would fall apart.
Well, we, we, we'll get to that.
But uh
I, I guess let's start here is why don't you give us a recap of the first cipher
con
and, and kind of the highlights you thought were, were really stand out.
Awesome and, and just the general feel for the conference of what the themes were
and the folks who attended and just kind of all that fun for the people
out there who maybe have never heard of cipher con prior to right now.
Sure. So, uh
we had, um
I mean, we had all sorts of amazing speakers, so I'm talking like 20 speakers,
I
guess. Uh I'll start with a keynote. Um We had Jo Cicero who's from Green Bay
and he talked on pissed
and pissed is privacy in a surveillance state of vaping detection.
And um
just talks about like,
if you wanna hide how difficult it is. I mean, if you're on the internet,
can they reverse back to where you are?
And there's just step after step,
after step of things you'd have to do to completely be anonymous.
And at the end of it, you, you're just like, yeah, I'm not anonymous.
I'm curious, did he talk about
between masking and hiding at all or any of the masking type stuff?
So, there were tidbits on, like, you know, here, here's what you could do.
Here's what,
um,
you know,
here's the various options on each of these different steps that you can do.
But a better answer would be on cipher
Con's website. We have the talks recorded.
So, um
you know, when you get into the nitty gritty details, I would just go watch the video
and that,
that's a great thing to know too is uh recording talks
if you run a conference and you don't do that.
I'm looking at Urs a uh shame on you because there is no excuse anymore to do,
not do that.
And I will put links to the videos and the conference website,
all kinds of fun stuff in the show notes.
For those of you who don't know, but for people too lazy to look at my show notes,
the uh what
cipher con.com, right?
And uh so I guess like some of the other talks we had like Scott Irving,
um he's well known in the uh the hacker realm for protecting medical devices and
setting up honey pots to see how many people are really attacking medical devices.
Um We had uh so this one talk that wasn't recorded, that was Raymond Benson.
He is a James Bond novelist.
So I,
I thought it was fitting that if we were at the
safe house with a Cold War espionage theme that we have um
one James Bond novelist for the fantasy side of things.
Um And then we also,
and we also had Warner um
one or a personal friend of mine uh was an actual US spy
during the Cold War caught in Eastern Berlin. He was sentenced to 13 years in prison
and did eight.
So he's like a Cold War convict.
So
I had some of the other speakers are like, you know, how can I compete with that?
You have a US spy that got caught and they had like imprisoned, like,
how am I supposed to,
how am I supposed to compete with that?
Yeah,
that's,
that's wild.
It's deep. Yeah. And,
you know, he pulled me aside and told me some of the, uh, like
some other stories of what was happening
and you could tell like
he was still kinda
shaky on who he could tell some of the stories. Um
I'm guessing like, you know, once you, once you're a spy, you're always a spy,
right? Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Seriously. Oh, man, that's so crazy.
So again his talk, his talk is recorded.
Um I would go check it out like that's probably, you know, I,
since he's a personal friend of mine.
Um, he's local. He's never spoke at a hacker con. So,
I guess for cipher con I've always wanted to
dabble a little bit outside of the normal. And, um,
I mean, really, what is the difference between
Cold War espionage and cyber war? You know, cyber war is still espionage.
Just a little more modern version.
Yeah. Oh, totally. Totally. Man. That's, uh,
that's a good point actually.
And, and I know, I love reading the stories of,
of some of that Cold War crazy that went on.
It. It was,
it's, it's surreal. Right. It's more bizarre
than most people can imagine, which is all part of the fun and,
and part of me is terrified but also excited
to read about the insane things they're doing today
that we won't find about for 50 more years, you know, assuming, like,
we don't kill each other, the robots take over before that.
I, I do have to wonder what the modern equivalent of acoustic kitty is,
you know, for those of you that don't know, the CIA attempted to
essentially turn a cat into a listening device
and the poor thing ran across the street and got, ran over, like, right away.
Um, so, I mean, yeah,
there's all sorts of crazy stuff and I can only imagine today what they're doing,
-- we don't
-- wanna know.
All right. So,
some of the,
some of the other speakers we had, uh, JP Smith of Chicago.
Um, Chris Roberts, the guy allegedly who, uh, revved up an engine on an airplane.
He came and talked to us about, uh,
hacking cows in the food chain.
So it's fitting for Wisconsin and all our, uh, our farming,
um,
Johnny Christmas hack for pancakes. Um,
I mean, we had all sorts of amazing top notch speakers
and then, like, even beyond speaking,
um, we had all the villages, so we had, uh,
our main village and it'll always be our number one village is cipher village.
Um, because we're cipher con obviously, right?
And, uh
have uh crypto um puzzles and anybody who
beats all the way through the crypto puzzles,
just like defcon receives a lifetime badge, except for ours is red.
I like to affect,
I personally affectionately call it the blood badge because
you have it for the blood of your life,
you know.
Right. Right.
And, and I imagine, uh it's a lot of math, right? And we all know math is hard.
So, I mean,
I don't want that to scare anybody.
Um, I mean, we're kind of like a, like an entry level crypto
con disguise is a hacker con,
but our crypto puzzles are not meant to like, be like, oh my God, you don't know math,
you can't do this.
It's more of let us show you
kind of some interesting entry level things that slowly evolve into
kind of a intermediate and then into hard
and we had a lot of beginners just love it so much
that they worked their way all the way up to the hard stuff
and, and we're willing to hold hands.
It's not always about winning the prizes, you know.
So let me ask this then is how many lifetime badges did
you give out at the end of the con last year?
But we had
four contests that were available
to win a lifetime badge.
Um One of them being crack the safe in the safe house.
So there's an actual safe
that to my knowledge has never been opened in recent times.
And I said if anybody opens that safe and whispers the code in my ear
and I go over and pop the safe open,
they win a lifetime badge.
Um,
nobody was able to pop the safe and, uh,
I've kind of made it my mission to personally make,
made it my mission to open that safe since
and nothing is difficult.
So I don't blame anybody for not popping that thing open.
-- I'm just,
-- I'm curious, is it, so it's like an old time mechanical safe or
like a bank vault type deal or
it, it, it's like a, it's a, I don't know, like a 3 ft safe by 3 ft,
um, with the old dial on it, the thing is from like
wanna say the forties or fifties.
Um,
I found the manual for it but I wasn't, wasn't able, you know,
the default codes didn't work.
Um, I thought of sticking an auto dial around there and just dial the crap out of it,
just brute force into it.
But,
uh,
like, I think that might be a little extreme here.
I am sitting in this restaurant for like eight hours waiting for this thing to dial.
Right. Right. That's not completely ridiculous.
Uh So, so what are the other, what are the other ones other than the,
uh unbreakable safe?
-- And you, there's three more of them,
-- right.
Yeah. So we had captured the con. So capture the con is,
I guess we have all these various villages like hardware hacking village, you know,
diffuse a briefcase bomb.
Um uh What else do we have?
We have uh you know, like lock picking where you pick, you know,
um basic medium, hard uh handcuffs behind your back
and you scored points throughout all these villages.
So we essentially gamified cipher cat.
And if you moved up and captured the con and the points at the end of it,
the top five people got prizes.
Well, one of the prizes was a lifetime badge.
That badge was indeed given out. So
somebody did win the uh lifetime badge
um
from capture the time. So we will bring that back for 2017. People loved it.
Um They ran around to all the different
villages doing different challenges to win points.
We had social points. So people were being introduced to each other.
It just really brought the conference,
uh a whole different feel that I really enjoyed.
Um
And then we had our wireless capture the flag.
This is run by a guy named Eric Escobar and he won.
Um I, I believe two years running Def
Con's wireless capture flag
and he's like,
he's like, dude, I, I love, you know, competing in them, but I wanna try running one
and he just,
he blew it out apart.
Yeah, I mean, like, you know, what, what do you do when you,
you're the best in the world, right?
You, you jump on the other side
and uh
he, he just blows my mind on how well he knows wireless.
Like if you have wireless, be fearful of this dude.
And so
just to confirm, are we talking like wifi or other things than wifi?
So we define wireless as anything that transmits through the air? So,
um
I mean, everybody's thinking traditional wireless for your internet.
Um But we're thinking, you know, RF we're thinking Boe, we're all over the place.
Um And I wanted to expand it because
I want people to get outside their comfort zone when they come to Cipher Con.
I want to be
easy to get outside your comfort zone and find a new, new area to explore.
And um
that's kind of like one of the cornerstones of Cipher
Con is be comfortable diving into something unknown.
That's awesome.
And, and number 441,
uh was, it was that
34,
there was the
Khan
uh the
H
theon,
the wireless kept to the flag and
-- one
-- more
and I'm, uh, I'm looking through the notes right now.
I cannot, maybe, maybe it was three,
like
the whole thing. The whole thing is like a wedding, right? Like
you don't remember any of it. You look at the pictures after and be like, holy crap.
I did that.
Right.
-- So
-- that's the crazy thing about running a con, right? Is
I've never put on something to this degree,
but I've been involved in various events in the past and
it's like it's so much work and it's completely thankless.
So
I,
I personally think you're crazy for doing this twice in a row
and not like conning someone else just doing it for you.
Well, if I'm not crazy for this, it's,
it's a separate issue and I'm just straight up crazy.
Um
So might as well have an excuse for being crazy, right?
So I guess uh we kind of covered cipher con one point.
Oh,
now tell us all about 2.0 what are the new and
exciting things we can look forward to this year that,
that maybe weren't there last year.
All right. So safe for count 2.0
is gonna be March 30th and 31st and a Child Day on April Fools Day. No joke.
So I'm super
excited about
actually is uh for those of you who don't know, and I'm gonna,
I'm gonna hijack this for a second.
Is
I was at Circle City Con, which is a, a hacker con in Indianapolis, Indiana.
It was, um, I forget when it, when it even was, but
my kids were with me
and they were very kid friendly and my kids had a blast
going around seeing the stuff.
They thought it was like the most amazing thing they'd ever done.
So, if you have kids bring them with you to this, you will not regret it.
And the craziest thing though is my daughter was seven at the time.
She is better at picking locks than I am, which I found terrifying.
So
you never know what you're gonna learn, right? When you bring the kids
and I recommend if you're bad at picking locks, just get like a um a blowtorch cutter,
you know, right.
-- Just cut right through that lock. So
-- you
heard that
uh
when you go to cipher con bring your blow torch cutter?
Yeah, and there goes my budget for walks. You,
you're not getting that deposit back man.
So um and and let us explain a little bit about the Parent Child Day, right?
So we want we,
we call it a Parent Child Day instead of
just a Child Day because we want the adults involved
and, and, and we talk about things like
online safety that creepy guy online or were supposed, you know,
13 year old girl might not be who they say they are.
So, we're trying to teach kids like, you know,
start questioning your surroundings.
Of course, we have, you know, uh, entry-level lock picking, we have Caesar cyclers.
You can break, we have, um, you know, entry-level coding,
you can take apart a computer.
We have all sorts of things that just spark our, uh, our youth's mind and, and,
and get them excited about, um, career paths.
Um, We have some interesting speakers that will be announcing soon
and uh it's just an overall really exciting time and
it's in a children's science museum uh for a venue. So
I guess we should talk about the venue of Cipher Con itself, right?
Yeah. So Cipher
Con
is at Discovery World in Milwaukee.
So
those not familiar with Discovery World,
it's essentially a building that's on a pier out over Lake Michigan
and
this building is uh three stories and up on the top is a 360 degree floor
to ceiling window view of all of Lake
Michigan and the skyscrapers of downtown Milwaukee.
It's beautiful.
Um And that's probably I'm like
cipher kind has been blast where we've had the f
hotel, the Safe House and Discovery World,
which I think are like the three best places in town.
So like,
I
think the the entry level um or the entry ticket of 175 for two days
is worth just the venue itself.
There you go,
sell it, man. Sell it
now. But what are you gonna do when you run out of good?
You, you're using up all the great venues. You gotta have like a couple of
years to get people stoked about, you know, going somewhere new and exciting then.
Right.
So, I mean, we'll always have excitement and they,
Lake Wisconsin has all these amazing venues, um,
um, out even outside of Milwaukee. Right?
So we consider ourselves a Wisconsin hacker conference,
not a Milwaukee hacker conference.
So, uh,
you know, it started here in Milwaukee. Um,
but I could foresee it jumping to maybe Lambeau Field
in Green Bay and there's some amazing places in Madison.
Um So we're kinda keeping our eyes open and,
um,
see how we scale seeing. Um,
you know, is there more demand than we know about?
It's really hard to judge where we'll end up.
Um We've also been discussing with, uh the Midwest Gaming Classic,
which is an arcade conference gaming, um, the gaming conference
and maybe we'll, maybe we'll co locate with the, with a,
a hacker conference and arcade conference at the same time.
So, like that would just blow everybody to mind
just to confirm. So this is like old timey arcade games, like,
like the stand up booth ones or?
Yeah, exactly. So it's like,
uh, um, you know, just classic arcade.
Um, and there's a lot of hacking involved with that, right?
So how do you take these classic arcades and just keep them operating.
There's all this hardware, there's all this software.
-- It, it just gets intense.
-- Oh, man.
So I, I was actually at a conference one time that had one of the,
the after parties was they, there's a place you can rent,
like all these old school arcade games. Right.
And this guy shows up in a truck and he's like unloading them and I was hanging out and,
you know, talking to him and stuff and
yeah, you're talking about keeping him running is
the big thing he's got, is he one of them, he sets up and it didn't work.
So of course, he, like, he tears the thing apart and he's soldering stuff, you know,
on the floor of this hotel.
And I'm thinking this is like, completely crazy and he said this is,
you do this all the time
where these things, like, as soon as you touch them, they break because, you know,
the capacitors are old and the,
the C RT S don't quite work and they get out of alignment and like it was just,
it was bonkers how much work this guy did do.
And I just thought like, you've got to love this because
I bet you're, you're making like 75 cents an hour,
you're not dealing with this stuff.
So, like, I'm obviously friends with that circle and, you know,
hang out with them and I'm like, seeing them.
Yeah, solder capacitors on the circuit board. That's like, you know, older than me.
But I'm like, this is awesome.
Like, totally have to, we have to find a way to work together
to
totally. And, oh, man, I just, I love the
old games too.
I said, hey, you know, maybe for 2018 we can do a co location hack conference,
arcade conference, you know.
Um, and they're like, oh my God, that's awesome. And so
they didn't wanna wait till 2018.
So one of our villages this year in 2017
will be game console hacking village run by
our friends at the Midwest Gaming Classic.
They'll be showing off like, you know,
here's how we took this original game and we modified it and now it's, you know,
it's got somebody else, you know,
like their family's heads on the characters in the game or
they created a game from scratch. I mean, it's stuff that blows my mind, man.
That'd be so cool.
And then like, it got me thinking, I'm like,
you know what?
I started off as a kid playing games and that got me
excited about the games and then I ended up hacking the game,
right?
Because
if there's a limitation in the game,
man, I, I had to overcome that.
So I started,
and I started hacking
and a hacker like, I mean, that's overcoming limitations, right?
So then, um and this is gonna be a spoiler alert here
at Cipher
Con two. We're gonna have electronic badges
and it's gonna be the blend of
how everybody got started. So, a blast from the past meets the future,
the electronic badge itself is gonna have a game in it
but the game is gonna have some twists.
Um, but I wanted to show like,
even if you,
you have no, um,
passions into hacking or you have zero knowledge,
it starts off with a game
and
if, if you could play a game it's gonna turn into, um, you don't,
you won't even realize that you're starting to get into hacking as you play the game.
Oh, man. Now, now I wanna see this badge. I'm, uh,
II, I do have my ticket, by the way, I bought it.
Um, I think the day you open ticket sales, in fact, just to make sure I got in, you know,
before they all sold out.
Right?
Yeah. So these, these badges are gonna be highly sought after. Um,
I mean,
uh, a product child of my group, but I,
I wanna say it's gonna be the best
hacker electronic badge at any hacker conference ever.
And those are big words because that's a competitive area.
Oh, man, you're, that, those are fighting words there.
-- You're gonna get shift or something.
-- I don't watch
that.
No, no kidding.
So, uh,
so I guess the game hacking village, um,
that,
that's one of 12 villages we're gonna have and villages are just specializations,
right?
So everybody's like,
hey,
Cargo, how can I get more involved with cipher count? And I'm like, all right.
Well, what do you, what do you like doing? They're like, well,
you know, I'm really good at lock picking.
I'm like, cool, go work with the lock picking village
and see what interesting innovative things you can come up with
and,
and I get these little groups together and let me just
read down the list of some of these other villages.
So I said lock picking,
we have safe cracking, right? So
a lot of conferences put those together, but I feel they're different skill sets,
you know, you can pick a lock.
But getting into a safe requires just a different approach. I can,
you know,
in
fact, I have never broken into a safe, but I've picked
many, many locks. So that, that's awesome.
Well, and come to cipher crime and there'll be some hands on, you can just, you know,
beat, beat on the safe and see if you can manipulate it open.
-- I can use the torch I brought to uh, get into the locks
-- right.
There you go. And I have to add another budget line. All right.
Yeah.
So, uh
so we have a hardware hacking village.
So we had hard hardware hacking village at Cipher Crow
one.
And um,
and we, you could purchase a kit,
put it solder together and you had some kind of device that did something really,
really amazing.
I'm excited to announce soon. Um we're still working on the details.
Uh So tentatively,
um
uh a sponsor might be purchasing all the kits
so you can put these kits together for free.
So I'm really excited about that.
Can't wait to announce that one.
So again, we have uh Escobar running uh wireless capture the flag for a contest,
but we also have him uh on standby at a wireless hacking village.
So he can actually explain and show you how to defeat, you know,
limitations and wireless
new this year is car hacking village. I mean, that's, you know,
with all this automation of, uh, you know, self driving vehicles,
like let's get those things secure first before
somebody slamming on your brakes on a highway.
Um
Yeah, no kidding.
It's a little frightening but, you know,
at least it might stop half the people from texting while they're driving.
But,
uh, um we have vintage system hacking village.
So it's our friends at the uh Chicago Classic
uh computing. Um That's a conference that focuses on vintage systems.
Like, you know, we're talking about like Wise Edition Mac
and uh
just really old school systems.
Like that's hacking in itself, just like the, the old arcades.
You gotta, you gotta hack these systems together.
We'll
uh be jail breaking an Apple two, right?
Yeah, I mean, they, they've done some incredible stuff. Right. Getting,
getting II, I mean, I guess come to the village,
I'm not a specialist on all these areas, but
like playing some of these games that you played in, like the early eighties.
Um, the actual hardware from the eighties is just, uh,
it just brings back so many cool memories.
Um,
and, uh,
uh, we have, uh Espionage Village.
So, Espionage Village is, um, kind of a, you know, it's,
there's always gonna be that piece of espionage.
Uh, as far as I know,
we're the only hacker conference that has like an espionage twist to it.
Um,
this year we're focusing on, um,
the Milwaukee area on the summer fest grounds, uh which is the big music festival,
uh, used to have
night missiles with nuclear tips. And, um,
it's gonna be hopefully some speakers discussing, um,
what it was like to operate some of those anti, uh,
anti aircraft youtuber
missiles.
It just
blows my mind.
Thank
goodness.
Right.
Yeah.
Well,
you know, it, it's just crazy how, like in the fifties,
like downtown Milwaukee had nukes.
-- That's crazy.
-- I didn't know that. Oh, my goodness. That's, oh my.
I
remember reading about this. It was, it was like doctor strange love
levels of insanity
because like there was no other option, right? Like,
oh
yeah, just put it in the show notes, the Nike Zeus missile system. It's, it's like
so completely insane.
I, I believe it is still the fastest, like,
it's the most fast accelerating thing man has ever made
is the missile itself.
So, uh
they, they, they told everybody that these missiles on the summer fest grounds.
So when you're at the music festival at
Summerfest and you see all the concrete everywhere.
It's eerie to know there's bunkers underneath.
And, uh,
so
these
nukes they told the, the public like, oh, don't worry,
this is protection from Milwaukee and Chicago against the Russians flying, um,
aircraft over Lake Michigan.
Right.
We're gonna, we, we find
out
and we find out later
that
three suburbs of Milwaukee
actually have the full on like missile targeted on Moscow,
like right here. So
the, the, the defense of the city was kind of secondary,
right?
It's just people we can replace them, you know,
that's so crazy.
So I'm always gonna have like kind of a, like a touch of espionage. Um
And I guess for full disclosure,
I'm on the board of directors for the Cold War Museum.
So you're gonna feel that
nice. That, that's cool too.
We should have you back to talk about that, that at some time.
-- But
-- anyway, man,
no, nobody will sleep.
That's all right. We're, we're security people.
We, we have enough trouble sleeping as it is
totally. Um So another village we have is privacy invasion village.
So there's privacy and crypto villages at other places.
But I wanted to demonstrate like here are the different
ways and how easy it is to invade somebody's privacy.
So I'm still working in the disclaimer,
um that I'll have when you walk into the conference to make sure like, hey,
everybody's got the heads up that, you know,
it's gonna get creepy.
But uh
we have some exciting ideas for privacy invasion village that I
don't wanna tell you guys because I would give it away.
I, I don't wanna know like this is one of those things.
I just know I'm,
I would not go in there or talk to any of those people because I know what they can do.
And I'm just gonna put, this is like not going to the doctor because you know,
you're going to die, right?
Like just no,
and, and, and truly, um coming to this conference is all like
it, it's a, it's a learning experience
but it, it's safe, it's like a safe environment.
Um
You come to cipher
Khan to
be in this
uh exercise or this, this
safe place to experiment on stuff that in reality
is very scary or intimidating.
You come to cipher
Khan to, to
just practice
and to learn.
Um,
and there, there should be nothing intimidated. No, nobody should be intimidated.
No,
I,
-- I'm terrified. Right. There's a huge difference isn't
-- terrified.
-- The default setting for most security
-- people. Oh, it is. I know.
I know. Unfortunately.
-- Anyway, and,
-- and I mean, we have,
we have people that attend that just come for the social, um, you know, have a Drake,
see some cool stuff.
Um,
you know, and then we have other people that come in and, and see the talks. Right.
We have 25 speakers for year too.
You know, there, there's something for everyone and,
and if there's not something for you, we have food and beer.
So that might, that might, who am I missing at that point?
-- There's something for everyone at that point.
-- Right.
And I guess, let, let, let's talk about some of these speakers.
We have, uh,
Richard, the,
who has spoke at every decon
except for two. So Defcon has been around for 25 years.
Um
He, he's actually a local to Wisconsin
and a lot of people aren't aware of that.
And uh
we have
my friends from Canada. So shout out to Canada there.
Um
Hey,
come on, Kurt, here's your chance, man. Jump
on that
because so Wisconsin is big on cheese curd.
So like, do you guys have poutine down there?
We don't, we don't, we uh we do, we do deep fry them though,
but we don't uh pour gravy on top of them.
It totally seems like something Wisconsin should be eating because
Wisconsin is like the worst diet on the planet.
So I'm surprised poutine isn't something we eat here. I, I,
yeah, because I mean,
there are few ways to make French fries more unhealthy and poutine is one of the few.
So, um
I mean, you say worst diet. I, I say best diet. So it's,
you know,
Toma tomato, tomato.
Yes. Our, our waist sizes show how, how best it is. Right.
That's, that's true.
I could, I could probably jump on the treadmill a little bit more.
Um
Anyway, so, so our friends from Canada
in Sydney and uh friend Melanie are
gonna be speaking on brain based authentication.
So instead of using, you know,
your finger for biometrics or typing in your password,
like what if the unique configuration of your
brain allowed you to log into your computer?
So,
it, it's a fascinating concept and I can't wait to see, um,
what they have in store for us for this talk.
I'm like, I'm like, 50% scared of, of this one for, for not any reason I can justify
other than it's, it's just
let's combine this with your, uh privacy invasion village.
And I think we're, we're
on the right path here. Right?
And, and we're, we have bio hacking village also
and, um,
they're a big aspect of the bio hacking village
and that
can you use electrical currents
to go through to your skull and modify
your brain and set up electrical connections that
don't normally exist in, um, what nature I guess
they may or may not be having a device that would do this on site.
So
I think prepare your brains for this.
Science fiction has shown that messing with someone's brain always ends well.
Right.
Absolutely. Absolutely.
So, I, it's interesting that, um, you bring up science fiction, right?
So that we have so many aspects of science fiction and
year two's theme.
So we just announced this theme about a week ago
and the theme for year two is called Fringe Science.
So we figured we're in a ma
a science museum
and we're touching on all these fringes, right? Like,
like cybersecurity
or, or, or iot or anything that we're dabbling in in this career path
like we didn't exist 10
or at most 20 years ago, right?
Our career path is so new that we're on the fringe of,
of all these different methodologies and these sciences and these
attack methods.
So we think it's fitting to do fringe science
for
-- you.
-- That's fantastic actually.
And this is something that Kurt and I talk about on a regular basis is the fact that
security is still, I mean,
we always like to think about it as kind of being old
because a lot of us have been in the industry for maybe,
you know, 10 or more years.
But in reality, compared to most mature industries,
we are brand new
and we don't know what the heck is going on.
And in fact,
this is something that I've started doing some research on and I
keep talking about this and I have to stop at some point.
But like
I,
I started writing a blog post to compare
uh security to the kind of worker safety in, in the industrial revolution.
And I've gone down this insane rat hole because it turns out
if you look at literally like every part of human history,
we let things get like on fire, everyone's dying bad before we even care.
And so when, when I hear like Bruce and I are going and talk to Congress being like, oh,
we have to care about iot it's like they don't care right
until like half of the population is dying because of their pacemakers.
Like nobody is going to care.
Which is terrifying
because I don't want to give up.
But I don't, I don't think we're gonna fix this one any time soon.
Yeah, it's, uh,
I mean, so one of the reasons why I'm pulling in the Cold War is like,
what happened in the Cold War is repeating itself now in Cyber War.
And, um, I'm, I'm,
I'm just trying to
demonstrate like, like this is not different.
Wow,
that's really true. Actually, we should,
I wonder if anyone's done that where they've kind of
gone through the parallels of the Cold War compared to today
because I, I imagine it's
horrifying how things line up.
Uh In fact, I don't know if you guys have ever read, there's,
there's a book out there called Ghost Fleet
where it's this author kind of does like a future war concept
where it's all very, you know, electronic and, and the uh
the Chinese attack
America.
And they, they basically because they built everything they, like,
take over all the computers and ruin them all, you know,
it's kind of a bit Battlestar Galactica in that respect where they're like crap.
We have to use all the old garbage now because all the
new stuff has been taken over by the bad guys and it's
part of it. I, I chuckled at and part of it, it's like this is,
this could happen because it's exactly true.
I mean, to some degree it's already happening.
I mean, those, you know,
there's been a couple of big cybersecurity attack incidents now, you know, like,
what was it last week in Saudi Arabia? Right.
And I can't help but wonder how much of this, you know,
it's kind of like those proxy wars we used to fight,
-- you know, in the Cold
-- War still fight.
Well, yeah, granted.
So it's, it's, and you hit, it, hit the nail right on the head.
Um, these nation States can blame individual, any hackers
and, and get away with doing stuff that would
spark wars. But they say, oh, that wasn't us. That was that group anonymous, right.
It, it, it gets really bizarre really fast
and, and actually, um, funny you say that because, you know,
I'm gonna ruin this for most of you, but I won't ruin it.
But, uh, Anonymous is a character in the book, Ghost Fleet,
which I found extra hilarious.
Right. Right.
It's always,
it's always that anonymous person online that just
ruins it for all the Nation States.
Right.
That's right. That's right. They
do.
I've always wondered how with a straight face we claim that there's this
cohesive group called Anonymous who
has no aim or, you know, like,
doesn't
have a structure and yet somehow they're co
cohesive and we call them anonymous. You know,
it, it seems rather strange to me.
I don't think we have time to cover that one
-- maybe next
-- week.
Well, I, I guess I can give another little teaser of what's coming up for cipher con.
Uh, based on this is we hired a film crew to put a little promo video together
and we're kind of taking the little teases of like, uh f society from Mr Robot
and, um anonymous with the whole V for vendetta mask.
And we're doing our own little twist on that
and it's essentially gonna be a recruitment video for cipher con, right?
Like, like,
you know,
I, I, it shows somebody going through the process of
one of the, uh, the puzzles that we have crypto puzzles on our website, right?
Anybody can go play with them.
Um, you know, we'll help you through it.
It's kind of like a little fun thing between the conferences, right?
And this is a
devoted hacker
that, uh, you know, jumps up, spray, paints a camera, you know,
does a little picking.
Um, it, it's gonna be a really intense video
and, uh
I'm excited for uh its release probably mid January
now.
Not only is it really cool. Right.
But it, it, it focuses on the emphasis that cipher
con has beyond traditional hacking
is we're,
we're trying to reach out to people interested that have various skill sets.
Right. So here's a, here's, here's a film crew and a film director
that does all this artistic stuff.
Um We're also looking for artists that wanna show the hacker culture and visuals.
There's um
a, a friend of mine is gonna be playing music at Cipher Con.
It's, you know, hacker music.
Um We're looking for all the different mindsets that
I is considered hackers. Like,
you know, like, like for
some bio hackers, they say, oh, you know, I'm not really a hacker.
I don't break the networks, I don't get into servers.
And I'm like,
but you're hacking your body. Like that's crazy.
That's like you're more hacker than some of the traditional hackers.
And II, I want,
I wanna reach out to these artists, these hacker artists
and I wanna see these, these fringe um
these fringe hacker cultural representations.
Um A and this film should be like one of, one of the big pieces of saying like,
Cipher comes beyond the traditional hacking and getting into this new fringe
mindsets. And that's how we need to look at this discipline, right?
We have to look at it beyond.
Just let's break into a server and oh my God, we own somebody.
I it's,
it's a culture, it's a group of people. It's a family
and, uh,
I think you're gonna see a lot of that coming up.
That's awesome, man.
One thing I gotta ask, uh, are you gonna be releasing any of the sort of,
uh, parent and kids stuff
publicly?
Because like, I've actually caught one of my sons who at the time was five years old.
He was banging away at my laptop
and I'm like, Felix. Uh, what are you doing? And he's like,
I'm finding the password and I'm like,
I, I just had the moment I was so happy. Right? And at the same time, I was kind of like,
oh,
um
but, you know, because he seems to have that
he understands like if he gets the pin number to somebody's phone,
he can use that person's phone and play games on it, right?
So
he's pretty like he's quite seriously motivated to, you know,
to break into stuff because he wants to play games on it or whatever.
And, and so I've kind of been wondering about, you know,
resources for kids like that.
-- Yeah.
-- So our heck kids event, the tickets are available right now.
Um We're putting together a little bit more
details regarding the agenda of the event.
Um
So if you wanna blindly trust us,
uh you can buy a ticket now and we'll guarantee you'll be happy.
Um or um in the next uh probably week,
we'll be starting our marketing campaign of saying like,
you know, hey, um
you wanna take your kid
and show him some of these really awesome stem
subjects here at uh the Discovery World Science Museum, right?
And um
hang out with some really cool hackers and the adults will have fun.
The Children all have fun.
Um But yeah, wait, wait for those details in probably a week.
We're really, really close to the quality control that we are known for.
So we wanna make sure it's solid before we let you know.
Nice. That's fantastic. Cool. All right. So we're uh we're coming to the end here.
So I guess Michael, is there anything else you think that,
that the folks out there need to know about cipher con?
So
we have one speaker
named John
Platas and he's a former colleague of mine
and he is speaking on predictive analytics
and in a lot of cases,
we already know what you guys are looking for and we're gonna deliver it.
So I just let him run his computers and,
and, and, and soak up all that knowledge from you guys using your
uh your social media credentials. And
so we're potentially stalking you and we're gonna deliver exactly what you,
you hope to see at cipher console.
Make sure you do buy a ticket so we can deliver that right to you.
That's crazy.
That's the future
man.
-- Tell me what
-- to sell you.
It's still terrifying. Kirk. I, I
do, I want my illusion a free choice even though I know it's fake. I want it right.
I need that.
-- Amazon says you should buy
-- this and you're right.
But I still want to pretend I made that decision.
Hind hindsight is 2020.
But like if you can start predicting with some degree of accuracy of what you
want and then deliver it to you before you even know you want it.
I think that's pretty awesome.
-- Alright.
-- Anyway, that's
I
think about this right now.
So uh
so after,
after we,
yeah, after we hang up on this call,
I'm guessing you're really hungry for a cheeseburger, aren't you?
I'm I'm pretty sure you're gonna go get a cheeseburger.
I'm I'm ok. Actually I just hate suffer not long ago,
-- so
-- I'm
-- fine. I'm fine.
-- Yep. Yep.
-- You're
wanting a cheeseburger is essentially my default setting. So.
All right. All right, Mike.
So we have something fun to do at the very end here is before we go,
we have a lightning round for you two minutes.
We have a bunch of questions you've never seen
and feel free to just skip them if you want.
-- Yeah,
-- you can just say skip. That's the
ski
here we are.
So for our listeners, this is shamelessly stolen from George Strombolis
who is a Canadian TV celebrity. I
I'm not making this up. Ok, like go Google it.
Of course, nobody outside Canada has any clue who he is. But um, yeah, so
if you don't like it or if it's weird
anyway.
All right. All right.
You got a timer.
Yeah, I got my visual timer
which is not helpful as this is a writer of the mind, right?
So everyone imagine a timer in your head, which is set to two minutes
and we will hit start and then it will count down.
OK. So who's asking you or me?
I will,
I will let you ask the questions as long as you believe you can also work the timer.
OK.
It's a visual timer. Everybody. So pay attention.
All right, starting now. All right.
Well, you mentioned earlier. So what's your favorite dead operating system?
Oh,
I'm gonna skip that one. That one's dangerous.
OK. Uh
Maybe something a bit easier.
-- Uh Picard or Kirk. Uh
-- I'd
kill them both.
All right. Uh Your favorite open source project.
Um Me
exploit,
uh Your favorite Rs. A key size.
I'll just stick with 256
256 Rs.
A man that's embarrassed like you could crack that in real time on a phone.
Well, it, it's my favorite for other people to have. OK.
-- That's fair. I, I'll let that one go.
-- I guess we gotta clarify that question in
future.
-- Um Here's a question. Do you encrypt your email?
-- Uh
I encrypt my email but yours is wide open. P
All right. Uh Here's a good one, favorite movie portrayal of hacking.
Uh Oh, I have to go with the original hackers. I mean, that's just
-- classic, man.
-- That movie is phenomenal. I love that movie so much.
OK.
And then, um
uh well, here's a good one. What's your favorite or most? In your opinion?
Your most insecure language,
programming language?
Oh God, there's so many.
Um
I'm
gonna go back to my,
my original was Pascal. I'm gonna stick with Pascal.
All right.
And uh OK, what's your favorite? Um
Dead Protocol?
Uh
-- Nothing
-- ever Dies. Kurt. You should know that by
now.
Yeah, like, like dead. I'm like questioning what's really dead.
Nothing like,
like
beyond that, we're gonna go with like apple talk.
Good one. All right. Well, that's our two minute timer.
There's no noise. No one can see it. Kurt. You need it to make
noise
-- right. There we go. Ding. All right. Yay. Well done.
-- Well, I put my phone on silent
points.
So
you're done.
Awesome. All right, Michael Cargo. Thank you so much.
It has been awesome having this chat. I'm very excited for
Cypher.
I'm even more excited now after talking to you and I'm sad. I have to wait,
but I guess folks out there, uh, buy your tickets, buy them early, buy them often
and
you don't have to worry.
You can go try those cipher puzzles on Cipher
-- con.com. It's
-- easy to do that though. I want, I want someone to spoon
feed.
You need like,
like some version of it that just kind of solves it for me right where where I
can pretend I'm doing something and then it
just gives me the answer after five minutes.
So, you said your, your, your five year old was trying to break into your, uh,
your computer.
But we have like, 10 and 12 year olds cracking these crypto puzzles on our website.
So you gotta stop embarrassing yourself and go try.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, that's fair. Uh, I guess,
uh, little housekeeping then is. So, uh, how much is the ticket?
Uh, 175 and we throw some snacks at you. It's a two day.
Nice. Very cool. And they can go to Cipher
con.com
and purchase a ticket with
links are all there. Uh, 175. I assume you've got what? Credit card?
All that fun stuff. Yes.
Can you use
-- Bitcoin
-- paypal? And
we can use Bitcoin and not only can you use Bitcoin but
-- you get a bonus. If you use Bitcoin a bonus,
-- I already bought my ticket.
Maybe I should buy another one.
Uh,
what's,
what's the bonus? Let me know. I'll know if I should buy two tickets.
-- I, I can't disclose the bonus.
-- See, now, that's even worse. Now I'm gonna be like,
what is it? Should I buy a ticket?
We'll see. All right. Anyway,
well,
you can earn the bonus at the,
uh, at the conference, but by paying Bitcoin, I feel you already earned it.
Yeah. And, and so you see, that's the lazy way out, right?
I just pay with Bitcoin and then I don't have to do any real work at the conference.
Have
-- gone through ransomware. I guess they'll know what to do.
-- That's
true. It's just, yeah.
Right. It's just like ransomware.
Awesome. All right, Michael. Thank you so much. It has been an absolute pleasure.
Uh Good luck with the show. I will see you there
and, and folks out there buy your tickets
and hopefully we'll see you all there as well. So, all right, thanks guys.
Have a, have a great one.
Bye.