Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 177 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- Well, Happy 2020 to you, Kurt.
Yeah. Is it?
I guess it will be
the magic of podcasting says it's going to be 2020.
-- So
-- it will have been, has been.
So the, the, uh, the Douglas Adams grammar for time travel.
That's right. The,
the, the horrific
era
-- of the 20 tens is now past.
-- Yeah, because
-- the twenties, like we're in the decade of the twenties. Like,
-- that's right.
Nothing bad happens in the twenties.
And, you know, I remember the
Os the teens, I mean, the teens just sounds immature because they are.
But the twenties, like the roaring twenties, you know,
will bring back the flappers.
It'll be awesome.
Yeah. And the twenties were a great time. Right.
-- Nothing bad happened during the 19 twenties.
-- They
just ignore the, uh, the Weimar Republican those things
and we'll just wait for you to stop dying.
That's right.
That's
right.
I was ok. This is a segue but I was just thinking
somebody needs to go through the shows the first, like, two minutes of every show
and just chart
how much we talk about being sick to see. You know,
the cyclic
probably in the last couple we have because we're actually sick.
But I think I feel like it was also this time last year, the same.
It wouldn't surprise me. I mean, we have kids and
humans get sick on except, like, noticeable patterns.
It seems like, I mean,
if only the security industry had the kind of data the CDC has on disease,
but we don't, so we just make crap up. It's great.
Yeah.
So anyway, speaking of safety,
I'm thinking marketplace safety kind of timely being that
we just had Christmas and uh the online shopping
extravaganza that is Christmas and New Year.
Yeah. Yeah, that seems fair.
Although I don't do very much New Year shopping, I'll say maybe for tacos.
I'm just trying to remember, what was that?
Uh because Canada Post actually officially
gave out a day. Here we go. The Canada
uh the Canada post,
the official deadline to send stuff to get it in for December uh for um for Christmas
and it was for priority mail December 23rd for
Express Post the 20th and for regular parcels,
December 11th
and all those dates have passed. So if you've missed them all for this year or
for 2020 you have plenty of time to make those deadlines.
So uh but yeah, no looking at the marketplace because like I do,
I basically do all my shopping in November online.
Right.
And then packages show up for the next two weeks and I'm done, it's very stress free,
very forward
thinking of you.
And then I also buy, like, my stocking stuff and stuff.
Like I go to Mini.
So it's like this Japanese department, mini department store thing.
That's really nice. I don't know if you have them down there in the States,
you know, and I, uh, yeah, I just buy my stocking stuff or kind of,
you know, just buy random stuff locally. Right. Nice.
But it got me thinking about
because I've, you know, there were some things I wanted to buy
that were kind of very specific, like branded high quality items
and I'm looking for them. Yeah, I was getting some stuff that was,
seemed kind of cheap.
Did it have, I guess logos and names on
it?
It was
probably counterfeit
stuff.
Like I've got a rule now, like, if I'm buying cables online, I'm either going
for the anchor stuff or if it doesn't really matter that much.
I just buy the, the Amazon brand one which is,
I know it's probably garbage but it's probably not
garbage that will catch my house on fire.
Maybe not. I mean, yeah, just buy your cables by the pound. It's fine.
Well, because the reasoning is,
and this is backed up by what Amazon Amazon is recently doing.
So on the Amazon marketplace, there's a lot of counterfeit stuff,
-- like a lot of
-- count. I've heard it's a huge problem actually.
-- And
-- going back to economics and externalities,
Amazon is basically claiming we're a marketplace, sort of common carrier status.
We're not responsible for what moves through our marketplace.
So if you buy some fake stuff on our marketplace and it goes horribly wrong.
Go to the person who made this and sold it to you. We're just the middleman.
It's not our problem, right?
Whereas if that happens in a physical store, like a,
like a Walmart or a Target or whatever,
you can hold Walmart and Target responsible, right?
So
I hate to say this,
but so what I do is when I'm offered the cheap
choices and I want the cheap stuff I buy the Amazon
one. So that Amazon ultimately is sort of held responsible. So my hope is
that Amazon did at least a little bit of due diligence
and made sure like that this USB C cable or whatever
-- is, you know, reasonably not going to catch fire or
-- you, you'd think so.
But I understand what you're saying.
Whole weird marketplace atmosphere is why I stopped buying computer gear
from new egg because it became a situation where it's like,
is this new egg?
Is this like some random person? Oh, I did not know that.
Yeah, they started doing it a couple of years ago and I, I just,
I started buying stuff and it would either take forever to ship or you'd get
like broken boxes and stuff and the sellers were non responsive and it just,
it wasn't worth the pain and suffering.
So, screw it. I quit.
And see, and conversely, I have found one marketplace that seems to work really,
really well
and it's for a very high quality product that is very hard to
fake and that I know is near and dear to your heart.
And that's Lego.
-- Is
-- it a podcast? Oh Lego. Ok. Yeah,
Lego,
it's Bricklin
and,
and what's really kind of wild is Bricklin is
actually apparently being acquired by the Lego group.
-- So it's going to become like an official LEGO thing. But
-- anyways, what is Bricklin?
I don't know what this is.
So the idea of Bricklin is
you want to make some specific
-- thing out of LEGO and you're missing like two pieces,
-- ok?
-- You
-- need
-- those
-- two pieces, right?
-- I would go steal them from someone else
-- probably.
Well, that's basically what this is.
So people basically inventory all the lego they want to sell.
And I mean, like, I'm dealing with one guy locally that has something like 5000
different pieces inventory.
And I'm just wondering like, how does he store this stuff?
-- There can't be a return on investment to doing that.
-- I don't know, man,
I was like, I was doing a bit of research into this and I decided number one,
I would need some sort of like storage system
that can store like a million small things easily.
Number two, I need like some sort of robotic vision thing because
you know, if given a piece of lego, I know you like,
eventually you'll be able to find out like what
the part number is and like inventory it properly.
But man finding that part number can be tricky, you know,
because how do you describe it?
But anyways,
the thing I realize Lego is incredibly hard to fake because like every
piece of Lego has the word Lego printed on it in general.
-- Even the little like the the little posts have Lego inscribed in them. It's
-- exactly.
Yeah.
And number two,
when you touch a piece of not
like I call it
Flegel
like German for fake Lego.
Um
like even my son is like he will find a piece of like,
ah and then he'll like run off to the garbage and throw it away,
you know,
you can
Yeah, but dude, it doesn't fit together, right? The color is off, the feel is off.
It's like a wax ear plastic. It doesn't,
you know, it doesn't snap in, right? And
if you build something with it and you like drop it, it like falls apart immediately,
right?
Versus you build something out of Lego properly and drop and
it breaks into two pieces that you just put back together.
It is true.
But I will also add that the knockoff legos are
like a quarter of the price of the real LEGO.
Here's the thing.
When we go to my parents' house, we still play with my LEGO.
-- Yeah.
-- Doesn't everyone? Right?
When you like,
everyone's parents have their old Lego in a box and they still
work the exact same and they look the same as they did
30 years ago
and we'll maybe post this in the show notes. Two very special pieces though.
I have a piece of lego. That's the old pattern.
It's, if you flip it over, it's got the square pattern,
not the circuit pattern underneath.
And here's the best part I'm holding in my hands. A six by one black standard piece
with a manufacturing defect.
-- And what is the manufacturing defect?
-- One of the pins on the bottom
is
sticks out by about half a millimeter. There's like a bit of spruce sticking out.
OK.
So you can't put, you can't attach it to another piece of Lego.
And
I remember playing with this piece of LEGO and I'm like
trying to click it to another piece and it wouldn't click.
And I was so confused like it took me a good half hour to figure out
and finally flip it over and look at it and really examine it closely.
There's, it sticks out a little bit in the middle.
-- I don't
-- think I've ever gotten a piece of lego that was
misshapen and all of the probably millions of pieces
of lego I have touched in my life.
Exactly. So like I'm keeping this like I this sits on my desk as a reminder.
But as perfect as lego is
I have a piece with a manufacturing defect
wild.
Now,
I will also say the thing that always blows my mind with LEGO is
I have never put together a Lego set that was missing a piece.
Sometimes they give you a few, too many, but I never experienced too few pieces.
I actually complained.
I was missing a piece once and then found it like two days later, it was like
pulling off
-- or whatever. And I was like, damn it, I knew
-- it.
-- Did. They send you a new piece?
-- They
Yeah. Well, and that's the thing, right?
They will just mail you a piece and there's people
on Reddit that talk about this that they just keep,
like they basically say, like, basically when they need a specific piece of lego,
they'll look up a set that has it and then
will be like,
I bought this set and it's missing this piece that I need and that's called fraud.
Well,
yeah,
it kind of is.
But anyway, so the idea with Bricklin is, you know,
these people put up all their Lego for sale,
they set a price and it literally can be anywhere from like
a penny a piece to like 20 bucks a set or,
you know,
250 bucks a set or even 10 or $20 a piece for like really rare pieces or historical
thing,
whatever.
So basically,
Bricklin is a marketplace of people's marketplaces, right?
So each seller has their like inventory and in most cases,
they have hundreds or thousands of different pieces of LEGO
and you place an order with them and a lot of them will have a minimum order of like,
say $3.
Some literally don't like I, I just recently
from one guy, I bought like 70 cents a Lego
and like he's
just gonna and shipping and handling on it is like three bucks, right?
And he's just going to fire it into an envelope and mail it to me.
And again, I'm just wondering like, yeah,
-- the return on investment of doing this like man,
-- that's,
that's got to be low.
But ok, so here's my question then is how does Bricklin make sure you aren't
selling
knock off Lego or
-- there's a
-- feedback system, right? Just like ebay or
whatever, right? Like
ebay then, right?
So like I've already got a positive feedback because I
made my orders and paid.
So the buyers, I guess ebay has buyer feedback too
because I'm not sending you a laptop.
If you have a feedback rating of like this dude's a scammer.
That's fair.
But yeah, and so I think in this case it works well because here's the thing.
If I receive fake Lego,
I can tell right away.
I can validate that this is or is not proper LEGO really easily
because like I start building with it and I'll know pretty quick.
But the problem is there's a lot of products I buy a great example being a USB C cable.
Like, unless I do the, the digital multi meter test and have that equipment,
I don't know if it has the right resistors and stuff in it or if it's like,
feeding in too much,
-- you're not enough or
-- we can expand this even. And I always love when
you,
you talk to a salesperson and I'll pick on security products because they're super
easy to pick on and you talk to them about something and they're like,
oh, yes, it, it,
and it does your laundry and then you get it and it's, it's clearly a cereal box,
duct taped to a piece of wood and you're like, what did I just pay you for?
And I think this is, I mean, this is a problem across nearly every industry,
to be honest with you, except LEGO, obviously.
But it's, it's hard.
Yeah. Well, like cars.
Yeah, this car is anti lock braking.
Well, like, unless you let me drive it on a skid pan,
I guess I'm gonna believe you,
you got here sooner than I thought we would.
But cars are the perfect example of where things
start to get weird because when cars fail,
people die, when people die
some organization, be it lawyers or a government body or whatever pays attention.
Not always true.
Uh, so in Canada recently it's been discovered that when you,
when your car basically just catches on fire randomly,
the manufacturer doesn't have to report that to the Canada Transport Safety Board.
I, I bet if it happens enough
they do,
they just quietly settle these things,
you know, they pay you for the value of your car and have it towed.
Because what happens is there was, um, it was a,
there's a couple of different makes and models of car.
One of them being some Mercedes
where
somebody, you know, they basically bought one,
drove it off the lot and like two miles later,
the thing catches fire and burns to a crisp.
It's fine.
And so it makes the news and then like six more people come forward and say, yeah,
that happened to me too.
Interesting.
I'm surprised they didn't have to sign paperwork that said
we will never tell anyone our Mercedes caught on fire.
I suspect they did and
-- they
-- might have, yeah, it's probably not very enforceable.
But so, and here we go.
Perfect example then.
So like last year there was like a recall of tens of thousands
of little Mercedes smart cars because apparently they just sort of catch fire
-- except there is a recall
-- once they got
it got bad enough.
But here, ok. Now here's the question though. They might have caught on fire.
But did people die? I bet people didn't die.
I think if people die it's different than if they don't know.
Not that I'm, I'm saying cars letting on fire is ok.
-- But
-- that's that Tesla that caught fire and the guy
died inside of it because they couldn't open the doors.
Remember? Because the electrical system was wonky or something. And
the Teslas have that door handle that doesn't,
you can't work them from the outside without like power.
Yeah, there's, you touch a thing and the door handle pops out.
So it's like streamlined.
I'm, yeah, I'm just like, oh,
well,
the other thing I was thinking with the cyber truck demo
where he smashed the glass in the cyber truck with that,
like metal ball and it didn't smash or it's supposed to smash.
But my thinking is a normal car has a, has a failure scenario of like,
if I smack the glass with something harder than the tempered glass like that,
you know, I have that little seatbelt cutting tool with the metal end on it
in my glove box. Oh, sure.
So, I kind of want my windows to have that failure scenario so that I can, like,
smash them and get out of my car.
I would agree.
I think windows that can't be broken are an anti feature in civilized society.
For, again, it's one of those, for 99.9% of people. Absolutely. For like, the 0.1%
driving around with armed guards.
Ok. That's a different scenario.
-- You
-- got to
trick your car out anyway, in that situation because you're like,
bulletproofing the thing and all that stuff.
Actually,
I remember I read a story once I'll try to look this up and put it in the show notes.
But there was a situation where they had to transport the president
and they didn't have a secured vehicle and
they ended up like taking Al Capone's limo,
which was heavily armored for obvious reasons.
Yeah, that was the secret service with the first,
they wanted an armored car and that was the fastest way to get one.
Yeah. Right.
Like, oh, we have one because this guy, like, has a legitimate threat model.
-- He's defending against
-- army
guns.
Right? Brain prey.
But, yeah, yeah, for the majority of us, I, I want my windows to be breakable so that,
you know,
if I'm trapped in a burning car and my car door won't open because I was in an accident.
I mean, I want the policeman to do,
come up smack it with a baton
-- again. Drag my butt out of
-- there.
Ok. We're off in the weeds because we're trying to talk about secure marketplaces.
But anyway, my point being, I think automobiles are unique because
I think in most automobile failure scenarios
there's human casualty.
-- Well, and the constructive loss of an expensive object
-- and that's very true also.
Whereas like if you buy a Janky USB cable off of Amazon.
What's the worst that's going to happen? You're probably going to fry your phone,
right. Which
it sucks,
but it's no one's really getting all that hurt.
I mean, your house could light on fire, but I bet that's not common.
What gets me though is going to the marketplace is that, you know,
if you can externalize the cost of counterfeits, not just in the,
the liability aspect of it,
but for example
of most of these marketplaces,
you have to prove somebody is selling a counterfeit product, complain,
go through a process and get them delisted.
And that of course, is hugely time consuming and expensive,
so much so that there's now companies that do that,
that's like their business model, right?
They protect your brand
and some of it I would imagine is pretty simple because for example,
one thing I've noticed with a lot of fakes is
they use the stock photos from the real one,
wouldn't you?
I mean,
yeah, we already breaking the law. What's a little copyright infringement?
Exactly.
But again, you know, having forcing the,
the the company to go through and protect their brand makes it hugely costly.
And, you know,
I can't possibly know every marketplace where my product is being spoofed and sold.
Right? That's part of the problem too.
And so there's,
I was reading some articles where these
people were just not selling online anymore because
due to fakes and due to the brand damage that these fakes were doing
it just, they literally were,
people were trying to return faulty goods
to the original manufacturer and the original manufacturer
in this one case is like, can we get the serial number off that thing?
And then the person's like, oh, there, there isn't one.
Yeah, I must have bought a fake.
Right. But again, you know, you don't buy something online and then
examine it to, you know, see if it's counterfeit or not.
You just sort of, unless it's like, really janky and, like, totally fake,
-- you just sort of assume you got the right thing.
-- Right?
I can't think of a single thing I bought online and assumed it was fake.
Now at the same time,
I generally, if I'm buying something branded that I know is going to be good,
I will,
I, I can't think of any instances there.
I've been concerned but at the same time, like, I bought like, yeah,
USB cables by the pound basically on Amazon because I'm like,
I don't even care whatever they're using.
Like, the kids can charge your tablets with this.
I don't care.
And I've actually had really good luck, you know, knock on wood, I'm sure.
Now I do myself. But so anyway, anyway, uh, no, I, I get that. And
so what is, I guess what is the point of this conversation? You are envisioning?
Like, where do we go at this? And how do we, how do we, is there a way to even fix it?
Do you think?
Well,
I suspect if you made the marketplace liable
or even somewhat liable for counterfeit goods,
that would go a long way
-- to solving the problem.
-- How do you do that though? I mean, in the case of LEGO,
for example, you bought something counterfeit from Amazon,
Amazon has to refund you,
you think Amazon is gonna maybe spend a little more time
and effort solving this problem when instead of being saying,
oh, look, go to the original seller.
I mean,
I'll agree with you there.
But now you run into situations where Amazon's gonna say it's not
a fake and you're going to say it is a fake.
And now what?
Yeah,
see and, and that leads to part of the second problem is you can do uh for example,
a chargeback if you buy this, you know,
going back to our credit card debit card episode, right?
Buy things with your credit card because then you can do a charge back.
But again, yeah, if, if the merchant disputes it or worse,
what if the merchant decides to blacklist your account?
-- Because you're becoming kind of a pain.
-- I'm sure that happens on a regular basis.
I've only ever had to return like two things to Amazon.
Um And they were like, one was clearly the wrong product.
It was like literally a puzzle in a box and it
wasn't the puzzle that was on the picture of the,
or the one I'd ordered.
And then the second one was a plastic thing that was like cracked,
like it arrived broken,
you know,
and I was like,
this thing is a 3d printed object, you know, in the way it's printed,
you could tell that there's essentially it printed a thing part of it,
but then cooled and then printed on top of that.
-- Right? And so it just didn't bond.
-- Right.
I got you.
Yeah, that can happen.
But, uh, I, I feel like,
I feel like those European consumer laws around fitness of purpose,
you know, it has to be good for one or two years. Otherwise,
see, the thing is in Europe, in many jurisdictions,
you return it to the store, you bought it from, they're on the hook for it
and go back to my whole, you know,
Costco argument of why I buy stuff at
Costco is because Costco's like you're returning what?
Ok. Here's your money.
Yeah, they're pretty good about that.
Half eaten ham. You didn't like it? Ok.
Right.
And so my experience of Costco is they tend to sell decent stuff.
Uh, yeah.
But now at the same time I'd say my general
experience of Amazon up to this point has been,
they tend to sell decent stuff.
Now, I don't,
I don't know of an instance where I've been dealing with a
third party versus Amazon because I don't pay that close of attention.
Well, everything that arrives from China.
Well, basically everything that's not shipped in an Amazon box is probably not
from Amazon.
And, and even if it does arrive from Amazon, right?
They, so part of the challenge with Amazon is they also co
mingle products, right? So they'll get
say widgets from the widget company
and then they'll get
widgets like the same name and model and serial numbers supposedly from
some Randall reseller in like uh to pick on, you know, the US from the US, right?
And
so for example, when I'm buying widgets,
I might get a widget from the company or from the seller in the US,
even if I'm sort of quasi
officially buying it from the, you know, the US, the official US maker, right?
Actually, I've heard this is a problem buying SD cards off of Amazon
because
apparently the thing that's happening is Amazon's
doing this weird commingling and people are
basically like sending them bogus cards that get mixed in with the real cards.
So even if the seller is Amazon, they can end up sending you one of these bogus cards.
And so anytime you buy like an SD card online, you're supposed to,
there's,
there's applications you can test it with to make sure
it's actually the size that it claims to be.
Well.
And like, I've recently had two SD cards die that I bought on Amazon and they like,
they were less than a year old.
-- Wow,
-- that's pretty.
Yeah, I've got like SD cards that are decades old and they still work.
These are 21, I think they were 128 or whatever gig cards
in a Raspberry pi.
And like,
one day the Raspberry pi failed to boot and it
was the SD card and I'm not going to troubleshoot
it.
And,
you know, my, none of my machines would even recognize the card wild man.
Like, it was dead dead. And I'm like, I'm not going to return this to Amazon.
You know, it's like 2030 bucks,
but I'm also not going to buy SD cards off Amazon anymore.
-- Yeah,
-- that seems pretty fair. I, I will, I, that's where I bought online recently.
I'll have to rethink this process maybe
as much as I hate on Apple for doing that whole where this, like, for example,
the new iphone screens have that like encryption stuff
built into them so that they can make sure
it's an official iphone
like Apple iphone screen and not some, like
third party gray market made one
as much as I hate on that.
I get why Apple is doing it.
You know, and I don't necessarily fully agree with it, but I get
-- it
-- and they roll some of that back
sort of, but I mean,
they're just going to gently push it through because
again, from their perspective, right?
It makes their life a nightmare because, you know,
somebody gets their iphone repaired at a wonky repair shop and maybe it's perfect
-- and maybe it's not perfect. But who do they usually end up blaming?
-- Oh,
it's going to be Apple's fault. Unquestionably. I
mean, I, I get that
and so,
you know, II, I mean,
I love Luis Rossman and the Rossman group and
what they're doing for the right to repair stuff.
But on the flip side,
I also get the manufacturers wanting to control the supply of these
parts to make sure, you know, like going back to cars, right?
Car parts in general, you know,
I had to buy a new rear windshield wiper motor because the one in my car died.
And so it's like 50 bucks a Canadian tire,
you know, I buy it and I mean, it's a motor, it's a Reman
motor. So what's interesting is it was like, it actually cost $90
but as soon as I bring the old motor back, they give me a refund of $40 for the casing.
They want the metal casing, right? Because
I'm not going to like 3d print those, like nobody's making those casings anymore.
But take that casing, taking the motor out, putting a new motor in,
if you know what you're doing, that's like 20 minutes easy.
And so, you know, I swapped the motor out and yeah, it's been working fine.
My rear windshield wiper works great now.
But, you know,
I'm buying from a store they're in theory buying from a trusted remanufacture.
So, you know, there's, there's trust involved and hopefully, but,
yeah, with like SD cards and things like that. I mean, it's the wild west.
-- So,
-- you know, what you just made me think of is
if you go to kind of the Toyota model
of quality and they're obsessed with their supply chain.
And, I mean, this is one of the reasons that when, you know, when you buy a Toyota,
the things last like 100 years.
And
if you look, yeah,
most brick and mortar stores are going to pay
attention to what the products are selling are.
They're going to have people that inspect that supply
chain and they're going to want to understand what,
like I knew some people who worked for some brick and mortar stores
professional,
their, their job was right.
They'd like they would fly out to location and
they would understand what is going on here.
Let's make sure the thing I'm going to pay you for is what I'm paying you for
and whatever.
And
so anyway,
when you talk about these marketplaces and you
have these kind of third party sellers,
there is zero economic incentive to vet them because first of all,
-- you probably can't,
-- it's their business opportunity is to let these people in.
That's their actual business model, right?
-- Is to make it available to all these randos,
-- right?
-- And they get a cut and they have zero liability today that's
-- the ebay model, right?
The ebay model is literally
-- let completely random people sell stuff.
-- Yeah.
But I would, I would argue that when I go to ebay and buy things,
I know it's a flea market model and I know I could be buying,
you know, an old piece of garbage in a box.
And it is, you know, I know that when I go to Amazon, I'm expecting it to be a real thing.
-- So
-- I've bought a lot of old Baedeker's travel guides off of ebay.
Uh, these are books that are usually more than 100 years old.
You know, they're lovely travel books, fold out maps. Just beautiful books.
Weren't you just telling me before the podcast
that you're getting rid of all your books?
Yeah. Those I'm keeping and either reselling or keeping because they're,
I mean, they're
wonderful books. But anyways, the point is they would be really difficult to fake.
Probably. I mean, something that specifically, yes,
I think that's part of the problem is a lot of this
stuff that's being faked on Amazon is not necessarily easy to fake,
but
for example,
there's this article about these sort of four in one baby stroller car seat,
whatever thing and it just made CNN,
they tested it and like the thing just flies apart in plastic shrapnel everywhere,
you know, in a 30 mile per hour car crash.
And these things are selling like the cheap
version is selling on Amazon for 300 bucks.
Us
and I'm guessing
change.
Yeah.
And I'm guessing that, you know,
this thing is being made in China for a lot less than that, no doubt.
And,
yeah, I, I don't know. It's tough. Right.
Because the whole model of ebay and it kind of worked was
let completely random people sell completely random stuff.
But at least there, like you said, there's that,
-- I know I'm going to the flea market.
-- I know what I'm getting into. Right.
-- It's like, it's not a surprise.
-- Yeah.
Whereas I want a class 10, high quality 128 gig SD card.
I, yeah, I might be buying just a plastic wafer.
No, it's probably like a four megabyte SD card that
gonna lie to you and tell it, it has plenty of room.
I, I saw a
picture once this is, I'll try to find it and put it in the show notes.
But it was, it was on Reddit where somebody bought an external hard drive
and
they opened it up and it had like a rock glued to the inside of it with
a 256 megabyte SD card. Like,
well, and I've actually bought legitimate, like, 3.5 inch SD or, um, SSD drives
and opened it up just for funsies.
And it's like, just, it's like a tiny one by two inch, you know,
circuit board in there.
Yeah. Well, you don't need a lot of space.
Like, they literally just made it big enough so it'll fit in the mounting hole.
Right. And I'm ok with that.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Yeah.
Well, it's like the bee headphones where they intentionally put like,
little weights in them that they claim are like, to improve the hearing experience.
And it's like, no, so it doesn't feel like a flimsy cheap piece of plastic garbage.
Right. Right.
And I,
and in some ways I'm ok with that because certain things
are just more enjoyable with that when they're a little heavier.
But yeah, I get it.
I would like to think that, you know,
Amazon is working on A I and stuff to
help prevent the spoof products and the fake products.
But I think fundamentally until there's a real incentive to address the problem
and I hate to say this, but I think that's going to be regulation.
I think it's, it's gonna be,
-- it's gonna get worse.
-- It's going to get way worse.
It may never get better Kurt because unless people are getting hurt
then nobody cares. I mean, that's just the reality of everything.
And this is like the one thing I keep coming back
to every time I do security research into stuff like this is
if people are only getting ripped off and not hurt,
it usually doesn't matter.
Now if you start ripping off, like people in charge,
then they start to care a little bit.
But fundamentally if you're just screwing normal people. They don't care at all.
Well, we'll talk about this in a, in another show.
But, I mean, they just recently in the US and Canada have passed those new, um,
telemarketing bills to prevent spoofed calls.
Right.
I didn't hear about this but I'm sure it's a worthless law.
Here's the best part in Canada.
They either have to implement blocking technology
or
kind of give customers the option of blocking stuff.
And I'm like,
that's useless because what I'm going to do just
start blocking every fake number that calls me.
-- That's so not
-- helpful. You set up your phone so the default ringtone is nothing.
And then you said people you'd know to have real ringtones and
then when someone calls you who isn't in your address book,
your phone doesn't ring.
Yeah.
The challenge I have is the school calls and
the teachers use their personal cell phones and stuff.
So I do get
legit, you know, and I don't want to be like, you know, what I'm gonna do,
ask the school for a list of all the teachers, personal phone numbers.
I don't think that would be unreasonable. But
anyway, anyway,
no, I hear you.
I think the moral of the story is if you're gonna buy stuff online, you know,
if it seems too good to be true,
it is
-- not, it probably is. It
-- is.
I have a better moral of the story is I'm probably just not gonna care.
So, whatever, that's the reality of it.
I mean, am I gonna drastically change my buying habits? No, not really.
Am I gonna get ripped off? Probably.
Am I gonna get ripped off enough to care? Probably not.
Yeah, that's fair.
Welcome to 2020 everybody.
I guess we just give up.
But honestly it's not, it's like the whole package porch thing. Right?
Like, yeah, a few of them are gonna get stolen.
But ultimately, it's just so much more efficient that
-- it's ok
-- and yeah, and, and you know what, when you stop caring, life gets a lot nicer.
I'm just saying anyway. All right, man, it's time I'm gonna end it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for listening.
You can go to open social security podcast.com to hit up the show notes,
you Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too,
-- everybody. Thanks.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.