Hello and welcome to episode 96 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- How are you
-- doing, Kurt?
Good, good, summer's here. It's awesome.
Sweet.
So, I assume that just means you have less snow, right?
Yeah. And the grass is going from brown to green.
-- Wow.
-- Fantastic.
-- Oh, goodness. But now you have to mow the lawn. So there's that.
-- Yes. Yes.
-- I think my kids are almost old enough to do it. Maybe next
-- mine totally are.
And it's awesome.
-- That must be lovely.
-- It, it is. It's very nice.
Yes. But
anyway, anyway,
so we,
we had a chat after the last episode and
we thought it could be good to talk about backdoors
as, as we discussed the get cookies backdoor last time.
But in, in this time, do it in the context of legal backdoors.
Well, or even more, maybe specifically the legally mandated backdoors.
Right. Because I'm pretty sure,
yeah, I don't,
I don't fully understand or know what would constitute a legal
backdoor as far as like an end user license agreement goes.
Uh,
-- so that's
-- that
I wouldn't even think of it in terms of end user licenses.
But we'll say, like law enforcement,
I
mean, by
the
back
door where it's not,
you,
you have to put this back door in or else some consequence occurs.
And, I mean, this is not a new topic. I actually had to look like
this is, this has been going on literally for decades. I mean, we have the, uh,
sort of the last, yeah, the last sort of major,
one of the last major revs of this was in 1994.
So that's uh
oh my God, that's 28 years ago.
Sorry. 18,
wait, I can't math so good.
Yeah, 24 years ago. Holy.
Wow, sorry. That's.
Yeah. Wow. Uh Anyways, this is this thing called ka
the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act
and essentially my understanding of what triggered it is um
phones, OK.
This is going back, old timey phones were, you know,
like electromechanical relay switch devices
and like literally back in the olden days, you, you would tap a phone by literally
like taping a tape recorder and, you know,
hooking up the, not a microphone but like a, a wire with like two alligator clips
and like attaching that physically to somebody's phone line,
right? You know,
like straight up and,
and because I remember reading about how to detect
wiretaps back in the day and they would,
they would do things like, look for voltage loss, you know, like, oh, like
normally your phone line is like five volts. Now it's like 4.1 right?
Something like that.
And, you know, just all these things that it's like, like,
and I couldn't understand until it wasn't frame, you know,
till I put it in the frame of, oh, yeah, like really old timey technology because,
you know, back in the nineties everything was becoming computerized.
Just
-- it was that simple. And
-- it's also worth noting that
if, if we want to go back in time, you can,
a telegraph is probably the easiest way
to describe it where a telegraph was literally
a wire between two places,
right?
And so obviously tapping telegraph lines was incredibly trivial.
And then we got the telephone network and now we had
a wire
from,
well, telegraphs used two wires.
They didn't, they used a single wire with the earth as the sink
because I always was wondering about that because
yeah, I mean, how,
yeah, no telegraphs crazy. Cool. A single wire magic.
Right. Right.
So anyway, but,
but the trick with telephones was you had a wire from your house to a central office
and then the central office could magically connect wires as needed.
But we were still basically talking about
like a hard connection between your phone. Like
-- you were talking
-- to,
it was not
a packet based network.
It was a circuit based network where and it would
literally physically complete a circuit between you and the other party
Right. Right. Exactly.
And, and even then
I, I know there were wiretap laws about what law enforcement could and couldn't do
in terms of listening in, on conversations on telephones.
And this was also funny because,
you know, there's always like the old timey movies
where you've got the operator listening in and like that, that totally happened.
-- I mean, there's nothing that really stopped them from doing.
-- Well.
You had party lines in rural areas where you literally had a single phone line
servicing like 10 houses
and you literally would pick up the phone
and hear other people talking and supposed to,
you're supposed to put it down and wait your turn,
right. Which is just crazy to think about.
I mean, could you imagine something like that today? Just,
um, so
basically what what happened is, you know, back in the day, physically,
wiretapping stuff was easy.
You basically just had law enforcement drive over to the phone company and like
plug in some equipment. And of course, then, you know,
the phone company started doing it and just
charging law enforcement for it because uh ultimately,
now the beauty is wiretapping has actually become a,
a profit center for a lot of phone carriers,
right? They, uh in one case, they accidentally sent out the bill
for the wiretapping also to the suspect.
Whoops. Yeah,
that happened. And um,
so yeah, back but the, the thing that was happening is, you know,
phone systems were becoming computerized and more importantly,
uh phone calls were, well, the last mile was still, you know, physically your wire,
you know, running
like an old tiny rotary telephone or whatever.
But the back end the back haul was becoming things like, you know, FDD I, the fiber,
what is it, fiber distributed data interface?
I don't know. Sure. Yeah.
So you basically, you know,
you had fiber optics connecting all the major phone exchanges, you know,
with computers basically packets
the data,
shoving it over this fiber loop. And you know,
a lot better because the local phone company actually has
a museum and they have a um a section of wire
and it's a 3600 pair of wire. So it's 3600 pairs of very small wire.
And like
literally, you know,
people like you think a backhoe hitting a fiber is bad
nowadays with like 10 or 20 or 50 fibers in that wire
in that cable.
You know,
they literally would have instances where like a cable with
3600 physical pairs of wires would get dug up.
Yeah. Good luck splicing that thing.
Some poor bugger had to go down the hole and like spend, you know,
-- the rest of the month splicing
-- wire, man.
That's crazy
to think about.
Yeah. So
anyways they, so, you know, law enforcement,
you know,
they're not stupid and they saw the coming
computerization of it and kind of went well,
hey,
we can make this a heck of a lot more, uh,
easy and, you know, harder to detect by basically, you know,
forcing people who build this computer equipment
and software and whatnot
to put in the legally mandated back door so that we can go to the carrier and say,
you know, that guy over there with this phone number,
I want you to record
all the
conversations on that phone line out and incoming,
you know, and sent us that recording,
however, burn it to CD or whatever,
you know, and, and Bill of for Sweet. Right.
And, and that's basically what happened, you know,
the difference here being is that,
you know, there was still, the carriers were still heavily involved, right?
Like law enforcement didn't have like a direct line in,
uh, to the equipment to simply, you know, tell it to do what they want.
And I don't think that's really ever happened anywhere,
to be honest, not that I've read
-- what, what has happened where, well,
-- in the sense,
I don't think law enforcement has ever really been given like
unfettered access to switching equipment to, you know, turn tapping on and off
documents.
Well,
-- what happened
-- there?
Subtle difference. My understanding of that is that the NSA had traffic mirrored
to them.
Right. So kind of like a port span.
Well, basically it's, it's a, it's,
yeah, it's, it's a hair of a difference,
but essentially my understanding of that is,
is that they had traffic like a span mirror.
So, and then they basically just all the traffic coming in out of that
whatever device computer was then sent down a pipe, you know, to room,
whatever that magic room in that AT&T building was called.
For example,
where the NSA had a whole bunch of intercept equipment set up.
So it's, it's functionally basically the same thing. Actually. You're right.
Right.
You know, and,
and basically the biggest thing is this is before we even had an inkling of
in properly encrypted communications, especially properly encrypted,
end to end communications for, for lack of a better word, civilians, consumers.
Right.
Right. Right.
And, and in fact,
that's a really good point because I think in the last couple of years
is when end to end communications have really kind of become a big thing.
Whereas before that you had what, like GP G
and GP G was terrible to use or I guess P GP, depending upon how you want to call it.
-- That's true. It's
-- not
like
I'm sorry it has.
And the other thing I think that's really happened, that's interesting to me is
literally every, like, chat program that I have
or not chat program rather.
But chat service,
like every chat service in the last five years has just
added voice and video calls as a feature like slack.
Right. Right.
One day that little phone icon thing popped up and I was going,
I wonder what that does.
Click ring, ring, ring, ring. Oh, I guess it makes, you know, I can make, uh,
I'm going to sound old because I'm going to say it
makes a phone call except it's absolutely not a phone call.
It has nothing to do with a phone call or, you know,
signal being a great example of like, well, it was
end to end text chat and now it does voice and video,
you know,
and so
we have this idea, you know, law enforcement doesn't, for some crazy reason,
doesn't like the idea of, you know, the bad guys having
communication technology that they can't at all
monitor,
right? I mean, that, that's a huge,
uh, intelligence gathering resource to lose potentially, right?
-- It,
-- it, it goes even deeper than that even.
I mean, I, I imagine we'll get there, but kind of the topic of
the, the locked iphones keeps coming up in this context, right?
Where, where that you have a law enforcement agency saying we,
we need to unlock this iphone, you know, for reasons.
And of course, Apple is saying no and they're saying, you know, do it or else. And then
so far this like crazy Mexican standoff is, is not, has never ended
-- because
-- that,
uh Israeli company supposedly has provided software and
I guess effectively zero days to unlock the,
um,
the phones.
Yeah. And they sell the box, the box is remarkably affordable.
It's like tens of thousands of dollars. It's,
it's not expensive,
but the size of a deck of cards, I guess,
and you basically plug in an iphone and it unlocks it
using some sort of security exploit.
But again, I think that's kind of a different conversation. Right.
I'm more interested in the conversation about,
like, what if Apple did supply law enforcement with a,
with a back door into the phone?
-- Like, what
-- does that mean? Important distinction to make? Right. Right.
Now, Apple is like, no, we're not going to unlock that phone for you.
But what's more important is Apple is saying, no,
we're not going to build a service or an ability
to where we have like master keys that we can hand out to you
and there's kind of a couple of layers here, right? So
on one level, some of the older iphones,
it's believed Apple could create like an an update
that you could push on to the phone and it would unlock the phone, right?
The new phones though.
My understanding is they have their security enclave configured in such
a way they couldn't do that if they wanted to.
Well, the older phones don't as I understand it,
have the security enclave processor or whatever they have
is nowhere near as sophisticated as the current version.
Right.
So yeah, what, what Apple has done is essentially put hardware on the phone,
the security enclave chip where that's where the encryption and decryption
keys physically live and where they physically do their work.
And so my understanding of it, for example, is that you can still
one of the attacks apparently was you, you basically disassemble the phone,
get the security enclave chip out,
do a couple of attempts and then reset the chip before it kind of locks itself down.
Right.
So you can effectively brute force it, but you basically have to, you know,
disassemble the phone and have a lab uh
of equipment to, you know, do this attack, right. So it's pretty nontrivial.
Well, and not only that, any time you take a piece of hardware apart,
there's a nonzero chance that you're going to ruin it,
be it, you know, slip a screwdriver slips or, or something happens and,
and now it's dead forever.
And so the, you know,
the concern is Apple doesn't really want to
build something that provides a back door where
like I said, they hold all the master keys for example, or the fundamentally,
you know,
either Apple holds the keys or a third party
holds the keys or law enforcement holds the keys.
And you can talk about all the,
you know, three parties out of five have to agree crypto.
Like there's all sorts of possible technical means to supposedly make this secure,
that's with big air quotes.
But fundamentally, uh no matter how much technology you apply to this problem,
you've now built
a
massive potential flaw into the system,
uh
not potential,
potential in any way. It is guaranteed to fail at
some point
because at some point there will be a threat that, you know,
the government changes or
the government enacts a law that, yeah,
now we're, you know,
all those keys have to be given to law enforcement or you go to jail forever.
Well, in, in part of it too is which governments?
-- Well, exactly,
-- of course, my government is fine so they can do it.
But those other governments, like, we don't like those guys
as a Canadian citizen. Yeah.
Do I want the, us being able to unlock my phone remotely while I'm in Canada to do,
having nothing to do with America.
Exactly.
What gets me is this, this issue keeps coming up like it just won't die.
And, and I don't mean even the issue of legally mandated backdoors because that,
that will always come up.
People will like, there's just people that will never let go of that one.
Right. And that's just how it is.
But the fact that there's people who are like, yeah, we can do that securely
with like, no risk. It's like, no, that's not how reality works.
Ozzie, we're looking at you.
Yeah.
Um
and I, I think the best quote uh on, so Bruce Schneier
has this on his blog right now, you know, Ray Ozzie, former Microsoft guy said,
yeah, we should like legally mandate backdoors into like, well,
and that's part of the problem. What, what defines a communication device now.
Well, everything,
my b
Right. Yeah. Well, like my Amazon echo,
right? Uh my Amazon Alexa
or whatever the hell
that one's already listening to you.
So,
no worries,
it's unplugged.
But um
that's a funny story for another podcast. But uh
so
one of the proposals was that if you are going to propose this,
you actually have to give a concrete proposal with
specific details and not just this hand wavy.
Well, you know, the the smart engineers will figure it out.
Yeah, because some problems are somewhat intractable.
You know, like there's just, there's no
essentially, I guess how do I put it? There's no set of engineering trade offs
but
result in you having the system that is quote unquote, totally secure,
but also quote unquote law enforcement gets what they want,
right? Those are just two opposing views of reality.
Let's let's break it down. Ok.
So we start at the beginning and we'll say
a device manufacturer builds a device that has a back door. Ok?
Ignoring the fact that we know we can't build it today. But let's just say you can
two problems with that. Is that back door in hardware?
Is it like physically there and can't be modified or
is it in software where it can be modified?
I mean,
can't be modified? Ok,
we're gonna say, can't be modified because that,
that simplifies the conversation.
So now you have,
you need a way to get in to the device. Ok.
So you kind of have two options.
You can have like one master key that can unlock
every single device or you have one key per device.
Ok.
Now you can imagine one master key
is much easier to deal with because you have one key.
But if you lose it,
all the devices are compromised,
if you have
one, you will,
that's we'll get to that.
You have to share it with so many people, right?
And, and you can also have one key per device.
But now in like in the case of apple, they would be managing a billion keys.
What do you think the odds are of handling a billion keys and not screwing it up
-- under zero
-- percent.
The other thing is too, is, is by having this
legally mandated to back door.
Does it go over regular communication channels or is it like I can
-- magically talk to it over Wi Fi even if your device is disabled
-- Wi
Fi? Let's ignore that stuff.
Let's just say you need to have physically have the device. Ok?
You have to plug in a cable and then send it
a magic command and then you can do whatever you want,
right?
Because
that's one of the challenges is this,
this conversation can get very out of hand quickly.
Yeah. Well, see that's one of my frustration.
If you physically need to have the device to unlock it,
then your chances are you can also physically have
the owner of it and you can basically,
um,
what's that law in the UK called where basically if you don't give up your password,
you go to jail.
UK Rip Act.
Yes.
And, you know, there have been people who sat in jail for a very long time
because of that.
So,
um, and, and the other thing too is, you know, for a lot of this, they're, they're,
they're gonna go, well, yeah,
we could have a back door where we physically need access,
but we want the one with remote access.
Well, well, it's even more complicated than that because, I mean, like,
for example, you could have a,
you could have a victim's phone
and the victim is dead.
Right?
You can't unlock a dead person's phone with
the dead person's knowledge because they're not there.
So there's,
-- unless they wrote it down
-- somewhere
-- there,
-- which
it does.
But anyway, anyway,
so the issue kind of becomes you either have one key or, or millions of keys and,
and both come with their own set of problems.
And now here's the thing, anyone who tells you, oh, the keys will be secret.
We'll put them in an HSM, we'll lock him in a vault. What? Blah, blah, blah.
Here's the thing.
Has anything ever been kept a secret in the history of humanity?
No, nothing ever has. Right. The answer is no, because
this is, you know what, you know what I always think of when I,
when I talk about this is,
do you remember like the hacker mantra back in
the day of information wants to be free?
And I remember III I love that.
But the thing is, it's not so much information wants to be free.
It's the fact that once information exists
in public,
you can never make it un exist, right? There's no way to put that genie back in the box.
And just by its very nature and beauty, like digital information is
infinitely and
I want to use the word trivial but even more trivial than trivially copy.
Right. Right. And, and that's exactly the problem.
You, you cannot undo this once it is done.
And so kind of from the, from the context of a back door,
you like we could do it today.
But the problem is we can't do it in a way
that's even,
I would say 80% secure because those keys are going to leak and let's face it if,
if someone knows Apple has a vault somewhere full of super secret keys,
like
you might as well paint a job,
can't target on that building and say, come on in guys because every
intelligence agency on the planet is going to make it their job to get that stuff.
-- I mean, how would you vet those people that work there? Good
-- Lord.
Right. There's, there's like
there's no way right.
There is no way and, and people will say, oh,
but you need three or five keys and we'll do
multiple things and sign off and it's just no,
it, it,
there is no way
you're going to do it.
And imagine if you were like one of those people, man, you could,
you could be collecting like some fat
paychecks from every intelligence agency on the planet
pretty much.
I mean, it's just,
it's, it's one of those things that this is,
I don't think we can ever solve this as human
beings because we screw things up way too much.
Yeah.
And so, I mean, fundamentally what it boils down to,
for me is the frustration that these people are like, oh, it can be done.
So we should therefore see the problem is you could very easily mandate this in law
without having a good technical solution and then you
would probably end up with a bad technical solution.
They've sort of tried doing that more than once.
It's, it's not made it yet through, through any,
any congress or anything in the US at least.
But it, it would not surprise me if, if we see something similar eventually.
Well, I mean, as, as proof in the pudding, the Rip Act in the UK in 2000,
right? We, we, they basically acknowledged we can't,
there will be technology that we can't subvert or otherwise,
you know, intercept or whatever. So
plan B,
if we think you're guilty and we want your passwords and you won't give them up.
We chuck you in jail.
And
so this legislation has passed in,
not just in some crazy despot country, but, like, in the western world,
like, I expect this kind of thing and, you know, the,
yeah.
No, I, I understand what you're saying though. Right. This is a very fair point is
now
ignoring the politics because I don't want to
get into a political discussion because I,
I no good ever comes of that.
-- Everyone has their
-- opinion.
We also have the entire world, right?
Where every like you're in the US, I'm in Canada. There's some very big differences.
Well, I travel places, right?
Like what happens when I go to another country
now?
Great. So my country protects my phone but theirs maybe doesn't.
And, and
do they get access to my secret backdoor key because I'm in their country?
Right? But I, I don't know.
So, so anyway,
now the one thing I will give Ray Ozzie credit
for in his write up about his uh backdoor proposal
is one of his ideas was when law enforcement basically backdoors the phone,
it would have like fuses inside of it that would blow,
rendering the phone or, well,
I guess the device will say basically rendering the device
useless for the most part where it kind of becomes read
on
that. That's actually a good idea.
Yes and no, because that's great for phones.
But what about for like general purpose computing devices.
What do you mean?
Well, I mean, more things like desktops, laptops, tablets, do we put this on every,
you, you'd have to build them special? I mean,
so then essentially what you're saying is if I break into the system,
I can render every computer on the face of the planet inoperable,
conceivably sounds like a win.
I'm not gonna completely disagree with you there.
Um, but, you know, at the
same time by building this capability in that, that's a potentially a huge problem.
But the, the value of it I think is you couldn't have say law enforcement,
take your phone while you're
in the shower, quick hack it and then, you know,
quick put it back on your dresser while they run out of the hotel, right?
Like if this is a one shot deal, you do it and it's done
and, and, but, but
again, it's not technically possible.
-- So,
-- well, it is technically possible, just not in the way that they,
I think are claiming it can be done quote unquote safely and securely.
No, I'm, I'm going to say it's not technically possible using, using the what we
assuming humans have to build it, which is true.
Knowing what we know today,
you cannot build
a, a backdoor, key escrow system
that is going to be secure and reliable.
That is, that is what I will say
100%.
Um,
especially if you care even remotely about the security
and safety and privacy of the end users,
which I mean, look, let's face it.
And that is literally enshrined in law in many countries. Right?
Canada, Human Rights Act, the US, what? Fourth Amendment,
these are some pretty core legal principles here in
most western countries and even non western countries.
And
that, that's all well and good. Right.
And, and I, I appreciate that and I love that aspect of democracy
but it's
even ignoring the legal ramifications, just technically speaking, it's,
it's not doable.
Right.
And I'm also not sure.
I mean, because my understanding is so far we've had many times where, oh my God,
it's the end of the world if we can't get access to this and it hasn't
been the end of the world and they also have been able to get access,
you know, through other means.
-- And
-- this is something that
I, I think law enforcement recently has kind of screwed up
is you can't say if we don't get this, you know, think of the Children sort of thing.
And then when they don't get what they need and things still are ok,
it's like you guys lied to us, right?
Like you were making up some crap
and you kind of got caught, you know, and
that's not healthy.
And I think honestly that the security industry
in general is kind of in this position
where we've been screaming at people for so
long about doom and gloom and they're like,
yeah, but like my, my lights still work, you know,
you guys are,
are either wrong or you're lying and either way I don't want to listen to you
and,
and that's kind of one of those things that
if law enforcement wants to be viewed as
somebody who could be trusted with this sort of technology,
they need to have a certain level of, I guess just upstanding. This isn't a word.
But, you know, you know what I mean?
They have to be seen as like the good guys and in this case,
it's like you guys are kind of being weasels about this one, you know, come on, do,
do a better job here.
Yeah. No, I'll uh, I'll agree with that. Cuz,
yeah, there's been a lot of, oh my God.
Yeah, the end of the world, if we lose this capability,
-- we lose the capability and the world keeps ticking along
-- well.
And it's even crazier too because I, I,
from my understanding is while the FBI was yelling at Apple,
they, they were also working with celeb
right to unlock these phones.
So it's like you guys knew you could do this and you're pretending you can't,
I'm assuming it was, you know, more political in nature than
I
imagine so.
-- But
-- still,
I mean,
here's the thing from, from their perspective,
having this capability would just be amazing, right?
Like I just recently downloaded, actually,
I have Google location enabled on my phone
and I downloaded the, uh, the file with all the data and, uh, I need to plot it in
something,
you know,
and it's gonna be, it's gonna, that's basically my life.
Like you'll know where I get my Slurpees.
There's a way you can view it on Google Maps. I forget what it is off the top of my head.
-- Oh,
-- there's a ton of things to manipulate the data.
-- It's, it's a very standard file format. It's
-- super crazy imac
or something.
I,
I don't know, I, I opened mine up.
Uh, I don't know, maybe 34 weeks ago and I looked at it. I was like, holy crap
everywhere.
I've been in the last, probably seven years was on that map and it's like, well,
I'm just gonna close this and
go back to crawling under the blanket and crying softly.
Yeah, I, I, it's amazing to me that in the span of 12 years.
Uh, well, and even prior to 12 years, you know, smartphones are from 2006,
but prior to that we had phones and logging of this location data,
although not quite as fine grained as it is now. But
yeah, in the span of what a good solid 20 years, we've, we've just trained pretty much
half or more of humanity to carry a tracking device.
Uh
Yes,
that's pretty amazing,
you know.
Ok. No, it's not amazing because most people don't realize what's going on.
You and I have the unfortunate reality of knowing.
-- Well, no, no,
-- even more than that,
it doesn't matter because this thing is so fundamentally useful.
-- I don't
-- care.
And I'm kind of in that situation too of. I know they're spying on me.
I know they're stealing an insane amount of my personal data.
But at the same time
it's like I, I haven't,
-- I can play angry birds at the checkout line.
-- Ignoring that. My, my, my take is always
I go on a trip now
and I don't bring any paper with me and I get on airplanes and I
get off airplanes and then people pick me up and they bring me places and I
to hotels and it's like this is
magic
is,
yeah, we were, we were running errands the other day and I'm like, oh,
can we swing by the bank?
And I'm like, oh no, wait a second. I poke away at my phone.
I'm like, oh, wait, no,
I can do this online and I set up a bill payment and paid it and I was like, ok,
never mind.
-- We're not going to the bank.
-- Seriously. II I haven't been to my bank in months
and I'm glad,
you know, it's no
lines.
They do and they're always very slick. Well, because now they have one teller
because nobody goes to the bank.
Well, I think it's kind of like ts a precheck approval.
It's called this by definition,
the people going to the bank are not very good at this and they have a
long time.
-- Probably
-- true.
-- I
-- think that's part of it.
-- I've
-- noticed that, you know what, man,
I was in San Francisco a couple of weeks ago and the TS,
a line was significantly longer than the normal person line.
And it's still like, smoked them in terms of getting people through because,
you know, the normal people are like, what do you mean?
I can't wear my winter coat and boots through this thing.
It's like, just listen to the nice person and take your stuff off. Come on.
Yeah.
Oh, well.
But anyway, anyway,
-- all right. So,
-- backdoors, I think, well, no, no, legally mandated backdoors.
I, I don't think,
I don't think they can be done
on a large scale even remotely securely and,
and that kind of sucks because on the one hand, the magic part of me that's like, oh,
you know, the good guys of law enforcement because
honestly, in my experience, generally speaking a lot,
most law enforcement is pretty,
they're not complete raving lunatics. Right.
They, I think they do generally have, they do generally want to help society. Right.
Granted, there have been some, well, a lot of bad things
in the past, the thing,
I'm going to the threat of law enforcement itself and just say that
using our current technology and know how
my fear isn't law enforcement.
My fear is Apple accidentally posting the keys to an FTP site and then
that's the thing. Once this stuff is out, it never comes back.
And that's the problem. Right.
Well, what I was trying to get to is there are numerous
cases of, you know, the police abusing their powers to
track people to surveil people, you know, all sorts of naughtiness,
um, especially around journalists and stuff. Right. So,
it's, you know, I would like to live in a somewhat free and just society and
we need these checks and balances and
giving, you know, a group like law enforcement,
this unfettered access to everybody's personal data
-- makes me a little
-- nervous.
No, I, I agree completely. And it's,
it's tricky man.
II, I guess here's what I'll say again,
I'm going to ignore law enforcement and just say
we cannot do this today
in a reasonable fashion,
full stop
and it's the way it is now, it is conceivable.
Somebody will figure out a way to do this correctly and then we
can have another conversation about the fact that now that this exists,
what do we do with it?
Well, and one thing to keep in mind too is do we actually need this,
like straight
up,
you know,
and
that, that's a political discussion in all seriousness.
Well, see that's what frustrates a lot of stuff around law enforcement is,
does this actually
help or benefit? Does it make a difference? Right.
Like people often call for, I want more police in my community,
like walking the streets or whatever.
And it's
the majority of studies have shown that like that doesn't really matter.
I will compare this and, and we can kind of close on this is,
it is similar to a lot of security advice. Do you need a password manager? No.
Does it make your life better? Yes.
Right. And, and there's a number of security things
and this is kind of part of that advice of. Do you need this? Well, technically, no,
but would it make certain things better? It might.
Right. And that's what it's going to come down to?
And that, that is not necessarily a decision I want to be trusted with.
It's quite likely no human should be trusted with it.
But unfortunately,
that's not how it works because somebody's going to make some laws
and then that's what's going to happen
and they'll probably say think of the Children
and then it will, will get passed. But anyway, anyway.
All right, man. Any, any last thoughts on backdoors?
Uh nothing other than, you know,
please don't.
Yeah, that'll work.
All right. Awesome. Thanks, Kurt. Thanks everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
You can use Pound Os S podcast hashtag to get our attention on social media.
And yeah, nothing else. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.
Thanks guys. Bye bye.