December 16th. We're getting close. The kids are getting excited.
Santa Claus is coming. So 1616 bit computing.
So, one of my favorite things in it is this constant theme
where
a large number of people hate
change.
Even when that change is very obviously
for the better.
-- That's humans in general. It's not it
-- people,
but people who choose to work in it and hate change.
I imagine that that is very stressful.
It's, you know, it's like hating cats and working at an animal shelter with cats.
I mean, I guess
that's fair and it's interesting to me that you and I both
went through the switch from 32 bit to 64 bit computing.
You know, we remember,
I remember my 1st 64 bit system, you know, the, the deck alpha stuff.
Uh I had access to it, didn't own one.
And then when AMD came out with affordable 64 bit computing, it was fantastic.
Yeah, it was amazing for sure. So, actually I have a fun fact,
one of a company I worked for long ago was called Progeny Linux systems.
And there were a bunch of Debian people who
worked there And I think it was Hewlett Packard,
maybe paid progeny to make Debbie and run on the itanium systems.
-- Yes, I remember those days
-- the big challenge,
there was the 32 to 64 bit switch over and getting
everything to build and work correctly in a 64 bit world.
So it was,
and it was awesome because back then, I mean, this obviously was a million years ago,
but we had these two gigantic itanium machines in the
server room and they were super fun to play with.
-- Oh,
-- did you actually have those, whatever? They looked like sun 10,000 servers?
Like they were fridge sized monsters.
They were smaller than a fridge, I would say was this,
these looked more like maybe a very long filing cabinet.
I would describe them as they were strangely shaped.
-- So
-- they were those top of the line hp monstrosities.
They were beautiful computers
and then the itanium, no one, no one even knows what it is anymore.
Well, it just didn't work and it didn't really offer any benefits.
It was
no, ok.
It should have offered benefit.
The problem was it was too complicated for basically anyone
properly utilize that is what it came down to.
-- And so it failed.
-- And I love
AMD 64 bit was essentially, we took 32 bits and kind of just
-- smashed it into 64 bits. We
-- stapled 32 more bits onto the side.
We glued two together.
-- And you know what? It worked beautifully.
-- It did work cause Intel ended up.
And in fact, even today, if you look in the Debian world, their 64 bit architecture,
they still call
AMD 64.
Because back in day it was Intel was pushing
it.
I always try in my brain, I always say Itanic, which is obviously a plan,
Itanium and Titanic.
But
Intel was pushing the Itanium and AM D was like, oh screw it.
We're just going to add more bits and
AMD one and it worked. It did, it did work. So anyway, anyway, I agree though.
-- I remember the 32 bit to 64 bit changeover
-- or
remember the change to Elf Binaries from A dot out.
I was,
I don't remember that mattering
and I don't know why because I remember that world,
but I don't remember it being a problem, but I feel like I think I started running.
I made the jump from Munich to Red Hat and I think Red Hat was already on Elf by then.
And so I just never really noticed it.
I just remember,
I think a lot of what this boils down to is there's a lot of code that's poorly written.
But the minute you take it off of its sort of home environment, it breaks
and then the developer gets angry because they have to fix it. But it's also kind of
implied strongly because it's true that their code quality is kind of garbage.
-- I mean
-- that's one of the I so for what it's worth like.
So Apple is making a jump right now from
Intel chips,
custom arm chips. And
you can imagine certain things are looking like it's going to be slow to be ported.
And what that really means is any application that doesn't basically
move over quickly has is probably not written particularly well.
-- Yeah, Photoshop being one example
-- like this is one of the things actually that,
that gave Linux a superpower
is Linux has existed on many, many architectures for a very, very, very long time.
And so like when you add a new architecture like arm,
it probably took a couple of months and it was all working,
-- you know what it
-- always reminds me of is scaling, scaling from 1 to 2
is not that bad, but scaling from 2 to 3 is 90% of your work and once you scale to three,
you're you're fine
and, and right, and most open source
works on all of the platforms.
And so it automatically gets a free pass in a lot of these cases.
Well, they already dealt with the weirdness, the difference,
they already dealt with that technical debt.
Right. Right.
Yeah,
like my guess is getting something like Homebrew working correctly on
the new Max is probably not going to be that heavy of
a lift because most of this stuff already builds on on arm
architecture because it's all running on Linux and BS D and,
and whatever else.
So, anyway, anyway, all right, we're out of time. We will see you
on December 17th.