Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner thought crime.
-- Josh Bresser.
-- Holy cow. Do I have a story to tell?
So, I have been fighting with my network for the last two days because I've had,
you know, and obviously when you work from home and your home network is down,
it is an extremely anxiety filled event.
Right.
It's not like other things. Like,
I don't know if electricity goes out.
I'm like, oh, I'll just sit here and read when my network is broken.
-- It fills me with dread.
-- Well, it's something you have to fix
and worse. If you call somebody in to fix it, they're probably going to make it worse.
Well, and so that's just it. Right. First of all, I made sure it wasn't the internet.
Ok.
And here's what was basically happening is
intermittently,
things would just like, flake out, the whole network would flake out. Right.
And for like, one or two minutes and then it would start working out
one or
two minutes,
minutes, like minutes, not seconds, minutes. Right. And
this kept getting worse and worse
as time went on
and I'm like freaking out because
obviously I have to work. The internet's not working at one point.
It's just literally like everything was dead
and I could not get it back.
So if you were in this situation
now, remember I also replaced my Google wifi with TP link
Deos was running my network. What would your assumption be in
this particular instance?
Well, that I,
I actually just had that like plex was behaving a bit badly
and I just recently upgraded my Google Wi Fi mesh to uh
what did I buy again? Netgear, no link.
And I forgot to forward the port in.
So it was just taking a long time to connect because
it would have to time out and then do something else.
So I would assume like, whatever it is you change to last
is
what
broke
because
that's how technology almost sometimes works.
-- Right.
-- Exactly.
So I
obviously take all of the,
the TP link stuff and I start like, doing some tests,
like moving some things around unplugging some things and whatnot
and
it seems a little better. I'm like, ok, great. I, that must have been it.
Then it, it falls apart again and I'm like, oh crap. It's not that.
So my switch
in the basement and I have a switch upstairs, Ethernet switches.
This is funny because I also have a Nintendo switch and I was talking to
someone about this and they thought I meant my Nintendo switch and I'm thinking,
oh, my, my switch died.
They're like, oh,
well,
that's actually what a normal person would say.
I, I, yes, I, I agree completely. I realized my
mistake eventually.
But anyway, so then I think, ok, the switches are old, they probably finally died.
So I take my old switches, buy new switches
and things seem to work
and then they don't,
and I'm like, what is going on? Like, this doesn't make any sense.
-- And this is, this is Ethernet,
-- right?
I would start maybe testing cables. Like you can nail a cable or something.
We'll get to that.
So my first thought is like, I can't get anywhere on the network, right?
I wired, nowhere wired, nowhere wired on the network,
the whole wire network is dead.
Right. Exactly. I'm like, what is happening?
This is why my desktop is wired is because so I just wireless can, like,
-- who cares? Man? It's broken. Great. I can work.
-- Exactly.
So I'm like, I'm trying everything. I, I literally just take all the TP link stuff out
and I put my old Google Wi Fi back in which is in the e recycling box.
Thank goodness, I hadn't e recycled it yet. So I put that back in, I turn it on
and nothing works and I'm like, what the heck is going on?
And I start unplugging things and I'm just like,
I'm trying everything now the whole while I'm doing this. Mind you, I'm I
do my test
and then I would come to, like, this little studio we record and I have in my closet,
I'd come here and check my Linux computer
and it, oh, this computer always worked.
-- So, like a DH CP or I,
-- I don't know, I, I don't know why I'm working on some more testing.
But basically what it ended up being is when this computer went to sleep,
it was basically taking down the entire wired network with it,
but only when it was asleep.
So I, the, the reason it worked intermittently is when this computer would wake up,
everything was fine.
And normally I don't leave this computer plugged in,
but I knew we were recording again in two days.
So I thought, oh, I'll just leave it in there plugged in.
There's like that weird QT five application intermix issue where people's wi fi
-- breaks horrifically when they run like a paint application or
-- explain this.
It's so hard to solve a problem like this because I tried so many things.
Every time I would try something,
it, it didn't seem to make sense and it was because modern computers, like
when I put a computer to sleep now it doesn't stay asleep,
they wake up and they go to sleep and they wake up and do stuff and go to sleep and
it was messing with me
when you turn an Apple iphone off. Now
it's still on
like the, the
-- baseband chip. Like, I can find my iphone when it's turned off.
-- That's right.
And the thing that's, that's really just driving me nuts.
So,
the testing I want to do now is I want to boot this
computer into windows and then see if when windows goes to sleep,
does this happen as well?
Like, is this a Linux problem or is this a computer?
-- I don't know the answer to that yet. Like a
-- Lenovo something or other? Right.
Right.
I don't know. It's a idea pad. I think it is. Um,
yeah, sure. That's what it is.
I tried to get windows to go to sleep. I cannot make windows go to sleep.
Now, granted, I haven't run windows in months and months in this computer.
-- There's like a key combo for it. No,
-- no, it's, it's not the key combo.
I think it's, it's updating all the crap in the background.
I let it sit for like an hour and a half and
then we recorded this so I had to move back into.
But
like, I,
at some point I will boot it into windows and just let it sit for
however many hours it needs to go to sleep and see if it happens.
And at the same time, Kurt, I set up, I've got, uh,
there's this thing called heartbeat that,
that works with elastic search that I can like ping my internal network.
I was peeing a bunch of hosts.
I'm watching ping times I'm watching when things are dropping off,
I'm looking for patterns and
-- like, I could not figure this
-- out here.
This is this guy called Ando or sorry Andrew wrote a
really good blog post willing to it in the show notes.
So what is it? Late last year?
I started experiencing some unusual intermittent connection
issues on my desktop in general,
I had a stable connection with average latency.
However, at seemingly random times throughout the week,
I would start experiencing sudden 2000 plus
millisecond latency spikes every couple of seconds.
This made all audio and video calling software,
unusable and most long games unplayable.
Right.
-- I mean, yeah, that's, that's a long time, right.
-- Two seconds.
Yeah. No, that's not gonna be usable.
So anyways, then he talks about it,
talks about a stuff he troubleshooted the heck out of it.
You know, he like,
tried all these different wi fi dongles and like a whole bunch of stuff.
-- Right.
And, and I can relate to this because like when my network was having issues, II,
I have all new switches in the house.
Now I've, I've replaced tons of stuff because obviously
you think of those as the problem, generally speaking. Right.
So then he, and it was things like, you know,
turning off a box fan in his room unplugging his Wcom
drawing tablet,
you know, closing Firefox
and then closing a program called Medibank Paint Pro and that fixed the issue.
A paint program
time out. So like
he ran Medibank Paint Pro and boom, it happens again.
And he's like to quote his article, why,
why the hell would digital painting software?
Cause Wi Fi leg spikes? I mean
he's not wrong
as it turns out there are multiple instances of
people complaining about this issue with uh the program.
If we take a quick look with process monitor,
we can see it's definitely doing something odd.
So it boils down to
it starts querying the registry keys for all
the network interfaces looking at the call stack,
we see that the first non systems library in the call stack is QT five network.
Surprisingly no more debugging is needed as a quick search for
QT five network ping issue will lead you to QT bug dash
40 332. And basically
any QT five application prior to version 5.14
using the Q network access manager will check for a Wi Fi
interface changes every 10 seconds for the purpose of bear management.
So basically it can like wander around and stuff
and this causes massive leg spikes or the packet, the packets to drop entirely.
That's it, right. And here's the best part.
I suppose the workaround is simple enough set the
environment variable QT bear po time out to negative one
boom done problem went away.
But like
there are,
can we just imagine for a moment how many thousands
of people years of time has been wasted discovering this,
like rediscovering this bug.
It's probably a lot.
I would argue that this thing needs like a security identifier and
it needs to be like a critical mandatory fix just based on.
It's like having
a pothole on every driveway in the city, like everybody using QT before version.
What is it? 514 is affected by this? Potentially?
Let's ask the question of if it deserves a security identifier
in a little bit because I don't want to talk about that
because I think that's going to be a weird discussion.
I think the more important thing is something that I I this bug
as well as my annoying two days has kind of made me realize is
as much as I thought I had a grasp on technology.
I
it's clearly well beyond my ability to comprehend what's going on.
I, I had the exact same thing, right? Like Plex, I changed up my Wi Fi Gear.
The man that Wi Fi six stuff is fast.
Yeah, it's really nice when you connect to Plex on a mobile client or whatever,
there's like a few seconds pause and then it
spits out an air saying there's no pinned media,
blah, blah, blah.
And then a few seconds later, it just starts working again.
And I'm like, oh man, what is it?
So like I update Plex on the mobile,
make sure Plex and everything's updated on the server
and no what it was, is I forgot I
had enabled UPNP thinking that U
universal plug and play would
let Plex tell the firewall to like I need this port forwarded to me.
So stuff works, right.
That wasn't happening.
So I manually forwarded the port in, you know, set a static IP on the machine,
running it forwarded the port in and
poof pro went away.
Right.
You know, and, but,
but because it was like one of those things where it's like trying to work
at times and it falls back to something else that works or it just,
yeah, so it kind of appears intermittent even though it's not.
But again, chasing it down, I'm like, oh,
I think it's the port but I enabled UPP it should work. And I'm like, well,
I manually signed the port and it started working so clearly
up and I realized I have no way to query my wi fi gear.
Like there's no way to query my Wi Fi gear and say like, hey,
what are you doing with UPNP?
Like, have you done anything
for sure? There's, unless I'm running like a Linux box where I have a log file these
lysis machines as far as I can tell, I have absolutely no way to know what's going on.
Now, I will confuse you further. I also run Flex
and I do not have a port forwarding into my house and it works just fine remotely.
It will work.
Uh because it like pulls out or whatever and it enables that kind of back connection.
I don't know. But yeah, like on mine it was, I was getting that weird delay and
like I'm running plex on windows. So maybe that's it.
Yeah, I run it on Linux
and,
and you know what, you know what? I love those. So I use it for over the air TV.
It's like my DVR and stuff
and I have an Amazon fire stick. I travel with,
I can plug the fire stick in, like, in a hotel anywhere in the world.
And I have all my local TV. And it just like works flawlessly from plaques.
It's absolutely amazing. Not that I watch a lot of local TV, but it just amuses me that
I can do this.
Well, I mean,
what I love is I can actually download my kids show
so they don't suddenly disappear or move to another platform.
Like Pink Panther used to be on Netflix and then one day
it's gone.
And I'm like, oh man, that's bad.
Luckily they'd moved to youtube. So I'm like, ok,
you know, I showed Wolfe and then he's like, oh, ok.
-- You know, and like, he's happy again, but
-- back to our topic of the day.
So, so these are two
bizarrely difficult problems to solve that. I think when you think about it,
they,
they shouldn't exist. I think in our,
-- we'll say knowledge of the past.
-- Well, let's pick on QT developers for a moment
when they
did, they not experience this in testing
and see that's the problem is this is one of those things where it's like an
application has to be running that has a
behavior to trigger this pathological behavior in QT.
-- They,
-- they obviously didn't because if they did, they would,
they would have fixed it or they would just wouldn't have done this.
-- You, you say that, But I,
-- I, I'm completely serious.
Like, look, developers aren't stupid and they're not evil.
And so if they would have seen this sort of,
but my suspicion is they didn't see the
behavior because they were probably doing their development.
They probably had their test suite.
They run the test suite and they're not going to be using their Wi Fi because
obviously the test suite is going to be pounding the crap out of the CPU probably.
And everything seems ok. The test pass, we're fine.
The thing I love is, you know, how all this
is,
-- how,
-- how old is it? I did, I open the bug. I did it
2017.
Where do you see this? Sorry. Hang on a second. Where was the year?
I thought there was a year. What was the initial year
-- it
-- was created the 21st of July in 2014,
2014. Yeah. 1417.
So, yeah, it's an eight year old bug that people are still dealing with.
Clearly something has gone wrong here.
Well,
-- dude, it made the top of hacker news a few days ago. I agree,
-- something went wrong.
And if you look at the, the thread of this bug, it is really long, like really long.
It's a lot of people have run into this and ended up here finally.
And this is a perfect example of this.
This isn't just like a nice to have bug fix that improves network performance.
This is something that is eating up
tens or hundreds or maybe even thousands of people years.
-- Well, that's easy to say.
-- Now people are still running into it now though.
That's the thing. So like, why don't we just
do something about it?
Like, yeah, we should have done something about it eight years ago,
-- but better late than never. Right? No,
-- that's too easy to say I think.
And I think this is one of my complaints about the security world in general
is we're always like, oh, you should fix this thing. That is bad.
I think what we see often is the
developers don't understand how important something might be.
Like, I haven't looked at this bug.
Does it, do they change the severity from the initial filing?
I don't know if I can tell in this bug tracker.
-- It's P two
-- important. Well, now it is. But was it,
was it initially like, I don't, I can't tell.
Yeah, there's no, it's I, I cannot figure out the his
there's no history.
But, but anyway, so here's the way to think about this,
I think is when you're a developer, you have a million tasks to do
and someone comes to you with a bug and you might look at the bug and think, oh,
that's not a big deal, right?
Security people will come to you with a bug and say, oh, this is a security issue.
You need to fix it. You might say whatever, no one's ever going to do that.
And it is sometimes very difficult for the developers to understand
like what, how do,
how can things line up that this bug maybe
is significantly worse than I think it is initially.
And so I'm never gonna bash developers for not fixing something right away because
if they didn't think it was important,
-- they're not going to fix it.
-- No, no, no, no. What I'm trying to say is
we should advertise the existence of this bug more heavily we
should so that people don't waste time trying to fix it.
They go,
I like they hopefully Google like Q
Q
five network latency spike and they end up at like QT five
network latency spike.com with a link to this bug or something.
Now, this is I agree with you. However,
so let's say we assign it a vulnerability identifier,
-- CV E or GSD or
-- whatever this means.
Now vendors have to acknowledge it and fix it and there will be more fixes,
ok? But here's my suspicion.
I think in some instances that's true.
But
I don't see a lot of end user
scanning or vulnerability recognition for the most part,
I think,
I think you're not wrong in a perfect world,
but I am skeptical assigning this an ID would actually
raise its awareness the way we want it raised.
Well, see, but here's the thing,
uh, how many times have we had a security issue that did not have a CV identifier?
And
so what? But the moment it gets a CV identifier,
uh All these big corporations, a 30 60 90 day clock starts ticking.
And
obviously, that's probably not going to be so much the case here because, you know,
it's eight years old, probably a lot of people have fixed it.
But more to the point
enough people I feel are still running into this.
This is a pathological bug that is eating up and destroying people's time.
Now,
if I as an attacker could cause some sort of denial of
service remotely on your system with the same two second latency spike,
we would clearly give that an identifier right now.
The thing is this cannot be directly attacker triggered, but it's
triggered commonly enough by, through just software like running
and
pooping all over the network stack. But,
you know, again, like it made the top hacker news. There's tons of people going.
Me too.
There's this bug that's eight years old that has
current like relatively up to date feedback in it,
you know,
going well, going back to 2020. OK. That's been quiet for the last two years.
Clearly,
there's a whole bunch of people with older versions of QT running into this,
right?
-- And, and
-- so,
OK, so that's enough.
You, you've pontificated on this enough, the point is people need to know that,
that this is a problem and you want to use
security vulnerability identifiers as the way to convey that.
Now you can obviously make the argument that this is a denial of service
-- and no one will argue that
-- it has an impact on quality of life.
-- But
-- there's lots of things that do that we don't call security issues,
right?
Well, maybe we should.
And I mean, that's the question obviously is
we draw this weird line of saying like vulnerability, not vulnerability
and it,
it's so fuzzy that it's really hard to
say because like something that might affect you drastically
-- might not affect me at all and I won't care about it.
-- Yeah.
Well, same thing with security,
right?
You don't have much
like a credit card processing bug. Home Depot versus a mom and pop shop, right?
You know, one's gonna get a giant fine from the sec maybe. And the other one's
not even gonna get noticed. No, I would say so.
The traditional,
one of the traditional definitions was it crosses a trust boundary
and
I would say two things. One,
there's is there not a trust expectation that
when you run software it doesn't like mangle your system.
I don't think anyone would say no.
But how many times have you run your web browser?
And it just consumes your CPU until you have to kill it.
-- Like I had Chrome crash twice the other day.
-- I haven't seen that in a
long time.
Ironically enough, loading a hacker news comment thread
seems to have triggered it. It's probably a hacker. I don't know.
But anyways 32 restarts that loaded it fine and stopped crashing.
But
I mean,
the other thing is chrome, for example, now when it crashes,
it comes back and it actually reloads all your tabs and you,
-- I mean,
-- they've been doing that for like a decade.
Well, but what I'm pointing out is
they have minimized the impact of these crashes so that they are not as severe.
So again, that goes back to the quality of life argument.
Like
nobody used to upgrade their web browser. Why? Because you have 10 tabs open.
And if you close your browser,
you have to manually reopen all those tabs and get back to where you were.
Except now you hit that update button and it just bloop
and like 30 seconds later you're back up and running.
Sure.
Do we want to make life better for the end users?
Less hassle. Easier
question the, the
yes, everyone wants to do that.
-- Right.
-- How do we go about doing that.
And one of the few sticks or kind of methods we have
is bugs that are labeled as security,
typically get sort of forced action and review that regular bugs don't get.
Well, they, they do. But I mean, when I say,
like I'm talking about from the end user actually applying the updates.
Well, no, not from end users. It's from the, the systems managers
that care about this. The end users don't give two craps
about whether a piece of software has a security vulnerability or not.
They literally don't care how many times have you been in a Zoom?
Call someone shares their screen and that little chrome
update button is just sitting there nice and red,
which means they haven't clicked it in a long time,
but the users do care about two second latency spikes.
Sure. Sure.
But
here, ok. So here is,
I think the thing we need to think about there are
different personas for any sort of buck, right?
And now when we think of things like vulnerability identifiers,
we're thinking about like security teams and system management type people.
That's the persona this has been targeting, right?
You're talking about end users and I'm telling you the
end user persona for security just has a ha ha ha
in the poop emoji.
And that's basically what they care about.
And now you, you are technically correct,
which we all know is the best kind of correct.
That's Right. Exactly. I
actually, we started watching Future Rob and I got to that episode. I was like,
but anyway,
you are technically correct. But now if
we exist in a world today where the vast majority of
organizations cannot functionally handle the
current volume of security identifiers,
it is too great.
And that's because our tooling and process is functionally broken. Right?
-- No one's gonna
-- argue that.
Well, we don't have any, we're just barely getting automation.
-- It's
-- being created like things are getting significantly better right now.
But we're still a ways out
now if we take your
tact of saying, oh, we should assign, identify
all this stuff.
Now, we've gone back to overwhelming people and
the answer isn't going to be, oh,
I'll build better tools. It's going to be screw all this stuff I'm done.
So one comment I would have is there, don't have to be a lot of these.
Like, I'm always reminded of
one of the gold standards for security bug is like, does it end up on CNN?
I remember with heartbleed, I was traveling,
remember for the um for uh Red Hat Summit
and you know, the I
create customs here in Canada, in Edmonton.
And you know, what's the purpose of your visit?
Oh, I'm attending a business conference. Bla
bla bla Linux
is like, you know, they do the classic, like, what kind of work do you do?
And he's like, oh, have you heard about Harley and I'm like,
yes, yes, I have. He's like, oh, do I have to replace my router?
And I'm like, oh, for bla bla
bla,
no, you don't have to replace your router. Just update it, blah, blah, blah.
It'll be fine
-- but like,
-- just update it. No, you can't, you can't update routers.
Well,
his wifi router thing. Right.
Anyways, the point is
when a security bug,
like, ends up making it into normal people's conversation,
we need to do a better job handling it.
Like the log for J thing, that thing needed a good
human readable text which we wrote for the GSD.
Like I wrote that thing with workarounds.
Here's the best detection, here's the best hot patches.
Here's the best blah, blah, blah because like that thing made CNN, like it was on BBC.
It was,
it didn't make print media because,
well, yeah, come on,
you'd have to be really bad to bring print media. Did
I guarantee you log for shell was in all the newspapers.
-- I
-- mean, actual physical print. I don't know. I haven't seen a paper,
I guarantee
it was in the New York Times,
no doubt.
But that's the thing. I'm not saying we do this for every single like thing.
But if a bug is eight years old and
still getting this kind of discussion and activity,
it kind of wins an award.
Ok. I think there might be a different way to think about this.
I think you're still trying to hammer the round peg through the square hole,
which you can do as long as you hit it hard enough.
Actually, most people don't know this, but there's a woodworking tool.
I forget the name of it,
but you cut little, um, um, like
not cylinders. Uh, uh What do you call the, like a rectangle peg with the square top?
Like a square peg? We'll call it a square peg, peg, a square peg.
That's a good name because that's what it is.
Anyway,
you cut little square pegs and then you literally hammer
them through a round hole and you make them round
and you're thinking um in machining, right? With the uh broaching tool,
-- I don't know
-- what it's called.
So a broaching tool is actually turns a round hole into a square hole.
No, no, this turns a square peg into a round peg and then you use it for your dowling.
And because
it's actually because it's hammered through, it's not very smooth,
which is good because it holds a glue better.
Anyway. Anyway, that's another story. I forget the name of it.
I'm sure the woodworkers listening are like screaming at me now, but that's great
uh at
me on Twitter. So anyway,
there are
various levels of security issues and not right.
If we think of it like AAA sliding scale, right?
There's like the big, big bad stuff, heartbleed log for shell, whatever.
-- There's cross site scripting. And then there's the stuff that matters.
-- Right.
And that's just
right.
And eventually we cross a line which we've
artificially drawn today that is security vulnerabilities.
But the reality is, it just depends what it is and how it affects you.
Now, you can take something like this particular QT issue
which you can, you can make the argument, it's a security vulnerability
and we want to push it up into the security
sphere so we can fix it using existing process.
But the reality is I think this falls more along
the lines of like there's this huge bucket of stuff,
be it security or not security issues that
like an update comes out for a library and
you just want the update because it fixes bugs,
it fixes security issues,
it fixes all this stuff and you don't really want to track like the 700 things,
it fixes.
You really just need to take the update.
And I think that's one of the pieces. This is where like depend
AOT on github,
right?
Depend
AOT is just like there's a new version, you should upgrade it.
Well, a great example, like
there was a red hat product. They, they shipped an update for it.
It had a classic um fail to release memory after use. So that is not a memory leak.
Folks, memory leaks are when you actually like leak the contents of memory.
When you fail to release the contents of memory, that's
technically not a memory leak.
It's this use not released after free, whatever point is
the product would die after like 2, 2.5 days. So it got fixed real fast.
And even though
it did not technically get labeled as a security bug because like,
an attacker couldn't trigger
just
days.
And again, I, I was kind of like, I think maybe, well,
I was like, regardless of whether or not we labeled it as a security update,
it's so bad that people are gonna update.
So,
but the problem is when you have these kind of like two second latency
issues,
it's not so bad that you're going to like, throw your computer out and buy a new one,
you're gonna kind of fight it and
try and fix it and like, uh
you'll probably assume the neighbor's kid is doing something on the Wi Fi or
they bought a microwave that's
not,
it's missing
-- a, that would
-- be, that would be my assumption.
I'd assume it was wireless interference from something, not
the paint program.
Now, now you, you raised an interesting point, you talk about Attackers,
Attackers can't trigger this, right?
No.
And see, and that's part of it is,
there's a lot of pathological and bad behaviors
that cannot be directly triggered by Attackers,
but that do have a massive impact on quality of life.
But,
but, and, and there is, again, again, there's a gray line,
let's say because there's that gray line of,
if a program advertises a security functionality and then
to do it properly,
that typically counts as a security vulnerability.
So like if it says I have a firewall and it doesn't, that's a vulnerability.
So, for example, in this case,
well, for example, it's, it's generally implied
that this program is not going to destroy your wi fi performance.
-- It's only
-- implied the,
the feature list does not say will not destroy your wi Fi performance.
Like we're fine, we're, we're good. We're in the clean.
-- I know, right? Like it only contains 10 ant legs per pound of cereal.
-- It's fine.
It's all good.
So I, yeah,
I see the problem I have is we don't have like what
other method do we have to kind of drive this forwards,
get it into scanning tools, get it into people's in front of people.
We don't have one
and look,
I I, you are correct that if we assigned it a CD E, it would get more attention.
But
I think
abusing an existing system for something like this,
it, it creates trust issues.
-- Well,
-- so,
and that's the advantage of using it in GSD is we're gonna be adding metadata to GSD.
So that for example, you can have a CV E compatible view of the world. Very simple.
Everything that has ac va
you can have a um as I put in my email, like a vulnerability
compatible view of the world, which is essentially the to some degree.
The CV E inclusion rules are applied a bit more broadly
because we'll also be doing like backdoors and stuff which CV
-- refuses to do.
-- That's right. Or malware,
they don't cover either of those,
-- right.
-- Like github
has started covering them. Thank goodness.
-- But yeah, there's,
-- well, like that freaking colors for Js stuff and like where it's,
again, it ate up
thousands of months or years of people, time
caused it broke a ton of systems and it's like, yeah, whatever. It's
the guy that did it intentionally. So it doesn't count what
I mean. Again, this is the technically correct territory.
Well, and what I love is if he'd accidentally done it,
then we would have assigned it a vulnerability identifier.
-- That's true. Actually, that's a very good point. But
-- because it was intentional
and then that raises the question.
Well, what if somebody breaks into his account and does it intentionally?
What if he let them break out?
Right? Like
I'm let me put it this way. Here's the question.
Does assigning this a security vulnerability, uh,
security or vulnerability identifier?
And I,
we should actually start separating those two things but does assigning this an ID
make life better.
And the answer right now is no,
because
the tools and everything,
but part of it is too, it's a chicken and egg problem
is how many of these bugs are there?
Is there only like one of these weird QT things per decade or are there? Hundreds.
I,
I have a better way to think about this because I think this is too weird of a problem.
Let's say I have a fuzz
and I run my fuzz
and I find
100 bugs that are maybe security issues with my fuzz, but I can't research 100 bugs
and I've got some metadata that says these are potentially questionable.
What do I do with those today?
There's a project called Os S Fuzz that does this and,
and Google Os V captures some of this if you
brought that to something like any existing security database.
And we're like here, we should give these identifiers,
they're gonna show you the door
because it would create too much work and people can't
do anything about it.
Well, the low quality of it
and right, it's not very high.
I mean, the answer to this is just upgrade your freaking library, right?
-- Like here's the fix
-- like a single flaw, 100 flaws.
The person running the Fuzz has done the correct work and it is not one bug.
It is 100 legitimately different bugs. Now as, as a consumer of this kind of data,
I can't consume this today really.
But the correct answer is just upgrade the library,
get all the fixes go on with your life.
No one really cares.
But now what I really want to do and this is,
this is one of the challenges in the tooling is there's the, I'm gonna, today,
we're zoomed in, we look at every vulnerability separately as a unique snowflake.
But there's kind of different levels like log for shell. Yes. Zoom in on that.
That's fine.
But I want to kind of back up a step and just
look at the aggregate and say like how many unfixed things,
security bugs, regular bugs, whatever are in this particular library.
Right.
And then I want to be able to set some bars that say, ok,
I'm willing to handle like 10 low bugs.
Fine. More than 10, let's fix it, right? 100 bugs, fine. More than 100 bugs.
I wanna fix it. Right.
-- And today we can't really do that very
-- well.
It's, it's slowly getting there.
I mean, a big thing is, you know, NVD enriches data with C PE S so that we can
programmatically identify and track these.
You know, again, with GSD, we're heavily,
we, you know, we want to use P
URL S, we want to use.
Everyone hates C pe.
Yeah, see, well, again, people forget like 20 years ago,
what else were we going to do?
No, seriously.
Like, I love how people complain about these technologies and it's like
this was like this is old enough to drink.
-- Well, you
-- know
what I like,
but the difference is it should have evolved and changed and grown.
A lot of them didn't.
And, and,
but you know why?
Because look at so this is,
I'm just gonna get on a soap box here for a few minutes before we end the show.
Like, because why not?
I
-- mean, you edit the audio, you can say what you want.
-- That's right.
I can make you look smart or dumb curt.
It's all up to me and you know what else I realized?
Actually the other day is I keep all of my stories in, but I cut a lot of yours out.
So it's like, oh, I'm like the evil dictator here.
But anyway, there are especially in security. I feel like there's people who just
plane to complain
and like there's nothing wrong with complaining about something.
But I feel like you all, you have to follow that up with action,
right? Just saying, oh, this is terrible and everything's bad. Well,
ok, like what now like what do you expect me to do
with this
insight you have gifted to me?
And the answer is nothing obviously. But
I think the challenge there is in the past, that kind of behavior was useful.
Like, hey guys that Bush over there is rustling and there's like a tail sticking out.
The problem now is this happens 1000 times a day, right?
And if, if it was like, if there was one good insightful complaint per day on Twitter,
awesome.
-- But it's not, it's like a billion low quality complaints,
-- complaints
don't matter
because they have to come with something else. You can say like C pe s are terrible
but, or I could say C pe s are bad but pearl is better. Let's go work on pearl.
We can't fix C pe. That is a reasonable statement.
But at some point,
there's where you recognize a problem and you don't
yet have any idea of what the solution is.
But you have to start by recognizing the problem.
And then from there,
one of the problems with a lot of the people that complain is they're
not complaining from the perspective of I want to start a conversation about this.
They're complaining from the perspective of I just want to complain about this.
Absolutely.
Because
complaining is fine, but it has to be followed by action.
Starting a conversation is an action, right?
Just whining and complaining and saying everything is terrible,
that is making everything worse.
And that is, I, I think this, this is all part of it, like this whole conversation.
It's, this is uh this is such a weird bug. It's, it's so many weird problems. And
I mean, like even what, what I'm going to do with my network now,
like I'm going to figure out is it the computer, is it Linux?
And if it's Linux,
I'm going to go file a bug if I can prove Linux is creating this problem.
And here's my question. Now, how many people are going to listen to this show?
Who have, what was it again? Uh Lenovo idea pad.
Yeah, idea
pad.
The,
no, I'm serious. Say the model number and put in the show notes because
some poor schmuck is gonna google this or hear this and be like,
oh,
yeah, I got one of those too and my network's all funky.
-- It could
-- be. I, I'm, you know, I shouldn't do this.
-- I have my computer tipped over right now looking at the bottom and like, yeah,
-- I was,
like, nice floors.
By the way,
I do have very nice floors. It's 100 year
old.
Is it
maple, maple? They're maple.
And it's funny because the trees were all old growth forests.
-- Like there's no knots because
-- here's the thing, I'll bet you a dollar
-- somebody listening to the show is like, oh, it
-- could be,
I don't know. I hope so. If I can help someone, that's great.
You literally cannot be the only person with this think pad
running Linux.
-- Like there has to be more than one
-- and I haven't, I need to do more work.
Is it just the think pad?
I have the thinkpad plugged into a dock and then the dock plugged into.
And I also one thing, so one thing someone's gonna bring up that's listening.
Yes, I verified the outlet is properly grounded.
That was the first thing I thought of is maybe the
grounding is bad and I got up my tester and every,
all the blinky lights lit up the right way.
-- So I don't think it's that
-- there is a whole bunch of stuff I remember now about,
uh, laptops and docks
and not sleeping and having weird problems, especially causing network problems
with wake on LAN and stuff. And that is well documented in
-- Google.
-- This computer does not have wake on l I could find in the bios.
So,
but the dock might,
-- the
-- dock might, that could be.
That was, I mean, that was also one of my thoughts because I went in the bio.
I'm like, I'm gonna turn off wake on land. I'm like, oh, it's not here.
But, but again, well, this computer doesn't have an actual Ethernet Jack.
The Ethernet Jack is in the dock, right?
But I mean, the thing to remember is like docking bays are no longer just a dumb thing.
They're a computer
with software that will never be updated and
-- cause all sorts of problems.
-- So, I, I want to end this on a call to action
and the call to action is there's a project called the Global
Security Database that if you listen to the show you've heard about,
if you've never heard us talk about it, we, you, you're welcome to.
Welcome to hell.
But,
but
it is, I'll put a link in the show notes.
It's what is Global Security database.org, I think is the website?
-- Yeah. Or GSD dot id. We got the short
-- one or GSD dot id. That's right.
I forget you bought that that's, that's such a good, such a good, shorter.
Yeah, that was,
-- that was kind of a pain.
-- But that's, that could probably be its own show. But anyway,
like this whole concept of how do we track things?
How do we, where do we draw lines about what vulnerabilities are,
what they aren't like,
-- what do we track? Like, I'm not, I don't know anymore.
-- Yeah.
No, I absolutely like the more we talk about this, the weirder it gets, I think it is a,
it is an open source project that the cloud security alliance has
and everyone is welcome to join, whether you're a CS A member or not.
And we would love opinions and thoughts and even just questions, like,
come through the mailing list, join the mailing list, ask questions.
There's a ton of work to do. I, we know our getting started experience is awful.
-- We apologize in advance. Like, if you show up it's, we
-- don't have one.
Well, we technically have one. It's, it's,
-- here's our repo. Good luck.
-- Right. It's mostly, yeah.
Yeah, wading through garbage and, and
to avoid the fire. But anyway, like, that's the call to action here.
I think it's like, I think there's a larger discussion around all of this and
it's something that I don't think anyone else is
having today other than the Cloud Security Alliance.
And so I think it's great.
And additionally,
the other big one is because the Cloud Security Alliance has a foundation.
This isn't one of those
Yin Kha
and taking everything and leaving,
which has happened many times in this vulnerability database space.
That's a big difference is the inclusivity like you and I are
members of like CWE or what's the one you're on with?
The the thing with
-- the
-- OS SSF with Linux
one,
right? And they're not real publicly kind of available, easy to interact.
The open SSF is that
one is
pretty good, but their focus is not vulnerabilities.
Their focus is the open source ecosystem.
Like this does not overlap with that in any reasonable way.
And that's one of the big differences. We are very like we're on
the Twitter and on the github
and you can yell at us and just
drive bys and we're, we're happy with that.
Yeah, absolutely. Like all data is good data. So anyway.
All right. All right. I'm going to call this one. We kind of dragged this on.
So I, I'll, we'll see after I do some more testing,
hopefully I'll have more info on this bizarre network problem.
But thank you, Kurt,
you forgot to say the Linux
-- distribution.
-- Uh
Fedora, I run Fedora,
I've run Fedora forever and it's because I know the Fedora
people so I can yell at them when something breaks.
It's perfect. I love it.
And,
and actually that's why I also buy Lenovo stuff because
I know the Fedora ex developers all run Lenovo Gear.
So it It always works. Anyway.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to Open
source Beauty podcast.com. Head up the show, not Susy Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.