Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in real crime. Josh Pressers.
-- Ah,
-- man, I'm getting more nervous about you in this intro.
I feel like if, if one of us goes to jail the other is going to
and while I don't plan to go to jail, it still concerns me.
-- The other one will have to be extradited
-- unless
one of us travels to the other location,
-- the crime spree. I don't know, but
-- you'd still have to be rested in all that.
-- But
-- I'm concerned you're going to slowly nudge me into a life of crime.
And I, like, I won't even know what's happening because that's, that's how it works.
You know what?
Maybe I'll just give you a, like a,
I'll replace all your American nickels with Canadian nickels.
I think I can spend those in America as if they were us change. I think there's an
agreement between the United States and Canada coins are the same.
-- Well, but
-- like, what about dollar coins?
That's probably different because we don't have dollar coins because, yeah,
-- you do, Susan B Anthony,
-- it's complicated.
So for people who don't know because a significant number of
our listeners do not live in North America about half actually,
which I'm very proud of, but
he
doesn't know this.
I
show you statistics. You don't pay attention.
Anyway. Anyway,
I want to see that line moving up into the
-- room.
-- That's
right.
-- So, anyway, in America we have dollar bills like
-- paper. Yeah.
-- And they smell terrible.
-- They do, they stink and I guess they're full of cocaine.
According to tests, we'll look, we'll look it up in the show notes,
but
they have tried repeatedly to use dollar coins in
the United States and it has never worked.
And the very, so originally we had this thing called silver dollars,
which were these like gigantic coins.
And they're actually really cool and they're
really hard to find now because obviously
they haven't been made in like 50 years and I have a couple,
I love them.
But then they, they switch to a smaller coin called the Susan B, Anthony dollar.
And it looks like a United States quarter. It's only slightly larger.
It is the same color. And you can imagine how this happened. In fact, I still,
I still get some as quarters every now and then when I go to the store, like,
it's pretty rare.
But, yeah.
-- So, anyway, I
-- just, I love how, like,
when it comes to change people super don't pay attention.
-- Yeah. No one does. Exactly.
-- Literally.
I'm pretty sure you could give them a fistful of, like German coins or Euros
and like, they're round and shiny.
Yeah, exactly. Exactly. So,
then they tried making a US dollar coin.
That was a gold color, but it was the same size as the Susan B Anthony coin.
And so, like in a vending machines, for example,
you could use either coin interchangeably.
They, in fact, they, they even passed a law
where they,
-- that's
-- not, that's actually kind
of pretty there.
There's a bunch of them and there's all different
presidents on them and they're very nice coins.
I have quite a lot of them
and
they, they even passed a law said, you know,
the US mint has to mint X number of coins a year or whatever.
And
like, the people just hated them and didn't use them. So
now we have warehouses full of coins.
Well,
my understanding is the primary use case for these dollar
coins was you bought them on your credit card and
then took them to the bank to pay off your
credit card bill to rack up your credit card points.
Yeah,
that's basically what everyone did because the US mint
would ship them for free to your house.
I cannot imagine the cost on that. I,
-- they were, they were trying to get people to use them.
-- I understand.
But I mean, like shipping that stuff
-- and
-- don't get me wrong. I love dollar coins. I love going to Canada and Europe.
And having
a, a coin that is of a, we'll say useful quantity.
Well, and I'll be honest, I've lived in Germany where, you know,
they had back in the day up to five mark coins, like a, basically a $5 coin,
which was great because, like,
vending machines could actually sell expensive stuff without you having to, like,
like,
what always gets me about the US is if I want to buy something at a vending machine,
-- I better have a lot of quarters.
-- There are some that take bills now.
Well, now they take credit cards and stuff.
-- Mostly they have the adapter
-- and to make it even more obnoxious in the US.
-- All of our bills are the same size.
-- Well, we also do that here but
-- we have braille on them to identify which is, which
-- are Canadian.
Canadian bills are all the same. I haven't actually seen Canadian money.
Canadian bills have historically all been the same size. But his story
because we don't want to be jerks to blind people. There was braille coating on them.
There was raised bumps. I get that.
So you can, like, you can actually even, even you and I can feel it like there.
-- It's quite, it's really obvious.
-- I bet the last 10 times I've been to Canada
-- because I usually get there a couple times a year. Not
-- anymore. I'm not.
Yeah, exactly.
I've not had cash though because credit cards are
so pervasive and easy that it's just not worth
-- cash.
-- Wait time out. When you say, don't you also use debit cards down there.
They exist. I don't use debit card. There's a whole pain in the butt reason.
So, the problem basically comes down to the United States.
-- If someone steals my debit card number, they can drain my money.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah, we talked about this on a show.
-- Right.
Whereas if it's credit card it's not my problem. So, debit cards exist.
I never use them.
So, in my brain, I just say credit card because that's how it is anyway. Anyway.
All right,
I've got a question for you.
Is the moon a star or a planet?
Well, it is a light source so clearly it's a star
or maybe it's a moon
but you can't use it. So it's not a light source.
It reflects light.
Yeah, that makes it a light source. So I took my bike ride this morning.
I actually take a bike ride every morning
because pandemic was, like, making me fat this morning. I saw Venus in the sky.
Is that, is that a sun?
It's a light source.
No, it's a,
it's a planet. Planet Venus.
Yeah. It's also bigger than a peanut.
It was not bigger than a peanut if I was holding a peanut at arm's length.
No, I meant the real thing.
-- I meant the actual, the actual star is bigger than a peanut,
-- is it?
Yeah.
-- You don't know that.
-- It's true. I haven't been there but if I have a
really big peanut.
Yeah, that is true.
I, you know, I've always wondered about this, like,
what would happen if you like Hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy?
Tried to make a planet of some arbitrary material like cotton candy or, you know,
egg white.
There is a, what if I will find it and put a link in the show notes. The XK CD guy
Randall Munroe, his name is, he's got this site called, what if, where you people,
I don't know if he still runs it,
but people would ask ridiculous questions if someone asked about a
mole of moles and a mole is like some enormous number.
So what if you had an enormous number of moles?
And he talks about like the gravity and the fact
that you just end up with this gross meat planet?
And so anyway,
I will look it up and, and,
-- but it's, it's more horrifying than you would hope it is.
-- Oh, I imagine.
Yeah, it's six,
-- it's six times 10 to the 23rd,
-- which is a
big number. A male of males is a lot of malls.
So,
-- anyway,
-- well, and related to this, I've, I've been looking into because
I've, so I've recently installed a ring security system in my house.
And then my question is when I sell the house, number one,
does it come with the house or not?
And depending on how you
define, you know, fittings and attachments in the house.
So, like, you know, the cabinets in the kitchen are probably staying,
I'm not going to rip them out and take them with me.
You know, typically the major appliances like the fridge and the, you know,
washer and dryer stay.
Right.
They can, it depends how you sell your
-- house.
-- Exactly.
So,
but the question then becomes most people typically leave
the refrigerator and like whatever kind of stuff that's,
you know, permanently affixed, right?
But the question is with the ring security system, how do I,
how do I transfer ownership
in a way that
person receiving it can like knows that they actually have ownership of it.
-- The worst thing is too, is now smart appliances. Ok.
-- These are all related.
So let's tie them up before we go off into the tangents.
So there is a QVC clip,
we will put a link to where the people on it are trying to decide if
the moon is a star or a planet and it's fun to laugh at them.
But it is interesting to talk about because these people lack the,
we'll say vernacular to actually have this discussion
and this is completely related to security
in general because obviously when we talk,
we have a certain vocabulary
that normal people don't have and then we can tie that into
kind of there's a story we'll obviously put in the show notes,
man, we're gonna have a lot of show notes this time.
But, uh,
a story we'll put in the show notes where basically a person sold
-- their house and they didn't lose access to their security system even
-- better.
They tried to cancel access to the security system. They called Viv
and they, a long story short, they still had access and when they finally kind of,
the thing started to hit the news and stuff and it phoned Viv
and like VT turned it off in 30 seconds.
Exactly. And so like this, this all comes together into one kind of
thing to think about inec security is
there's ways to talk about things that most people don't understand
and it can create problems because for example, I bet this person called
Viv
and they probably tried to explain what was going on and
I have a very strong suspicion there was a communication problem.
Well, the point is they shouldn't have to explain what's going on.
It's the guy sold his house called Vivan to cancel his security contract. And
thus, you know, the, the smart home security system.
And
Vivian said, yeah, we'll cancel it.
But the problem is these companies have their cancellation stuff set up so
that it's really more about customer
retention than actually canceling the account,
right?
And so they essentially didn't actually like turn
off his access to the devices and stuff.
So he had access to, for example,
cameras that also had a microphone and speaker on it.
The guy did.
What, in my opinion is kind of the right, well, the best right thing he could, which is
he notified the existing homeowner by basically scaring the bejesus out of her.
Right.
I'm not sure if I agree with that necessarily,
but how else is he supposed to contact her?
But anyways, it also as, as much as it scared her,
it also gets the point across that this is a real problem, you know,
like those baby monitors that were insecure
and people were hijacking them and like,
-- they're still
-- insecure.
Yeah,
I, I think this guy did the best job he could, you know, with responsible disclosure
or given a company that's a total bage of weasels.
But I'm thinking so with the security system it's
relatively easy to make people understand that it's like,
look, your home has a security system that somebody else has control over.
Well, ok, that's probably, you know, a normal person would say that's bad.
But what about your fridge or
there was just an article today in the reg about, you know,
hacking old coffee makers to turn the burner on and, you know,
either attack other stuff in the house or,
uh, I'm,
I'm guessing that a lot of those things
don't have physical safety cutoffs and could experience.
What's the expression, an unanticipated thermal event?
Like a fire?
Yeah,
I think about this problem a lot
and I think
it is
80% communication and 20% engineering. And the reason I say that is because
it's easy to talk about, oh, you can ransomware someone's coffee potter,
you can hack their coffee pot or you can do a bad thing.
So what ends up happening is for example,
there's a story that just came out of someone put ransomware on
their coffee pot and they were using it as an example,
but like the attack is relatively impractical in all seriousness.
And so now we end up in a situation where
you have what appears to be a very sensational story
that quite frankly no one is believing because I think it's just been like,
we've cried wolf so many times you've got the security people being like, oh,
it's not that bad and the normal people are like whatever nerd we don't care.
Well, here's a, here's a more concrete example,
I'm actually planning to buy a new TV.
One of my biggest concerns is having ads shoved down my throat.
-- You just don't ever connect that thing to the internet,
-- right?
So, but looking at, for example, Samsung apparently has been updating their tvs to
show more and more ads like on the user interfaces
that you like have to use to use your TV.
No, you don't.
And this guy showed a picture of one where it's like
the bottom half of the screen is an ad for,
I think it's
-- Butter or yogurt. Maybe
-- it wouldn't surprise me.
So I have a Samsung TV and I bought it, I connected it to the internet.
I installed the new firmware because I assumed there would be magic update
or something.
And then I disconnected it from the internet and
it has never been connected to the internet since.
And I use fire TV on it.
My plan is to go to Costco get like the cheapest,
decent looking TV and just never plug it into the internet.
-- That
-- is
-- exactly what I did
and actually so fun fact, all of my tvs, I've,
I think I might have talked about this on the show a couple episodes ago but every TV,
I've owned last me about three years and then they just die
and
you can go to Costco and if your TV costs less than some amount,
I don't remember what it is even
it was, you get,
you can get a warranty for like 30 bucks for a five year warranty then from Costco.
So when my TV dies in three years, which I totally expect it to do,
I can bring it to Costco and they'll give me a new TV.
So I'm looking forward to that.
Well, and because the other thing I've noticed, for example,
every rental car I've driven, you scroll through it and you all see these,
you see these people's phones.
Yeah,
all paired and in some cases,
some of their contact list got dumped into the car's system.
-- So
-- that's a good example of most people don't know.
That's actually a problem because why would they,
they probably unpaired it on their phone.
Well, it's a very unapparent problem.
Right.
It's not,
it's like the same thing as a security flaw
where until somebody actually goes looking and poking around.
-- Yeah, you're not going to notice it. Now,
-- here's how I would explain that one.
How do we tell that to a normal person?
So,
when you pair your,
we don't, the answer is we don't, what we need to do is so this is,
this is where we frame communication.
We need to tell the developers of cars don't freaking save this stuff.
Like have a rental option or something, right? Like this is a pure techno
-- problem,
-- like have a rental mode for the car entertainment system.
Yeah, like when, when you know, you haven't seen the, I don't know, maybe I don't,
I don't know exactly how to do this, but you get the idea is I always,
I bucket these communication things into different places
and sometimes you need to talk to people,
sometimes you need to talk to engineers,
sometimes you need to talk to other security people.
And I don't think we ever make that determination.
We're like, oh, your coffee pot can be poked and burned on your house.
-- And it's like, ok, well, who are you telling that to
-- the other thing too?
Is I keep coming back to is why are we allowing users to
make dangerous mistakes when it is actually
reasonably possible to engineer the system.
So those mistakes aren't possible.
Well,
it should be actually so funny enough,
you mentioned that I just read a news story this morning where Nist apparently is
coming up with some guidance on like
determining if something is a phishing attempt when
like
the first thing I thought of in reading, that is just,
this is just another way to shame users.
The answer is just fix the freaking technology. So fishing isn't a thing anymore.
Don't,
-- don't try to bucket fishing attempts into a category
-- problem
with fishing is so you have what I would,
I would classify fishing into two main buckets,
technical and sort of non technical technical fishing would be like I
send you a password reset link and I intercept it and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And then there's non technical phishing where it's like, hey, you know, this is Bob.
I'm in a Mexican prison. I don't have access to my regular email address.
So I'm emailing you from this weird Gmail address and I need you to send me 500 bucks.
You're never going to make that go away. Exactly.
And then there's actually, you know what I would say, there's,
then there's sort of a third bucket which is the process fishing where it's,
you know, so for
locally that university based on an email reset the payment information for
a large contractor and sent like $10 million to some random bank account
and, you know, a big chunk of it went missing. Strangely,
that's just good old fashioned fraud.
Well, I was gonna say that that is weak internal controls because to me, if,
if I'm paying somebody on, like,
when I'm doing an electronic transfer to somebody online for like,
more than 20 bucks, I'm like, double checking.
Their email address is correct.
And if I'm,
if I was paying somebody 10 million dollars
and they supposedly sent me new payment details,
I would verify that.
I mean, I would hope so, but at the same time,
like if you're a company doing transactions of this size,
you probably have insurance to help protect you from this sort of problem.
And your insurance company is going to say
-- you have no internal controls. We're not insuring you.
-- Exactly.
And so, I mean, again, that's that
how was one person able to change or maybe not one person?
But how were these people able to change these payment details
in a way that was clearly wrong. Like there was no verification done.
There was no right.
You know, and again, that to me speaks that the business process is, well,
their internal controls are so fundamentally broken.
-- I have a hard time blaming the user at that point. No,
-- it's not the user's fault at all.
And again, like let's, let's, let's think about how you communicate this. Right.
It's easy to tell the story and laugh and be like a ha ha. They're so stupid
and you could blame the user for being stupid.
You could blame the company for being stupid.
You could blame maybe if they have insurance, the insurance company was stupid.
But
-- like who are you talking to? And what's our message here?
-- Right.
Well, and is the message actionable?
Right?
Because that's one thing that always,
every time somebody says check if links are safe before you click them,
I want to punch them in the face.
Yeah. What does that mean? Because they all go to a URL shortener. Yeah, exactly.
I just actually started paying for a Ur shortener to do some
testing because we have some long URL that I want shorter.
And one cool thing is URL shortener.
Of course, now can do things like, oh, based on country of origin,
we can send them different URL S based on time of day based on browser.
Oh my goodness. Right. Well, but that's the thing, right?
Like so somebody clicks on your shortened URL and you want to say like, OK, well,
if they're from Germany, show them the German ad.
If they're from England, show them the English ad.
If they're from America, you know, show them the American ad based on time of day,
you know, we want to show them the lunch special versus
for example, here's a, here's a shortened URL to our menu.
Well,
I'm going to show you the brunch menu or maybe the lunch menu or maybe the dinner menu,
right?
And so
I'm like,
this is actually this could be very useful for like advertising type stick.
You know, now, I don't have to build it in my application on my web server.
I can just do it at a rules level at this, you know,
$20 a month. URL shortening service.
And again, like, so, you know, here's the URL that goes to t.co slash bla
bla bla,
right? So I saw, what is that Twitter? I think
Twitter,
you know,
I was listening to a podcast where they were
talking about to this company and this company is,
you know,
they have these malware exploders where you basically run the document in
a sandbox and see if it like makes changes to the system.
And it's like now we have URL exploders where we actually like go and
download the URL and see does it drive by attack or something horrific happened?
We have phishing detection, you know, like keyword stuff and blah, blah, blah.
And I'm thinking like, you know,
it reminds me of what Google gmail did where remember we used to put
like tracking beacons in email to see if people opened their email or not.
And Google had the response of cool,
-- like we're just going to download all those images and cash
-- them
exactly, which is awesome.
Yeah,
they solved the problem.
And so it occurs to me that like if you send an email to me in a web page,
I kind of at this point want my, like, back end
them to, like, go grab that web page, render it,
make sure it's reasonably safe and then somehow serve me a cached copy.
-- If I click that link, I
-- would be comfortable with that.
Because what's the, there's no safe alternative other than don't click the link,
which is not going to happen.
I got to get my job done. Yeah, exactly. I mean, people send me links to things.
I have to click the links and
I do and, and not only that, let's face it.
How many, how many probably
trillions and trillions of links are sent every day
and what percent of them are actually malicious.
It's a very low percentage for sure.
Well, it's a very low percentage that gets through the initial spam filters.
I suspect on the back end there's a ton of traffic but it's just so dumb.
-- It gets filtered easy. I mean, and
-- there's definitely some of that for
sure.
Like I've really noticed spam filters have gotten better but I still get
a ton of spam for attendee lists and that key phrase right there,
attendee lists, right?
They're always spam.
I don't understand how this stuff gets through
-- Google's filters
-- unless people don't think it's spam.
I consistently market as spam and it keeps coming in.
And the other thing is I get a lot of Japanese spam and I
wish there was a way in my brow or in my gmail to say,
look, I only speak bad English.
-- So if it's not in English it's probably not for me.
-- Yes,
I know. I know exactly what you mean.
-- Oh,
-- and an uptick in Spanish spam,
I think. Yeah, that's Spanish. Yeah, the accent.
But anyways, so I just, yeah, how do we,
especially when the interface is opaque or the
the sort of failure mode is very subtle or hard to, you know, my smart TV,
somebody still has an account on it.
There are smart tvs that I have built in
cameras and microphones for doing Skype or whatever.
So that's, you know, a surveillance device. And so that's understandable.
But what if it doesn't have a microphone and camera like, oh somebody can like
view my Netflix
-- preferences or something? Like do I care?
-- Yes, you have to care.
So, OK, so that's another topic another day about.
Should I care about what seems to be minor information about me?
And the problem, the answer to that is yes, because if enough of it gets out,
you can paint a very disturbing picture of what's going on.
But that's a story for the other day. I'm not talking about that today.
So here is what I would say to round the square.
When we communicate about these security things,
we'll say be it an incident or a problem or an attack or whatever it is.
We're really bad at first explaining it in a coherent and reasonable manner.
But then there's also the question of like, what now? Right.
How do we, how do we look at something like? So let's say there's an attack.
Yeah.
This also presupposes that the technical
person explaining this actually understands it.
And I'll be blunt, I've met
a lot of people who think they understand something.
Um, but they're on that Dunning Kruger curve of like, no, you really don't.
Is it a star or a planet?
And the answer is it's a moon.
It's neither of those things.
Yes,
that is part of the problem is you have to understand
how to communicate about the thing you're talking
about if you don't have the vocabulary.
Well, you have to understand the thing you're communicating about.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, that's part of it. Right. That's kind of step one.
And it, it can be hard to know if you do or don't understand
what's going on around you. And I don't know a good answer to that necessarily.
Well, I'll be blunt, how can anybody
possibly truly say they understand what smart TV S are and do unless
-- they work in a smart TV manufacturer
-- even then you probably can't.
I've used smart TV. S and it's clear that there's a lot going on under the hood
that I'm not aware of at all. Like the fact that some of them now have an antivirus.
I was like, what? But, oh, it is a computer.
No, like
it is.
The fact that I hadn't considered that proves that I'm
not really all that competent to talk about smart TV.
S and that's fair yet. We are so,
well, I hate to say, but we're probably the most competent of the least competent.
-- We have a
-- podcast. We could talk about anything we want with authority.
We have authority because we said so.
So, ok, so anyway, like this is all part of the story though, right?
Is, is there's an amount of understanding,
there's I think a difficult thing to do is just to say, I don't know.
-- And I don't think that happens very often
-- again, back to Dunning Kruger.
A lot of people don't know the bounds of their knowledge.
No one does. No one really knows the bounds of their knowledge.
I mean, this is,
I feel like this is the most important skill I'm teaching my Children is,
it's ok to say, I don't know
because my son will like, start making crap up.
And I'm like, do you know this or are you making this up? He's like, I'm making it up.
I'm like, so what is the actual answer to my question? He says, I don't know.
And you can tell he's like, God, dad got me again.
I know I do the same thing with Felix and Wolfe
-- and it's like,
-- it's important though.
Well, it's, and here's how I frame it.
-- I don't know, is the beginning of, but we can find,
-- yeah, exactly.
Like, let's look it up instead of making garbage up.
Let's just look up the answer and find out.
-- The
-- funny thing is there's a whole thing about this, you know,
confidence intervals.
There's like a whole
chunk of math and statistics to basically say how to,
what degree are we certain that this is correct or not correct necessarily.
But that this is a factual statement, you know, and, and I,
because I worked with a lot of ex-military
and law enforcement people back in the day.
And the one guy literally qualified almost every statement he made.
Like, if you literally, he gives the example of like my wife asked me,
is it raining outside?
And he will look outside and it's like raining outside and he'll be like,
I am highly confident it is raining outside.
It just, it was so ingrained in him because he was an intelligence officer,
even if you like know something is a fact,
maybe it's the other side playing tricks with you.
And like, it's a fake fact. I mean, that's fair.
And so he spent his whole life training this and training people. And so
actually,
I really enjoyed talking with him because you kind of
knew where the conversation stood on a factual basis of,
ok, he's very confident about that.
So it's pretty much guaranteed to be correct.
But on this other stuff he's saying, yeah, I'm not sure.
Or I'm not confident,
I would say this leads itself to a second half of our point of saying, I don't know,
is when you think, you know,
if someone questions your knowledge,
it is ok
and saying, well, let's look it up and make sure I'm right.
There's because I know so many people that if you say,
are you sure they become offended that you question their knowledge.
And it's like,
that's not how
-- truth works
-- and stuff changes,
it sometimes changes,
people remember things wrong.
I used to think I had a phenomenal memory
and I don't know if I just got older.
It was probably more likely I was just like a young a hole,
but like there's so many things now I look at them
and it's, it's, I think that is not what I'm remembering at all,
but it's obviously it's obviously not true what I remember.
So this is the real thing. And so, I mean, this is something important, right?
Is just that I don't know and being willing, willing to accept
a challenge to what I mean, essentially it's a challenge to your authority.
-- Let's face
-- it.
I actually double check a lot of my knowledge now because part of it is also,
it's so easy now, like back in the day it was not easy.
Yeah. Right. Right. Right.
I wanted to look up facts. You had to go to the library and hope they had a book on it.
Exactly tangent.
But I,
we just got our new downtown library just opened last week
and it is gorgeous and they have like 3d maker space.
They have a music studio.
They have, it's just the children's area is beyond amazing.
And they still have a bunch of cabinets with microfiche
with all the old microfiche stuff. Right.
Because it's just too expensive to digitize it all.
But the thing is the microfiche machines they have now. Holy cow.
They fancy looking
like the old ones where, you know,
you had like the plate and a light source and like the, the, the lens and a screen.
This one is like, oh man, it is all the way fancy. That's pretty cool actually.
So I'm actually looking forward to using them.
But, you know, I didn't want to touch stuff because in this time of COVID,
anything you touch,
the library has bins all over where you have to put the stuff in the bins and then they,
like, quarantine it for two weeks to make sure the surfaces are clean.
You can't wipe a book down with Lysol.
Well,
you can,
-- you shouldn't.
-- Yeah, but then your collection gets small fast, right?
So they're just taking the tact of, you know,
every time somebody touches a book it goes in a bin it goes in a room for like, yeah,
like one or two weeks
-- and then it goes back in the stacks.
-- That's wild.
Anyway. Anyway. OK, we're, we're running out of time.
So I don't, I don't wanna, I don't wanna dwell on COVID. So back to
like, like, how do we start all this stuff? And I would say step one,
I don't know, even if you think you do, it's OK to say, I don't know
because knowledge is a journey. But then we have to find ways to, to
understand the audience and understand who can help us.
Because like, so favorite example,
let's talk about the coffee pot burning down your house.
The story,
you tell the person building the coffee pot is going to be different than the story.
You tell the person buying the coffee pot,
right?
And in some instances,
the person buying the coffee pot might not even know or
care or need to know depending upon what's going on,
-- right?
-- In theory, every electronic I buy should be
or whatever listed so that it literally specifically does not burn my hose down.
-- Yeah,
-- but you can,
you can get a listing because they aren't going, I mean,
they might try to hack a coffee pot, but it's highly likely
they're not going to get that far.
And there's, there's also going to be things you can do.
Like for example, let's say it has a cut off switch,
-- but if you can disable the cut off switch in software, well,
-- well, for example,
-- you could just have a thermal fuse
-- and that's the right answer.
-- But at the same time, so let's say you don't,
-- that's an extra 10 cents per unit.
Well, not just that.
Does anyone even know you might think? Oh, my software cut off switch is just fine.
Well, is it,
who's there to tell you? It's not, how are we going to even even learn?
That's a problem.
Does the insurance company know to ask questions like this,
does underwriter labs know to ask questions like this?
And the answer is probably not, not right now.
And not only that, how many,
how many legitimate coffee pot attacks are going to burn down someone's house?
Right?
The number is probably zero right now and my guess is in 10 years which Lord forbid,
we're still talking about this.
-- It's probably still going to be single digits. Most
-- likely. I agree.
I mean, I just, I keep coming back to that,
that concern that self driving cars are a
computer with 1000 pounds of mass and velocity.
And so while coffee pots may not, you know, run you down, there are going to be
systems hooked up to the internet that that can and, and that's fair.
I think part of my concern is I don't necessarily think the whole industry
that makes anything that attaches to the
internet needs to really think about safety.
But a perfect example of this, this is why I won't buy a smart door lock is,
I'm not concerned about somebody hacking it.
I'm concerned about that thing not letting me my house when it's minus 40.
-- I understand that completely
-- because that has happened,
-- like across all of Britain at one point,
-- people who live in nice places are like,
what's he talking about?
Minus 40
fun fact for the audience minus 40 is the same in Celsius and Fahrenheit,
it is minus 40.
Another fun fact for the audience,
there's only one country
-- that we have to use that disclaimer
-- for. Is it my country?
-- Liberia and Myanmar went metric
-- a few years ago
for them.
Good for
them.
You're the only
left out
there.
There's a video I will put in the show notes where there's people like to say, oh,
there's two kinds of countries in the world.
There's countries that use the metric system and countries that
went to the moon and this youtuber made this this.
But no, no,
it's funny though because this youtuber made this
brilliant video talking about Werner Von Braun,
who was the German who actually built a rocket that brought us to the moon
and he's, and Von Braun starts talking and the guy goes,
listen to that thick Alabama accent.
I've not, I've not laughed that hard
in a long time and actually Von Braun insisted
on using the metric system for everything he did.
Well, I think NASA still does, don't they?
Anyone reasonably uses it?
-- And I know the US military does and
-- English units are insane.
How many inches is two miles? I have no idea.
-- Well,
-- foot pounds of torque, everything.
-- It's all, it's all
-- ridiculous.
And if you want to read a really great
shenanigans is go read about operation paper clip.
-- I don't know what that is.
-- That's where basically the US decided, hey,
as bad as some of these people were,
they scooped up 1600 German scientists post World War two.
Von Braun and his V two rocket team.
-- Alright.
-- Alright, I'm gonna, I'll give you the last word on this one man.
-- Take us home.
-- I just honestly,
the way I buy electronics now is by buying them
at a place that offers a one year money back.
We don't care because I'm reasonably certain they're not going to sell me garbage.
And that's all I got like because there's
I I work in this industry and I am in no way qual
like how is Costco going to let me borrow like 20 different TV.
S and run pen tests on them to find a secure one.
And more to the point I'm not going to ever do that because like I have a life to live.
That is also true. The answer is just don't hook up to the internet.
Well, the answer is basically admit defeat in a way and just say, look,
I don't trust or like this TV, the supposed capabilities it has built in.
I'm going to reasonably trust Apple or Amazon firestick and use that instead.
I mean, that's probably fair.
That sucks because that's, you know,
that's an extra 102 100 bucks on the top of the TV.
And I've also got this giant chunk of electronics that's not being used.
I mean, that's fair.
I think if I was going to give the message to normal people, it just don't,
don't trust it no matter what it is.
You buy a house with the security system, don't trust it.
Call the company, make sure it's yours. You know, I'm going to
end it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Head up our
show. It's Suzy Pound
Os Podcast. Hashtag Def hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fabulous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.