Hello and welcome to episode 81 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So, have you heard of
Autos?
-- Yes.
-- And the world
-- hasn't ended yet. Not
-- yet. Give it time.
You know, I think,
I think the problem is we need to start
using the Mayan calendar instead of the Julian calendar.
It
didn't, the, the
Mayan calendar lied to us. The world should have ended in what, 2012.
And it did not much to
many people's dismay.
Yeah.
But my understanding was there was like an interpretation error or something.
-- I don't know.
-- Oh, is that what it was?
I think somebody got a date where carried by one or
one of these days. They're going to be right
soon.
You know what I thought of when I read about Autos.
Spit is, well, I guess first of all, just to make sure we, we set the, the
field here is
autos
is a tool that basically you pointed at
someone's infrastructure and it looks for problems,
right?
Using a bunch of automated tooling and this is nothing secret.
It's all just public stuff
and of course people are flipping out
and I remember I read this and that my brain immediately went to,
do you remember a tool called Satan
from the nineties?
Right.
Right. Remember how
he did get fired for writing Satan? And I remember all of the crazy
no say like it, it became a corporate,
like it's a, it's a company now and they sell the thing.
Well, but more importantly, I think though is,
do you remember all the people claiming like the
world was going to end because of this tool?
Well, I think there was a perception
and there still is,
the security problems are hard to exploit.
So if people sort of don't explicitly point them out, we're fine.
But then you like, for example,
go on youtube and look for the lock picking lawyer and watch him just
break locks open in like one or two minutes that
are supposed to be like good high security locks.
And it's like,
yeah, no, the world, if people are competent, it's,
it's actually nine times out of 10,
pretty easy to exploit the security of a system or of a device.
Well, and the thing that gets me always as well is
the vast majority of compromises I see aren't like some crazy zero day attacker.
It's crap like you're running a 12 year old
version of wordpress and there's 17 r ce flaws that
I could use against it.
I'll pick the one I like the best.
And this is one of those things that
people release tools like this and, and a certain group always flips out.
In fact, I saw somebody put a tool on github
that, that prevents showdown from scanning your infrastructure.
And it's like that doesn't solve anything
that that's putting a bucket under the leash, proclaiming
the
noise.
Well, it's ok, but depending on how you run your network and stuff,
it can maybe reduce the noise and the false positives in
your alerting system if you actually have people looking at them.
Um
But I think part of that would be in general
in general, you'd have to have such a mature
infosec sort of process and infrastructure for that to be a value that,
that it almost applies to nobody.
I don't even think it needs to be mature. I mean, look if, if you're running
some sort of threat detection system
and you can't basically like blacklist or whitelist showdown and say,
stop telling me about these guys.
What are you running? Like you do your job?
Well, the problem isn't just that showdown
scans it,
but then showdown puts it in the database and other
monkeys and script kitties and whatnot all you know,
have
a
and some of those are good to know because let's face it, man,
you can scan I PV four in what, like seven minutes now.
I mean,
you're not hiding from anybody.
It's,
I don't know. II I look at a tool like this and then I look at the outrage and I think
you people are, are, you're bargaining up the wrong tree with this?
Well, this is the classic shoot the messenger, right?
Like how many, uh,
organizations get super angry when somebody points out a security
flaw or a problem in their system or process?
-- That is true. That happens all the time. Right?
-- I,
I can't count the number, like,
how many articles have people written online where it's
like I tried to responsibly notify my bank or
something of this flaw
and, like,
they threatened to sue me and then they had the cops show up and take all my stuff.
Right. Definitely. And in fact, I, I've seen
many instances myself of coming across situations like that and
just saying nothing because it's not worth it and,
you know, that, you know, there, there's certain organizations that,
that, you know, will not respond in a positive manner to receiving any sort of,
I, I guess, advisory or warning that they're screwing something up
and, and the funny thing is
many of those organizations are the same ones, you know, complaining about autos,
spit and at the same time,
like, fix your stuff,
the solution isn't to complain. The solution is to do things. Right.
Think of this as,
as you're being dragged
into the future, whether you want to or not.
-- And, and in a couple of years you're going to be glad you did.
-- Yeah.
I mean, I remember was it last year
or a year, about two years ago? Maybe the General Motors basically
promised not to sue security researchers that came to them with flaws.
And at first I was, like, well,
great, awesome.
But honestly, no, that's, that's a good step forward
because, I mean, a large company like that, if I found a flaw in their car,
I would, yeah, either prior to this, I would have either not said anything or two.
I would have somehow anonymously, like, you know, put it up on Twitter or,
you know, emailed a bunch of journalists or whatever,
but there's no way I would put my name on that because like I,
yeah, no, I just, I don't have no,
-- I
-- totally get it, man.
Like potential hassle and
the beauty is you don't know if it's going to be a hassle or not until you do.
And,
and like this is one of the things I will say that I really
like about having a bug bounty program is when you have a bounty program.
That's like you put a sign up that says, you know, researchers welcome,
come and test my stuff.
I'm not going to sue you.
And that's, that's a big deal.
It's
absolutely.
And,
and I see that as a bigger advantage than almost anything else
in terms of dealing with these guys because they know it's,
it's a safe place and they can come and come and work with you and,
and not be worried about, you know, what's going to happen?
Are these guys going to sue me? Are they going to come get me?
Because it's, it's scary, man. I, I know what it's like.
Yeah.
Yeah. No. And, and the other thing too that this brings up is it used to be
sort of hiding in a school of fish,
used to be a somewhat viable security strategy in that
there were just so many other vulnerable systems and stuff that, you know,
the old Attackers that wanted to build AD D OS platform or, you know,
whatever would basically do, sort of the cheapest,
most
quick to return on investment, you know, attacks because
they're on a budget and time constraint, right?
So things like drive by downloads are great because you can
serve a bad ad to like a million people in a day
and, you know, if even only 100 of them are exploitable still, that's 100 you know,
attacks in a day with minimal effort.
And I think the reality is, you know, things like autos
flight just really do drive home that you can't,
you know, if you have a public IP. Yeah, you're gonna get scanned
and you're going to get scanned a lot and
especially with IOT stuff you're going to get,
you know,
they're going to try connecting to the tel net port and
-- trying like whatever the top dozen or 100 credentials are
-- and,
and it'll take 10 seconds.
Yeah. And
there's, you can no longer hide in the school of fish kind of and, you know,
be secured because
there's like, well blue whales coming along trawling the entire ocean basically.
And I, I don't know what the answer is.
I think one of the simplest answers for, especially for home users though,
is get like a decent router so that everything is behind it.
And you know, as much as I hate Nat and you know, network address translation,
breaking the whole concept of end to end connectivity for the internet.
Now, the reality is
especially for home users, you know,
you stick everything behind a single IP on that because it's not
like your ISP is giving you much of a choice anyways,
right?
I mean,
but uh in the last uh 10 years, uh all the
equipment my ISP has given me basically does not whether I like it or not,
unless I explicitly have a business account and buy multiple IP S.
Um
And the one I noticed actually
by default was giving me a 1 92 1 68 address. So the the, the router like
the DS L modem itself was doing the that rather, you know,
and I prefer actually to have my own device doing it realistically for home users.
That's, that's probably the best solution.
I mean,
because we can't fix the IOT stuff like I'm buying
iot stuff a bit now and it's just like,
yeah, this stuff's garbage and I can't secure it,
but it's not like I have an option of buying high quality iot that's secure.
Right. There's nothing with a good track record. There's nothing.
No, no, there isn't.
And more to the point though, it really shouldn't.
I mean, what, what security settings should my smoke alarm have,
like force http S no, that's like the default and it already does that to some degree.
So. Ok, cool. Like,
really what, you know, this isn't a PC, right?
This is just a thing doing a single thing that happens to have
-- a whole computer on it
-- and, and let's face it.
It's looking more and more like security is not a feature, the market demands.
I mean, my favorite is actually, was it, was it yesterday,
there was a news story saying the,
like the investigation into Equifax has been put on ice
and it's never going to come back, let's face it. So, I mean,
nothing.
Well, what's, what's gonna happen
even if they investigated Equifax?
I mean, the reality is we, we know what went wrong, right?
They tried to throw that poor guy under the bus saying, oh,
we had one employee who was responsible for this.
We didn't do his job. Right. Well,
that means the process is very fundamentally flawed.
You know, if it's a small medium business, like, like if it's my, like my accountant.
If he gave me that story, I believe it because it's, you know,
it's a small accounting firm.
Right. Like,
it's like 10 people
-- but
-- like, there's two sides to that. There's either one
there, it's true.
Which,
which is shameful or, or they're lying, which is also shameful.
So there's basically,
there's no end to that story that ends well for them. But, but at the same time
it clearly doesn't matter. The market has spoken.
They don't care about security like full stop.
Well, this is why they're called
Equifax
already once and they rebranded.
So like no, like we this is round two.
Like what really frustrates me about this whole Equifax thing is everybody's like,
oh we should like
do something. Ok? Cool. Like what like stop being an Equifax customer.
No, you're actually the Equifax data and you, you, you can't opt out of this.
Ok. Well,
get companies to stop using Equifax. No, I mean,
well, in theory they could switch to Transunion or experience or whatever.
They're no better, right?
Somewhat like choice point for background checks or whatever.
But
yeah, they don't,
they don't care. It's not like this affects them. I mean,
and that's what gets me about these kind of,
it's like an industrial disaster like when you know BP,
polluted the entire Gulf of Mexico,
right? Like what can I do about that? Stop buying gasoline for my car.
You could, but there's nothing you can do and and BP paid what,
like a billion dollars or something which,
yeah, exactly. Rounding error.
And, and this is,
this is one of those things that from, from the research I've done,
there's kind of two paths that make a company carry.
You can have the market decides something is, or isn't important.
And in terms of security, the market has clearly decided it's not important.
So now the other option is essentially government regulation and we could use.
Airlines are my favorite example of this where
where
the customers
probably care about airline safety, but let's face it.
I have a suspicion, most people would still buy the cheap tickets
even if, if one airline had a less good safety record than, than some of the others.
Whereas government regulation has basically forced these guys
into doing a lot of things correctly.
Well, the thing is it's not just government regulation,
it's also things like the N TSB, the National Transport Safety Board,
I count those as regulation
and the FAA and this
not just regulation but also a framework of
improvement and also people to execute that framework,
right?
Every time a plane crashes or there's an incident, they investigate it,
come up with recommendations and then ideally implement said recommendations.
So you get this continuous improvement and you do that for 50 years and then
you get to a point where we are now which is like last year,
-- there were no airline disasters in the US
-- Right.
Right. And, and for what it's worth, I, I would put that in the,
the bucket of regulation.
Right, because at the same time, like if the FAA tells you to do something,
you have to do it,
you don't, you can't be like, I don't like that. That, that sounds dumb.
Yeah.
Well, I think a good example of that though where regulation has failed is like PC I,
right, we have this regulation for the payment card industry
and clearly
it's not working like the Home Depot breach, the Equifax breach.
Like we're talking about breaches now with over 10 million people
-- or in some cases like over 100
-- million.
I would argue PC I is doing exactly what it's supposed to do.
PC. I isn't to protect us. PC, I is to protect Mastercard and Visa
and, and they seem to be doing ok.
This is, yeah, hard to argue with that.
-- It's
-- completely correct. PC. I isn't for us PC, I isn't for the merchants. PC.
I is for Mastercard and Visa.
No, like straight up, it's,
that's a good point
and,
and it is working very nicely for them and, and again,
they have an incentive to protect themselves.
They have no incentive to protect us and they have no incentive to protect merchants
and that's just the way it is.
-- Yeah.
-- No, I, I often because I was listening to the radio and they were talking about
making changes in sort of in culture,
uh specifically they were talking about head trauma in hockey, right.
That's a big thing here in Canada. Hockey. Right.
Like, right now we're aware of how bad it is with football turns out, obviously,
hockey has a problem too with concussions.
And they were, they were talking about how,
uh you essentially have two things, you have awareness and then you have, you know,
policy and decisions being made around that awareness
And quite often people are like, oh, we have awareness but
it's, you know, not working. So let's have more awareness, right?
We'll we'll have more awareness and that'll, you know, fix it sometimes.
That's true, right?
Because you only have a little awareness and then you get
more awareness and then people actually take notice and you know,
make change in social policy or tax policy or whatever.
You know, the essentially the government can craft any number of policies to
affect social change, right?
But until they do that, you know, clearly,
it's probably not going to change a whole lot,
right?
And they were talking about how like with this concussion thing, I mean,
clearly we have awareness like we know about this
and yet the politicians haven't done anything. So like, what do we do?
Do we do more awareness?
Well, you know, it's like, like the best example would be smoking.
Come on, folks, we clearly know smoking is not good for you.
-- Maybe more education will help.
-- There's limited things that help.
I mean, they,
they increase taxes in some cases and that
does seem to make somewhat of a difference.
But let's face it, the only true solution would be to
just outright ban tobacco.
And
I don't know if anyone would ever do that.
Well, it's funny because here in Canada,
I know in the States a lot of the tobacco companies are starting to
not so much divest themselves from tobacco,
but they are starting to essentially plan for a tobacco list future.
And for example, moving to things like vaping or cannabis.
Yeah. Yeah. II I suspect it's, it's going to happen.
It reminds me of, you know, the fossil fuel industry, it's,
it's the smart parts of the fossil fuel industry are already going like, yeah, no,
this like the golden era fossil fuel is over.
Let's, you know, what's next and you know, renewables and whatnot.
Yeah.
It's kind of like the,
there's a quote I heard once I really like that says
the stone age didn't end because we ran out of stone,
right? Just like the oil age isn't going to end because we run out of oil.
Which is funny because when I was a kid,
all anyone talked about was we were going to run out of oil and it's like,
uh guess guess what didn't happen?
Somebody gave me a good example of that.
OK, I give you a bucket of paint and I tell you to paint a wall. And what happens? You
paint the wall and what happens if I don't give you enough
oil in the can or enough paint in the can to,
to paint the wall?
Right? You run out. Yes. But there's still a bit of paint in the can,
right. So you get out a paintbrush and you kind of scoop it from the bottom.
The reality is like a paint can, is,
is you end up spending more and more effort to recover less and less.
And that's the problem with oil. It's not that it's going to run out completely.
It's just that at some point,
you know,
recovery of that oil is going to become so
expensive because we'll have grabbed all the easy oil.
You know, we'll have done the tar sands, we'll have done the shale oil.
-- I don't know what comes after
-- that
solar power,
you know. So, I mean, that's the thing, right.
We, it's not that we're going to run out of oil.
It's just that it's going to become incredibly expensive to produce
until somebody invents some bacteria that does it
-- for damn near free
-- for what it's worth.
I have a suspicion, this is how a security is going to evolve is
what we do today is clearly broken
and I don't see us fixing what we do today that I have a suspicion, new,
new technology and procedures and just everything is going to evolve.
I mean, I'll use cloud as one of my favorite examples.
If you're using a public cloud, it changes a lot of your security problems.
I, I won't say it makes it better necessarily. I think it just changes them around.
Oh, it does make it better. Um,
like I'm, I'm, I'm dealing with some, uh, GD GDPR compliance
and honestly a lot of it,
you know, things like physical security. Yeah. No. Amazon.
-- That's, that's true. Actually all the physical security goes away.
-- Yes.
Right.
There's like a lot of things where it's just like, not my problem,
like data is encrypted.
So all that,
you know, like how do you decommission machines? Uh we don't
click,
we click, delete,
you know, things like that, you know, so, and,
and it basically then boils down to what's our internal policies and training and,
you know, do we track where the data lives and kind of, you know,
make sure it doesn't get all
woodle. But
like, honestly for a lot of the really sensitive data,
the answer is extremely simple for us sales force.
That's it. That's my answer,
you know, and it's,
and sales force obviously has a rather
significant incentive, shall we say
to make sure they do, you know GDPR correctly?
That is true.
And, and they, they've actually been working on it for quite some time.
I read some of their documents about GDPR and they're definitely,
they're ahead of the curve. I'm comfortable in saying
-- and, and that's, well, see, here's
-- the beauty, right? It's,
that's one of those things that,
where security then actually becomes a competitive advantage.
That sounds like crazy talk.
I know.
You know,
and that's one of the things like that's one of the things I love about Red Hat.
Right is, is
we've gotten really good at fixing security flaws. Like,
you know,
like I remember back in the day not Red Hat, but I remember some vendors
they would take literally years to fix really bad
security flaws like flaws that were publicly known.
There's still people who do that man, look at, look at project zero with their 90 day
limit
on security issues. And, and
when you read some of these advisories,
like they hit the 90 days more often than I think they should have to.
But there's places that just struggle with this stuff even today.
Well, the good news is like the, you know,
at least the operating system vendors like Apple Microsoft,
all the Linux vendors have generally got their stuff together to
a degree that like 20 years ago would have been magic.
Yeah, definitely. And, and I,
so actually you,
you're kind of proving my point to me about kind of evolving security is
a significant amount of what most people do today is in a browser
and the browser manufacturers do a great job of keeping things updated.
So now we've kind of pushed the security off of my machine
onto
the, the service I happen to be using, right?
And some services are better than others.
And so my ability to pick and choose and understand I think is,
is significantly better.
I mean, my favorite example, like the, the, the horse I love to beat is flash player
because its track record is abysmal.
And I remember when like you had to have it,
you didn't have a choice and keeping that sucker updated was basically your job,
right?
And these days, like, I don't,
oh my goodness,
I installed Java the other day and it asked me to enable it in Chrome.
And I was like, nope,
definitely not.
And
yeah, I mean, that's another great example, right of,
of if you're just using a browser, these guys have an incentive for security and we,
we've moved the security
onus off of the user and now it's been pushed into some of the services.
And I think that's,
that's the natural evolution of solving a lot of these problems, I think.
Well, the reality is you have to have
secure defaults and not just, I mean, configuration defaults but like secure,
reasonably secure code, things like
uh Mozilla just uh in Firefox changing the refer,
I think it was the refer headers or whatever
to strip the path or something for third party sites so that there's less
data leakage.
You know, like I know you were at ebay, I don't know what you were looking at at Ebay,
right. You know, things like that.
And
because I mean, the number of people I see that like for example, you know,
use the uh the browser extension,
no script which completely blocks javascript and then you selectively enable
the entire
web.
-- They're basically also the people who wrap, you know, their cars in
-- tinfoil,
what would wrapping your car in tinfoil?
Like it's already metal.
I don't know that
I,
you know, I used to run no script and I became
annoyed with the pain and suffering of doing so.
But it's also something I realized the other day
is I haven't used no script in several years.
And I have had literally zero incidents
because I didn't have no script.
And I find things like my password manager and two factor off
are far more useful to me than no script.
Well, I think part of it honestly is 99% of what I want from. No script.
I, yeah. Oh
my goodness. I,
so I, I got a new computer for my kids to play games on
and obviously I turn it on and I opened up the web browser
and the first site I go to, I'm like, what is wrong with the internet?
And then I thought, oh, I don't have, I don't have you block origins.
So
that was like the next thing I did and then the world was good again.
Yeah,
I actually saw an ad the other day for something I actually was
interested in but then I clicked it and it took me to,
-- like, some surveys,
-- of course it did.
So, it was like, I,
I find if I do see an ad for something, I often just go to Amazon and type it in
because clicking on ads is, is ridiculous.
And you always end up on some dodgy website.
Yeah. So, speaking of things not being what they appear to be
-- face swapping.
-- Oh my goodness, there's so many crazy stories,
right? So
this I love because
I mean, traditionally you could, you know,
somebody with good Photoshop skills could easily move, you know,
one person's head to another person's body or whatever, right?
Except now of course, computers being good at stuff and
people writing better and better software,
a guy did an open source implementation that basically lets you
face swap for video
and like you basically just give it the image and you're like, you know,
go ahead and like make this actor look like this other person or whatever, right?
And you know,
people are freaking out and the best part about the article was that they were like,
and all copies of the video have been removed from the internet and
it's like, wait what? That's, that's really not how the internet works.
But this, you know, this software was released as open source and,
and people are again kind of like autos spit, they're kind of freaking out because
this has actually been possible for a long time. It's just, you know, not been
easily done, right. It, it would be quite costly and expensive.
But I mean, the fact that like Gollum, you know,
they didn't hire some guy that looked like Gollum, you know,
some dude wearing a green suit with like little black and white
-- guy
-- who did the
Andy Circus.
He was also King Kong and he's been like,
he's making a name for himself as being like a character actor where they, yeah,
they put him in like the goofy suit and he actually, he did the voice of G
as well. I don't think he did the voice of King Kong.
OK. Well, because I've seen some really terrible CG I capture
stuff where it's like whoever, you know,
the actor doing the motion capture was clearly like
stuck in a green room and they're like,
pretend there's an apple or you know, whatever, right?
And the guy clearly wasn't getting it.
Well, that's even assuming they had motion capture for summer. I mean,
there's some things you watch and it's like,
clearly they did not use motion capture for this.
The other thing to remember too is we have things like, you know,
real time voice manipulation and there was that
um oh I have to find that,
but basically somebody wrote some software again that given, you know, a small
uh relatively small example of you speaking could
then generate your voice for all things.
Sweet.
That sounds great.
And so this introduces a whole bunch of things like,
well, you know, this person phoning me has the right voice. But are they really that
-- humans are quite good at voice detection and recognition? You know,
-- we think we are.
Yeah,
this is, I mean,
this is a topic we should probably discuss online
and really in any sort of media
you can't really trust what you see anymore.
And this is like a new problem for humanity because we've,
-- we've been able to rely on things we hear and things we see as being real
-- pictures
or it didn't happen.
Yes,
like straight up pictures are
we're releasing the video
-- and, oh, ok, that's what happened.
-- Exactly. That's exactly right.
And so now the chance and of course there's people who say, oh, but you can,
you can detect,
you know, when someone modifies a photo or someone modifies a video and no,
we can detect it today maybe.
But the day will come when we can't.
I think it,
it really seems a lot like doping in the Olympics
where now the strategy is they hang on to the,
uh, athletes urine for several years or something.
So that later on when they invent better tests, they can retest the urine and,
you know, strip them of their medals post
Olympics or whatever.
Um, but yeah, I mean that it's, you know,
it's that cat and mouse game where the Attackers will come up with something new and,
you know,
uh we may not even know it's a thing and for months or years and then we figure it out,
write some detection for it and it's like, oh, ok, you know, this was fake,
this was fake.
Those Nixon tapes that came out, turns out they were fake
or whatever, you know, the missing Nixon tapes. I mean, I'm sure
somebody's going to generate those things.
They've tried, man, they've tried.
It's, it's gonna be crazy to think about.
At some point.
There will be probably we'll say detection. A I just because that's a fun name
and, and they're going to point to that many things from the past because now we,
we keep everything forever and nothing ever goes away
and it's going to be amazing to say, you know, oh this, this thing here, this was fake
and,
and what happens when it was 20 years ago
and it was like some world changing event and,
and all of a sudden now we can say that wasn't real.
Like that's crazy.
Well, we've had things like that happen, you know, where it turns out that this was a,
you know, like a
government sponsored event versus, you know, it was terrorists or, you know,
whatever.
There's been all sorts of crazy things like
the Tuskegee syphilis experiments, right?
Like you read that and it's like that can't be real like,
seriously.
But
I hear you, man,
those crazy conspiracy theorists.
Oh, the CIA is importing cocaine to the US, to blah, blah, blah.
Well, oh, that actually happened like
it
is, I don't know, man. I mean, this is one of the things I think about is
in this, this falls in line with security where
humans and was it, is it Schneider who said human,
the human threat model is like sub Saharan Africa
and basically anything that,
that doesn't fall in line with that we struggle to deal with.
And like, this is totally one of those things like,
is that a lion?
I
don't know. Is it good? Is it bad?
What should I do in this?
And like, I always think about this in the context of phishing emails,
you can't teach people to recognize a phishing email, like,
unless it looks like a lion and is hiding in the, in the weeds, they don't know,
I don't know what the answer is.
But, um, I think part of it will be maybe increased transparency, you know,
for example, kind of that, um,
you know, where did this
come from? Where did this video come from?
You know, here's the guy that claims to have taken it, you know,
he's available for interview or whatever, you know.
Yeah, maybe, I mean,
that's sort of supporting evidence, you know, like the same way journalists do it,
right?
Like journalists will use, you know, quote unquote anonymous sources
but they'll verify it. Hopefully, you know, if they're doing their job. Right.
And, you know, well, you've heard those statements where it's like,
it's an anonymous source but, like, we've got, like, 17 of them.
Like, we're, we're reasonably certain,
either this is true or it's like such a gigantic campaign to fool us.
We can't tell the difference,
-- you know.
-- But there, there are gigantic campaigns to fool us now.
I mean, thanks to things like Twitter Bots, you can totally do that
again. Like humans,
-- humans are incapable of.
-- Well, that's why you actually meet the human in person.
Right? There was, do you, we should link to this.
There was a vice news or, or sorry, the Washington Post. Remember
they, they, the some person was trying to troll them with a fake news story.
And so they turned it into an article
about this company that actually that's what they do
wild man, right?
And anyways, they actually like interviewed this like they, they, you know,
oh yeah,
we'll meet with you in a coffee shop and then they followed her back to her office.
Yeah, here's a hint.
If you're like pretending to be somebody else don't go
back to your office where you actually do work.
And um anyways, it was,
it was a fascinating article about how the Washington Post is basically like, yeah,
somebody tried to fool us and like, well, here's like
what?
That's crazy.
Uh These are, these are rough problems. I'm not gonna lie. I don't,
I, I don't know how we're going to fix it and, and I guess this is part of the,
the great challenge in front of us.
-- Now,
-- the beauty is,
some people have already had this problem and already fixed it like journalists,
right?
People come to journalists all the time with fake stories or
stories that they want to put a certain spin on.
You know, and, and they have a process to deal with that.
My argument there is a journalist is a profession and so they have
certain standards and expectations where it's like
my grandma looking at things on youtube
is very different.
And so I, I don't know, man, this is going to be interesting.
-- Well,
-- even youtube is starting to, um
uh for example,
they now have a policy where they're labeling
government sponsored content that they know of.
Yeah.
And well, I mean, that's what I mean by part of the part of what will help here is,
is that
where did this come from? Like,
you know, for example, if you with a lot of things, you know,
who sponsored this message?
Oh, ok. I see what they're saying now, you know?
Sure,
sure.
Uh
I don't know, man, I don't know.
-- So
-- I, because we can't tell the fakes from the reals at some point, it is just,
-- it's
-- too good. We're gonna, we're gonna find out, I guess so.
All right, man, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
If you want any of the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com.
You can use the Pound Os S Podcast,
Twitter hashtag to get a hold of us and you can find a link there
to our Facebook group which you are welcome to join and harass us on.
-- So, yeah, if nothing else, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You
-- folks.