Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
Hello, Kurt and I am very excited. We have a repeat guest today.
We have Liz Rice, who is the VP of open source engineering and Aqua Security.
-- Say hello, Liz. Hello,
-- Liz. That's not what you meant, is it?
That's perfect. I love it. I love it. And
you are here today because you wrote another book, which is awesome.
It's called Container Security.
Why don't you tell us a little bit about what you've done?
Yeah.
So I suppose for a few years now,
I've been doing quite a lot of presentations about how
containers work and how to secure containers and,
and various things that you can do to compromise containers.
And I wanted to
take the opportunity to sort of dive into that material a
bit more deeply which you can do in a book.
So
it's called Container security. It's really
a lot about how things work under the covers so that you
can think about security more than it is a sort of guideline.
It's, you know, it's not just like a
list of things you should do. I want to try and get people to understand
what it is that, you know, if they take a certain action or they use a particular tool,
what it actually means for their containers.
Sure.
Now I will put a link in the show notes to the book.
Aqua security has graciously made it available as a download for free. Right.
Absolutely. Yeah.
-- Yeah. Just the price of your contact details. But yes, it's,
-- it's true. Only
free. Now. I want to start with. This
is an o'reilly book and naturally if it's an o'reilly book,
it has an animal on the front and yours is the armored catfish.
I'm curious why that. And, and how does this process even work?
Because I, I love the animals and I'm always curious,
how did you get to where it is?
So, as an author, you basically don't get any choice in it.
They, um, they go through this huge process. It's really interesting.
They source these, I guess Victorian era
plates
and they have artists that convert that into the form
that they use on the front of the book.
They've just started colorizing them as well and they're all unique.
You know, they never reuse a plate again.
And I think they, you know, find, you know, maybe they, they,
they find a new book that's, well, not a new book, an old book,
a new to them book that has a series of plates that they can use.
And you know, people are constantly coming up and going, hey,
I want a panda or whatever.
And
lovely though, that would be, they don't necessarily have,
did pandas exist in Victorian Times,
-- I'm pretty sure.
-- So actually I'll dig up some pictures as well.
What you just reminded me of is I know that for example, elephants there would,
people would draw pictures of elephants back in those days, never having seen one.
They just would read a description of them.
And so some of these pictures are absolutely hilarious. But wow, that's wild.
They really are. And,
and they would draw sketches and like somebody would see somebody else's sketch,
you know, there would just be,
you know, one.
But you know, if I tried to draw an elephant,
it might not look very much like an elephant.
Then if you copied my elephant, you would end up with, you know,
an anti to at best or something.
And uh yeah,
I have a suspicion. Our, our drawing skills are similar. K
I was meaning more based on my drawing skills, but
I'm,
I'm not impressive. Wow, that's well, so, so you had no say in this animal.
And so OK, I guess why armored catfish then? How did you get to that?
-- So
-- they said we have picked an armored catfish for you.
And I thought actually that's great.
-- It is, it's a cool animal because
-- it's really, you know, relevant.
It's armored it's secure. So I was pretty happy with that and I knew
from previous discussions with, with the o'reilly folks really,
you don't get to choose.
So I, I embraced my armor catfish and I am actually really happy with it.
No, I, I agree. It's a cool,
ok. I read this book. I finished it up a couple of days ago and
I, I want to give you just my, my general thoughts here because I think it's,
it's worth reading.
I think regardless of who you are,
maybe in your container journey and I felt like you split it
nicely where the beginning,
but I would say the first half to three quarters of the book,
you lay the foundation of what container security is.
And I think that's hugely important
because I feel like as security people,
we take a lot of that information for granted.
Thank you very much. Yeah, I, I think that's,
that's very true. I think a lot of security.
It sometimes revolves around checklists or instructions or best practices
that may be completely correct or maybe for
a particular environment aren't necessarily so applicable.
And if people really understood what they're doing
with those checklists or those guidelines or,
or whatever, then they can make their own decisions about what's
applicable and what isn't. So.
Yeah, II,
I also think it's just more interesting if you really understand what's happening,
that's kind of more fun.
Well, the thing I'm noticing
is how do. I put this nicely.
A lot of security people try to enforce the rules because those are the rules rather
than enforcing the rules because they understand the
why and why those rules are applicable.
Absolutely.
And so, yeah, your book covering sort of some of the why and the under the hood stuff.
Yeah, I mean, it matters because I've seen people where, you know,
they do containers in a certain way where it's like, yeah,
we just don't care about this aspect of container security because
it just doesn't matter for us because we engineered this other thing
or it just doesn't matter or whatever.
Yeah. And I've seen security people freak out and be like, you can't do it that one.
It's like sometimes it's OK to cross the road without looking both ways
when you're in the middle of a desert or whatever bad example.
But this is the metaphor for things like, you know, running a container as route,
which is generally speaking a very bad idea.
But some listeners will be, you know,
they will have a use case where they have to run as
route or maybe they even have to run as privileged and ok,
those use cases exist.
That's actually one of my favorite examples because like Google, for example,
very simply went cool, you can do whatever you want container,
we're just going to wrap it in its own VM boom done.
And, and so what I love is you know,
every time there were these major container escapes.
Google is kind of like, yeah, we,
we don't care because you're stuck in your little VM anyways.
Yeah. So, so they use G
visor?
I'm,
I'm pausing on that because I don't know for an
absolute fact that they use G visor for all containers,
but that's their technology for providing that extra kind of sandbox
VM, like environment for a container.
I'm going to keep us from rattling here as much as possible.
It's a problem. We have
the,
the first thing I thought of those as well. And this is, I, I guess
you do a lot of work with Kubernetes and this
book doesn't have a lot of kubernetes in it.
And I'm curious,
was that deliberate or is that just something that sort
of shook out once you started working on this?
It was really about trying to keep the project of writing the book manageable.
Um So I previously written uh o'reilly Guide to um
Cerne security with Michael Halasz
and that's, that's a relatively short, it doesn't go into so much depth, but
I knew I wanted to go into a lot of detail and a lot
of depth and I would still be writing if I was trying to cover
C as well.
So, yeah, it was more about sort of scoping what I thought I could cover, you know,
it's the first real
sort of proper book that I've written that you know,
you can buy on Amazon and that I'd written by myself.
So I didn't want to go completely war and peace with it.
That's fair. That's what was the big one? It was the Send Mill book. Right.
You could be the person to death with back in the day.
But it was,
it was like 1000 pages long
and it was a perfect example because they covered all the M four syntax and M four.
It's like its own world.
-- Right.
And plus all this, you know, technology is changing very fast and i
it was already a concern to me that by the time it, you know, once,
once I'd finished it, that it would still be relevant and up to date.
And I don't think anything has dramatically changed too much yet,
but bigger the book,
the more the chance of something that will really seem quite dated very quickly.
That's a fair point actually because containers are evolving.
I mean, it, it's less rapid than it used to be,
but I remember probably five years ago it was,
it was bananas, how much would change with every single release of, you know,
be a docker itself or one of the container runtime or the the standards,
whatever it was nuts,
I think coming up, we will see
move to rootless containers, which will be great from a security perspective.
Um You know, so I talked about that in the book,
I guarantee there's listeners who don't know what a rootless container is.
So educate us,
imagine that you are the administrator of shared
computers at a university is a great example.
And students want to run containers on your university machines
and
you don't want to give them
privileges to run Docker because you basically have to be rude to run Docker.
And so you are basically saying, no, I'm,
I'm I don't trust you to run Docker because that's the equivalent of giving you
root access on this shared machine.
So rootless containers basically
make it such that you can run a container without needing
uh root privileges
and therefore anybody, any user can be
permitted to, to do that.
So it makes it more secure from the point of
view of just who do you allow to run containers.
But also once you then start a container, you're not root by default on the inside.
So win,
-- win.
-- You know what this actually really reminds me of is this is going back 20 years.
But when the web started and CG I bin was the thing, you know,
when a user wanted to run AC G I bin, it was kind of like, well poop.
Now you control the web server, right?
And then, you know PHP and my
Q all came along and made it a lot easier to, well,
not basically give users privileges over the web server and it took off.
And,
and this is kind of what I'm seeing here is, yeah, I mean,
I'm cool with whatever the Devs do on their own machines.
Like they can have root containers on their Dev machines. Sure.
But, yeah, in production. No, we just can't have that. Absolutely.
And I think that's one of the things that's been holding back,
container adoption for a lot of people is I can't give all my devs
access to all of production. You know, the auditors are going to scream at me
-- if they
-- know,
I think we're seeing lots of other kind
of ways of keeping production machines at arm's length
in particular. I'm thinking of get
ups essentially saying that human beings don't really get to
run containers at all in production. They're committing
code changes.
Some of those code changes are the specification of what you want,
the state of your production cluster to be and automation
takes it from, get into reality.
-- Well, and
-- I think that's part of the maturity piece here too is like seeing it go from,
you know, we, we, well, we still do a lot of handcrafted it unfortunately, but
more and more people are actually, you know,
building factories that produce the it that they want.
And of course, I think, you know,
containers are a major part of that of actually getting
those binaries to run and do the things they want.
Yeah, I think it's a big part of cloud native in general.
You know, if I think about the CNCF definition of cloud native, which is
about three paragraphs long and, and, you know, not something I've memorized,
but it definitely includes automation.
That's one of the kind of key principles
that in order to have things scale dynamically,
you need to be able to automate
basically everything and that includes security.
Well, and here's a thought because the other thing I keep coming to is is
unless you can properly measure things, how can you fix them in my experience,
measuring things that humans keep touching
versus measuring things that are automated.
And I think that's another big part
of the containers and container orchestration world,
right?
Is that automation piece and that actually measuring piece and knowing, well,
for example,
knowing whether these containers run with root or without root privileges,
right? Yes. Yes.
So the observable in all kinds of dimensions including things
like observing the state of security in your cluster,
which kind of
am I allowed to mention a new project that
we literally just released yesterday because that kind of segues
nicely into it. So uh it's called Starboard. And the idea is that
you have a variety of different security tools that are running in your
cinetis.
Well, either in your
knees cluster or running on artifacts related to what you're running.
So things like
scanning your container images or maybe
checking your nodes against CIS benchmarks.
Essentially the idea of Starboard is to say,
let's take all those reports pull them into
kubernetes, custom resource definition
and then make that information accessible over the
CS API so that security information is right there
next to all of the other information about resources
that are running in your cluster or or
the other states of your production workloads.
So bringing things like your vulnerability reports right
next to the pods that you're looking at.
Josh.
Would you like to talk about container
scanning and vulnerability reports for a bit?
Actually, I was, I
gave Liz a heads up to this before. So
we like Liz a lot and Liz works for Aqua Security
who actually I have a great deal of respect for.
And
I think a couple episodes ago we did quite a lot of complaining
about container scanners and I wrote a very long blog series about them
because it is, I guess what you're describing though is, is heavily related to this.
And so let me explain to you what I see
and I think
you can help clarify some of this.
So what,
what I think I'm seeing today in the universe is
there are lots of people who have lots of different
tools and I think there is often a lack of
understanding of what some of these tools really are.
And so like the easiest example is
I'll have someone
run, I'll, I'll pick on Aqua just because you're here, right? They'll run the
aqua container scanner that looks at all the
stuff in your container and it basically gives
you a report that says here are all the CV ES we found in your container.
And generally speaking, most of these findings are correct.
And I will give Aqua a big plus because
there are obviously different kinds of false positives.
But the one where like the stuff just isn't there and it's getting reported.
I rarely see that with Aqua which is cool because that's a
really hard problem and that's easiest of the hard problems to solve.
I see these people say, ok, this, you know, you need to fix all these problems. That's
that can't be done for a variety of reasons.
I think then they'll also show up with another report that says, oh,
your containers are violating these cis benchmarks.
We have so fix them all. It's like that's also not a reasonable request.
And I feel like what,
what you're describing here is a tool that can kind
of take all of this information in and give you,
I guess a reasonable view of the risk you have in your containers. Is that accurate?
-- Yes,
-- it is.
So I think first of all, what we were saying earlier about understanding what
the security issues really mean, like what are the implications of these,
these different things? What does it mean if an audit says,
I don't know that your note is not configured correctly? Well, how serious is that?
What does that really mean? Yeah, exactly.
And then also with Starboards being able to at least visualize,
I don't know if you've come across a thing called,
which is an open source dashboard for
CS. And so, you know, you can click on your different deployments.
And with Starboard, we've got
tan plugins.
So you can just see, oh, right next to your or as part of your display of the workload,
you can see.
Oh, this workload has three critical vulnerabilities and try to at least
surface that information as part of that kind of holistic view of
what's important about this workload.
Maybe critical vulnerabilities might be an important thing. Sure. Sure, sure.
But I guess then there's, there's further things you might want to be able to do,
for example, in a way you can do things like acknowledge certain reports to say,
well, yeah, I know about that, but it's,
you know, in this particular circumstance, I don't need to know about it anymore.
And that makes a lot of sense to me. I think
it is
partially an education problem and I think it's also a sign of the fact that
containers one and now we're trying to hammer these, these, you know,
square pegs into our round holes.
And I think in some cases that creates unique challenges for these teams,
I think one of the things it really creates is a huge scale issue.
You know, you're not just talking about however many machines you're talking about
all the containers running on all those machines and, and all of the, you know,
operating system dependencies and so on,
it demands new tooling because you can't look at these machines,
we can't look at each container individually.
That's actually a really good point.
And I think that some of the parody I see is where, for example,
if you have an operating system,
you might run a
vulnerability scanner on it and it's going to
say you're missing these four security updates from,
let's say Red Hat.
Right?
And then you run a container scanner on it and now you're looking at
way more stuff,
but they're different, right?
You can't treat them the same and, and that's kind of,
I think that's part of what I'm seeing here.
Yeah. And I think there is scope for better too
and better sort of. You get these sort of remediation
advisories that there's more that can be done to make, to automate that process,
I think.
All right,
we're on the precipice of me just complaining about
container scanners for longer than I want to.
So I, I want, I want to move on. I want to move on.
-- They have good sides as well.
-- Right. They do.
I look, I'm, I will be the first to admit that as much as I complain,
this is the future
and they, they, they get better,
they're constantly getting better and I have no doubt in
five years I'm going to look back and be like,
wow, I was just a grumpy, a hole there for a while, wasn't I?
And I, I cannot wait to be there and I have no doubt it is the answer to
this particular problem. But anyway, anyway, I, I want to move on.
There's,
there's a really cool thing that I have on the top
of my list to ask you about from your book.
It's in chapter six
and it's about the security of layers and the fact that people
think sometimes they're deleting stuff out of their containers and they don't.
And I really, so in fact,
it's funny because a friend just emailed me last night about this exact topic.
And I'm like that's hilarious.
But anyway, why don't you explain to us what that means?
-- Because this is like mind blowing, I think.
-- Yeah. So if you look at a Docker
image, for example, when you do Docker pull,
you can see all these different layers being pulled.
So you kind of know that it's coming in these different layers,
these different parts of the file system,
they're like diffs,
you know what you start with a base image and
then you kind of have diffs for for each separate layer
and one layer might include a file, another layer might remove that file.
But the file is still present in the image. You can
pull out that layer individually, you can unpack it.
It's just a, you know, compressed our file
and you can still find that file. So if that file is you know sensitive data,
you deleting it in a subsequent layer in your Docker file.
This is the other important part of it. Your docker file describes what is
contained in each of those layers.
Like every time you run a command inside a Docker file that creates a new layer.
So one of those commands is delete my sensitive password.
Well, the previous layer has that sensitive password, so
-- I can just extract that
-- stupid question.
Can you extract it from like when you're
logged in within the Docker container or do you
sort of need to be external to it and be able to look at the layers,
you need to be external to it and look at the layers.
Yeah. So once you're running inside the container, it's all been expanded into a
regular file system layout.
I'm not aware of a way I probably shouldn't say you can't, but I,
-- I don't believe that there is a way
-- you, you shouldn't be able to, we'll see.
But I mean, so the the danger here though is obviously if,
if you had a file in one of your layers called Liz's secret passwords and you
delete it in your Docker file and then you push that Docker file into Docker hub.
I can go in
-- and extract that file out of a layer even though you think you deleted it,
-- correct.
Which is
crazy
kind of I mean, I, I think so this, this actually harkens to,
I think it might be the episode right before this
we just released was where there are certain security problems
that we don't always even know about.
And then when people learn, oh yes, it was the last episode because it was like,
for example, your web browser can connect to local hosts with web sockets
and like ebay was using this
to and systems and now that we know it's like holy crap fix that.
And I feel like these darker layers are a similar problem
where most people just don't even know this is a thing.
-- Well,
-- it's,
it's one of those classic security things where it
unless you really explicitly go looking for it,
you're not going to see it.
And it is another thing that some scanners will find for you or at least they will,
they will look for things that look suspiciously like passwords or tokens
or keys or whatever that might be embedded in the layers of a
-- of a container image,
-- right?
Except now the question is how many container images on Docker hub
are full of secrets? And no one even knows.
-- It's
-- a good question.
I
have
a feeling
it's going to be not zero.
I have a feeling that people may have done some research to,
to sort of check out that kind of thing
related story.
We at Aqua our research team just released
a thing that they call dynamic threat analysis
and it takes a container image runs it live in a,
in a sandbox and observes its behavior and it's looking for things that look like
malware, like behavior patterns of, I don't know,
connecting to a Cryptocurrency pool or something.
We did
scan some images on Docker hub and then reported them as good citizens to, to the
well to the Docker security team to,
to let them know that they there were some images that we're not behaving well.
Oh Interesting.
So kind of like the Google Play store thing
where they scan the apps to look for shenanigans.
Yeah.
Yeah. And by running it so not just sort of static analysis but actually
-- dynamically checking the behavior,
-- which is pretty cool.
And I mean with containers obviously that's
trivial.
Sorry, I just because I was like part of me was going to say, well, you know,
for example, on github,
there's a variety of projects that scan github
repos
for like entropy strings look like passwords.
And I kept getting false reports because strings and emails.
But anyways, I just looked at Docker
Hub and there's just over 3.5 million public images now,
like I knew it was going to be a big number but 3.5 million.
That's nothing. How many node modules are there? The lots. Yeah, more than that.
It's definitely an amazingly large number.
-- Just
-- the effort to download all of these and run them all let alone actually,
you know, observe their behavior and qualify it as good, bad or indifferent.
I'm reasonably confident we didn't do all 3.5 million.
I think the lesson we can take from that as well though, is that
one of the things we're notorious for insecurity is our obsession with all or none.
And you don't.
I, I bet you of the,
the 3.9 million probably what a couple of 100,000 Macs are actually
full of like useful and good things that people are running.
-- So literally
-- 51 or darker
five
-- what?
-- 51? That's it?
362 are from verified publishers, which is shockingly low.
And then 163 official images,
which again is shockingly low because I just would assume that
everybody at some point now has their official Docker image.
All right,
these numbers feel questionable and we're not going to hash this out right now.
So,
yeah.
Well, I, I think what I'm seeing is, you know, we're,
we're not at a point where container security is what I would call good yet,
but we're also at the point where it's still rapidly evolving
and not just the security of it but the actual containery
bits of it. Like we never mentioned uni kernels and that's a whole other set of quasi
container issues.
-- Yeah,
-- there's all sorts of different uni kernels.
You can kind of see them as a sort of a sandbox like G visor like firecracker,
that kind of run time environment.
There've been loads of things to harden the container run time over the years.
You know, I think we're, we're finding
serious vulnerability.
I can't remember the last time there was a, you know,
proper regular container escape,
but they don't come up every five minutes for sure.
Yeah, it's been a while.
Vulnerabilities exist and are still found,
I think yesterday or the day before there were a couple of networking related
certis issues that patches were published for so upgrade Jo
-- Bettis,
-- it'll have been almost a week by the time this this comes out. So,
-- yes,
-- let's hope that's been done. No, I mean, that's, that's a good point. It's,
that's one of our challenges as well, right? Is if,
and, and I'll, I'll pick on,
you know,
container scanning here again is the fact that I could scan a container today
and then I could literally scan the same container in a week.
And my results could be quite different because it depends on
what the security issues are that were released between the two scans
for sure. And it's again a reason for automation, you know, you can't be doing that
manually across the whole production cluster all the time.
You know, you really want to be doing it automatically every day.
Yes.
OK.
So we are nearly out of time, but I wanted to kind of there,
there's one other chapter that I love in you
and you talk about secrets management in there.
And I just, I, I want you to briefly explain to us like,
what is the challenge of container secret management?
Because we just learned,
obviously don't put those things in your
container because they're in the layers now.
-- But what does that mean?
-- You have these, you know, secrets that you,
that your application code needs in order to do its job.
You know, like,
let's say it's a database password and there are a limited set of options,
how you could
feasibly get that password into the running container.
And some of those feasible options are really,
really bad ideas from a security perspective.
Like you could build the password into the container image.
And I did a talk, I guess probably a couple of years ago about
secrets management and I gave it maybe two or three times and the first time I gave it,
I thought, you know, I'll just mention in passing the fact that, you know,
it would be a really bad idea to have the
password built into the container image.
And as I said, it thinking nobody will actually be doing that, will they?
And I could see people like taking notes and I, you know, I can see, oh,
a penny has dropped, but that really, they sh they should probably check that.
They haven't got that password just sitting in plain text in a, in a Docker file.
So, you know, that's one thing to avoid.
But then if you, you want to get your secrets inside somehow,
you basically have the option
passing in as a file or as an environment variable and the file, you know,
you're mounting a volume and passing the file through that way.
Essentially,
you're looking for a way of keeping that secret encrypted
whenever it's in transit or at rest right up to
the point where you give it to the application and
then it can decrypt it and hold it in memory.
It's an incredibly hard problem for sure.
And OK, so we are functionally out of time for this chat. And I, I feel like
this is such a complex and nuanced topic. We could probably do 100 shows.
It never run out of content, Liz, I will let you give us the last word on this.
What, what is the thing you want everyone to know other than read your book,
which everyone should do.
I was going to say,
should I just plug my new book?
Yeah.
No, no, I mean, definitely, obviously we'll have a link to it in the show notes and,
and I would highly recommend everyone give it a look.
It's, it's not a super long book,
which is nice because some security books are very long and boring,
but this one definitely is not that.
-- And it's a nice book. I, I
-- enjoyed it. Thank you very much.
That's, that's really nice to hear. Yeah.
So hopefully people will go out and try that,
maybe
get in touch if you have questions and,
and things that you think I haven't covered enough yet
because I want to keep this material up to date.
We, we talked a bit before about, you know, how these things evolve.
And uh you know, II, I want to make sure that as things evolve that the,
the book also gets new additions so really interested to hear what people think.
Awesome. And I will put some links to how to contact Liz in the show notes.
So if you're interested in that, just hit up the show notes. So, all right, awesome.
I'm going to call it then. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, Liz.
Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open social security podcast.com for the
show notes I discussed and you can use the Pound
Oss podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
-- and Liz and Kurt have fantastic rest of your days. Thanks
-- everybody.
-- Thanks
-- very much for having me.
Marvelous. Thank you so much, Liz.
It has been a pleasure.
As always, you'll have to come back and see us next time you write your next book.
Will do. Wonderful. Thanks, everyone. Bye bye.