Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefert and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
-- So
-- we're going to talk about the Matrix today because we wanted to do that last week.
-- And then life
-- happened
and to be clear,
-- it's the uh the movies
-- 12 and three because it is quite
possible someone will find this after the fourth Matrix comes out,
which if it follows the current trajectory of the Matrix movies,
it's not going to be very good at all.
I would argue that the first movie was excellent.
The second movie was like, I don't know about this and the third one was like, wow,
that second movie sure was good.
So
yeah, I saw the trailer, I am not happy about this.
Uh Really, I, I'm indifferent.
I think I, I feel like the trailer gives me nothing to work with.
I feel like it's super formulaic and it's going to
be exactly kind of what people want and nothing,
-- I mean, interesting or challenging.
-- As long as it amuses me,
it's
like,
see, that's what I like about. The first movie is the first movie did
I think two things. Well, one day has some groundbreaking visual effects, right?
Bullet time. That was new. That was,
yeah,
I, I remember seeing that and I remember my brain just going. Huh?
Yeah. Like, how did they possibly do this? And then when you see how they did it with
like, what 200 cameras? It's like, this is ridiculous.
-- Yeah. And
-- it's like, oh, that's actually really simple and clever.
Like, in terms of like building a nuclear weapon is simple.
Like you just take a chunk of uranium and compress it quickly,
I don't even think.
No,
-- you just have to find 300
-- cameras and get the
timing right and get them in the right position and the
green
-- screen,
-- all that
stuff.
That's
easy. Now
it probably wasn't. But
yeah,
but uh so it, it had some groundbreaking vision,
special effects and what I love too is it's really clear that
they basically blew the budget halfway through the film,
right? So they have this mixture of really wow,
special effects followed by like just some good old fashioned Hong Kong Wire work.
The kung fu is really good in that
-- movie and
-- there's nothing and to be clear,
I love high quality Hong Kong Wire work.
I love those films with that, like just that real good physical comedy,
violence dance
thing going on, right? Like it's just, it's poetry in motion
with people, you know, they do those flying spins and it's just like, wow,
man, that, like, I'd be puking my guts out if you spun me that quickly in the air.
Right. Well,
this is, we've never trained for wire work.
-- I imagine if you had some training you could easily do it
-- and there's, you know,
the tricks like figure skaters do.
But anyways,
so, and then secondly, it told a very,
the first movie told a really interesting story.
Right?
Because it was kind of like a really nice sort of
kafkaesque. What if waking up is a bug in a room kind of thing? Right? But in reverse,
you know, the whole,
instead of going through the looking glass,
-- looking glass
-- just in case
I'm gonna, I'm gonna say this now and maybe I'll put it at the beginning, but
-- we're going to spoil the crap out of this movie. So if you've ever seen
-- the
Max, I
mean,
I'm just for the sake of
I, I just being a decent human.
Actually, I was listening to a Star Wars podcast the other day
-- and
-- dude, it's old enough to drink.
I agree.
I know there are people though who mentioned this at the beginning of
a Star Wars podcast if we're going to spoil it for you,
even though it came out in 1979.
-- Anyway. Anyway,
-- yeah, the Matrix came out in 99. Like
I know,
I know I actually did a lot of reading on
it and I rewatched a whole bunch of Matrix stuff
over the last week. It's been quite fun. It's the movie,
the first one holds up better than I, I expected it to.
-- Well,
-- because again, good story
and, and some very subtle touches like the whole the dojo scene with the hand wave,
right? Like that's become a meme that's become a cultural icon.
I mean, no, there's no way that's from The Matrix.
-- That's got to be from some other kung fu movie.
-- Probably,
-- I'm skeptical it's from The Matrix.
-- The
-- Matrix
-- made it popular
in, in modern day.
Sure. Sure. So anyway, we want to talk about the security of the matrix.
-- Not just like ramble on about random matrix stuff.
-- Ok. Now, quick question,
what is Cannon? Ok. Obviously the three movies are cannon, right?
I don't care
about
the,
what about the Pre Matrix? The cartoons
are
those cannon?
Do I care? No,
they're important if we're talking about the security
of the Matrix and those poor little.
So I don't remember those. I know I watched them but I couldn't recollect them.
Nor were they part of my research? So if you want to talk about them, that's great.
But I'm going to be a flopping fish.
Ok. Well, I'm going to say the Animatrix is canon because it was
part of the back story.
I'm fine with that.
I'm fine calling the video games can actually the
video games are really good when they came out.
-- I hope they make some new ones, you know,
-- did they ever come up with a VR one?
Because that would be interesting.
Uh, not that I know of. I remember playing it on, like the Playstation or something.
It's been a long time
anyway.
Ok.
So
here's where I want to start talking about the security of the matrix
is number one,
I think anyone who
came into,
into being in the nineties
and wanted to consider themselves a hacker.
This was one of the movies you watched
and it definitely was something you kept in mind at all times
because hypervisor security matters
not for that reason because it was cool. It looked cool and there was hacking in it,
right.
This is, it's like the movie hackers,
which we should talk about someday too just because it's so much fun and epic.
I do love that film.
-- Like
-- that was another one you watched. It, it was part of who you were at the time
and it, it, like I remember watching them actually so fun fact
when I went to see The Matrix in the theater,
I literally had no idea because I
was purposely avoiding everything about the Matrix.
I could at the time
-- I sat in the seat with no clue what was going to happen. It was amazing.
-- No, it's,
uh
I mean, there's actually n map made it into the films. Remember in the second or third
one,
we'll get to that. Um Well, they used an ssh exploit. But
we'll get to that. We'll get to. That doesn't matter.
All right. So, anyway, anyway,
first of all the cultural aspect,
but then I think the, the secondary part of this
is,
I think it,
it's very
nineties in a lot of ways where, for example, there's an obsession with the hard line
because you watch it now and you think, I don't get it.
But in the nineties there were cell phones and
there were landlines and landlines were seen as like
the, the old trusty landline. This will never let me down.
Whereas your cell phone was like, maybe it'll work, maybe it won't, we don't know,
cell phones were crazy unreliable 20 years ago compared to now.
Right. Like, I remember,
like, now it's funny because there's like a,
there's about a 34 mile long dead spot on the way to my parents' cabin in a valley
and it's always just shocking because I'm driving and I'm like, oh, I,
I better not crash because I will die out here alone.
Right. Because I'm so used to having cell coverage everywhere I go.
Right. It's just a given
until you don't have it.
And then it's kind of like,
remember this summer I went to that place in or not this summer.
Sorry.
Yeah, it was in June.
I went to that place in BC that had no cell
phone or internet coverage and I was kind of like her.
Right. Right.
No, I know it's like,
it's like no electricity now where I feel like
no electricity and no internet are functionally the same.
I can, I can bring candles. I cannot bring internet with me.
Right. If there's no electricity, you also have no internet. That's a double whammy
man.
At least my refrigerator works
when I have electricity.
That's nice.
So you get one of those fancy fridges that will die.
And that's another show why the ads, whoever is dying is a problem.
I'm never getting one of those anyway. Ok. Matrix. Talking about the Matrix
and
now we're talking about refrigerators
anyway. Anyway. Ok.
So I've got a bunch of notes that I
scribbled down and there's a handful of interesting events.
But since you already mentioned it,
we should bring up the end map and SSH Exploit, which is,
it's at the very end of the second movie,
I'll let you explain it because you brought it up first.
Uh, so long story short, they need to,
uh, break into a building with a floor where no elevator goes
-- and this floor is full of doors or whatever.
-- Stop all the
metaphorical crap. They need to shut off the power.
-- Yeah,
-- they need to shut off the power to shut off the security system.
It's classic diehard trope.
It's
very heist movie. Right. Absolutely.
And so, uh Trinity basically breaks into the power company
and
hacks the power company to shut down the power grid.
But what's cool is on the screen,
you see the end map, the end map command literally being run.
And you see there is an SSH exploit they used,
that was a real SSH exploit that had been fixed.
I mean, many years prior to the movie. But you get the idea which,
yeah, because the power company would never
ever have out of date software.
-- So
-- here's what's funny, you just said that and you just made me realize
when I watched that,
I was like,
there's no way anyone would be running software this out
of date because it was very out of date.
Right?
And I was like, there's no way a power company would be online.
And now in 2021 I'm like, both of those things are completely reasonable to accept.
-- Not just
-- reasonable, man. There, we have documented instances of this.
-- We do now we did it in 1999. Well, it was probably, what, 2000, 2000 one,
-- right?
People kept that stuff quiet back in the day. They weren't posting, it's
a or whatever,
maybe whatever. I, I, we would have heard if someone hacked a power plant, I
-- shut up the power.
-- True. But I, but on the flip side,
I,
I know a lot of anecdotal stories where stuff was
swept under the rug and put out as like,
oh, you know, uh, unanticipated maintenance event or whatever.
Right.
Whatever, whatever we're going on. I don't care. I don't care. All right.
So that was really cool because that's a real actual thing.
And then they, of course, went on Matrix E and they
had a dude make a key and open the door, which I think all of the,
the bizarre symbolism they use.
The second one was really,
really heavy in the symbolism and the third one to a degree as well
was
this is one of those things that I looked at at the time and I feel like it,
it reminded me a lot of, like, Neuromancer, for example,
where it was just one of those things that
felt surreal. I think when I, I experienced it in the nineties. But now
I think using these,
I, I guess
I, I don't even know the right word for it,
but like these symbols of the virtual to the
real seems like something more expected and practical now.
Whereas in the nineties it felt strangely science fiction.
Well, here's a good example,
this whole concept of having sort of God in your ear saying, you know, walk left,
turn right, go down the stairs.
Well, yeah, I mean, we have security cameras everywhere. We have cell phones. It,
that's a thing that, you know, in reality
that happens.
Right. Like,
it's not a matter of just blindly trusting your luck and
hoping the security guard isn't where you want them to be.
It's like, no, no, no security guards on the fourth floor. Go now.
Right.
Because we can see them on the security camera, how,
because we hacked this camera system,
you know, again, in the nineties, that was a ridiculous notion.
Well,
and now we have the NDA A act which explicitly bans Chinese security cameras on us.
Government property.
I had to read the
doesn't matter, but you keep going. We got a lot of crap to cover here.
One thing I also love is I'm just,
I pulled up a screenshot of Trinity hacking and it's like straight up the old
and when I say Mac O si don't mean like the Mac Os, you and I,
and everybody else thinks of,
I'm talking about the Mac Os on like the old timey boxes with the, you know,
the two boxes and the, the horizontal lines,
that terminal interface, like it is
-- old, tiny, old, it was
-- a nineties yo,
well, that interface stuff was probably from the early nineties because, you know,
it's not like movies,
they still use all that weird kind of old it stuff to,
you know, show
like my favorite is Office Space. We'll talk about that movie someday.
-- I don't think that's that good of a
-- movie.
Fractions of a penny, just like Superman,
whatever, whatever. All right.
So anyway, anyway, OK, so we got covered the hard line.
Now, the, the other thing that I think was really interesting
was
the notion of hacking
the way they portray it because I think it's kind of two pieces to this.
There's the actual, like, hacking of computers, like, we might think about it.
And I remember,
well, not remember.
I literally just watched this when Neo's computer gets hacked by Trinity.
And it's just like, text and it's like, knock,
knock Neo and there's a knock at the door.
Right.
Which
back then it was like, that's, that's not reasonable.
There's no way you could do that.
And now you think about it and like back during someone's computer
-- totally reasonable
-- and
they have a web camera, I mean, there's,
they didn't have a webcam back then.
I mean, we'll assume they had weird matrix knowledge or something. But
I mean, like the Pegasus spyware, right? Like this stuff is everywhere now.
But back in the nineties,
the idea of infecting someone's computer to the point you could like,
print arbitrary text to them
was
I think I viewed that as sensational and ridiculous.
And now it's like, yeah, that's fair. That's,
which is funny
because
once you have command execution on the computer especially,
well, anything before 2000 running a Microsoft product was,
-- you know, there was no concept of user, an admin,
-- really
whatever.
I'm sure Neo ran Linux.
Let's not pretend
it was text based.
I thought it was always, I just assumed it was like ad Os box or something,
-- whatever
-- it was,
we're going to say it was Linux because he was
cool and cool people ran Linux in the nineties.
-- They still do mind you. But that's not, I don't
-- know that cool is the word I would use.
-- But sure, yeah,
-- I'm comfortable using that word.
So, anyway, but then there's also the hacking aspect,
which I think is very amusing of they, they call it,
like bending the rules where they can jump
really high and move really fast and whatever.
And,
and this one I always struggled with, I think a little bit where
this is how Attackers do it on systems. Like, oh,
you'll let me enter the password, password. Ok.
What about password, full quote greater than blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Oh, look at that at
the table of your database,
right?
And that's, and that's been my experience. A lot of hacking is
ask politely
-- and then ask, you know, like a little nibble, a little nibble,
-- like a simulation
that has physics rules and they're violating what? What's straight? Wait. Ok.
So let me, let me rephrase this.
It's, it's obviously in a massive physics simulation that they've created, right?
And then
there's apparently rules that everyone has to follow.
And there's a handful of people who have the ability to bend the rules but be
quotes
and then,
but, but only certain things like why can they jump really high?
But they can't fly, you know what I mean?
-- Like, I don't know, he
-- does Superman later on.
-- Well, Neo does, but none of the other people can because
-- they don't believe enough.
Right.
Ok. But then that, like,
uh, oh,
I hate this
party. Right.
It's, this is like, ah,
well,
here's my take on it is think about a
modern system and how ridiculously complex it is.
And there's
like a web app and there's all these little fidgety places where you can do cross site
scripting or cross site request forgery or header injection
or prototype pollution or all these weird things.
And if you 0.10 hackers out that system,
are they going to come up with the same set of vulnerabilities?
No, absolutely not. They're all going to come up,
you know, with this wonderful 10 dimensional Venn diagram of like Europe in
the middle of world war two, basically,
maybe, I mean, OK.
OK. May maybe, maybe I'll let this one go, but I always felt like that was
just a bizarre thing. And then there's agents who supposed it.
Although,
although we learn at the end that the agents are probably basically just pawns
in
a bigger story.
Well, they're part of the simulation of the second layer.
-- Yeah.
-- Right. Right.
And, and so whatever that's,
we'll,
we'll kind of ignore them a little bit because I
think agents from the storytelling perspective are obviously just a
plot point because there's tons of stuff they can and can't do.
They shouldn't be, you know what I mean?
-- It's
-- this massively complex system with multiple A is running around it.
And don't you think that, like
by definition, you have two A is running in a compute infrastructure.
Like logically one A I would try and murder the other A I to get
all the computer instance because that's what the other A I is going to do.
I mean, that's kind of the plot
you have all these competing A is that
are kind of struggling trying to find exploits,
trying to, you know, get more power, get less like whatever.
So I, I think it actually
having,
let me put it this way.
Remember when Sony sued itself,
right? Like
when you get a large organism, a human body is a perfect example, right?
We have an autonomic nervous system.
We have, we have an immune system, we have all sorts of stuff going on
and you can have autoimmune diseases. Like my favorite example of this is
OK, cool. I'm gonna go eat some tasty, delicious spicy food
and then eight hours later my body's like, no,
you know, they're like, nope that, that
not go well or I, I smell something and I start sneezing like why? Just why?
Because we're stupid bags of meat. This is a computer.
-- They could have gotten it right?
-- My appendix tried to murder me many years ago.
Why is,
why would a bunch of a is running around a computer system be
any different than an A I trying to murder the whole system accidentally?
I mean, that happens and that, that's the plot.
Ok. Ok. So I, I got another interesting
note I wrote down
is so in the very beginning of the very first movie,
the,
the main character Neo works at this big stuffy corporate programming job.
And in the nineties, I remember at this time, like,
that's what my first job felt like where it was, you had to dress nice.
You had to go into the office. There were business people in charge
and it was very stuffy and it was very followed the rules or else.
But there,
but there also wasn't like this vibrant start up culture
that we have now of like dress like a hobo.
-- No one cares.
-- Well, the
sort of culture was underground at that point.
Right? It was on the fringe.
It wasn't part of mainstream now start ups have gone
mainstream because if you want to be a billionaire,
you do a start up or you inherit it and most of us don't have inheriting it as an option.
I mean, look at like the, the freaking NSA or the dod,
like the hackers are allowed to wear whatever they want.
-- Everyone else has to wear suits.
-- A bunch of these places.
Roll back the rules on testing for cannabis.
Yeah, because they had to, because the war on drugs was won by the drugs.
I mean,
no, I know, I know.
I, I totally, although I don't think the FBI has done that yet,
-- but they're going to have to because there's no one to hire
-- tech stuff.
They were because,
I mean, I,
I remember even 20 years ago working at a place and I
was actually kind of curious because it was based on DC and
they actually did not have drug testing policies. And I was a Canadian.
I'm like, I'm used to that because
it's, well, up here you can really legally only test after an incident.
Right.
So somebody drives a forklift into a wall and then it's like, ok, go pee in this cup,
you can't pre-test legally, which is not to say it doesn't happen.
Now, it's actually quite a common thing. Now.
It's a thing but most places up here aren't union shops so tough.
But, um,
yeah, like the, the company straight up said, you know, we, we,
we consciously don't have a drug testing policy because we know, like,
-- yeah, we can't get rid of half of you. Right.
-- Right.
So, anyway, anyway, I, I found that interesting and it's, again,
this is one of those things that when you watch it the first time
it's just,
it doesn't register because it was just normal and now it's not normal at all.
It used to be normal that everybody smoked everywhere.
I mean, yeah, I know. Right.
Yeah.
Yeah, I remember playing with the, I remember one of my favorite things to do
on a 747 was to play with the ashtray.
I've never been on a plane with an ashtray. I'm sad to say.
-- But anyway, anyway, a long
-- time
ago,
so
there's so much to talk about
in so little time.
-- That
-- sweet, sweet nokia phone.
I know. Ok. Yeah. Yeah.
-- So the cell phones are, I think a great topic and so explain the phone they
-- use,
they use a nokia phone.
I forget which model it is. But it doesn't matter because it's a nokia phone.
It's a, it's a custom phone.
They, they made that phone just for the movie.
-- No, nokia phone, like slid down like that.
-- Ok. I was wondering about that,
but the point is it was a nokia phone.
So at some point during the heat death of the universe,
those phones will finally cease to exist.
Well, look in the nineties,
-- there were no smartphones.
-- I had a nokia, I had a nokia phone. It did not break
-- ever.
-- Well, who cares? There is no smartphones in the nineties. Oh man.
T nine.
-- Texting was awesome though. Like where
-- you, but they don't even text ever. Do they
uh in this movie though?
They don't text because texting wasn't a part of culture because
you had to learn how to text back in the day.
Like, remember you had to learn how to do T nine text entry.
Yeah, it's just all, it's all phone calls, right?
They're calling each other constantly.
Which is also funny because when was the last time you called someone?
Uh Well, ok. Uh, ignoring, like my parents and my kids
basically.
Yeah.
Never.
Uh,
I know, like, if someone calls me
-- do incoming spam calls count, I
-- mean, maybe, but, you know, like that's it.
The only time I saw a funny meme that was basically
how do I know when I'm getting a spam call?
My phone rings.
I
know I'm getting a spam call.
So they have this wild phone,
they made just for the movie because it looks
cool because the movie had a look about it.
And in, in 1999
like cell phones weren't common.
So if you had a cell phone,
you were probably a drug dealer or a hacker like that was basically,
or a serious businessman.
I actually met a cell phone number broker back in the day.
So basically this guy had an in with the phone company
and he managed to basically bribe people to give him cell
phone numbers that he could then resell to doctors for like
five grand because the cell phone debate and these are like,
we're talking back in the days of big
phone where like having one of those was a status symbol. Like I have a cell phone.
You do not,
right?
Um And so literally he would like bribe people at the phone company to
release cell phone numbers to him that he could then resell on for,
yeah, like five grand a pop
wild.
I was watching a documentary on uh AT&T on the original,
not cell phones but radio telephones.
And they, so they had these big radio towers set up in New York and all over the place
and there were three channels for all of New York City.
Yeah, because six people probably own the things. Yeah.
And so obviously AT&T is like, this is a great technology but, you know,
we'd like for more than three people at a time to be able to use it
and then we got sped rectum and all that magic going on. Right.
But
no,
yeah, I, again, I, I remember I actually had a pager before. I had a cell phone
because I could not afford a cell phone
when I was,
I remember that
I remember that man, those were the days, weren't they?
And that self that pa
was,
it was indestructible and pretty awesome.
Yeah,
they were all indestructible because people cared about that stuff back then.
Now everyone just buys expensive cases to put
their expensive phone in and it's fine.
Alright. So anyway,
uh we'll keep going. Uh hacker handles.
I suspect this movie was one of the first time
a lot of people were introduced to hacker handles.
Yeah.
No. Yes.
Yeah. Well, and thinking about it again, in popular society,
anybody
basically have two options.
You can go by a nickname and it has to be like
well known like uh like Richard and Dick or William and Bill
or you have an alias in your criminal.
And there's no third option for not going by your real name. Right.
And there's, it's back to that trope of real names and your name have power. Right?
Knowing somebody's real name, like Rumpel Stiltskin has power.
And I think that's where a lot of this hacker handle thing came from. Right.
Is people wanted to have an online persona
that, you know, didn't get them arrested
-- to a
-- degree because I remember one guy I knew he hacked into
the Edmonton public school board system and left his freaking name on it.
So that's a perfect example of where you should have used a hacker handle.
-- Tell
-- him
-- to come talk to me for the hacker History podcast.
That sounds like a really good story.
It was so long ago and
it wasn't even really hacking.
It was more like, it was like the war games hacking, like, oh, the password is pencil,
tap
out.
I mean,
there's so much of that though. People forget how, how dumb everything used to be.
Well, it's not that it was dumb. It's just that how like hacking into a computer
was like
mission impossible where you had to physically gain access to it because there was,
there was no internet.
Well, there were, there were cell phones. I mean,
you know, that's my favorite scene from hackers where it's like, ok, you know,
it's the box by the computer with numbers on it.
You know, he's trying to describe them to turn on the modem and, like,
hook it up and everything.
But
I,
part of it is just
like I look at smartphones, smartphones only existed since 2006
and they went from 0 to 60 like, basically five years and they were pretty common.
And now,
yeah, if I see somebody without a
smartphone, it's kind of like, wow, that's like retro, like, you're,
you're committed to that old phone.
-- Like, I mean,
-- cool. Maybe it, well,
they work, right and they,
and for some people cool.
But the point is things like, how long did email take to take off?
Like, I remember having an email address and a web address and people were like,
what is that good for?
And now of course, it's normal.
No, no, there's, there's a really important thing that to think about here. So
I think the best
comparison to use for that is going to the moon
where
in the sixties, humanity went to the moon
in spite of the technology we had.
Whereas if you look at the tech we have today going to the moon
is infinitely easier
and the reality is,
and I think email is the same and the same thing with smartphones is
like, we had weird screen smart devices back in the nineties.
I mean, do you remember like the Apple Newton and the Palm
Pilot and all that stuff?
I remember the Apple Newton because we, nobody was allowed to,
to write on it because it had finally learned Kevin's writing.
That's right. It did learn your writing.
I remember it expressly forbade anybody else from writing on it because it was like,
screw it up and he wouldn't, it wouldn't understand him.
That's right. But anyway, you get the idea right.
And like this technology was created in spite of everything else.
But then by the time
cell phones, well, smartphones came around,
there was the cloud and internet and mobile data and
all the things you need to actually make it succeed.
And I think like going to the moon today in 2021
is a very similar story where you could technically do it in the sixties,
but it was an enormous amount of heavy lifting.
But now in 2021 like,
we have cheap rockets,
we have the ability to get things into low earth
orbit for millions of dollars instead of trillions of dollars.
Like the, the difference is drastic.
And so I think if we go to the moon now it's going to be like, oh, that was neat.
You went to the moon instead of holy crap. We went to the moon.
-- You know, it's like
-- Mars, how many times have we been to Mars now?
-- A lot.
-- Exactly. It's become common enough that you don't know the number.
-- Yeah, I agree. I agree.
-- We even put a little helicopter up there.
And so anyway, anyway, but the reason I bring this up,
there's actually this is part of part of,
I love how we always go off on these weird tangents. This one was on purpose. So
when the original Matrix movies were made, those movies, the technology,
I think the special effects were made in spite of
what we had available at the time, right?
They did amazing things and they still look ok.
But now the thing I'm waiting for with the current one, when we make this new one
are the special effects going to be in line with
the kind of expectation of society of Oh OK.
We get this or are they going to push the envelope?
And that is going to be the question.
Well,
there's a third option where you essentially do the Star Wars thing of essentially
using all the possible modern special effects like the the volume, right? The
the volume is this thing where essentially it's a sound stage
covered in L CD screens.
Yeah, they use it in the Mandalorian and I'll try to look at
the
story about
the V FX artists react have a really great article on it
on you.
Um And so, but none of the thing is it's not just a sound stage with an L CD background,
it's a sound stage with an L CD background
and a computer controlled motion camera all synced together.
That's the magic part,
you know, that's the complicated bit.
And essentially, so you get these amazing new special effects,
but you keep it in line with the feel of the older stuff.
Otherwise you're going to annoy people. Right?
So, same thing with Star Wars where they d aged,
um, Luke Skywalker
and then turns out, you know,
they actually a I generated it and then the guy online did a better job of it.
So they hired him blah, blah, blah,
you know.
And so that's my hope is that they essentially use
all the, the tricks of the trade that are available today
but keep it in the feel and the, the
gestalt, I hate to use that word because it's German and it's pretentious. But the
gestalt
of the original three movies.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, I would, I would accept that. I, I hope so. I,
I'm, I want to like it.
That's what I just keep saying, but I,
I'll never forget
going to see the second Matrix movie in the theater and being like,
that wasn't a very good movie.
And then I went to see the third movie and I remember walking out of it and I said,
I feel like I've been stolen from, for buying a ticket because it was so bad.
And that's why I won't watch any of the newer Star Wars films.
I've seen like all the Star Wars stuff, but I,
I feel free after the last one because it had space horses.
And so now I have no qualms if I if I watch another one, great.
-- If I don't watch another one, that's ok too because space
-- horses,
I feel like at this point watching all the Star Wars is like completing chemo.
Like yes, that's
if you have to do chemo, you should complete it. But if you can avoid it, just, yeah,
that is not a fair comparison in any way.
I'm not saying Star Wars the later films cause cancer. I'm heavily implying it.
They were bad.
Oh
It's
that,
that's my fear of the Matrix Four. Like I saw the trailer and uh
so we're running ourselves out of time. We only have a few more minutes
and I feel like we've touched on nothing of
the things I was hoping we would talk about.
But that's ok.
So I guess here is the question
that we can all think about
as we end. This one is so if you look at
the Matrix movies, we find out at the end that supposedly this was all planned
and this has been done a bunch of times
and it's just kind of how it all works.
Yeah, because the human body is not a power generating battery.
Well, we know that it was supposed to have been actually in the original script.
It was meant to be like compute power
and they, the the studio thought
audience wouldn't understand that which they may not have back then.
So they wanted to call it, oh, it's a battery. Instead.
But obviously everyone knows like love thermodynamics.
There's no way a human body can generate more power than it consumes blah blah, blah,
blah blah.
But so in my brain, I just always think about compute devices and batteries.
So anyway, anyway,
we find out about like the architect and the
oracle and this was all planned and whatever blah,
blah, blah, blah blah.
And
it, it,
it, it really makes me think of the fact that like
you are a compute system, you are an artificial intelligence,
you are theoretically infinitely smart
and this is the freaking best you can do. This was a terrible society.
And
what just ii I don't know.
Yeah, like if you want to keep the humans in tanks,
put some plexiglass over the top of them instead of that gooey stuff.
I don't know anyway.
But I guess that's part of it as well is in any story,
there's always going to be plot holes.
And I feel like the super intelligent A I isn't very super intelligent, which
-- I guess well,
-- and maybe put this in the journals.
But if you want to see some or read some
in my opinion, more interesting more, I don't want to say realistic,
but I think well thought out, yeah, we're going to go with well thought out
science fiction along these lines. Charles Strauss's Story Glasshouse
is really intriguing. I have not read that one.
It's, it was not a commercial success.
How do I know this because he actually wrote about this on his blog last week.
But it was one of my, it's one of my favorite stories from him.
And it's funny because the actual real British Glasshouse is
the reason I now make my bed every morning.
There was a British drill sergeant. She was talking about
one of the reasons they have this discipline is because
when you make your bed in the morning, no matter how crap your day is
when it's done,
-- you have a nice bed to go home to.
-- I agree. I do the same because I find
that having
a, a made bed at the end of my day
definitely is helpful. Um
So, ok, so the thing I always think of that if you want to talk about like, what I,
what I envision A is to really be, it's um what is the, the, the book?
Um I have no mouth and I must scream. It's what a Harlan Ellison
short story
that's like every time I think of a I, I'm like, that's it.
That's the story
of how it should have turned out
pretty much. Well, that's the other thing is I hate the term A I because
like, are we talking general A I, are we talking like evil terminator? A I?
Are we talking happy
A I is clearly some sort of self-aware giant
computer system that apparently only goal is to perpetuate,
-- perpetuate its existence,
-- right?
And we've had a bunch of those A I movies and stories where, you know,
they keep the humans alive.
Why? Because that's what we do.
Uh,
well, that's not what they do though.
They hate the humans, they just, they need them for their compute power,
apparently.
I mean, I mean, more in general terms of A I stories, you know,
where they're keeping the humans alive.
-- Why? Because that's what we do. Right. It's tradition.
-- What, what is that?
The thought experiment of? You?
Tell an A I job is to make paper clips
and it turns the whole universe into paper clips pretty
much. Actually, I'll put a link in the show notes. There's this, like,
there's this amazing game called universal paper clips on the internet and like,
if you want to get fired from your job,
go play this game because it's amazing and it's like all button pushing text.
-- It's, it's phenomenal.
-- There's an even better one.
The TV, show Lex has those self replicating.
Please tell me you've seen the, the TV series, Lex.
I watch like, no TV. You know, this,
-- well, this is from 30 years ago. It doesn't
-- matter. I've never seen it.
I
know it, Lex is,
it's only one of the best ever weird
Canadian science fiction TV shows
all
of.
Yeah. Well, oh, worse. The series is a Canadian and German Coro.
Yeah. You've never heard of it? And I'm, I,
-- I, yes, this is
-- why I've heard of it.
I've just never watched it because I don't watch very much TV.
-- Is there a book?
-- I read the book.
I don't think there's a book.
So if you're a TV, producer or a movie maker, write the book,
so I don't have to watch your stuff.
That
sounds, that sounds mean.
Um, anyway, all right, I'm going to call this, this,
I feel like was a super rambly weird episode.
But man, it was fun and if nothing else, I had a blast researching all this. So
if you made it this far, go watch the Matrix movies again,
you'll only partially regret it when you get done with the third one.
Anyway, thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to put
social beauty
podcast.com. Hit a pressure, not ju
Pound
o this podcast hashtag hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone.
Bye bye
the