Hello and welcome to a special Christmas episode
of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and Josh Bresser
warning this show may contain Christmas spoilers tree nuts and disappointment.
-- Kurt,
-- every episode has disappointment.
However, in this case, if you have small Children, I would suggest you escort them
from the room
very soon
-- or just make them do ear muffs for an hour.
-- That's right. Right ear muffs for an hour.
I love it.
Fantastic.
So, how you doing, man?
I'm doing well. I am really looking forward to Christmas
who isn't looking forward to Christmas. Right.
Yeah.
Well, some people, bad people. They're just. No.
Yes. So,
uh, the security of Santa.
Yeah.
Now,
do we actually want to start with the big one or do we want to start with his minions?
What's the big one?
-- Well, the big one is Santa, but he, he doesn't travel
-- alone, like,
like apart from deer or, or something else.
Well, I'm, I've been thinking about the elf on the shelf.
Oh, that thing, I hate the elf on the shelf. My kids have that and it's a nuisance to me.
Oh, my goodness.
I,
the worst part, I mean, apart from the,
the whole police state mentality that it brings
is just remembering to move the thing
because
-- every freaking day
-- I
only, I,
I read up on it about, about it online
and I have to admit I was horrified because correct me if I'm wrong.
But the premise seems to be
this thing is watching you and if you do something
bad it'll report back and you get no presents.
Uh It's, well, I mean, that's not unlike the,
the general historical nature of Santa, right?
Where, where all parents can tell Santa anything at any time somehow
and if you're bad, then you get nothing,
which is never true because you still always give
your kids crap no matter how rotten they are.
Uh And then obviously on, on December 26th,
they can go back to being terrible Children and everything's fine till November.
However,
so the idea behind the elf on the shelf is it is a money
making scheme that is working better than anything I've ever seen in history.
You get this Elf which comes with the book and cost a ton of money.
And the idea is the elf comes out after when, whenever in, in our case,
it comes out after Thanksgiving and it,
it move every night,
you it, it, you put it out somewhere
and every night it flies back to the North Pole
and then tell Santa all about the Children in the house and how, no doubt,
wonderful they've been
that particular day
and then he comes back before the Children wake up in the morning
and he sits somewhere else in the house. Right.
And then of course,
uh I, I don't,
I don't do this but I know people who will tell the Elf things or the Children will,
will talk to the elf and ask questions of Santa
and various other things.
But I mean, fundamentally, it is a creature that is spying on you
the entire time and,
and will essentially report back to uh Big Brother as to
your behavior and if you are deserving of presence or not.
So it's, it's horrifying to say the least.
Yeah, I mean, when I, when I read that and I'm not a huge fan of that,
but what even gets me is they,
I know they're doing it at my kid's school in the classroom to some degree
and it's not the Elf on the shelf. It's some sort of more non
-- denominational holiday. It's
-- not,
it's an Elf,
but
there's also,
I'm pretty sure they have like one for Hanukkah now and also the Hanukkah,
some of the other celebrations.
The Hanukkah zombie. Right.
Yeah.
So, I mean,
yeah. No, it's, it's,
it's worrying to me that we're, we're,
we're teaching Children that it's normal to live in this, you know,
surveillance state.
Well, it is now. So we're just preparing them for their future
in
Facebook and Uber know where you've been and,
and what you're doing just like Santa Claus, right?
They know when you're sleeping, they know when you're awake,
they know if you do bad or good should be good for goodness sake.
You know,
Uber
clothes,
I have to assume because this is not a new trend when you think about it. Right?
There's also things like furby. I don't know if you remember furby back in.
When did that
back? Dude,
you can buy
furs.
They were terrified.
You ever see a furby without, without the fake hair,
they look like like nightmare fuel.
But uh I mean,
I remember the NSA banning furby and pretty much all
these other intelligence services banning furbies from the premises,
right?
-- Because they can record and play back randomly.
-- Right?
Well, you know, funny enough you say that and
uh
inside
Red Hat,
we have a bot
called sec bot
that I assume you're familiar with which I gave in Eliza brain and, and you,
I vetted a bunch of quotes and it's hilarious to talk to.
Of course,
I, at one time had it learning from one of the uh security Irc channels we use
and it had picked up too much embargoed information that we had to wipe the brain
and make it never. Yeah, which is really funny.
So I totally get this fury thing, right? It sounds ridiculous.
But like I've experienced this where we had a bot
that, that knew about you know, secret security things
and anyone could talk to it.
And so we had to fix that very quickly.
You had to pull a Westworld on that poor bot.
I'm not familiar with what that means, but I'll
-- assume. Yes,
-- you haven't seen Westworld.
I don't have HBO. I barely watch TV.
Honestly,
Gilmore
-- Girls, though,
-- we'll
-- talk
-- about it.
We'll talk about Westworld on a different episode.
I'll make
it
-- back
-- to Santa.
Um So, yeah, so he's got this huge surveillance apparatus,
I guess for lack of a better word.
And what's interesting to me is he's, he's gone technological, right?
Like it used to be, parents had to
send in the information, right?
And as I understand it, Santa now, you know,
has remote monitoring capabilities with these elves on the shelves and,
you know, I'm pretty sure
um, well,
there was actually the case of um some of these new children's toys that take
like voice input and kind of talk back. Apparently.
Uh This obviously is done in like a cloud back end in some cases,
like it's not done on the toy
that it's like Siri,
it sends it back to somewhere for processing and then generates a response.
And apparently one of the companies doing this is like part of a defense contractor.
Conglomeration.
Nice,
you know, like, um
yeah, it's just, it's,
the future is far weirder than I could have ever imagined.
You know, like you read Cypherpunk or, or
sorry, cyberpunk, you know, genre stuff or even cypherpunk stuff. And
man, they, they really got it wrong like we,
yeah, we seem to have willingly taken on all this, you know, surveillance
and
the dawn to our kids or
Orwell
and Huxley got it pretty good,
I'd say.
Yeah. Yeah.
You know, it's, it's not AAA mirror, it's just Facebook on your mobile phone, which,
you know, is better because it's in your pocket.
That's right. It's Oh man.
So, ok, so, so let's focus. Santa has the largest surveillance network
on the planet without doubt, right. Did Santa have Santa lines?
-- I don't think I've ever really found anything that says he
-- does
wonder about it because I,
I know on Google Maps now they have the Santa tracking app shown up,
it showed up in
Google
in Maps about
a
week
ago.
Well, or yeah, I mean, I don't know if he's,
I don't see, that's what I wonder is,
is Santa cooperating with NORAD or is this
like like an actual like potentially hostile flight?
-- Which is why they track him?
-- No. Do you know why they track Santa?
The story is amazing actually.
So no, there's a story behind it. So, so what
-- happened
-- in
airline disaster documentaries
-- as well? No,
-- it does. It does. This is a happy story.
Yeah. And don't oh man, those airline disaster things are terrified anyway.
So, so here's the deal is
long ago.
There was a, I believe it was a radio station, put an ad in the newspaper saying,
you know, find out where Santa is or talk to Santa or something like that call,
this phone number, right?
And they put the wrong phone number,
they were one digit off and the phone number they put in was for NORAD.
And so these little kids kept calling NORAD and in the first couple of calls,
I imagine they were like, what the heck is going on.
But they started playing along. Right.
And they were talking to kids and telling
them all about Santa and the tracking of Santa
and apparently it was so popular and they had so much
fun doing it that they decided after that every year they
were going to track Santa and let's face it if any
organization other than Google is best equipped to track Santa,
it's NORAD.
Right.
Yeah.
Yeah, they got the satellites, the, the distant early warning line.
Right.
Yeah, all that stuff.
Well, I mean, he comes, you know, he's taking the same ballistic track as a missile,
you know, coming from the North Pole over to the US.
So.
Right,
because he,
he visits the other parts of the world too. Right.
Visiting, um, we'll say wealthy countries first
and, and probably
as
he followed the Dateline.
Yeah, that's, well, if you, if you track Santa on the no
website, he actually does that where he obviously starts out in,
uh, Australia and Asia
and then works his way across the planet until he obviously hits
North America and then we can all start telling our kids to,
you know,
go to f, to sleep because Santa won't come if you don't.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know. It's, uh,
so I would assume he probably has, like, maybe a transponder on his sleigh, you know,
to play along because, you know,
you don't wanna get sucked into a 747 flying out of Melbourne.
Right.
That's a good point.
I wonder if there's ever been a, uh, well,
you've been watching aircraft disaster shows.
Has Santa ever collided with a commercial aircraft?
To
the
best of my knowledge,
to me that at
least in the US, he'd be flying in unrestricted airspace below 500 ft.
Do we know how high Santa flies though? I mean, I guess he has to come down
but
when he crosses the ocean,
you know, Google probably knows.
But what's the altitude limit on a, on a reindeer before they, like, pass out 2 ft.
But, I mean,
technically if he's going from house to house
and not like long haul across the Pacific,
he should be, I would imagine staying low.
Right. Like he's not gonna
fare and, oh, you know, that's a good point.
Actually, the, the way that the, the planet works out is quite nice because he,
although he's got to hit a bunch of those little islands in the Pacific because,
like, people don't realize how big the Pacific Ocean is.
Like, it's half the planet.
I mean,
it's crazy.
And so you've got to think, I bet the, uh,
the return on investment of hitting those like remote
islands with only a handful of people is,
is significantly high, given the terrible density of that whole side of the planet.
So,
so, yeah, Santa His,
uh, the economics of this are clearly not done very well. Right.
I, I suspect that Amazon does not have prime in, in American Samoa
or Tuvalu.
Right.
Well, I feel bad for these, you know,
small places and not only are they small and out of the way, but now they're, you know,
being
ending up under the ocean. And
I think one of these uh van who was seriously talking about relocating
to Australia,
-- they don't really have a choice,
-- I suppose.
And you got to think uh the North Pole is not a land mass, it is an ice sheet.
And so Santa is gonna have some troubles
if, if that ever uh melts,
-- right? Maybe now Santa will use a boat instead
-- of
assumed that he has some sort of extra dimensional portal type technology.
Well,
then why does he fly in a freaking sleigh
instead of just appearing in your home magically deposit?
Well, I guess he kind of does. We'll get to that.
Like I always assumed he had some form of portal gun
because you know what if you don't have a chimney.
Uh,
you have to be in sight with the portal gun and
you can only shoot it onto a lunar dust coated surfaces.
Yeah. Yeah, I've never played the game. Oh
man.
Portal is fanta actually Portal one you have to
play just to understand kind of what's happening.
And then Portal two, they cover a bunch of history behind
the facility that the portal people. It's called the Aperture Labs.
It's, it's really good
just for honestly, for the story of the second one I think is, is phenomenal.
And I had more,
I get more enjoyment from that than I do from actually playing the game.
But I do love the portal games. They're, they're fantastic games.
Yeah.
So let's just assume for a moment that we'll,
we'll just pretend the travel thing works out.
I
-- think you have to
-- accept the
Sonic booms.
-- Don't just flatten the entire planet every 24 or once a year
-- or does
he have some sort of space time device that allows him to stop time
or warp space or some combination of the two?
Yeah.
So, but moving around.
So
he's got this. Yeah. Well, you know, it's like a lot of things in life.
I mean, I, my car works when I turn it on.
Really? Do I do? I know how it works when it turns on. No,
no, I really don't.
There's fire inside and then things go.
Exactly.
So he's got this huge surveillance database.
Now, this is, this is kind of interesting to me because
I remember back in the day when having
like large databases was a very nontrivial problem.
Like, I remember the excitement of I was working for a government agency
and they got a Dell server
with quad CP us
256 megabytes of RA M
and something like 27 gigabytes of storage in
two enormous external cases hooked up through like, and this is the weirdest part,
they had dual scuzzy cards so that if one card failed, they could still,
it would still work,
you know,
and, and the size of these cables, right?
They were like half an inch, they were just massive cables,
you know, with a bend radius.
Um
And you know,
I remember they made me carry one of the towers and I really didn't want to because I
didn't want to drop it because it was basically
worth like my salary for the next decade.
Um
But, and you know, I remember being so impressed with it and now, I mean, well,
uh as an example of scale, you know, let's let's assume right?
7 billion people on the planet. Uh
We're looking at probably a megabyte of data,
-- a piece because
-- maybe that depends what he tracks though.
If he's tracking any sort of graphics, any images,
full motion video man is crazy
so
well. But one megabyte,
-- you
-- know, just locational data because some people live and there's no address.
Uh, that's true,
you know.
Um, anyway, so let's assume a megabyte each because it's easy math.
That's, that's seven by petabytes of data,
right? Which,
you know, used to sound like a lot.
But, um, I mean, yeah, last week and, and this makes me wonder if they're kind of in
cahoots. Amazon announced snowmobile, right? Like they originally had snowball,
which was a couple, I
think, tens or hundreds of terabytes in a,
in a pack in a basically in a ruggedized case that they would ship to you.
You put your data on it, you ship it back to them
and now they have snowmobile which is up to 100 petabytes and it literally,
-- it's a 45 ft shipping container full of hard drives,
-- which is crazy.
Yeah.
And like there's even an option for an armed escort if you want,
-- which
-- I assume Santa would need that because there's probably various,
uh we'll say government organizations that would be
very interested in acquiring copies of his data.
Well,
just think about what you've probably done in the last year that nobody knows about.
Santa knows. Right.
He keeps the list, I hear he checks it twice.
Yeah.
So, well, and you know, it's good that he does data integrity. That's
true.
-- That's
-- true. And if he
maybe he has two megabytes of data on all of us.
So,
but yeah, I can't help wonder.
But, you know, like these massive data storage projects, snowball and snowmobile.
Yeah, that's true. It checks out, checks out
-- because you gotta
-- think, right?
A lot of like the reason we have integrated circuits is because of the, you know,
the Apollo Moon Pro uh Project, right?
You know, miniaturized computers and, you know,
things like data storage again from the military, right?
So I can't help but wonder is Santa essentially
a technology incubator as well for surveillance technology?
-- So
-- are you suggesting that Santa is part of the military?
Well, not directly part of the military but, but like the military,
he develops technology that nobody else would be willing to spend the money.
-- I understand.
I got you, I got you.
Well, you, you look at Futurama and Santa is definitely militarized there, right?
-- But he means,
-- well,
no, he doesn't. His goal is to
-- he's there to murder everybody. He doesn't mean
-- well at all, only the bad people,
all of the people Kurt in Futurama.
Yeah. Yeah.
So, so for those of you who have never seen it,
watch the Futurama Christmas episodes because they are awesome.
But essentially according to the show.
And if, if, if none of you know,
I'm like an insane Futurama fan to the point
of I can generally tell you the episode names,
if you tell me what happens in them off the top of my head, which is disturbing.
Anyway. So in the Christmas episodes,
they, they talk about Santa was built in like 2030 no, 2020.
I forget what year it was, it was in 20 something or other.
They're in the year 3000 in the show.
Basically, when he was programmed, they made his uh naughty
algorithm
too sensitive. So he's determined everyone is naughty. Actually, except Dr
Zoidberg. Dr
Zoidberg gets a pogo stick in one of the episodes because
he's not naughty but everyone else is naughty and Santa uh,
kills them or, or hurts them badly.
We'll say
as, as part of his.
Yeah, it's, it's really funny. I love those episodes
and,
uh, Bender becomes Santa in one of the episodes as well,
which is one of the best ones ever because then, uh, that's the one where they, they,
uh, Santa comes in and they've got, uh, Doctor
Zberg shows up as, as,
and I'm, I'm Santa's friend Jesus.
Right. And it's, it's really good anyway. Anyway.
Uh, right. So we know Santa has an impressive surveillance network he has
and he would have to as well for his, uh, for his supply chain.
It's true. Oh, that's true. We could hit supply chain.
I
mean,
it's
because
I, I, you know, you think Amazon is big and ships a lot of stuff. I mean,
you know, can you imagine if you told Amazon? Oh, yeah.
And by the way, you only get to deliver for 1 24 hour period every year.
That would, that's not Amazon's problem. That's fedex's problem. Right.
Speaking of, I was at the Lego store, I was shop,
I was looking at the Lego store the other day
and they, they, they take,
they take orders up until December, I think 15th
and then not until February 1st,
I get that. I bet.
I don't know if, if the, the shipping companies changed the rates in any way.
But if I was a shipping company
I would make it significantly more expensive
to ship something after December 15th.
Yeah.
So, but yeah, I mean, you would have to have surveillance. I mean,
part of me wonders though, if you're,
if you're an Elf living at the North pole or in some extra dimensional
thing tied to the North pole,
for example, you steal children's toys. Like how do
you, how do you sell them? How do you get rid of them? Like, what do you do with them?
Look, you're talking about a being
that already knows everything about everyone.
He's gonna know you stole toys from him
and I would assume aren't
people?
Uh Oh,
that's true. They does seem to track his elves.
And let's assume
he does though because why would you not track your indentured servants
who are building and running your empire?
Right. That would be a completely foolish mistake.
And in fact, it would be very much like game of Thrones, right?
Where you'd have a constant, we'll say
attempts on your life as Santa by the various Elf
minions who you do not track in any reasonable way.
Yeah.
I always thought things like that would be impossible because you know,
how could you have like a clearly insane leader,
like leading something doing crazy things?
And I hate to say it, but every time that topic comes up, I just think of North Korea.
Are, are you suggesting Santa is insane?
Well, I mean,
I want to
pay the elves. Does he treat them well?
From a lot of documentaries we've seen like Futurama, for example, makes it very
clear the elves are not,
they're not elves, they're neps.
Yes, it's totally different there in those. That's a robot.
Santa that was built probably as
when the real Santa was. I, I wonder what happened to the real Santa?
Actually, it's interesting.
However, now if you look at most,
we'll say child appropriate television and movies that involve Santa,
he appears to treat his elves with a certain amount of love and respect
versus I
guess
the movie Elf, which we could take as canon because it's
sure we'll call that Cannon. The movie Elf is Cannon. All right, folks.
You heard it here.
So,
yes. And in the movie Elf, uh Santa is nice to the elves and treats them well. Right.
And is even willing to pretend a human is an Elf for much longer than they should have.
Yeah. No, I've always wondered about that because the whole
sort of the, the this gift based economy that he runs,
-- you know, I mean, I'm imagining does he have, it's not
-- an economy, Kurt,
it's pure output.
Where's the input to this? Right? Milk and cookies? I mean,
well,
you know what
I think actually now that you bring up the milk and cookies issue,
looping back to travel, I think there may be a thing there.
Um,
-- because also back to the future is Canon, I believe,
-- of course it is,
you know, Mr
Fusion, right? You, you, you gotta, you gotta put something in the Mr
Fusion drive to fuel it
and maybe milk and cookies are the optimal fusion fuel.
But his, his sleigh is powered by
eight, maybe nine. Reindeer
Reindeer
grass. That's
a
good question.
I would imagine these Reindeer are like a little bit, you know, they,
they've had some custom modifications, right?
They can fly. Rudolph has a red nose.
Um, if we look at, for example, taking, um, Ice Age the Christmas episode
again as cannon,
you know,
uh Blitzen can make lightning.
So he's got like some sort of electrostatic weapon which when you think about it,
true, they would also need,
right?
Because like what if they fly into a flock of geese, you know,
you don't want to take a geese in the engine and
-- you know, crack,
-- they don't have engines, they're deer.
No, but if you take like a goose to the face at like 300 miles an hour, it's gonna hurt,
I would think. So. It hurt the guy in front.
That's why it's probably good to be in the back. Right.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Get that slipstream.
It's about, uh,
yeah, I mean, you know, as we've learned from a variety of air accidents, you know,
like when you fly into a flock of birds it can end poorly.
-- So,
-- for example,
that can,
so, you know, like these reindeer I would imagine have some pretty, you know,
custom modifications,
like to deal with these situations.
Well, dealing with turbulence because for example,
there's some pretty fragile gifts coming through the system,
right? People give people get puppies for Christmas,
right? I wonder how they build those.
Well, you, you just, I, I would assume he just has like
Santa Puppy Mill
basically,
you know, I mean,
it's,
I, well, well,
this also assumes that he does everything and just
-- hasn't outsourced it at some point without telling
-- us
he has outsourced it and
we'll get to that that towards the end. But,
yeah.
All right. All right. So we've decided that reindeer are possibly
fueled by milk and cookies.
However, I don't know if this is a tradition where you live, but where I'm at,
you leave out milk and cookies for Santa and also carrots for the reindeer.
Right. True.
Yeah, we do,
we do the Saint Nicholas thing because we're well of
German descent and so Saint Nick comes around on,
I think it's December the fifth and it's kind
of like a practice warm up for Christmas.
Uh So you basically get a warning
and a little toy for good or
a
bad. What do you
-- do? You give ST Nicholas a gift? You leave
-- a carrot for his, um
I want to say donkey,
he has a donkey
and you only leave the carrot for the donkey. You don't leave anything for
because Saint Nicholas is a nice guy.
I
see.
Unlike
Santa who
is
just ignore
the slavery
does.
Oh, yeah.
OK.
Well,
that's uh actually there's David Sedaris has a little thing he
gives where he talks about Christmas and whatnot around the world
and he gets one where I, I forget which country it's in.
But
there's Santa with uh yeah,
three slaves essentially followed him around according to their traditions,
which is, of course, when, when he does it, it's hilarious as all of his things are.
But I'll, I'll put that in the show notes. I'll, I'll dig it up.
But it, it's fantastic. So, anyway, OK, so
maybe milk and cookies feel reindeer. Maybe they don't, we don't know for sure.
However,
we do know that vast quantities of milk are consumed
on Christmas Eve and a large number of cookies are eaten
and they are for something. We don't know the purpose. We'll say
maybe fuel, maybe that's
how their economy works. Presents come out. Cookies go in.
I don't know the details.
You know that would work with, I mean, that would work with Children.
I know my kids are, you know, highly motivated by cookies as currency,
you know, and Skittles and M, and M's even
candy. Candy, candy works on me, man. I'm not gonna lie. I'll do anything for candy.
Well, I mean, uh, look at the, what is it? The US Senate.
There's a, traditionally,
there's one desk towards the front that's full of candy and it's, I think the Senate
minority whips.
Yeah, there's some, it's some tradition where they have like, just, yeah,
they have a desk full of candy.
-- Now,
-- I'm super
interested in being a senator
just for my free candy. Right. That's totally the right reason to do it,
which is probably actually a better reason than
most of those guys got into the Senate
about American. So I can't really say, speak to that. But,
so we've established.
So I guess that we got to really come back to the, how does he actually, that,
that classic problem, the last mile delivery problem
breaking an en,
right. He's a master thief.
He sees
into your house, steals your milk and cookies
and, and leaves behind gifts.
Well, is there an implied contract with the milk and cookies?
There's an offer given,
there's the offer
taken and there's the,
the, the reciprocation. So,
uh,
I'm wondering because, you know, a lot of law works on historical precedent,
right? Cases and so on
and
gets you the gifts. Right. Not the milk and cookies.
I would see the milk and cookies as more of the, uh, tip for a job. Well done.
Hopefully. Right.
-- I guess we'd have to look that up. I don't know the
-- historical Santa Law.
I
bet that's covered in the Library of Congress.
Well, I'm kind of wondering too, like, you know,
when you buy a house, did you read all the paperwork that came with it?
I read a lot of it
but
I know what you mean.
I've often wondered because, like, you know, with,
with various products now there's user license agreements that, you know,
essentially have all sorts of crazy conditions.
Um,
you know, like some of them are just
absurd. Now.
-- Um,
-- now, now those I will admit I never read
and
I,
I read some research one time that said if you read
every UL A you're presented to be it from like,
apps and software and, and whatever services online, whatever, what not, you know,
it would take something like
a month or two of your life every year just to read them all. Which is crazy.
Yeah,
I've often wondered about that because he, he obviously,
you know, the, the police don't seem too concerned.
Are they powerless or are they part of this?
Well, yeah, that's a good question.
I mean, I really, I really do wonder about this sometimes.
Well, however, in the movie, the Santa Claus,
they arrest Santa and then there's a special
elf, like, like special ops unit
that comes and frees him and clearly, if you have a special ops elf unit,
this is not the first time Santa has found himself,
we'll say on the wrong side of the law,
-- but
-- he also delivers presents to some dangerous places.
Uh That is true.
That is true. Like Chicago,
I shouldn't laugh.
It's sadly not funny.
But
yeah.
So, I mean, well, I guess also part of it boils down to like there's been cases where,
you know,
um, for example, if somebody comes onto your property to put a fire out,
you're not going to charge them with trespassing.
Could you, you could, I don't know, in
theory you could, but
I mean, they might also be covered by good Samaritan law. So
there's a thought is Santa covered by good Samaritan laws.
Uh
That's a good question.
We need, we're gonna need legal counsel next year for our Santa.
I imagine it's a lot like bird law. Like, are there people that practice Santa law?
It's got to be international.
So
-- right there, super complicated.
-- It's true.
It's true and not only international,
but it's going to have tons of historical precedent
just given the fact that that Santa has been around for hundreds
thousands might be pushing it, but certainly hundreds of years.
I, I know, I think I'm pretty sure Christmas has been celebrated for quite some time
and the gift giving seems to
Well, I think humans have given gifts probably forever.
Right.
That's certainly not new.
-- Yeah. So it goes back about 2000 years, 2000
-- years of Santa.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Potentially.
Yeah. Wow. The Romans, yeah. Started with the Romans. Like many things.
Even the Greeks. What? The Greeks and the Romans? Ok.
-- Well, yeah, it still goes back like, all the way.
-- Nice.
That's crazy. Man.
Took quite some time.
Sorry. I've lost the show. Ah, there we go.
Um,
yeah, because, I mean,
and the other thing that gets me is he
breaks and enters without actually typically doing much damage,
uh, to my knowledge, he does no damage at all. And
so, historically speaking,
he would come down the chimney and every house used to have a chimney,
but these days that's a
little more suspect than it used to be.
Well, most houses have dryer vents or a furnace.
Uh, yes. Yes. Everyone's house has ways in, we'll say.
But,
but, but at the same time, if Santa's coming in through your dryer vent,
that's,
that's a pretty indirect route, right?
If you have the ability to make it through that, why not just, like, open the door,
right?
You clearly have the ability to do amazing things.
Well, I mean, thinking back to that X Files episode
with the, uh, the guy that could contort himself.
I don't remember that one, but I have not watched X Files in probably 20
-- years.
-- It's been a while. They're rebooting it apparently.
But uh back to Santa Claus. Hey, did the X files ever do anything on Santa?
That
don't know.
But because that would be good. Canon. I think
there was, wasn't there the, there was an episode where
someone dressed this? I'm not even gonna go there. I, I'm not gonna think about it.
My brain can't handle this right now. All right. So, anyway,
you're thinking of the bank robbery episode? Maybe,
maybe I
think that
was,
I don't know.
So, back to Santa, I mean,
so we've decided Santa Israel,
he can deliver
that.
We've decided he has an impressive surveillance network.
Well, that's where, that's where we'll get to Santa as a service, right?
Which is clearly
what Santa has become. And he's done a marvelous job of that in, in modern dev
ops fashion, right?
I suppose. Yeah. So, so Santa is a service. Let's, let's walk through that.
That's where you and I spend all our money on our
kids buying them crap they don't need so they can break it
and then complain about how much better Christmas was last year.
A
Yeah.
No, I'm just, it's, it's amazing to me that it has become such an institution in,
but at the same time very different than I remember it as a kid.
And I don't know if that's because I was a child or because,
and I wasn't the one paying for it.
Well, it's ok, so society changes, obviously.
But there's also, I mean, it has become, like you said,
it's a huge institution now because there are so many organizations that
have so much riding on the holiday season because people do spend
insane amounts of money on stuff. Right.
And this is actually where from the security angle, it's obviously very high risk
because, you know, it's kind of like why do people rob banks?
It's because of where the money is. Right.
Well, at the holidays, you know, there's people with money
everywhere
and I think that's,
you know, it's kind of like we had those, uh, with the, the,
a couple of shows ago we did the, the Cyber Monday advice.
Yeah. Cyber Monday advice and, and the advice was terrible, but the point is,
people are at least aware
that this is real and a threat.
So I guess what would the threats around Santa be?
I mean,
apart from some random person breaking into your
house once a year to leave stuff behind.
Well,
it's clearly the massive amount of data he's
collected ever being hacked and leaked by,
you know, some organization which ironically,
I suspect Santa's database kind of falls under the same problem.
You know, Google's database has,
is the only place you could put it after you stole it is back in Google.
So there's really nothing to do with it.
Right.
There's a thought security via
obesity of data
security via obesity.
Well, you know, like, it's like, um,
well, it's like, it's like the pyramids, right?
Nobody's ever gonna steal the pyramids because they're just too dang big.
But the Mona Lisa on the other hand,
small,
it's been stolen plenty of times.
But, but yeah, it has. Oh, it's got like a, a crazy history.
I don't know if you ever, I've never seen it in person.
I've, I've never been to the Louver but
if you look at it, the Mona Lisa is really small and the reason it's so tiny is because
in many of the instances where they steal it,
they just literally cut it out of the frame and run.
And so obviously every time it was stolen it
got smaller and smaller for a period of time.
And so now it's very tiny.
Why not just glue it to like a three inch thick piece of steel?
Because that would probably ruin it. I would
imagine
that frame it on a three inch piece of steel.
It's framed.
Well, now it's, I won't say it's impossible to steal,
but I suspect you're talking about like some serious movie plot
Antics
to get a hold of that thing now.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, that's the thing.
Like I, yeah, if you look at a database, the size of Santa's database,
like how would you,
I mean, there's a thought, you know,
with the facility it stored and even have enough bandwidth to move it out of there.
Would you like li
literally have to drive a semi truck full of hard drives up to it and be like, uh,
don't mind me.
Right. What kind of, what kind of internet connection does the North Pole have?
Right. I mean,
fairly remote areas you would have to
-- because, I mean,
-- you could run, you could run fiber.
There's no land.
It's an ice
sheet.
Is,
is the north pole connected to a land mass
that, well, the ice sheet is,
that's why we don't have the northwest passage,
right? The, the ice sheet comes down.
It's, yeah, it's coming soon, sadly. But, um,
no, traditionally the North Pole ice sheets, they did retreat in summer,
but they were still.
-- No, no,
-- no.
But you could lay the cable on the ocean floor
right down underneath the ice and then bring it up
at some point. I see no reason you couldn't do that.
So,
so we'll say it is,
we're arguing over whether a mythical creature can,
you know, fuel his deer with milk and cookies
like
the
internet. There.
No life without internet is weird.
So, so we'll say it is plausible that he has a hard connection.
Here's a question.
Does he simply tap into the existing fiber optic cables in the area?
-- So he's
-- stealing internet. You're suggesting,
well, you know, it's, I mean, we've,
we've established that that type of activity is possible.
You know, certain government agencies have
that, you know, have in the past
been known to do it.
I mean,
Santa obviously is technologically capable even if
it's disguised as like a reindeer.
But, I mean, let's face it. Right.
That's a long haul, you know, 12 engine bomber essentially
with, you know, basically unlimited payload. Like,
uh, now, does he have unlimited payload or does he have a,
we'll bring out the dungeons and the dragons here, a bag of holding
to hold all of his stuff.
I would assume there has to be a bag
of holding or something involved because just the aerodynamics,
right? Like
the biggest airplane I'm aware of, like, what is it?
I think there's the, well commercially
the guppy thing and that thing is huge but still like,
you know, it's not
that big. Like
when you think about like,
well to put it in terms of how many Amazon warehouses could you fit in there?
You know, how many
Amazon warehouses?
So I would assume that there has to be some,
you know, the more, the more we talk about it,
the more I think some sort of portal technology or b
of holding type stuff makes sense.
Well, here's a question too,
like he might have to haul a lot of coal and that stuff's heavy
and maybe that's
maybe that's why he's done Santa as a service to outsource it
to the parents who don't punish their kids by giving them coal,
thus reducing global warming and ensuring the safety of the North Pole ice sheet.
-- I think we figured it out.
-- What, say that again.
I
know
-- coal to
-- bad kids. Right.
When you burn coal it creates CO2 and all that and global warming,
global warming reduces the ice sheet
which threatens Santa. So by outsourcing Santa as a service, it's a win, win.
Right. He doesn't have to go over all the presents
and there's less global warming gasses because
there's less coal being burned by Children
do. Children was Children burning coal like AAA
problem.
I,
I don't know, give it, put it back in the coal pile downstairs in the basement and
burn it.
I guess I,
I'm not gonna say you're wrong because I, obviously I can't prove it,
but
we'll say it doesn't make sense.
Yeah.
Well, I, I think, you know, that we live in a post truth world, it could be correct.
That's true. It's, uh, uh what's,
what was, what was Colbert's
turn me made up truth
or
truthiness.
Truthiness. That's it. Right.
There's a certain element of truthiness to it.
It's,
you know, so here's the other thing I love about all this right is
in hindsight
when you think about
Santa is a service and everything that goes on here and how it all works. It's like,
it's so absurd
that
I, I can't even begin to describe it is you look at this all and it like it,
none of this even remotely makes sense and Children like they eat it up, they love it.
Right. It's,
I guess the bigger the lie, the easier it is. Right.
Well, what's interesting to me is just, you know,
yeah, as a culture we just buy into this and, like, happily,
well, it's fun to do it too. Right. Like, it's fun buying kids stuff. It's fun having,
you know, all the silly games we play and all the things we do and,
and it, it is what it is, I guess. Right.
Yeah. No, I mean, I'm certainly looking forward to it. Like, I mean,
the, you know, especially with little kids, I think I, once they,
from what I've seen, teenagers are not so fun around Christmas, dude,
teenagers aren't fun any time of year.
Right. Christmas is no exception.
This is one thing I've really noticed about parenting is parents seem to be
a lot more candid now about how much they really dislike their Children.
I
think some are, there's still a lot of snowflakes out there, man.
So, anyway,
so we've established, Santa is plausible.
It's, it's totally not plausible.
However, I think Santa's uh surveillance network is not out of the question.
The, the volume of or I guess the, the necessary amount of storage can and does exist.
Getting an internet connection to the North Pole
would no doubt be a significant challenge but not
impossible.
Especially if you already have a giant warehouse that is full of slave labor.
So why not just, you know, have a couple of them dig some holes in trenches.
So whatever we can deal with that, that's fine.
So it's, now, here's the other thing I wonder though is, let's say you have a multi
pab
byte database of various data on all of the people.
I wonder how long it would legitimately take to conduct searches over that data.
Like if you wanted to find all the people named John who are naughty.
-- I think
-- it depends on how much ra M you're
and servers you're willing to buy because you could,
you could hold that in memory,
right? With given enough servers, right? Like a petabyte.
Uh Well, let's say it's, you know, seven petabytes.
Well,
you divide by say 10 million servers and that's what
700 or seven gigs of ra M per server.
Well, let's just say a million because that makes the numbers come out easy.
So that would be
uh
you would need 7 million megabytes of ra M per server. So 7000 gigabytes.
-- So seven terabytes of ra M per
-- server. Not out
of the question,
you can buy instances on Amazon with two terabytes of RA M right now today.
Sure, sure, sure.
And there's some amount of overhead with metadata and whatnot. But
I wonder could you have
in in this actually something folks out there listening. Are there multi pab
byte databases today that are actually functional and usable?
I understand you could do certain things with no SQL.
But I would be interested in doing conducting
like some crazy sequel type searches where you're
looking for various unrelated bits of information and
then tying them together because you gotta think
even at a million servers getting those,
I,
I guess all pointed in the right direction and all
conducting the correct operations is a very nontrivial problem.
It's been done
really
designing a multi petabyte database for LLSST which if memory serves as the large
something something telescope,
right? It's a,
it's a 3.2 gigapixel camera essentially
taking, oh, here we go.
The 3.2 gigapixel LSLSST camera will produce approximately half a pet of die
by
uh sorry, half a petabyte of archive images every month.
So
six petabytes per year.
uh I guess the bad news is this is not only possible, but it's been done
well. OK. OK. No, no, but here's the difference, right.
Here's the difference is you're talking about enormous image files.
So practically speaking,
they're probably talking what maybe a couple of 100
or maybe a couple of 1000 image files per
day.
Why would
somebody break it up? And um
you know, because you'd also like
-- uh
-- but,
but here's my point,
here's the point is when we're talking about a database like Santa
has and this is even true of all surveillance databases on the planet
is you have lots of little pieces of data. It's not big pieces of data.
I mean, unless he's has full motion video or something.
And then obviously you also, his storage needs grow exponentially.
But when we're talking about tons of little pieces of data things get crazy.
One thing you can remember too is this database
would be very easy to partition and shard.
Oh, that's true. Because you could segment it by, by
continent or, or time zone.
Yeah, that's true. That's true.
You
know,
and maybe I here's a crazy idea. Does he maybe do it in real time?
Do what? In real time? Well, essentially if you know your delivery route, right?
Because obviously he solved the traveling salesman problem.
Oh, he solved the traveling salesman problem.
Sure, why not?
Yeah. So, so if he solved the traveling salesman problem, then,
then we don't
have
a
-- series of sequential lookups.
-- He could be grossly inefficient for all we know.
Right?
He doesn't necessarily mean he's delivering any
of this stuff in an efficient manner
and, or, or why bother solving it when you have Santa as a service, right?
You don't need to solve the traveling salesman
problem because everything's as a service salesman,
as a service, that's the solution, right?
So,
so they did the LSST multi pab
byte database on my SQL
and they also evaluated MS SQL server and IBM DB two.
And basically,
uh but it looks like my SQL worked for them because it has a partitioning engine.
Like that's the thing to remember, right?
Is, is problems that used to be like ridiculous scale problems.
Like I remember when,
well, here's a great example, folks go
run emacs and open a file larger than 10 megabytes.
And emacs gives you a warning that it's opening a very large file.
Right?
And I'm like, I don't think I have any, you know, like
I like,
and I remember when opening a one or two megabyte file was a big deal and actually
getting it to load without crashing and editing
it and saving it without crashing was like,
wow,
I have accomplished something.
-- I
-- can't even beat that. I remember when I was a cis
edin on some sun gear.
Way back in the day, we just, we uninstalled emacs because it used too much memory
when you
opened it.
So
everyone had to use V I
Yeah, I mean, the, the joke was eight megs and constantly swapping.
Right. Right.
You know, and now I,
yeah, I mean, so that's the thing to remember is a lot of these,
that's something I'm having to, you know, constantly remind myself is,
you know, these problems of scale we used to have, have
in many cases been solved and in many cases been solved
and just put into open source software and boom done.
Like,
you know, some of these message queuing uh software packages that can handle,
you know,
hundreds of thousands of messages a second with
like barely any tuning on a single server,
you know,
these databases like my SQL and post press SQL which can handle like abs
like literally absurd amounts of data would I think be the technical term,
you know, certain amounts of data
uh
you can buy, you know, one terabyte PC IE cards, you know, 16 channel cards with,
you know, that'll handle, I think, what was it like?
I was looking at one and it was half a million I OS per second, you know,
at four kilobytes each or something like,
again, for something like a database of this type, you know, being able to
pull 500,000 records a second.
And that's just a single card.
Obviously, you would have like many, many, many of these.
So it's definitely doable.
I think it's safe to say that that the
Santa Surveillance database is quite plausible in reality,
which is kind of crazy because actually when I
started writing this stuff down and thinking about it,
I'm like, oh ha ha.
This is funny. This can't happen
and really it, it, it kind of is,
you know,
I kind of want to do like just a little back of
the envelope spreadsheet looking at and this is like commercial pricing.
I'm sure Santa gets a discount because if not you get on the naughty list.
That's
true. That's
true.
That's right. He's got like mob style power here, right?
-- It be like, be a shame if something happened to that there,
-- those presents,
if they didn't uh,
-- or worse, it'd be a shame if something happened to your kids presence.
-- That's true.
Right. Right.
I mean, it's one thing to punish somebody but to get their kids to punish them,
that's a whole other level of pain.
It's
well known
evil. Right.
You go after the family, that's how you get to the person you're trying to reach.
But I'm thinking this actually wouldn't be as
difficult or expensive as we think because the biggest thing like, you know,
like it, you can just partition this database up,
you know, and that right there, you know,
solves a lot of problems.
Interesting.
Is there an Amazon data center at the North Pole?
Uh They just opened one up in Montreal like literally yesterday,
like a few days ago or it was at the beginning of December.
Um
So again, they're, they're gradually moving north,
you know, coincidence. I don't think so.
That's right. That's right. And cooling, right? Cheap cooling.
-- Let's
-- go for that most of the year. Yeah. Yeah. Just crank open the windows.
-- Yep.
-- Yep. Yeah.
Oh man.
All right. This has been
an awesome episode to say the least.
So
for the show notes and there will be many this time as we,
we talked about all kinds of crazy stuff.
It's open source security podcast.com
and
go there. We'll, we'll have links to all this fun stuff. It's,
I love this topic. It's been crazy to think about.
I've had a blast writing all these notes down throughout the week as,
as we discussed it.
And
if I don't know how many more of these will have before Christmas.
But I, if we don't catch anyone else before, then everyone have a fantastic holiday.
Whatever it is you may do
and
not do
or not do. That's true. We don't judge
and if nothing else
until next time,
take care.
Thanks, everybody.