Hello and welcome to episode 108 of open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
Well, we broke Bluetooth again.
Oh, yeah, like security. Not like it just stopped.
Yeah, I have,
I've got so many Bluetooth devices that will
work with most of our phones or computers,
but not like
all of them
like speakers that will pair with one phone but not the other phone,
things like that.
Yeah, I, I have similar problems.
Bluetooth is surprisingly flaky,
but we should probably explain this particular issue,
right?
Yeah. Well, so
it's not even worth explaining. I think basically elliptical curve,
elliptical curve cryptography is difficult
and if you don't do it right,
it doesn't work so good. And of course, what do software people do?
They don't do things, right?
That's the
nature of software's fault or is this hardware's fault? Is it both
anyway?
Well, ultimately, the hardware was designed by somebody who then, you know?
Ok. No, no, let's, it's a security podcast. We can't, we can't weasel our way.
All right. So ec DH
elliptical curve Diffie
Hellman
is what that is. And there's a
an algorithm, many of us may be familiar with called Diffie
Hellman, which is essentially a way
for you and I
to
share
like a public key each
and then use that to generate a private key.
Only the two of us know it's actually a very ingenious algorithm that
like without it, the much of the modern internet couldn't exist.
-- And
-- even more simply than that, it's a way for two parties to share a secret such that
a third party cannot see the secret
and both parties can be absolutely certain
that
they actually got the correct secret
from
sharing the correct secret.
There's a really cool video using paint.
I
see.
OK. I'll put it in the show notes, but it basically it gives a demo of
kind of how this works using paint, which is quite clever.
But anyway, anyway, so the issue being ec is just elliptical curve D
Hellman.
And basically there is an issue with the way the
algorithm works with certain Bluetooth devices it sounds like.
And essentially
the the device doesn't make sure that the divvy
Homan handshake happened correctly,
meaning the it sounds like an attacker and I won't lie.
I'm not an expert on this. I just read this today,
but it sounds like an attacker could essentially man in the middle,
certain Bluetooth handshakes
and render them such that the encryption key used is extremely weak
and then you could basically steal it and
and go from there, obviously decrypt all the Bluetooth communication. It
sounds more like a somewhat active man in the middle of his card. Quote.
From a certain note,
the device must also uh the devices rather must
also agree on the elliptical curve parameters being used,
right?
Obviously, you know, you,
you can't do VC DH D without agreeing on which curve frame you're gonna use.
And a bunch of them
didn't
like make sure that they were validating that they were using the same one.
Whoops,
you know, classic software. Whoopsy.
It happens.
It, I guess here's, here's what I keep thinking of though. Here is,
it sounds like some of the Bluetooth stacks on operating systems are at fault
and it also sounds like some of the devices,
all
of them,
it was Apple Broadcom, Intel, Qualcomm,
Microsoft Android, Bluetooth sig.
So that's like the standards group that does that Google
and the Linux kernel were all affected or sorry.
No affected was Apple Broadcom Intel, Qualcomm,
Microsoft was not affected.
And then the rest, the last four I listed are unknown, but
like Apple Broadcom and Intel and Qualcomm are all affected. Then it's,
that's pretty widespread.
Well, here's, here's what I'm wondering is,
and, and this can be more of a hypothetical question than anything is
my assumption is you're going to have to update the clients and the servers
and obviously updating an operating system is something that can be done.
But updating a lot of these devices, like, I,
I have a Bluetooth headset that costs like $5.
Oh,
-- yeah, that'll never get an update. Right. That's
-- never getting an update.
But does that mean then that the, the client that the,
that the computers are going to have
to support the broken Bluetooth handshake forever?
Uh, sort of, I mean, the, the, the, the real potential there would be, for example,
you have like a Bluetooth keyboard
and maybe I can now, you know, more likely impersonate the keyboard.
Right?
Sure.
But the client in theory, if they fix,
if they fix one end of the Bluetooth, then that end should refuse
to talk to the other side.
And so if you're fixing all the computers and phones and tablets,
then you don't really care if somebody can attack your keyboard.
Uh Maybe, right?
I don't know
in
I'm
saying in general, right?
Like in general, the concern more is that you're attacking the computer, you know,
you're Impersonating a keyboard
and sending keystrokes to the tablet saying, you know, like delete everything or
go send the banking password to this Russian,
whatever,
the more dangerous part of a keyboard is being able to sniff it and get the password,
right? Because I type my passwords on my keyboard.
This is, this is a marvelous segue
into the article Krems just published saying that thanks to UTU two F and UBI
keys that Google hasn't been fished in the last year.
Yep, that's like,
it's awesome. Right.
The first thing I thought of was like,
this is proof that fishing training doesn't work but U two F keys do work. Right.
Well,
I'm honestly at the point now we're
trying to solve technical security problems with people
that doesn't work and it doesn't scale. Right. It's like the spam problem.
Yeah, you could have a human being review all your email and delete all the spam.
You need like 400 of them,
400. You need at least one person per employee who gets email.
-- Well, no,
-- I mean, no, no, no, I meant 400 people per person.
-- I see
-- with the amount of spam I get.
It's insane. Exactly. You know,
I should say that I have no idea how much spam I get anymore.
Well, exactly,
because the computer works.
Um, and the same thing with, like, the fishing stuff is like,
yeah, like the, the human will be hyper vigilant and always
do the correct thing and never make a mistake.
No, that's not, that's literally the opposite of how people work. Right.
That is correct.
And more to the point is that cost effective. I know UTF keys are 50 bucks done.
You replace them? I don't know every couple of years.
If somebody accidentally smashes it with a hammer,
they're not 50 bucks,
they're, they're like $20 or less.
Well, I'm talking about the nice fancy ones that also do NFC wireless and all that.
-- Other stuff which you want
-- because whatever, nobody needs all that.
Yeah, you do if you want it on your phone.
I want my UTF key to work on my phone.
I do all my stuff on my phone now.
-- I,
-- I do a lot on my phone but I'm, I'm thinking
most of the logins on my phone
are now the result of an action I took on my computer though.
So I, I won't disagree with you.
-- Somewhat.
-- True. Yeah. Well, regardless, 20 to 50 bucks,
50 bucks is still cheaper than no offense.
An hour of employee time taking fishing training,
that's 50 bucks of lost productivity.
Right.
Wait, I bet you could buy them five
UB keys
because most of the fishing training is like a couple
hours, if not days.
Yeah, totally. And, and let's see, from, from what I've read
when you, before fishing training you'll probably have like,
30% of your employees clicking fishing links and after you'll have, like, 20%.
So,
it's not a good investment.
And not only that,
I bet you're paying more per employee than the cost of a UBK per employee.
Right.
Well, a lot of this stuff is like some BS online course. That's not very,
you know, I,
you click through it as fast as you can because you got work to do.
Really?
-- Wait.
-- I'm, I'm what? No, no, you're not supposed to do that.
You're supposed to go through the course and and pay
attention and then take the test at the end.
Yeah, I, I've, I personally
met people
through as fast as,
like, like you and me for
hands
up.
Oh, man. I, I remember at, at,
there was
an employer. I
know
exactly.
And we would have contests to see who
could complete the training the fastest every year.
I, I got it down because it was the same training with the same exam every year.
I got it down to about 1520 minutes and, and in fairness though,
I actually remember the answers because it was pretty clear that like
you shouldn't take bribes to build a bad orphanage that then burns down.
Like I generally would agree that that's a bad don't thing.
Well, you know,
it always amused me about some of those questions is
there were questions that are legally acceptable but morally wrong
and I'd always get this wrong.
No, I would not do that. Like, no, no, it's perfectly legal to do this.
And it's like, I don't care, I'm not doing it right.
So, anyway, anyway, no, that's,
I love,
I love my, you know,
it always makes me laugh is when you explain how to use a up key to somebody
because a lot of two factor authentication stuff is a right pain in the ass, right?
You have to either install an app on your phone and then you have to
like take screenshots of QR codes or you have to type in stuff or,
or you have to like badge your administrator to mail something
out and then you like have to sync the token or,
you know, blah, blah, blah, right. UB key. You like
literally
um it arrives in the mail and you uh stick it into,
like you go to a site that wants to set it up, like, say Google or github
or whatever.
So you plug this little USB thingy into the computer and
the little green light goes on and then you touch it
right?
And that's it.
There's, there's, that's it, that, that basically syncs it
to that
service, Google github,
whatever,
you know, because basically every UB key has like a built in like little
secret and a random number generator and all that good stuff.
And so
yeah, basically you have to,
you have to register the UB key with um sort of each site you're going to use it with.
But that registration basically consists of plugging it in and
touching the little copper pad that has a green light
in
the really important thing with U two
F. Is that
what's you?
It's,
I don't even know what it stands for. It's the
Fido alliance, it's universal
two factor, universal factor.
Thank you.
So U two
F, what it does though is
when I go to say google.com
and it wants me to put my U two F key in
the, the URL and this is why Google has
not the URL or right? The host name, I'm sorry, the host name, google.com
is packaged up with some other information and then basically sent to the U key,
right?
And it's, it's basically a hash goes to the UE key
and it's kind of like challenge response where there's
like a uh like think about public key encryption,
right?
Where there's kind of like a key on the on the U A key
encryption key.
And when I hit the button, it transforms the data,
the browser sent it and then sends back a response.
And so
the reason phishing doesn't work with this and you can still fish people
with like S MS or even the the number generator on their phones
is because the the domain I am visiting in my web browser is part of the challenge.
If I go to
google.com,
I will not get a proper response.
So the fishing side doesn't work. But the in theory man in the middle could work
but any well, no, no, let me finish please.
But
anybody doing this is gonna be using TLS correctly pretty much,
right? If it was over an unencrypted http channel,
in theory,
it could maybe be man in the middle
like essentially you could proxy the authentication request,
you could not.
Uh
No, no,
I mean once you get in like so you UTF uh authenticate to Google Google
hands you back a token over a clear text channel that's what I'm talking about.
It
does
not
work that
way. You can't act,
no, no.
What I'm saying is the actual UTF itself can't be man in the middle.
But then what the UTF sets up like where Google hands
-- you a token or a cookie
-- or you mean like whatever,
man, if you're doing that
and that's my point.
That's my point, right? Everybody now does TLS because, well, for one thing,
our, as of what is
as of today, our web browsers
because this isn't coming out for weeks
of
July
Day.
Yeah. As of July 2018, you know, Google Chrome now labels insecure websites
or rather labels http websites as insecure now rather than labeling htps as secure
that
-- which
-- is great
and it's totally the right way to do it, right. It's one of those things where
these small changes are going to have huge impacts.
Yeah.
Um but yeah, no UTF itself is pretty much
I'm not gonna say un hackable, but
as we understand cryptography,
yeah, it's, it's, yeah, you're, you're, you're ok.
And as long as you don't do something totally dumb,
like use UTF and then hand a token over http
-- Yeah. No, you're fine.
-- But that's not even U two F has nothing to do with that.
That's just,
that's what, but the thing is U two F only does the authentication. You still,
no, but the thing to remember, right is UTF doesn't exist in a vacuum,
you have to have other stuff wrapped around it.
Right. Like it's not like IUTF and then magically my email works.
The majority of this stuff is being used with a website. So, right.
So the website still has to do authentication properly. But
the good news is well as you pointed out and I think you did this presentation where,
you know, that's a framework problem. Go use a good framework.
That's it. That's just literally go pick one of these like frameworks
that is well known and reliable and they all do authentication
proper.
Exactly.
Well, it's even easier than that. Just don't do off anymore. Right.
Let people log in with Google.
That's,
please
don't ask for access to all my email and documents. When, when I do do that,
that's a secondary problem.
And, and I,
I still wish Google had the ability for me to like uncheck those boxes and say yes,
I want to log in,
but no, I don't want you.
Exactly.
And I love that you can like,
do that on Android now or you can just take away permissions to stuff
and I love it when I start something up.
But it's like, please, sir, can I have access to your location? Like? Nope,
sure can't.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, I, I get some apps legit needed location
data while I'm using it like
apple maps,
but not like all the time. Like when I'm ordering,
you know, it's a pizza app or whatever.
Yep. Yep. Exactly. Exactly. I love it when web browsers ask for my location.
Just, no, you can't have it. You know, I'm not going to let you
send alerts to my computer either. Right.
People didn't abuse it. It could in theory be really cool. Right.
Like, for new sites for, like, weather alerts and stuff.
But no, no, it's going to be used to spam
you
totally. And I love that. Like,
80% of the websites I go to ask if I want to enable alerts for this site. And it's like,
yeah.
No,
-- no,
-- I
100% of people accidentally click. Yes,
-- that's
-- all I can figure. Maybe 10
percent.
Well, or some bright spark thought it was a good idea.
Pushed it through a committee and then, you know, some poor
had to implement it even though it's like a terrible idea and everybody hates it,
-- like, from a user perspective.
-- Right. Maybe,
maybe anyway. Anyway. All right, man. So we, we, we also wanted to talk about air gaps
which are vaguely related to Bluetooth according to you, which I disagree with, but
we'll get there.
Well, no, I mean, just in the sense of,
I think a lot of people misunderstand what an air gap actually is.
Uh because I mean, you got to remember like air gapping computers.
Well, it used to be the default state. We did not have networks,
right? Like
prior to the internet.
Having a computer on a network was
pretty rare.
Yeah.
Well, I remember, like, all the computers I used as a kid at school, like,
there was no network.
Like what, you know, there was, they were like boss boxes with floppy drives that
they
were,
-- that was,
-- you know, we played a local
turtle.
Turtle was the best.
Yeah.
Yeah. But, uh, so, I mean,
and then I think there's a lot of misunderstanding about why you would want an air
gap network because I think people always focus
on the being attacked part of air gapping.
But forget about
for a lot of people that air gap, it's actually more about the the data exfiltration
piece than it is about stuff coming in.
Uh I can see it both ways.
I mean, you can argue what was,
what was the name of the virus that ruined the centrifuges?
That
was
that you're right.
I was thinking something else anyway, right?
Like that's an instance of going in was clearly more
dangerous than coming out.
But
I feel like it goes both ways.
And
so, so anyway, let's
start at the beginning.
And what is an air gap? What is the intention of an air gap?
-- So
-- the idea behind an air gap network is,
is you have a computer or a computer network even
that is not attached to any external network,
-- which nowadays is a way to save
-- the internet.
Like there's maybe a gap of air between two different networks.
-- Yeah,
-- there's literally ideally no
physical link between this computer network and
the general internet or anything attached to the internet,
even if it's all firewalled and everything.
Right.
So the idea being that, you know,
some schmuck on the internet literally just cannot touch your network,
right? They would have to physically go to wherever it is
and try to hack it by getting
physical,
you know, I was talking to somebody. This is like 100 years ago.
And there are one way network devices
that can go from kind of like the the general internet to
an air gamp network, but they literally can only send data in one direction.
As you can imagine, the challenges here is
you need to build massive redundancy into your protocol because
you literally have no idea if a packet gets dropped.
-- And
-- so well, what I've seen actually, and this was like 1520 years ago,
was a device that
it was basically two physical computers sharing a memory,
like a physical memory device.
Uh And there was sort of an interlock,
so only one of the computers could read and write to the memory,
the physical memory device at a time.
And then there was a really well defined sort of,
it's just, it's like a file system, right? It's not like a network
thing, it's just like a file system.
And so essentially, you know, it's like,
it's, it's essentially you're sharing like a pad of paper, right?
So I hand the pad of paper to you, you, you read it,
you write on it,
you're done,
you hand it back to me and then I can read
whatever was previously written on it by myself or by you
and I can erase it and write new stuff.
And so the idea was that way you could transfer files
uh to and from an air gapped network in a very controlled way.
And the device also had things like
you could have um like filter, you know,
you had filtering expressions on both sides of what was allowed in and out, right?
So like, oh, you know, we're only going to allow like a CS V file with like,
like, you know, 20 characters for first name, 20 characters for last name,
the social insurance number and like what their balance is,
-- you know, things like that kind of, right? So
-- that's interesting.
The device I I learned of here was using fiber optics with the intent being
by using a piece of glass and literally having
the there was no hardware to transmit on the receiving end.
You didn't have to worry about it.
There was literally no way to make that send back across the line at all.
And that's where a lot of this comes in is that data exfiltration piece of, you know,
certain types of data
are incredibly valuable, not even to a targeted attacker, but just in general
you know,
um, or the,
the data being public could be horrendously embarrassing
to say a government or a company,
you know?
Ok. Well, so, so
the real reason this topic is being discussed is there's a story on
the register about Russia hacking us power plants over air gap networks.
And so this kind of comes back to the idea of
air gaps don't really exist,
right?
There's just
vast and slow networks,
right?
Air gaps are so incredibly painful because for example,
how do you get security updates to your computers?
Now, how do you get antivirus updates to your computer?
Now, how do you get any of the data you need to work with, to your computer? Now,
how do you get any of that data out into a reporting system?
So you can generate a nice spreadsheet for your boss every month, right? Like
the whole point.
Generally speaking of computers and data is
to share and mingle the data
to add value to it or to extract value from it.
Right. That's kind of the point. That's why the internet works so well.
Right.
And so there's very, very few use cases where you can like live without that,
you know, where you're like, yeah, whatever this thing exists, like you,
you can't have a bank that's offline because like, how,
how would I go get money from my account?
You know? Right. Like
-- it's all sorts of things,
-- you know. However, however,
apparently these power plants were air gapped and they were still hacked.
So, in theory and,
and the simple reason for this is because most
of these power plants have really old skater systems,
you know, supervisory control and data acquisition networks.
Most of these network protocols are sold.
They don't have any concept of authentication
or even remote security built into them.
Right. They're just
-- like open wide message buses,
-- which is probably why they were air gamp.
Yeah.
Well, uh no,
the reason they were air gapped originally is because they didn't talk TCP/IP.
Right.
They, again,
it was like the technology is sold and crafty or crafty rather that they
don't talk like what you and I think of as a network protocol,
like they have sort of network protocols, but they're like,
meant to be used like within a factory not
to have the factory talk to some other system. You know what I mean?
Um So no,
the reason they were air gapped originally is because
the technology was just old and crap and,
you know, you can't retrofit this stuff to talk to CP IP.
Well, you can now, but
you probably don't want to.
Well, except you do want to.
So you do and then you end up with a sort of, but not really air gap, you know, network
whatever.
Um But even the ones that are still physically air gapped, you know,
there's people swapping data around on USB keys
or
so you
know,
what happened is most of the time you've got some sort of technician with a laptop
and he literally unplugs his laptop from
the network over here and then goes and plugs it in to the
Skater system or in some cases they're still connected to the Wi Fi
and then they plug into the Skater system and it's like, you've just, like,
ruined everything, you know.
Well, the problem there is is that a laptop,
by definition is smart enough to run some code actively,
that the code can be smart enough to like go poke away the skater system and break in.
You know, like for example, if you, well, a better example, no,
that's a terrible example.
USB key I was going to say might be a better example,
but it's actually bad because USB keys again can
cause code execution on the remote system.
Um Same thing even with burned C DS, right?
A lot of air gap networks to transfer data back and forth, they will burn a CD.
Um
because then they feel like, you know, number one, it's easy to verify,
right?
Worst case example,
you can actually get a good optical microscope and like look at it.
Um you know, so you can't, well, no, the point is you can't really hide data, right?
It's, it's there or it's not
right. There's not like USB where you got this wonky
control chip that can
potentially be hacked to do things that are weird.
There's also the fact that when you,
when, when a CD is used to traverse a gap,
you're not supposed to ever put it in another computer,
you're supposed to destroy it after the data is copied just in case
somehow
something was copied back on the, the CD, which burnable C DS you can, I mean,
whatever, there's weird stuff you can do.
But, I mean, fundamentally,
right.
Yeah.
And,
but fundamentally this makes it so painful to use a computer
and the data and whatnot that like almost nobody does it
right? Because generally speaking sharing works,
lets us do things that are useful.
So, and then, then the problem of course is that even if you have,
let's assume for a moment you have a properly air gapped network, right?
Let, let's just say for the sake of argument,
you have a really old computer with no network card,
the serial ports are glued shut, you only have a PS OK.
For those of you that are younger, a PS two port,
it's like a round thing with pins that you plug your keyboard and mouse into.
Uh and let's say it is video out.
So it's like super, you know, old, even with physical access,
it would be a pain to get data off of it.
Well,
the thing is that computer still does things like probably as a built in speaker,
for example,
you can still make the computer generate like electromagnetic
energy and interference by monkeying with the CPU,
for example.
Right.
Uh There's all sorts of secondary channels that are not designed to carry data.
But, you know, for example, if you have a speaker on a computer,
you could make a play Morse code
and have another computer. Listen,
there's some group out of like Israel that does
all these wacky things with ex filtrating data off of
like,
does your
computer
have a blinking,
does your keyboard have a light on it that can be made to blink by the computer?
Like blinking lights and audio? And there's even one that they used like thermal
uh using, using the thermal signatures of the CPU to send
data.
It's completely
insane. But again, there's no such thing as an air gap. Like that's the lesson here.
-- Well,
-- that's the problem is to properly air gap, a computer,
you also then need to have it in like a tempest, shielded heat shield
-- shield room.
-- Humans are there like humans are the problem
unless you lock the door and don't let anybody in.
Now, your,
your
network is useless. But there's at least no people,
people are the problem like this goes back to the fishing problem. Right.
It's all people, people are the problem.
Yeah.
So fundamentally, I think like outside of like about three or four really rabid,
insanely corner corner cases.
Air gapping is,
yeah. No, it's,
it's something that will
not so much ultimately fail from a security point of view,
but we just ultimately fail from like trying to do anything useful.
Here's the other thing I think about a lot around things like air gaps is so now
if there,
if there's anyone like legitimately from the intelligence community listening,
uh
you're probably laughing at us
and that's fine. That's fine. Right.
But I'm thinking from the context of like a power plant,
if, if you, if you have an air gap system, you're going to be lazy
because you're gonna think, oh, nobody can attack this. So I don't care.
I don't have to install security updates.
I don't have to worry about login and passwords. Right.
I don't need any of this stuff.
And so this is a place where I have a suspicion
that having an air gap network is actually far more dangerous than if you just
plug the freaking thing into the internet because then at least you'd be like,
oh, crap, it's on the internet.
I need to protect this stuff.
Well, the other problem too is the discipline needed to maintain that air gap when,
you know, like, oh, man, I really want to get this data off this thing quickly.
Ok. You know what? Just plug the laptop into it,
you know, turn the Wi Fi on and just SCP the data out quickly.
Don't tell anybody you did.
I
just plug this
cable in for a few minutes. It'll be fine. Yeah,
exactly.
You know, we'll just stick it or we'll use it, you know, like the Stuxnet guys.
Oh, we'll just use a USB key. Those things are safe
in the
parking
lot, you know. It's ok.
Yeah.
Oh, I love that because, well, realistically if you find a random USB key, you,
you have two choices, you either throw in the garbage
-- or you plug it into something and see what's
-- on it.
Normal people plug it in,
I
guarantee it.
Yeah, because they're nice and normal.
Like, it's like when you find a wallet you open it up to see whose it is.
Not because you want to rob them. But like, oh, there's a driver's license here.
Great.
-- You know, or you give it to the cops or whatever.
-- Right.
Right. Right. You know,
I, I, um, sort of, I don't know
when I find
a
set of
keys,
I find a USB key on the ground and I, I feel like I've actually never found one on.
What is this? I want to know what's on it.
And of course,
unfortunately my better sense always tells me to throw it away and I always do
but like, there's a part of me that
it's, it's like the forbidden fruit.
-- Where are you
-- finding all these random USB keys, like, at conferences or something?
-- I don't find lots of them. Um, I find quite a few.
-- I never found
one.
Uh, lots of hotels. If you walk around hotels, you just for whatever reason.
Find a lot of USB keys, especially if you're near, if there's like public terminals,
there's
quite often they're already plugged in there
that where people, like, plug them in and leave
and, and again, it's like, they're like the forbidden
-- because
-- they went and got like, like a $2 USB key to get that one
file off their computer so they could print it or whatever.
And I've actually done that before too where I've,
I've gotten a USB key just for that reason where, like,
I copy a file onto it and then I bring it to the hotel
business computer and then I,
I print it and then I throw the USB key away because I'm like,
I'm never using this again.
Well, you know, the reality is like USB devices can trivially
be
any public computer. Who knows what that thing is? Right.
I, I know I, every time I see someone checking their email in a public computer,
I just want to, like,
grab them by the shoulders and shake them and scream what is wrong with you?
-- Like, every
-- time, you know, it's like licking soup off the floor,
it's worse than that.
It's, uh, oh, my goodness.
I, because like the thought of lifting soup off the floor while really gross,
-- appalls me less than using a public
-- computer soup
-- off the floor at an airport.
-- Uh, that, that would be pretty bad.
But I'm still, I'm thinking I would still, I would still do that before.
I would check my email on a public computer. I'm not going to lie to you.
Like I would do that first because at least looking soup off the floor,
I'm pretty comfortable understanding what's going to happen to me
using that public computer. I have no idea.
It's too many unknowns.
Oh,
man.
So,
I guess the moral of the story is it's ok that you
soup off the floor as long as you don't use public computers.
Anyway.
I, I probably set myself up for that.
So
fantastic, I guess. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for making it this far.
If you, if you want the show notes,
you can go to open source security podcast.com
and,
and check out our, our Facebook group. We've got a Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag I ju I just keep thinking about soup on the floor now like
you've ruined my day. Uh Anyway, thank you, everyone for listening.
Thank you, Kurt. Have, have a great rest of your day. You too.
Thanks.
Bye bye.