Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Ransomware Crime.
Josh Pressers.
Now,
I
don't think I've ever been involved in any ransomware crime that I know of.
So this topic, holy cow. It's all I have to say.
We put this on the calendar maybe a week or two ago before the timer recording.
And in that week,
I think what I thought we were going to
talk about has probably drastically changed at least three times
like what is going on.
I mean,
I basically titled this. So, so we, we track all of our episodes and get, um
and the title of this issue at the moment is like,
what the hell is going on with ransomware?
And
maybe I don't know if that'll be the title when it comes out.
But like, I don't even know where to start right now.
There's a couple of things that are most interesting to me.
Number one that this has now made
the media
like we had, you have reporters at a White House press briefing,
you know, saying, asking, I'm going to say it asking stupid questions and yes,
folks.
I'm sorry, there are stupid questions,
asking stupid questions. Like, you know, like ransomware seems to be somehow
caused or correlated with the new administration coming in.
Like, no, like ransomware has been a massive problem. It's just,
there hasn't been a very public ransomware attack
that actually affected America in a meaningful way,
ignoring things like not
pua,
like Maersk almost collapsed, you know, kind of a big shipping line.
I won't disagree that there's a correlation here but it's the same way there,
there's a subreddit that I forget the name of it.
But it basically, it's,
these people take completely unrelated graphs and they overlay
them pretending there's some and it'll be things like,
like, right, like this peanut butter sales versus, you know,
shark attacks or something,
two clearly unrelated events
that,
and, and this is the same thing like, yes, we have a new administration.
Yes, we have more ransomware,
but we don't have more ransomware because we have a new administration,
huge ransomware attacks. But, and I think part of it
and this is gonna maybe sound
anti-american but
like when you mess with certain things in America, they care,
like messing with their gasoline prices
cares
because as we saw people filling up grocery sacks with gasoline
in their trunk.
Well, and apparently that that kind of plastic is actually ok to store gasoline.
But obviously, you know, if there's anything sharp in the trunk that's going.
Oh, really? I, I didn't know, you could actually put gasoline in those.
-- Well,
-- if it's the same kind of plastic as a plastic gas can,
I see
that's
fine. The only, well, the only caveat being as mechanically it may not be
strong enough.
We're not. Ok.
Look, if you listen to this podcast and you don't understand why putting
any liquid in a garbage bag is a bad idea.
Well, if you've ever taken the garbage out and had to dribble all over the floor.
-- Right.
-- Anyway,
anyway,
imagine that it's a couple of gallons of gasoline.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna set that bar and say,
I expect all of our listeners to understand why putting
liquid in a plastic bag is a bad idea.
-- Well,
-- and not just liquid but flammable liquid.
Anyway,
anyway, I do think you are correct that when people mess with,
with petrol in the US, everyone understands that
the American lifestyle for those of you who don't live here,
it is heavily dependent on personal automobiles.
And so when the price of gasoline increases,
it affects people in a very personal way that annoys them.
You would not believe how much people complain about
the price of gasoline in the United States.
And then you go to Europe and it's like four times expensive. It's hilarious.
I remember when I was in the USA few years ago
and literally one of the ads on TV, for one of the gas station companies,
their tag line was fill up on a tank of freedom.
And the idea being that like, no,
that you had this car and you could drive wherever you want and do whatever you want,
right? The American dream.
Let's not,
let's not turn this into an analysis of what's wrong with America today.
I think it's unique in that.
Well, and then like a week later we have that attack on J BS which is
like the,
it's the world's largest global beef supplier. And again,
-- you mess with Americans hamburgers. Don't do that.
-- That's true.
People love hamburgers here anyway.
Anyway, so here's what makes this even more crazy.
So there was the pipeline ransomware which they paid,
there was the J BS ransomware which I don't know if they paid that one or not. And then
a little bit after that, we find out that the FBI has reclaimed
the pipeline ransom payment somehow. We don't know exactly how they've done it yet.
-- Well,
-- I imagine with that much Cryptocurrency,
you're going to want to wash it or run it through an exchange.
Well, and so here are the,
here are the theories I have heard and at the time of recording,
none of these are terrified in any way.
This is pure speculation.
The there's also a story about how the FBI basically like took over this encrypted.
-- Well, no, they
-- didn't take over it. They built it.
-- Oh,
-- they built it from scratch,
but basically the FBI was selling criminals secure cell phones
which apparently weren't very secure.
-- It turns out
-- well, no, it was an app for like it was a signal style app for criminals.
So there's the, the theory of the FBI is running
a crypto
washing service.
And so when they saw the will say right amount of money come in from the right place.
They were like, oh, this is ours now, too bad. There's a theory that the FBI somehow
acquired access to the wallet through there will say illicit hardware,
-- no technical means is the term you want.
-- Sure. Ok. Ok. That's better.
But right, so they, they had access to a hot wallet,
which if you're in the Cryptocurrency world,
you know that
being a hot wallet is a terrible idea.
Well,
but the problem is you when you're receiving three
or multiple millions of dollars in ransomware payments,
it,
it has to be in hot wallets at some point at the beginning
of the transition because it's not like you can just bump it offline
like you have to transfer the money into your wallet like online.
Ok, so no, here, here's how this would work actually because I've,
-- I've used to do this
-- with so like this came
up on the cipher trace episode where you know,
people do take ransoms and then
let it sit and get cold,
so to speak.
But
-- like I need to pay the rent now. I
-- mean, maybe
so the, the way you would normally handle large quantities of crypto.
And this is things like Coinbase, does this as well.
So this isn't just for criminals is the fact
that you would generally want to generate a wallet,
kind of, you know,
on a computer not connected to the internet or not connected to any networks at all.
You generate your wallet, you transfer just the public portion of the wallet and,
and then say, here's the address you send the money to
the money gets sent and then
you have basically a single use computer that you're going to put the private key on,
use that to move the money and then destroy that computer.
And it is obvious that is not what was done here.
-- Well,
-- or even if it was done when they maybe went to the washing service or something,
we, we don't know exactly what happened, but that's, that's part of what makes this
just kind of bananas and, and I guess
we will come, you can cover all these topics.
But the thing I think that really is in my brain over all of this,
everything going on is I feel like for the last decade,
the criminals have been light years ahead
of law enforcement in terms of capabilities.
And I feel like in the last month law enforcement,
like they clapped back and holy cow.
Well, and a big part of the problem too is a lot of these gangs operate out of,
for example, Russia.
-- Where they're effectively state sanctioned.
-- Some of them do.
Actually the pipeline, the Biden, the,
this is another thing the Biden administration said
a couple days ago that
they believe we'll believe in quotes.
The pipeline ransomware was not state sponsored by Russia.
Well, no, I don't mean, I don't, I didn't, I don't mean state sponsored.
I'm saying state sanctioned. Yeah,
we have this group of Russian hackers that is creating problems for
Western nations and extracting money from them.
Oh,
that is so terrible.
We must do something about this at once.
Right. Right.
It's, I mean, and this is what just makes all of this mixed together in this pot.
So, mind boggling and strange,
it's so hard to explain this stuff. It's so weird
and I feel like the more I learn, the less I know.
Well, II,
I really wonder how much ransomware has been going on out of the news because
I remember what was it? I want to say about three, maybe four or five years ago.
Remember Bitcoin? All of a sudden a lot of companies started buying Bitcoin
and I was like, huh?
And then somebody I know who works with law enforcement.
He's like, oh, yeah, they're all buying it for, to, for ransomware payments.
Like to have it ready to go because here's the thing, I'm a company,
let's put $100,000 into Bitcoin.
So if a ransomware incident happens, we can just pay it and move on
in days. Right.
Oh, I agree. Yeah. I mean, as much as I hate it
and as much as I think we should not pay ransomware and, you know,
you don't pay kidnappers because then you create a market for kidnapping.
Yeah. As a company I get why they would do it because also it's not illegal.
It's interesting.
You mentioned the pay kidnapper thing because that's
a legit economy in parts of the world.
Like, I know people who have been kidnapped, paid their ransom and then got out.
-- But
-- here's the thing in North America,
the FBI and the RCP Canada essentially
said we're not going to tolerate that behavior
and,
and in public that is their stance and in
many instances we'll say that is probably true.
But there are places that is not true at all.
Well, yeah, it's, I mean,
here it's rare enough that when a kidnapping
for money happens it makes the national news.
-- Right? Whereas in Colombia that's Tuesday.
-- I know
a nontrivial number of people who have been ransomed
and
I don't know many who've paid and most of them didn't pay because they didn't know how
and they wanted to and they were like, help me buy Bitcoin.
I'm like, no, I'm not, I'm not helping. I'm not being a part of this.
I bet you there are thousands a day at least.
Well, I mean, can you really blame some dental office with one guy that does it?
-- For them and has no backups.
-- Right. Absolutely.
It's tough because, like, what's the alternative? You go out of business?
Well, so funny enough. My, my wife is on the board of a local museum.
Right. It's down the street from my house and
they're always having tech problems and their tech person
used to be someone who worked with the museum
that then,
like, they, they, they left the area
and now they're like, we don't have any tech people.
And I'm like, well, yeah,
that's because you don't use freaking volunteers to run your tech.
Like this is what happens.
They're like, will you do it?
And I'm like, no, I'm not doing this because I'm on the hook for all this crap and like,
I'm not, no, you, you get trapped
and, and I get it when you're a small business or something. It's super hard.
Well, not really.
You hire AAA managed service provider and M MSP and
-- you pay the MSP to manage your stuff
-- now now.
But I will say like,
I know some people who run like little local consulting places,
they're like 20 years behind.
They're all about, oh,
you got to run a server in the closet and you got
to run your own exchange and all this and it's like,
just put all this crap in office.
-- 365.
-- Both my accountant and lawyer have a server
and I've confirmed with both of them that they have a tape well, not a tape.
And that's a classic one. They have a tape, but no, they
have
a tape rope,
you know,
-- and they also back up to the cloud and I'm like, cool. Good enough.
-- Anyway.
Anyway, so, ok,
I don't want to get into a discussion about
small business.
It's, it's, I think the problem is
there's a market for this because the numbers
we're seeing is there have been some ransomware payments
that are
in the millions,
like seven and eight figures of us dollars at the time of the ransom.
Now, obviously with Bitcoin prices and stuff.
Yeah. Well, what's really comical to me is some of those previous ransoms paid,
man. I hope they help those Bitcoins because, wow, you know, Bitcoin had a good year.
I remember when a ransom would be like five or 10 Bitcoins and that was like 500 bucks.
Exactly.
-- Not anymore.
-- But the problem is it creates a market and
like if the bad guys make two or $3 million that's going to fund a lot
-- more misery and criminal activity. And
-- this is a mind
boggling industry as well.
I will try to find a link but I listened to a podcast on,
I think it was uh cipher from the Vice
folks,
vice.com and they were explaining how the business model of all this
ransomware works where you can basically go to a company in,
I think they were in ST Petersburg, mostly Russia
and basically say, like I want to run a ransomware campaign.
This is what I want this many
people to get rooted or, or whatever terminology you want to use and
you pay them some money and then it's on you to, to take it from there.
This is nothing new. We saw that with the old uh email phishing.
But when email phishing was still, you know, sophisticated,
even just being able to send an email that looked like it was from a bank
was beyond most people's capability.
And so you like, I'm talking 20 years ago, like this is back when I worked,
like this is in 1998 and 99.
So actually more than 20 years ago
and they, they literally,
these software guys would come out like now with support for Ebay,
you know, and, and when I say support for ebay, I mean,
like it would send out emails that looked exactly like they were from ebay or,
and also have like
the web page and login screen that looked exactly like ebay
and harvested credentials, you know, for all the banks.
Like you got to remember 20 plus years ago, there was no such thing as two fa for,
for people using, you know, web banking or paypal or,
I mean,
I remember actually getting an RS a token for paypal
and talking with one of their employees about it.
And he's like, yeah,
even internally we can't get people to use these
things because they're such a pain in the ass.
Well, and I remember talking with one of the local school techs and he's like,
we are having a real problem rolling out RS a tokens
because our older teachers can't type the number in fast enough,
I suppose. Right.
You get a 70 year old teacher,
like a 70 year old kindergarten teacher and you want her to like,
whack in a six digit RS, a token code on her computer to use the D.
-- No, no, Miss Miss Grindle can't do that. I,
-- I feel that there's, there's
probably a term
that describes this feeling, but like any time
I'm looking at the two factor off app on my phone and it's like less than five seconds,
there's like this angst I feel of can I make it?
Can I not make it? And I'm like, I'm too slow now, I'm too old.
This isn't a video game like I will not make this,
just wait for it to flip and then do it again.
Exactly.
Yeah.
But
-- I can relate to
-- that, this kind of thing where, you know, you buy a
software package that allows you to then just
like literally these people would go buy a list of email addresses,
-- go buy a software package, basically smash the two together and
-- profit.
I mean,
I think ransomware now is the natural
evolution of these industries because obviously,
if we think about these criminal, so
where creators
as entrepreneurs, they're going to go where the money is and of course,
sending phishing mails is probably not profitable anymore.
But ransomware, there's a lot of profit in that.
So let's head in that direction,
especially like I look at my email inbox and it blows my mind that I still
do get some degree of spam through because it seems so obviously spammy to me.
But at the same time when I look at how much,
like I know how much spam I'd be getting if I ran an unfiltered email address.
Right, because I've run email servers on the public internet and I know
like it's bonkers,
-- that's why we quit.
-- Exactly.
We admitted defeat and we let someone else do the hard work and I get that and,
and I mean, honestly,
I think part of the ransomware story is going
to be a same outcome where we're just going,
I have to admit defeat
and outsource a crap load of this stuff to someone else.
Well, and I mean, I've already, you know, for example,
I use a cloud based backup of all our Google Drive stuff because not
because I'm worried about ransomware and not because I'm worried about an attack,
but I'm worried about somebody fat fingering nuking a
directory and then emptying the trash and being like,
whoops, it's gone because we actually had,
it happened twice now where somebody bought a new Huawei phone
and the calendar up on the Huawei phone,
at least in the past had some sort of glitch where,
when it like syncs to your Google account,
it just cleans out the calendars that have been shared to you.
What,
what a weird bug.
So not your calendar, but the ones shared to you that you have right access to.
And so we literally twice had all of our scheduled events white and
this is like three months after Google had added the whole delete something.
Calendar goes to the trash bin. It doesn't go away forever.
And I'm like, thank you, thank you, Google.
Like no, because otherwise I would have been up
like I would have been in a situation of like, well that it's gone.
I remember doing that in the early days where I would accidentally delete
an invite and like
-- it was gone. You never come back
-- too
bad. You don't get to go to that meeting
and don't get me wrong sometimes that was for the best. But
it blows my mind.
I get 20 years ago that when you deleted data,
you kind of expected it to be gone because also we didn't have a ton of space.
But nowadays,
like I, I don't delete data. My Google drive is some ungodly huge pile of garbage.
Oh my Lord. 110.19 gigabytes used. What's in there? Oh, that's pretty good.
And the answer is,
-- I don't know or care anymore because I've
-- search their search kind of blows,
but that's another story,
-- but it's better than a pile of local files.
-- Oh, yes,
for sure.
What gets me is that, you know, this,
it needs to sort of fundamentally transition and
shift sort of how they think about things
because
here's my concern about ransomware.
If you are vulnerable and not to the leak part,
because the leak part confidentiality, that's hard.
But if you're, if you're vulnerable to the integrity and availability of your data,
like if somebody encrypts your file system and it's gone and you don't have that
-- well. But what if the building burns down or you drop the computer? Right.
-- Right.
I think it's just, it's an un,
a previously unknown threat against your infrastructure, right.
-- Where it is comparable to fire. You
-- know, it's like getting a cold.
It's gonna happen at some point if you're vulnerable.
Like, yeah, like every time I let myself get stressed and run down, bam, I get a cold,
you know, except for last year where I got pneumonia, which was worse,
infinitely worse than a cold.
The one thing we saw with organized crime, if you remember back in the day,
especially with Capone.
I'm talking, like, way back in the day is they got Capone on tax fraud, right. They,
with the drug trade,
the one thing they realized is we can't stop the drug trade,
but we can follow the money.
And that's what I find curious is if they can
find ways to follow the money and recover most of it.
-- Well, that's a problem for the criminals. I mean.
-- Right.
And I think that's the expected next step in the
evolution of this game of cat and mouse is,
I think as law enforcement catches up to what the criminals are capable of doing now,
which it looks like that's happening, which is awesome.
That means the criminals are going to have to evolve
-- into something else.
-- I suspect we'll see
thing, like,
as well where the law enforcement can deal with
large crimes but they can't deal with small crimes.
Like, if your bicycle gets stolen, I'm sorry, your bicycle got stolen.
I hope it's registered.
They don't care.
I hope it's registered with the bicycle registry and I
hope you had insurance on it if it was expensive.
But fundamentally, I don't, you know, it's, it's, it's like the big Lebowski,
you know.
Yeah, we'll get our best detectives on it right away, you know, working,
working shifts,
you know,
like
I'm sorry,
but there's just at some level it's not cost effective or even
sane when we have real crimes and real problems to deal with.
And the ransomware people know this as well
because if you ransom a normal person's computer,
the ransom might be $250.
But if you're ransoming a pipeline company,
the ransom is not $250.
And in fact, I remember this was a funny story.
This is probably five years ago now, like a hospital got ransomed for like 500 bucks.
-- They're like, just pay it. Like, who cares
-- as much as I hate that.
Yeah.
Like the,
just having a consultant load the tape will take longer. Right.
And the story was you idiot should have charged us more, you know?
And of course, that's, that's where we are now,
but that's the obvious evolution of ransomware is a business, you know.
And, and so now there's kind of the,
the end of this conversation is something to think about is there's a
story I will link to from Adam Shostack where he basically talks about
like we keep obsessing over ransomware.
But the actual problem here is that our computer
systems are all basically like insecure piles of crap.
I don't think he's wrong. Here's the thing
for us to think about it.
Kind of along this line of blaming crappy, terrible computers.
Like we used to have this discussion about viruses,
we'll say 10 or 20 years ago where it's like
viruses shouldn't exist. These operating systems have terrible security.
And I feel like that's not, I mean,
it sort of solves because Windows comes with Windows defender
now and I will say it does an acceptable job,
but it's not like,
I don't feel like a lot of these fundamental
problems have been solved in the context of viruses.
I think it's just that the Attackers have moved on to something that
makes them money instead of just being a pain in the butt.
Well,
there used to be viruses that tried to extort money but they weren't very effective.
Right. Right.
Well, it was, you couldn't pay people. Right.
This is where we need the Cryptocurrency to anonymously send money across borders.
Which,
like, yeah, I mean,
write me a check and then mail it to this, my home address. You know,
it's not going to work.
Actually,
I think I feel like there was a super early virus that did something like that.
That was one of the first ones like, yeah, one of the fly,
it said mail money to some guy in Pakistan
or whatever and it was like completely ridiculous.
But, but anyway, anyway, the point is
I'm, I, I feel like saying
that operating systems should solve this problem and we shouldn't
-- have defaults that let this
-- Apple and icloud you,
your data is in the icloud by default and granted.
Well, not just icloud, ignoring icloud. I don't care about data backups.
That's kind of, I think a secondary conversation
if we look at what Apple's doing with some of their later operating system versions.
For example,
a binary can't write to random places on disk, right?
It's, it's like sandboxed into certain spots.
Well, for example, you know,
Dan Walsh back in the day has a whole pile of articles talking about how to get E Linux
wrapping. For example, your web browser and then allowing printing.
I remember that. Yes. Why does my web browser have access to my SSH key? There is no
no circumstance under which I want that to happen.
I think that's also a good counterexample though because while the work Dan did
with making Se Linux sandbox binaries on Linux was nothing short of phenomenal.
It never caught on because fundamentally no one cared and it was
hard to use even if we made it easy to use,
unless it is literally the default way
-- the system works. No one would ever use
-- that, you know, on my Mac now, right?
The, the Apple is getting more and more walled garden
with how Binaries work. And I'm having, you know,
I'm having more and more trouble sort of jamming in the sort of
weird open source third party free apps that I really want to need.
But I'm pretty determined.
I'm still, I take that mallet out and I'm just like, yi, I, you know,
and Apple's giving me increasingly dire warnings and I'm like,
I, I think I know what doing so, like just, you know,
I'm going to pound that peg into that hole.
-- I don't care.
-- I get it. And, but here's the thing, you're a weirdo.
Oh, absolutely.
You're not.
I mean, I look at, for example,
my wife is one of my favorite examples to pick
on about stuff like this is she has a computer.
She basically runs a web browser on it now and that's pretty much it.
You know, every now and then there will be something else that needs to be run.
But I would say 99% of the time
she runs a web browser.
And so like, yeah,
she's never going to need to install random binaries
off the internet and if she's trying to,
thank goodness they won't let it happen.
Well, and,
and it's interesting you say that because you actually can install
random binaries off the internet on your web browser chrome extensions.
And now for example,
Google just within the last few days is coming up with a
project to try and clean up their chrome extension space a bit
and also give you some warnings about like this publisher
is new because I remember looking at chrome extensions trying to
find the original publishers of them,
like a whole bunch of them were just super
anonymous or like didn't even have a website.
-- What was
-- the extension that was basically bought by malware people?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Well, and then, and then a whole pile of people popped out of the woodwork saying,
yeah, I run a pretty popular extension too.
And here's like the terms I was offered and it's kind of like
those are actually not bad terms like I might have taken that money,
right?
Boom, that's, that's a ready made attack base because here's the thing,
if you run a piece of software that has an update or built into it, which is, uh,
let me check all of them
and somebody gets access to that system,
either by hook or by crook or by paying for it.
They can now install software on your system.
Well, I mean, that's literally what happened at solar winds. Like, literally,
I think we're going to see a lot more of these sort of simple,
effective metrics around software.
Like, is this publisher well known? Are they new? Are they old?
Yeah, I think that's part of it. Absolutely.
A topic for another day that I think is related to this though,
is as we see law enforcement finally catching up to this game of cat and mouse.
I also think
we're seeing
some push on the policy side where there's some real interest being paid into.
How can we actually just, you know, like chop these attacks off at the, at the root
and, and get rid of them.
And so I'm not going to say it's going to solve all the problems, but I think like,
you know, we talked about that executive order a couple of episodes ago.
I think this kind of stuff while
of is going to be measured by in decades,
I feel like we're at least starting to point everyone in the same direction,
which is a huge first step.
Well, I mean, a big step, Latvian woman charged in us with R and cybercrime group.
So this lady apparently writes ransomware.
This lady is charged as part of a 47 count indictment with
participating in the cybercrime organization known as the Trick Bok group,
which authorities say operated in Russia and several other countries, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
But the point is
she better not travel outside of her country
or she's going to end up on a plane to the US
where she, you know, and,
and then things are going to happen that she's probably not
going to be a fan of doing things like that.
I mean,
it is, you know, when they do it against North Korean generals, whatever, who cares.
But right now this lady is kind of, if they do more stuff like this,
I suspect there are some people that are on
the fence about joining a cybercrime gang to,
you know, make money
that she
would say no because they don't want to end up in a US prison.
-- But
-- at the same time,
the only way to have the ability to do things like charge foreign nationals is
to have enough intelligence to know who these people are and what they're doing.
Right.
And I think historically that wasn't the case, but now it's becoming more obvious.
I mean, the thing is this is exactly the type of thing that the FBI is set up to do.
You know, they just, they, the focus was on terrorism and now we're,
I think we're realizing that there's a lot of other like post 911,
we ignored a lot of financial crimes and, well, 2008 rolled around and I mean,
we're still feeling the effects of that.
Right. That's
right.
So, I,
I think we're at the point where this is
painful enough that we can no longer ignore it.
That's the story of humanity. Kurt,
I'm going to end it on that note because
yes,
no one can argue with that. So, thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt.
You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up our show note, UZ
Pound
Oss
podcast. Hashtag hit us up on social media.
Kurt, you have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone.
-- Bye bye.