Hello and welcome to episode 92 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Presser.
Hey, Kurt. And today we have a guest, we have Rami
Sas with us from White Source. Say hello, Rami.
-- Hey
-- guys, nice to be
here.
Awesome. Thanks man.
And so I, I guess why don't you tell us a little bit about white source
-- and, and what you're up to and how it applies to security?
-- Sure.
So we at White Source provide a service that lets software
engineering teams keep track on their consumption of open source components
and then provides them with various insights on
the open source components that they use.
Uh the main driver for these teams to be using white source. Today's security.
We very accurately and very consistently
provide them with information about vulnerabilities
that are reported on
open source components. But that's not the only reason
uh other reasons include license tracking and the various different metadata
that you want to know about the open source that you
take on.
Uh But generally speaking,
the main focus today in the entire industry is
to make sure that the open source you take
is secure enough and when you put it into your software,
that's not going to get you into too much trouble.
Yeah. Then that's fantastic.
And I think that's a huge topic today as more and more people are recognizing that.
Just grabbing random open source they find,
isn't it? It,
it solves problems but you have to take care of it. Right.
It's kind of like having a pet. you need some care and feeding.
It's not just something you
you get for free and then never worry about again.
Right?
That, that's very accurate because you know, very generally speaking,
open source is great and many open source projects do a great job maintaining their
uh components and taking care of their users. But one that's not always the case
and two sometimes
some sort of disconnect between all of that great work done by
the community and what the end users of those components end up knowing about.
So we help the two sides of that equation sort of stay in touch, not by directionally,
but primarily by informing the users of the
open source about various issues that are found
and normally are even disclosed by the maintainers of the open source,
but that they don't have a proper way of tracking and knowing about
you, you talk about
tracking open source projects
and
that sounds like a good idea.
But I I know for a fact many projects and
or many products will say that that organizations are shipping,
contain hundreds to thousands of open source dependencies.
-- And I think expecting humans to, to track. That is crazy.
-- Right.
Right. Exactly. So, uh
we have actually a long experience with coming into our customers environments
and then comparing what they think they have versus what we can very easily,
automatically detect
that they are in fact using in their environments.
Uh Our
non scientific sort of research that we've done on this a while back
shows that normally we find three times as many
components as what the engineers think they are using.
And these are the teams that actually take the
time to track the components that they download and,
and bring in.
Oh OK. I need to ask about that. That's three times. That's an insane number.
Is that because there are like dependencies of dependencies or is
that because people are just legitimately yanking in, you know,
stuff and forgetting about it?
So it's, it's a combination.
So depending on the programming language, some are more prone to have a very broad
three of transitive dependencies
that get pulled in with, you know, a,
a
sort of benign looking
uh initial direct
open source component that you bring in.
Uh But it's also sometimes a result.
And again,
I'm talking about places that are mindful of this
issue and do try to track it manually,
not even discussing
uh teams that don't make an effort to track
the use of open source. Uh in those cases, what normally happens is that you
sometimes even need to get the approval
to use a certain component
and uh you do that,
but then when you up
create a version, you don't go and ask for another approval.
And then normally what happens is the newer version
has different transitive dependencies or
different versions of transitive dependencies
and that impacts the status of, of your overall inventory as well.
Uh And then sometimes you just forget to ask
or things get slipped through the system in
various ways. Yeah.
Well, I've definitely seen that where, you know, projects
that you're importing
all of a sudden they're pulling in a whole pile of other dependencies with.
Well, oftentimes I have no idea why, you know,
and I'll try and track it down and sometimes it's a, oh, they added spell check,
right?
OK. Cool. But
yeah, I find a lot of these projects, you know, they,
they care a lot about adding features and the easiest
way to do that nowadays is to import food,
right? So look, open source is just as much software as the
propriety
software is.
And
in the same way that you would want to rely on open source components
to avoid reinventing the wheel.
Uh The same sort
of thought process goes on with the people who develop the
open source projects and they rely on other open source projects
so that they don't have to re invent the wheel when they want to add some new feature,
turtles all the way down.
-- Right. Right.
-- Definitely.
I'm curious. Are you also tracking the health of some of these projects?
Because, um, I'm just trying to find the link but there was recently a,
uh, it was one of those f,
what was it? It was one of those headless web
client things that, you know, suddenly shut down and, like, froze their github
accounts.
We discussed it a few weeks ago,
right. I don't know exactly what you're referring to, but we do uh
in some cases, not all cases, we do
uh try to connect to uh the online back tracking systems of uh these projects
and also to the general repository
gab or otherwise
and get some sort of a, we call it the quality metrics or operational metrics
or what you call health status
by looking at reported bugs and how quickly they get resolved and how many
meets, how often you get to see comms.
And we also compare different versions of the same project
based on
uh coms
and the poor
requests and stars and so on and
the bugs that were reported and they resolved in each of the versions
and sort of provide an overall quality
score
uh for these components.
That's a fantastic idea.
I know that's something Kurt and I have talked about more than once is the fact that
if you have a bit of open source, it hasn't received, you know, a commit in,
say three years like that, that's not a healthy project, right?
But, but if, what you're talking about, that's,
that's a really cool idea. So, I guess let's, let's explore that a bit.
Then I'm curious,
you assign something a score and what does that mean for someone using your product?
Does it mean
they can say I'm only willing to accept software that's
above some level or is it just kind of like,
hey guys, be careful or, or what, what does that mean?
So again, we provide both alerts or
at least some sort of visibility into that information
as well as let you set policies based on that.
So we have a relatively advanced policy system
that lets you set your tolerance level on
various different matrices of the open source components.
So you can set policies based on
security vulnerabilities and their severity based on the
kinds of licenses that you are willing to accept and the ones you want to reject
and the quality score that we talked about,
and then we can enforce these policies for you back in the development environment.
So again, depending on how strict you want to be,
you can
construct the policy failure
to either just uh raise an alert and send you an email or completely block the bill.
So you can fail a bid if a developer is trying
to add a component that doesn't comply with your organizational policy.
So the best example again would be around security policy,
uh security vulnerabilities.
If someone is now trying to add a new component that has a known vulnerability
and you have set a policy to block that,
then that person would simply not be able to complete their bill,
their bill will fail and they will get a full report telling them what happened,
what the policy violation was in which component and what the policy says.
And they would simply have to go and replace it.
A sort of middle ground here is that we also
allow you to kick start some kind of a workflow
either internally in our system or by connecting it
with Jira or with the visual studio work items.
That's really cool. So I'm gonna,
I'm gonna make a statement that that could be controversial to some but
with a system like this
and the visibility open source creates
it with kind of just the universe in general.
If, if you're using
something similar to what white source offers you,
I would dare say open source is probably more secure
to use than, than a closed source.
Because when it's closed source,
you don't necessarily have any insight into what's happening,
right?
Depending upon what the vendor is saying, this is, this is crazy.
So
I won't let you pull me into giving you a definity.
No, no, no, I don't expect you to. It's fine. You can just tell me I'm a crazy person.
I'm
just
thinking out loud here.
Yeah.
You know,
I've heard these statements before but
I found that the people on both sides
of these arguments
feel very strongly about their opinion and I don't feel that strongly about mine,
so I'd rather not go there.
Uh, I,
I don't think there is a real way to determine
if open source is more secure than closed source.
Uh, what I do think is that security in these two cases behaves differently.
Yes.
And, and that's what I guess that's my point.
I think you said it better is I'm not
suggesting the open source is more secure necessarily.
I'm suggesting that
due to the openness and now things like white source existing
using an open source dependency can be more secure if you're doing it correctly.
Whereas with closed source, you're completely beholden to your vendor.
-- I
-- think part of it is the maturity model, right?
The the maturity models for open source and closed source are very similar but
slightly different in that. I think being open source forces you
to really avoid certain practices because, you know, you,
you can't be swearing in your bugzilla or, you know,
um it's just being open forces certain behaviors a
lot sooner than maybe in a proprietary company,
right?
And um
one thing I've noticed like there are well in the open source world,
there's vendors all the way like I've had, I had one project
argue they wanted more CV.
S like they wanted to break down their security
flaw into like very discreet chunks and CV.
All of them. And I'm like, no, that's,
there's like a root cause you just give that one root cause the CV.
And we're done and they're like, no,
we want to break it up more and be really clear and you know,
all the way to other open source projects where
they don't know what security is or it's literally,
you know, one guy working on it on his weekends,
you know, and then the same thing for proprietary software,
right? You've got all the vendors all the way from like, hey,
we'll pay you 200 grand for a flaw. Like Microsoft is a great example, right?
They went from being not very fun to report security flaws to,
to now like
being quite friendly about it and having bug bounties and then, you know,
you've still got the old timey vendors where it's like,
oh, we're going to sue
you, you know,
and, and everything in between, of course. Right.
So I think,
I think the open source model simply just
forces different behaviors sooner in the maturity process,
maybe
and maybe give you a different perspective on that.
Uh and elaborate a little bit about the differences in what I
mean by uh how security behaves differently in proprietary and open source.
Is that on the one hand,
uh
open source communities are relatively better let's call it at
identifying vulnerabilities faster and then patching them faster and push,
pushing those patches out uh
to the users.
But the flip side is
that these vulnerabilities get much more exposure and are very public
versus proprietary vulnerabilities
that don't get disclosed.
And that means that the Attackers and hackers
are usually much more aware
of a open source vulnerabilities and know how to look for them
and exploit them.
Uh
much more so than they are to close those vulnerabilities.
So that, that's the kind of the way I see it on the two sides of why
uh they are,
you know, there are different sort of security concerns
when you look at open source.
Yeah, I mean, that's definitely fair now,
I guess kind of elaborating on that then is,
does your product detect any
uh I guess closed source third parties?
-- Do you have any partners in that regard or is it strictly open source?
-- Right.
So we don't do that ourselves.
Uh
You know, we are much more focused on the open source side of the road.
We have partnered with some other vendors who do that much better than we
do and have been around for a long time and have proven technologies.
Uh Checkmarks is one and IBM app
scan is the other.
Uh these are good partners of ours and
they have very robust offerings around application,
security testing,
both static and dynamic.
Oh, very cool.
So I want to also talk about
licenses for a little while because I know you guys detect open source licenses and I
know it's not exactly security, but it's definitely it falls in the risk bucket.
Would, can you kind of explain
-- what, what detecting licenses means for, for people using open source?
-- Sure.
So maybe just spend a minute first on just
talking about what an open source license is.
I would even dare say philosophically
open source from a legal perspective is
treated just like any other literary creation
and it comes with a copyright
by default.
So when you create some poem
or a short story,
even if you publish it online,
you still retain the copyrights without doing anything special,
people cannot copy your poem and then even slightly modify it and sell it
as their own.
That's illegal.
And the same principle applies to
code to source code.
So if you want to publish
some source code,
in order for it to be open source, you must attach some kind of a legal document to it
that waves your copyright
of that source code.
So that's a really important point I think.
And it's something that I know for a long time.
For example, when you created a repo in github,
there was no license associated with it, meaning
it was basically illegal for anyone to use that source code.
And and thank goodness they've solved that problem. But
-- yes, this is, this is a marvelous clarification. Thank you please go on.
-- Sure.
Uh
So now that people do want to publish their creation as open source,
they would normally uh attach some license
to it.
Uh And there's a very broad range
but we know over 500 different licenses.
But most projects end up choosing from,
uh I would say 5 to 10 of the most popular
licenses.
Uh
The names you probably heard about uh Apache,
the Apache public license and the family of licenses that
falls under the category that's called the GP L.
That's the new public license that have
different versions with slight variations on, on
what they allow and what they don't allow.
Uh
And these are all there
uh primarily to
sort of take care of the copyright part of
the engagement.
But since they are there, the creators also added some additional provisions
uh in the more permissive licenses,
they at least want to protect themselves from being sued
uh by the end users for providing faulty
programs.
So if I want to publish some piece of open source,
and I don't have that many resources because I'm doing it for free,
I don't do very heavy quality checks and I may end up publishing a project that
uh could do you some damage,
you know, potentially,
but I don't do it on purpose.
I still don't want to find myself in a situation
when you come back and sue me for that damage.
So even the most permissive licenses have some kind of provision that prevents you
from,
uh, coming back and, you know,
ta taking some legal action against me for doing something,
uh, in, in the open source that I published,
uh, the more restrictive licenses, take it a few steps further
and sort of the, the most restrictive ones usually are considered
to have what's called the copy left
clause,
which is a variance of, of the copyright
that says, OK, we publish this project for free.
You can use it, you can modify it, you can do whatever you want.
But in return your own code also needs to be open sourced
and then
that those kinds of copy
left
licenses. Uh What I mentioned earlier is the GP L family, not all of it, but most of it
-- and,
-- and they're,
they're often viral with respect that if you use that source code in your project,
your project must be GP L license depends
how you're using it.
OK?
By the way, not necessarily GP L, it can be under a different license,
but it needs to be open source.
It's sort of soft viral. It's not
hard.
That explanation was marvelous and I thank you for that. But now now explain to me
why people should care, right? Why is this something
a security scanning company essentially cares about? Right?
Why should someone care about these licenses?
Right. Look so commercial endeavors
don't normally want to publish their proprietary code as open source.
So at the very least they want to make sure
that they are not bringing in any what you called viral
licensed
uh components that would then compel them
to release their code.
And there have been several legal precedence is
set on this where courts have enforced these clauses
and sometimes forced companies to either publish their code or reach some sort
of a commercial agreement with the original author of the open source.
That's the more extreme case,
the lighter cases uh is even if, if the license is not viral and not copy left,
there are normally some other provisions, especially around attribution
that compel you to give some credit
or mention the original author in some way when you distribute your software
and these are things that are normally easy to do.
You just add some clothes to your end user license agreement or publish
a list of the libraries that you're using online,
but you just have to do it,
you know, you can get into trouble for not doing it even if it's easy.
And it would be a shame, you know, just, just, uh not to, to let that slip by you.
Well, and now it,
it's also worth noting that some of these licenses
are incompatible with each other where you can't legally combine
cer certain licenses. Right.
Right. Yeah, it's, it's more nuanced than that.
So there are specific clauses in certain licenses that they
kind of collide with other specific clauses in other licenses.
And again, I think it, I'm not a legal expert so I,
I don't know how to give legal advice on that.
Uh, no, we, right.
Anyone looking here for legal advice,
like you're in way bigger trouble than the advice you're gonna get from
us.
I would say go find a phone book,
but I don't think those exist anymore but go find an IP lawyer.
Yeah. But those do exist. They are very
rare but
they're
out there.
So I was just, it's funny because I was just thinking back to that,
remember that guy that um basically contacted Mercedes and
you know, said, like, look, my car says it has open source, send me the CD
with it
and he got that Josh, remember from a few months ago,
I
just,
here's the best thing ever. Uh Google Mercedes open source
and you get open source license agreement, please enter VIN number, show license.
So if somebody I'm gonna try and find a Mercedes VIN number. But I'm thinking,
for example,
does your product allow people to create like manifest or inventories of sort of?
Well, I'm assuming it creates manifests and inventories of all the software and
inside and imported.
Uh does it also, for example, generate like manifests of the licenses?
Yes. So yeah, that's, that's like a like a very core feature for us is that we let you
produce reports that they list all of the different licenses and then help you
uh automatically generate some of the collateral
that you are required to generate and then
attach it to your own agreement or post it online.
So we try to make that sort of administrative part easier
and as automated as we can.
That's fantastic.
This is, you know, it's funny, I,
I love having these conversations and looking at what,
where the industry is heading because
Kurt and I've been doing this forever
and
we both got our start manually going through software and looking at
dependencies and looking at license files and looking for security flaws.
And
I mean,
I remember gripping source code for patterns because you
wanted to make sure nothing else contained some terrible bug
and it was terrible. It was so terrible to do
and, and the things out there now are, this is,
this is fantastic
and
it's also,
I beat my head against the wall because there are so many people in so many projects
that still don't understand this. And it's, I think we have a long way to go, I guess.
Let, let, let me ask you this. Maybe, you know,
do you have any research with respect to what percentage of, I guess,
either projects or products or whatever you want to call it?
Kind of realize this is a problem they have to deal with versus the ones that are just,
you know,
they have no idea yet.
Are you referring to open
source projects? Or to commercial development.
Uh anything really?
Right, because it, it, it affects everybody, I mean,
not just commercial vendors and not just open source projects.
Right.
Right. So our best estimate is that we are now at around the 10% line
of, of awareness or more than aware. So people who actually take action
to try and, and automate
uh these activities around open source.
So we are talking about
the what's called the early adopters,
right? Yeah, the entire market is still in the early adoption phase.
Although it's coming up on the end of
the early adopters and we'll probably start hitting
early mainstream
within a year or so.
-- Oh,
-- wow, that fast.
It's not that fast. We've been around for six years. But,
ok.
Well, and just for reference, I plugged in a 2014 sedan VIN number
uh and Mercedes for their C class.
It, it's a 1450 page PDF with all the licenses
and contents
-- like
-- it's totally reasonable.
It's got about 40 or 50 licenses in here. It's
uh
and
the thing that makes it so long is it's got a list of all the copyright holders
for every single thing,
right. So, I, I totally hope that they have some kind of an automated tool to do that,
but
there wasn't some cool engineer sitting, you know, hours before the G A day
sweating these licenses and putting them together.
Yeah.
But I mean, yeah, that's, that's, that's just thinking of that,
like generating a list of every single copyright holder for every
piece of software and use in a major project would be,
no, I would not do that. I would, would have to be automated
clearly.
Yeah, that's, that's not a good use of engineering time.
You know,
you're much better off developing new code
than doing these mundane administrative tasks.
Yeah.
So I'm, I'm curious because it, it seems, I mean,
this is something I've been wanting for a
long time because there's a ton of manufacturers.
For example, Linux is a real thing where
a lot of manufacturers grab a copy of like Linux and Busy Box and put out a product.
You know, for example, those uh I hate to say, but pretty much every low end video
security camera that's IP you know, enabled on the on the market is pretty much
they're pretty much all running Linux.
And so these guys, do you find that they're starting to be aware of this or they,
they just don't care
like is,
is there a chunk of the market that fundamentally doesn't care about this problem?
I I think there still is but they think it's
going away uh definitely see the bigger manufacturers taking note
uh even in, in the devices industry,
uh they care because they are, their exposure is much broader
then uh someone developing enterprise software
that ends up distributing the software
if they are very lucky to 1000 or 2000 different locations.
When you manufacture devices, you distribute them by the millions.
And then every single such distribution
could constitute a problem. It's also much harder to upgrade
a software version
on a camera
than it is with an enterprise software customer.
-- I
-- think by much harder, you mean they never update the
camera pretty much.
So, if you got some kind of vulnerability distributed,
it's pretty horrible to try and update software on, you know,
millions of devices that you already sold.
Right. Right. Well, what was the band that took down Krebs's website?
M Ira? I,
yeah. Right. Right.
And, you know, I
have a feeling that,
yeah, they're still around, I'm sure. Right.
Like none of those devices have been taken offline.
Well, I mean, the biggest thing is a lot of them hopefully have put,
been put behind firewalls.
Like we just recently had the thing with the MM
CD. Right. Where MM
Cash
D was amplifying attacks
and they managed to get most of them taken offline so that it's much less of a problem.
But, yeah, I mean,
when your solution has to be update software, especially in these low end, I mean,
I've seen IP
enabled cameras that cost 20 bucks now,
you know, I was at the store, you remember a few months ago and they had, uh,
they had wi fi routers for, uh, what was it, like, $16 or something,
you know?
It just blows like I just, I'm astounded, you know,
that you can even get that thing shipped here for that little money.
-- So, yeah, I don't know.
-- It's
my, my fear is that those are going to be the laggards
in the adoption curve.
And if we're only in, still in the early adopter stage, we have,
it's gonna be a long road until we get there.
I have to tell you, I, I, I'm seeing more and more of the larger manufacturers,
at least paying attention to these issues.
Smaller ones will take longer to get there.
But I think the, the awareness is already there.
That's,
that's fantastic. I think I'm, I'm glad to hear that just because
this is,
this is one of those problems that, that
I, I think a couple of years ago felt like it was never going to be better.
And now hearing you say that that makes me think,
maybe just maybe there's hope and once they have hope,
-- but I'm thinking maybe it's there so it's
-- definitely there.
I don't want to name names of specific companies that we talk to, but,
but some of them are very large device manufacturers.
Well, I, I think of this problem is a lot like food safety, right? Like
uh as much as people hate on, you know, fast food chains,
the majority of fast food chains now have very good food safety.
You know, they have the procedures,
they have the rules they have the implementation.
Right.
Um,
because, uh,
just so like I know a health inspector and some of the stories she tells us are,
are quite horrifying
and so I suspect it's a bit like that. Right.
It's, it's, it goes to maturity and also having the funding to, you know, to do this.
Right.
I guess part of it is maybe hopefully the market will speak at some point and,
and only buy
the good devices.
The challenge being is, you know, how do I know what those good devices are?
So, I'm curious, one thing, do any of your customers sort of
advertise or trumpet that they use
your software?
Because that's one thing I've kind of looked
around when I'm trying to look for software,
you know, uh
especially on the proprietary side, like, do they
like, how good is this proprietary software for security? Right. Do they,
for example, have a security contact email address, you know, do they
trump it any secure development practices or using vendors such as yourself?
Like, do you find anybody's using that as marketing or advertising yet?
Uh Not really,
but I don't really see many people advertising that they
have strong firewalls or that they do periodical penetration tests.
I don't see that becoming a marketing to.
Oh, my goodness. I hope not. That would be a train wreck, I think.
Well, you know, I think about cars, right?
Like for example, Volvo, their big thing is safety right,
three point seat belt and all that, you know, anti lock brakes, airbags,
which are now standard across the industry.
Yeah.
But that's, that's something, you know,
everyone can understand when you're talking to non
software development professionals.
What would they know about open source security
or even other kinds of software security?
Oh, I agree.
But, I mean, simple things even just ask your manufacturer,
do they know what's in this thing?
Right.
I've had to ask that before and they don't have an answer or can't give an answer.
So it's clear that they don't know.
Yeah. Right. But look, the, the day this becomes a marketing
feature is the day that your mother will start asking these questions. Right?
Yeah.
So never.
Oh man, I love it. All right, cool. So we're, we're about out of time, Rami.
I want to thank you so much for spending some time with us.
I think we had a great conversation. I really liked it.
I think we talked about all the important parts. So, you
know,
thank you.
-- Yeah,
-- come back soon and let us know how things are going.
Yeah, definitely. Great.
Wonderful. So thank you, Rami. Thank you.
Thank you, audience for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com to
view the show notes for today where we'll have links to,
you know, the things we talked about and yeah,
you can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit
us up on social media and you have nothing else.
-- Everyone have a great rest of your day. Thanks.
-- Thank you for being on
the show. My
pleasure.