Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Episode 171 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Bresser.
Hey, Kurt.
And today we are joined with Catherine Waldron,
who's a fellow at the R Street Institute.
-- Say hello, Catherine.
-- Hi. Thanks so much for having me.
Thank you.
And the reason Catherine's here talking to us today is there is
a white paper she wrote that's titled Resources For Measuring Cybersecurity.
And as anyone who's listened to the show for any period of
time knows that measuring cybersecurity is kind of one of our,
I don't know if I'd call it a pet peeve, but maybe our, our, our wish.
So why don't you tell us what you've done, Catherine? And then we can,
-- we can discuss.
-- Absolutely. So
the white paper, um it's a bibliography of resources for measuring cybersecurity,
different methods,
um different companies that are out there, different academic approaches.
And it's really part of a bigger project that my team at my,
the think tank where I work DC is working on, on measuring cybersecurity,
which is we're trying to see.
We don't really think people are doing a very good
job of measuring cybersecurity in a way that's very,
that's quantifiable,
uh that's transparent, that's easily adapted
and easy to assess across sectors.
And so as part of this project,
we want to sort of take the temperature of the landscape out there, you know,
see what's out there
ready, what approaches people are taking.
And that's, that gave birth to this first iteration of the project.
This white paper we're hoping for it to be to eventually become an online sort of
portfolio bibliography of like on that can be
updated ongoing as we come across new methods.
But this this first round was really just to sort of see what's out there. And so,
you know, the things we include, it's not, they aren't
necessarily the things that we think are best or worst there.
There's no, we're not recommending, you know, use this for your company.
-- It's really just what's out there, what are people doing,
-- right.
And in fact, you say in your intro, it's not an exhaustive list, but I must say
the list is intimidatingly long.
And that was kind of the first thing that jumped out at me was the fact that with,
I mean, this is already a really hard problem
and
there's just how do you pick? I mean, this list, it's enormous.
-- That's, that's all I kept thinking
-- looking at this list for me.
The thing I thought like,
so one of the projects that cloud security lines has
done is that cloud controls matrix where they basically took,
I guess, like,
15 or 20 different standards and tried to kind of map them to each other and, you know,
they did a pretty reasonable job, but
it really drives home
for me.
At least that, I think the worst part about all these standards is that they're
almost the same, but really not
-- quite the same.
-- You're exactly right.
There's a lot out there and they're all, a lot of them are very similar,
especially on the frameworks approach.
So,
you know,
probably the bulk of the paper that first section has to do with people with
different frameworks and like just lists of security control and a lot of them cover
more, less the same ground.
Like we did the most well known ones like NIST are obviously up there.
But it's like,
how exactly different is it gonna be if you use like n standards or like the BS A
framework?
A lot of them are very, very similar in regards to like it being exhaustive.
It's nowhere near exhaustive.
It's, it's a long list and,
but it's nowhere near the list of like academic papers and,
and other companies that I have saved somewhere in
the back of my computer that uh didn't make
the cut because they were too abstract or too
academic or didn't add something new to the conversation.
And actually, since being,
since we've released the bibliography,
I've gotten also several emails from people being like, hey,
would you please put my company uh on this list as well?
So I'm still getting those and,
and we do want to update it actually with more resources.
Even since uh
it, we sent the paper off to the editing process.
We've had conversations with different companies and organizations who are doing
really cool things that didn't make it in this first round
in terms of like, how did we decide what to pick?
Because we're in Washington DC and kind of in the policy business.
We were trying to pick things that you are going to be very well known.
They were kind of like leaders in the standards industry
or were very, very approachable.
I didn't want to, you know, give policymakers a list of like 20 academic papers that
if I can't understand it, they can't understand it for sure.
And my background is not in it, it's actually in economics and policy.
-- So
-- I think that was one of the most interesting things was on page
six where you actually broke down the different types of standards because I,
I'd never really thought about this clearly before.
So, you know, you've got the frameworks and scorecards which yeah,
I'm familiar with those
and then you've broken it insurance metrics which
yeah, I know that that is a very much different thing,
you know, the Roaro si ones,
then the cybercrime ones and then something I've never heard about before this,
I don't know how to pronounce it.
-- Siri Siri.
-- I don't know. I think it's Siri.
Yeah, it's the work done by the Department of Homeland Security at the moment.
-- So,
-- what I found most interesting about that though was,
was especially for me was that
difference between number 12 and three I
think was the biggest because looking at some
of these standards now they make a lot more sense in the context of,
oh, this isn't
framework. This is like for the insurance industry.
Yes,
yes.
And we've, we've talked to people and so as part of as part of this project,
we're talking to different organizations and different
companies to kind of see what they,
what approach they use.
And so we've talked to a couple of people in the insurance.
Um the difficulty with talking with companies like that is obviously
they're not going to share their mathematical numbers with us.
We don't, we don't get to see their equations. And so determining the exact
how, how good their metrics are can actually be difficult.
But I do think that determining uh depending on which one you pick,
whether it's a framework, whether you're using some sort of insurance metric or ro I
that's going to lead you to make very different decisions.
It's going to have very different like policy implications if you're
in Washington or it's going to lead you to make different like business decisions.
If you're like the CEO or the head of a company.
And I think that's one thing that keeps boiling down to me
is even when we start using a specific framework or standard,
how do we measure success?
Because most of them don't really seem to address that very well.
We're hoping to get a quantitative answer.
And right now, I feel like cybersecurity is very qualitative.
Like there are things we know,
we know that it's better to have a password than not have a password.
And we know that your password should not be the word password.
Um But it's hard to say at this point that, you know,
if I implement this cybersecurity control, you know,
I will be like 5% more secure and therefore
it's worth spending X number of dollars on it,
right?
And you clear, I mean, I mean,
this is a point you bring up on it at some
point and kind of near the intro of the framework section
is the fact that there's following too many frameworks could potentially
have a negative impact on the security of a business.
Which kind of my, my head exploded a little bit when I read that because I mean,
when you say that it's like, duh,
but at the same time, that's never, that's never the impression I get.
It's always, oh, we're following these 12 frameworks, people say, and it's like,
well, why?
Right. It doesn't make sense.
Yeah,
I think the framework was the most personally interesting because I think that's
where a lot of people go when they are first starting to look and be like, hey,
am I cyber Secure?
How can I like, work on my cybersecurity.
It's like, oh, they're easy, like frameworks are easy.
They're, they're accessible, they're well known,
but they can leave you in some kind of alarming
directions if you're not really careful about how they're implemented.
For example, one problem that we've seen is that
if you implement a framework and then
you don't update it regularly as the threat landscape updates,
you might have a false sense of security.
You might be like, oh, I'm checking the box on these five items, I'm safe,
especially if, if the person making that decision,
you know, isn't someone with an it background,
maybe it's someone higher up the management chain
and they're like, no, we're following this framework.
We've got these things in place. We're good.
And then the other, you know, other issues is, you know, a,
a company could be investing too much in cybersecurity
actually, or they might be investing in the wrong things in cybersecurity.
They might be like, oh, well, we're gonna check off the box on these small,
on these areas
when really those are not the threats they need to be concerned about.
I have a related question to that, I guess.
And I think you're in a unique position for this answer, Catherine, as you said,
your background is around economics and policy.
Yes. And I look at this list of frameworks and it is enormous.
And like you said, there's even more you didn't include.
And I'm curious,
is this a problem unique to the cybersecurity industry
or is this a problem other fields have?
I don't know that it's unique to the cybersecurity industry.
And this is a problem that was reoccurring, not just with frameworks,
but a lot of these different metrics
is that because it's still a new industry
or, or newer industry, we just don't have as much data
to recognize which ones are truly the superior approaches
and what's more the threat landscape is evolving,
I think at a much faster rate
than in other types of industries.
So, you know, if you're talking about physical security,
there's only so many different ways that that's gonna happen.
If, if you're, you know, protecting a building or something,
you're gonna put a lock on the door and things like that.
But people aren't coming up with,
they aren't typically coming up with that many new ways to,
you know, break into a house. Whereas with,
with cyber, there's so many different ways to,
to approach cybersecurity and hackers are always innovating as to how to break in.
And so that's, it's a much faster moving industry.
And also as new technology comes on board, you know, the internet of things A I five G,
there's also so many more risks from other people that are in your network,
in your supply chain.
Sure.
I mean, that, that's fair. I think that makes sense.
I was talking actually about your paper with a friend and he had a question was,
which was basically
what do we do with the types of risks that are sort of the existential threat risk?
You know. So for example, well, to go all science fiction,
you know, somebody hacks a nuclear power plant and, and
you know, manages to make it blow up or whatever
it seems like. That is something, those sort of Black Swan events.
That's something most of these frameworks and
strategies really don't really deal with.
I mean, I think,
I think you're right that I think most of these approaches don't
really deal with the Black Swan event and that's kind of alarming.
I think that's something companies need to be thinking about
quite seriously is how do we recover from that?
We can't imagine.
And I don't know if that comes from,
people need to get better at imagining the future be that
creative think tank sessions collaborating with people outside the industry.
Maybe we need to start talking to science
fiction writers more.
But I also think what you bring up about how
this could this could have very catastrophic implications if,
if foreign actors choose to engage in malicious activity.
That way, I do think there's,
there's hopefully going to be slightly different results if they get a hold of the
nuclear power plant as opposed to if they
take down a company during Christmas shopping,
I'm sure that the company will probably feel like they're on the same level.
But as a national security expert,
I'm not really as concerned about one as the other, but it is true that we're still,
we're really figuring out what counts as a act of war when it comes to cybersecurity.
You know,
the US has refrained from really determining from saying, you know,
this is exactly what is going to count when it comes to the cybersecurity landscape.
And it's a very gray area. And so, well, it's a slightly separate issue.
I, I do think it's something that is related in terms of like,
how do we measure what's a cyber attack as opposed to an act of war?
What's cyber crime?
What do we do when, you know, it's a very gray area?
What do you do when it's like sponsored by the Chinese government?
But it's act, it's not like officially part of like,
it's some sort of patriotic hacker who's trying to
break into an American company to steal their IP.
And is that, does that count as an act of war or is that just crime?
-- Like it's a gray area?
-- Is there anybody?
Because that's one thing I keep seeing is, you know, what is trust, what is security?
You know, what, what are the definition of these words?
And that seems to be something our industry doesn't even have yet.
You know, we can't, I mean, we can barely agree on what a buffer overflow is,
let alone something much bigger.
Like what is risk,
you know, what is a threat
-- and then
-- what is, like, acceptable
risk? Yeah, 100% agree. What is acceptable risk?
-- What is acceptable to eat or to, to allow to happen?
-- Because I think most of us agree.
We're probably, and, and maybe policymakers don't agree with this, but, uh,
we're probably, we're never getting to the place where we're 100% secure.
-- So, how much risk are we allowed to? Uh, like, let slide
-- essentially.
I mean, you have a whole return on investment section here.
And,
I mean, that's kind of the point, right?
Is if we take on this risk, what does, or doesn't it cost us later? Right.
Yes.
Can you speak on that?
That's something I always struggle with is we exist
in an industry where if we do our jobs,
nothing happens.
That's nuts.
Well, that's, I think that's why it's hard for certain people in business,
especially to sort of wrap their minds around it because
you are the, you're spending money and hoping that, you know,
you spend the money and that, that's it.
You know, you're just trying to prevent
an even greater loss.
And so
that is a slightly different way of thinking than
when it comes to other inputs in your business
where you're like, OK,
I spend my money on this and instead I'm gonna get something back,
I'm gonna get a profit back.
Whereas the
cybersecurity you're really just trying to ward off disaster.
And that can be like, I can understand why, you know,
CEO S look at that bottom line and they're like,
uh I don't know if I want to spend my money there.
And on a related note, I mean, coming from an economics background.
So what's your thinking on the whole Externalizing of costs?
Because it seems to me like most of these data breaches, for example, you know,
with the privacy implications.
Well, that's largely an externalized problem for the company of eight.
They don't actually, you know,
suffer and have to deal with somebody taking out
a credit card or a mortgage in their name.
And so far,
I don't think we've seen any legislation anywhere that
actually really holds companies to account for this.
The issue of externality is to put it in economic term is,
is a real issue with cybersecurity for, for a couple of reasons.
Number one is that a
lot of times companies can sort of push the cost onto the
consumer in the case of a breach or something like that.
Obviously, they will suffer some reputational
damage, especially if it gets well publicized.
But depending on how much your average
consumer cares about a cybersecurity breach,
a company may be able to avoid some of the worst of that damage.
And then the other issue is that a
lot of times because of the supply chain, if you're so integrated,
you know, if you don't implement your cybersecurity controls correctly,
maybe it's the company down the line that ends up
taking the hit because they're in your supply chain.
And that's where, you know, the hackers, maybe that's their true aim.
They're not, they're just using
you to get to someone bigger.
And so that's, I think something,
the cybersecurity insurance actually from is going to have to deal with a lot,
figuring out where to appropriately attribute blame and how to make sure that
the people you're securing aren't just implementing
good cybersecurity hygiene on their own,
but are also making sure that people in
their supply chain have equally good cyber hygiene.
So I want to pick on that one actually. And
I know you, you submitted
II, I know you had at least a written testimony to,
I forget which committee right now.
I, I found it on the internet while I was cyber stalking you prior to the interview.
And
yeah, basically, you talk about some of these, you know,
hygiene and supply chain issues that we see in the industry.
I think that's,
that's a fascinating problem
because I don't think people always understand that
when you're kind of the end producer of
something and one of your suppliers three levels deep
is a flaming me
on fire.
That's your problem
because you're kind of the, you're the, I guess
customer facing piece of that product, especially in cybersecurity.
I feel like that, that concept is often lost.
Yeah, it's a huge, I think it's a huge issue because if you are the end producer,
you are the face that people are going to recognize
like when something goes wrong they're going to be like,
oh yeah,
it was their fault and they're not, I kind of think, oh,
it was actually their supplier all.
Let's like, put the target incident back in,
I think it was like 2013. Where was the H VAC supplier?
But no one thinks, oh, no one's gonna think about the H VAC supplier. Only.
People are only going to think about Target. So, yeah, it's, it's a huge issue.
Definitely. Right. Right.
And I mean, that one's especially bizarre because if I was
concerned with
securing my infrastructure, I mean,
-- now I would consider H VAC but I think back then I'd be like, no
-- one
-- would
-- back then.
-- Right. It's just H
-- VAC. Exactly.
And as we like,
rely and integrate like internet of things and things more and more into our system,
there's just going to be things you don't think about.
No one's going to think. Oh, my smart scale is a security threat.
-- Right.
-- Maybe my, is it my coffee maker?
Like no, actually,
so Kurt has a smart scale and we probably talk about it more than we should on this.
Show.
-- So
-- I basically given up and I just buy the cheapest
stuff I can because I know it's all a flaming pile.
And,
but on the other hand, like,
I refuse to buy a smart door lock and it's not because I'm afraid, like,
a hacker will hack it and get into my house.
I'm actually more afraid that, like,
one day it won't work and it'll be minus 40 outside.
And, like, I want to get into my house when it's minus 40.
-- I think that's
-- a very, very fair
concern.
I've lived in very cold places.
Right. Right. Exactly.
Ok. So I'm, I'm also curious, one of the things I read in
this,
this paper you have is you said that, that our street
is, you're starting an initiative to kind of build a consensus around this.
So I'm curious, like, what does that mean? Right.
Is there, is there something we should be paying attention to?
There's something we can do to get involved? Like, what's the deal? Yeah.
Well, we're starting as part of the project. We're engaging in dialogue.
We're trying to, you know, if, if there is an answer out there
and we're not 100% convinced yet there is or there isn't.
Um, but we, we're looking for it and so we are
like engaging with just about everyone we know
to try to be like, hey, what's your approach? Do you think this is possible?
And it's kind of interesting my colleague,
um, actually recently put out a paper,
I think in law there on like the feedback we've
gotten and essentially we've gotten three different types of feedback.
We've gotten people who say,
hey, you know, it's essentially like the, the large corporations, the, the,
the people you would hope would be on top of their cybersecurity.
And a lot of them are like, hey,
you know, we've got
this, we have our own internal types of measurement, you know,
don't worry about us and then we go, ok, that's great.
Can you show us what you're doing?
And they go, no, we can't.
Um because that's private and internal and would
tell people all our cyber security flaws.
Um And, you know, we're, we're pro business.
So we get that, that,
that gives you a leg up on your competition
and that you don't wanna advertise your security flaws.
But at the same time, we're like, so you just want us to trust you.
Ok.
Um And then the second response is really people who are like, yeah,
this is never going to be solved ever.
You're hopeless. But thanks for asking, I guess.
And then we have people who are more or less like, yeah,
we don't know the answer either.
But when you find out the answer, let us know.
Right.
So no answers
-- yet.
-- I think Josh and I also would be in that camp.
I flip between the nihilistic camp and the let's keep looking camp.
So it just depends what day of the week it is fair
enough.
Yeah. Ok. So that's, that's really interesting.
Actually, I'm, I guess when you say that that is exactly what I would expect
because
I,
I know I've dealt with enough organizations to understand that half of them
do legitimately have very interesting security efforts going on.
They don't want to talk about and I think the other half
are just lying and they don't have a freaking clue.
So, well, maybe it's less than half now
-- and
-- we just don't know which ones are which.
So it's being able to distinguish between who's lying and who, who's being honest.
I fully believe
that there are lots of companies who are doing great jobs and I
believe that there are companies who have no idea what they're doing and,
but it's hard, you know, if you're a consumer, if you don't know which one's which?
-- Right. Right.
-- Exactly.
I literally just had the experience of looking at a,
a cloud service providers web page and they, they
proudly use this piece of software that I click on the link to it.
And the,
uh github page literally says this software hasn't been maintained in two years,
do not use it, go use this other newer thing.
And so I asked the company about this on Twitter and they're like,
please contact us privately at our about page and I, I go check the,
the web page and they,
they disappeared that information off the web page and they're like,
please take this private and talk to us.
And I'm like, oh, good. I,
ok.
Yeah. Fantastic.
And, and, you know, it could just be the, the web page was out of date.
Maybe they've updated.
I, I don't know, but I, you know, at this point I'm like this,
this smells kind of weird and doesn't look quite right.
Companies have an incentive to protect their reputation.
They don't have an incentive to always tell consumers everything they need to know.
So,
-- so
-- it's interesting you say that actually because
you come from the policy world and companies
don't always have an incentive to tell people what they need to know.
But they, there are certain regulated industries that like for example,
you can't say your product is gluten free when its first ingredient is wheat,
right?
Like there are certain industries
that have certain rules. And so I'm curious, kind of from the policy perspective,
what are your thoughts on cybersecurity and potentially some sort of regulation
enforced on us from the government? So
-- I'm a little bit anti regulatory in general, um just throwing that out
-- there and,
and that's fine, that's fine.
Not because I don't think that there, there are,
I think there are good things that can come out of regulation.
My wariness,
it goes back once again to the fact that
this is such a quickly changing landscape and that
I worry that something set in place through a regulatory body
doesn't have the nimbleness to be updated appropriately.
I worry that it'll be, you know,
it,
it's gonna get put in place and it's gonna be great at
the moment and then one or two years down the road,
it's no longer gonna be applicable and that companies will be there,
you know, evolved around it
or they will be constrained in a way
that actually hinders business and could hinder security.
-- In fact.
-- Well, I mean, we've already seen that with the cookie warnings for GDPR
that totally works.
Informed consent.
Right. Right. And actually I,
I know we've spoken with a number of guests in the past
specifically on this topic and, and that, that seems to be the,
the overall consensus I would say for the most part, at least in,
in the people we kind of kind of hang out with, I'd say.
And I mean, so, so that's one of the dangers here. Right.
And I guess that's the question, right.
Can we,
do you think we will ever see a point where
regulation could keep up with security or security slows down?
-- So, regulation and security you are in lockstep? I
-- don't think we're there yet.
I don't want to say we could never get there because II, I don't know how, well, um,
politically, I, I find that hard to imagine just with the way, um,
governing bodies tend to be set up and the amount of bureaucracy that,
that's almost always involved, you know, we might be able to get,
get there somehow through technology someday very far in the future.
Maybe A I will save us all.
But I don't, I don't think we're there yet.
I, I'm confident they're going to take over someday
and, and
be our benevolent rulers, all the movies I think, say that works out fine
so
well, then, then they can be in charge of the regulation.
Let's see how that
-- works,
-- right?
And the other thing I keep running into is so even like,
even I literally know people who are like one person companies
and they're international,
like everybody and everything is international a lot. Like if you sell T shirts
and you have a website,
chances are you're gonna mail at least one outside the country, you know,
a yearly or whatever.
And so the thing I have been struggling with
because I've been looking at a lot of privacy,
sort of law and compliance.
Great. So there's like 100 and 80 countries with
many have multiple jurisdictions. I think
America has something like several 100 different jurisdictions with different,
you know, slightly varied laws. Like, uh what is it?
Ohio has different, you know, biometric laws than California and
San Francisco banned facial recognition. And I'm just like,
I didn't know you could do law at the city level in the US. That, that was a Canadian
horrifies me. Because that's,
that makes it so complicated.
Yeah, it's really complicated if,
if you're a business owner and you're working on that scale.
Good luck.
Ok.
Right.
Yeah, I guess that answers my question because, yeah,
I've just been looking at this and I'm like, how,
how do I even become aware of all this?
You know, I, I, it never, it never occurred to me literally to look for, like,
city laws with respect to tech,
you know,
like I get parking enforcement and having laws about
who can sleep in the park overnight or can't,
you know, but like online privacy at the city level.
Yeah, I think this is an issue that I mean, at the city level, I think,
I think eventually we will see a push in the US
um for more standardization
um across cities and states actually to make things
like that so much to make that easier essentially.
But I do think the issue of like having to
with different rules and legislations uh like across the
globe is only going to get harder and harder.
Um as,
as countries become more concerned about issues like
privacy and implement like data localization laws.
I think that that's going to become very difficult for certain companies
that then begs the question with the hundreds of frameworks we have available
and there's probably going to be hundreds of privacy laws in the near future.
Like what the heck? Right. How does anyone even possibly keep track of this stuff.
Yeah.
I mean,
even I can't keep track of everything that's going on.
Find something that you, like, like mist and, and try to keep an eye on, like,
when things are that when they're getting updated for sure.
But it's, it's difficult. We actually should probably, we could do a little,
probably fewer frameworks and maybe just better ones. Right.
No, I, I, I agree with that 100%. It, it always reminds me of there's, although
there's that XK CD Comic where it
says something like, what is it?
There are 13 standards and someone says, oh,
I will make one standard to unify everything and
then it says later there are 14 standards,
right?
I've been on the receiving and now over I
think half a dozen vendor questionnaires this year alone,
you know, and
one of them was 30 tabs
in Excel and these
are not small tabs like, and this is a, you know, this is a very large entity with like,
actually really good cybersecurity.
But man, like,
yeah,
if it makes you feel any better, they probably didn't read any of your answers.
Huh?
-- I don't know if that made him feel
-- better.
-- It wasn't supposed
-- to, I suspect because I, yeah, just, yeah,
it's,
I don't know at this point what to do anymore.
You know, it's, it's like your paper points out.
It's, it's a very large complex problem
to some extent. Like you should have a marketplace for ideas.
So to some extent, you know, these frameworks,
they can all compete with each other and may the best one win.
The difficulty is when you can't even figure out
how who's competing in the marketplace at all.
Right? And I guess that's partially what you're doing, right?
Is you're going to help us figure out which one of these frameworks are worth
using and which ones maybe aren't.
Yeah,
I would say like the goal of this bibliography initially is essentially to say, OK,
who is in this marketplace for ideas at all, like who's playing, who's competing
and it's not even, it's not even an exhaustive list of the competitors, but it's a
if it'll let you know who some of the bigger players are.
Sure. And, and that's fantastic because I'm not gonna lie to you.
I, I thought I knew about most of these frameworks and there were a lot on your list.
I had no idea even existed.
It was sobering to say the least because I think no matter how much you think,
you know,
that, you know, it's what is it, the more you learn, the less, you know? Right.
That's exactly what this is.
Well,
and speaking of which do we have any idea of how many people use these frameworks?
Because I, I like, I know Nist is popular in the US because Nest.
But
yeah, like some of these I was looking at and I'm like, well, I know that name or,
you know, like the swift customer security control framework,
all the swift customers have to use that.
I would assume actually.
Yeah, let's make that clear. I assume that's the case.
I don't know. So that means basically, like all the banks are on there but
looking at some of these, you know.
Uh,
yeah, I have no idea.
Yeah, I don't have numbers for any of these but we did,
I did try to like only pick ones that seem to be used like fairly widespread.
Sure. Because of course, you know, anyone, anyone can
make their own framework or standards. So
that's true. We should, we should do that. Kurt, we can get it on this.
All right.
So we're nearing the end and I have one more question for you,
Catherine and I think it is the most important question of all.
And that is you work for the R Street Institute.
It's on New York Avenue.
What's the deal with that?
I get that
answer. Why aren't we on our street? I get that a lot.
It's the number one question people ask me, which is, are you on our street?
And then I have to explain it.
No, we're not.
I think, I think our original office was closer to our street than we are now.
Um, because there isn't, there is an actual our street.
Um, but it, it actually the name comes from, um,
the idea that, that our street in DC is kind of
um it's where residential neighborhoods kind of meet
uh the downtown, the the policy um sector.
And so it's this intersection, it's like the symbolic intersection, especially
like policy and people's everyday.
It is clever, except for the fact that we have to constantly explain, we're not
located on our street.
And I guess for those of you listening who
aren't necessarily familiar with the layout of Washington DC,
there are, it's often denoted by, by the street
and, and it's letter streets, right?
And, and kind of like K streets when you'll hear a lot about, for example,
because all the lobbyists are in K street and our street
is, it, it's a bit farther away from the Capitol we'll say.
But obviously, because they go in sequential order as one would hope.
Right.
Wonderful.
All right, Katherine. So, so we're going to wrap up.
Why don't I'll give you the last word here before we end it. So the floor is yours?
Well, find something that works for you because some,
some cybersecurity is better than no cybersecurity.
I, I agree. I think that's really good advice actually.
And now if people want to get a hold of you,
I can put some contact info in the show notes and if people want to get involved,
I guess the best thing would be to do what
uh contact me and I can, I can get that figured out.
Um Yeah, feel free to let me know if you have a method
that needs to be in
my bibliography.
Fantastic. Wonderful. Well, thank you so much, Catherine.
It has been an absolute pleasure to have you on the show. Thank you,
those of you out there you can go to open source security podcast.com.
You can find the show notes with links
to the various things we've talked about today.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag You hit us up on social media and yeah,
Catherine and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone.