Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 151 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
Awesome. Thanks, Kurt. And today I'm super excited.
We have David Brumley who is the CEO of for all secure
and he is a professor at Carnegie Mellon University. Why don't you say?
Hello, David.
Hi, everybody. Awesome. And I, I'm so excited to have you here because
your team won the DARPA Grand Challenge a couple of years back and that is so cool.
So I guess let's before I start getting all crazy on you,
why don't you introduce yourself properly?
Tell us a little bit about yourself and then we can talk about why you're here.
Absolutely. So I'm CEO of F all
Secure. What Falca
is trying to do is bring actual security testing through the full abs
lifestyle.
The reason this has been our mission actually goes back
to what you just mentioned the CGC for years.
We've been researching ways
that we can better identify exploitable vulnerabilities in software.
And part of what the CGC
challenge us to do is not only identify them but
repair them and then decide when to field those fixes.
So it was the full application life cycle from. Can you find a problem? Can you fix it?
And can you make sure that that fix when you actually deploy it? Does what it should?
Can I ask what CGC is where I I know you,
you're obviously very in the government space which you love your acronyms.
And so I'm going to keep interrupting you and making you define them.
Awesome.
Yeah. So in 2014, DARPA announced a cyber grand challenge. So DARPA,
the defense advanced research project agency are
the people who originally funded the internet.
And every so often they'll issue a grand challenge.
And probably the one that comes most to mind
for people are the autonomous vehicle challenges they had
where they said, hey, can we build a
driving car?
In 2014?
They issued a similar question, hey, can we build self driving app security?
And what they meant by that is,
can you come up with a fully autonomous system?
No humans allowed running on these big high performance
computers where their job is to ingest applications,
run them, provide, you know, high up time,
but also be able to find exploitable bugs,
be able to break into our opponents because we want to cause downtime to them
while defending ourselves,
right? It was actually kind of genius, right? Because
for a long time,
people have been talking about security is like a
binary value like you're either secure or insecure.
And what DARPA did is make it a lot more realistic. They said it's
not a binary value. What you're trying to do is win.
You're trying to beat the attacker,
not be the most secure system. And I think that's a lot more definable.
-- That's
-- awesome. So I guess the,
the first question
that everyone wants to ask is this how
the Terminator movies start?
-- You
-- know, I think it is.
I was just looking at the web page and
remember how excited we were for the DARPA autonomous
vehicle challenges and those were only 15 years ago
and now to be blunt, like autonomous vehicles driving themselves around.
Yeah, no big deal. Like it's a thing,
you know, it's, it's not ready for prime time but another 1020 years, it's,
it's no longer a question of, can we do it?
It's just a question of like, OK, we got to polish the edges.
So I'm curious,
do you think the uh the cyber Grand challenge might
kind of come to normalcy on the same time frame?
I mean,
I think so and I think the time frame you laid
out 10 to 15 years is probably about the right one.
So we're here two years after the contrast
trying to commercialize some of the technology,
but definitely not everything that was demonstrated at the CGC.
And it's going to be a matter of watching it mature.
Ultimately, I think the Cyber grand challenge in Darb
set the, the ultimate vision and what we're going to see is in 15 years,
that's a product you're going to be able to buy a self
-- defending computer system
-- because I keep coming back to app security.
And
for the last about, I'm going to say 50 years, we've kind of tried the strategy of, ok,
so programmers learn to program better and
secure apps
and
judging by the number of security flaws we still have every month,
it doesn't seem to have worked.
Yeah, I'm kind of a heretic at CMU.
So CMU,
we very much have the party line that we need a better programming language and,
and you need to prove programs safe and that's the way you go about security.
And I'm just like, no, I mean, no one ever is going to do that.
Maybe, maybe people who do like nuclear weapons, hopefully,
but not the average programmer.
Well,
and it's also worth pointing out that that CMU
is where cert the computer emergency response team.
Like that's where they came from. Right. That was the inception.
Yeah.
From the very first Robert Morris worm cmu served as
the Coordinations Center for like all major security events.
Right. Right.
So, like, that's,
that's the nexus point of security and if you're telling people they can't fix it.
I, yeah, I bet that goes over real good at the Christmas party. Right.
Yeah,
it's, uh, I mean, it's kind of a weird viewpoint, I think because
when you're a professor or an academic,
you want to prove things because you get this comfort and proof.
But the Real World is messy, right? And what you really want to do is beat Attackers.
You just don't want to get hacked.
You don't want to like, go through the effort of proving your programs, correct.
So, I
think CGC set it up. Right?
Like there's no, you know, there was no, like, yes, you're secure at the end,
I'm gonna bless you.
Put holy water on you and you're a perfect program.
-- It was. Did you
-- survive?
So, I'm curious.
So, what, what strategies did you use to get these programs to be here? Because,
you know, like, for example,
one thing I've seen that is somewhat counterintuitive is that
the ability to change the program and to make rapid updates to it,
in my opinion,
is actually one of the number one aspects that allows it to be secure now
to put it bluntly,
I've seen a lot of software where it's not that they can't ship security updates.
It's, they can't ship updates at all in any reasonable amount of time. Right.
So, it just doesn't matter how secure the program is
because at some point they'll find a problem and,
and then you got to wait six months to a year for an update.
Yeah, I, I agree, like a lot of programs aren't even, I call it testable.
Like, I've gone to companies who want to use CGC tech and they're like, hey,
can you protect this?
And I'm like, how do you test it?
And they're like, well, we put it on a vehicle and we fly the vehicle and I'm like,
I don't think our technology is right for you.
I think you need to be able to test that program
in like a regression test before we even touch it.
Because I don't want to, you know, die
and II I take for granted the idea of like unit tests and smoke tests and,
but the reality is, yeah, I mean,
-- a lot of people still don't even have that.
-- Most people don't have it. I mean,
one of the things that we're doing when we go to market,
right is we're starting to look more at modern dev shops,
not just
because we think they need it the most often.
They don't, they have the best security,
but because they're the most
able to absorb new technology because,
you know, if you go into one of these shops that doesn't, don't have even test cases,
you have to solve that problem
before you can get started.
Let let's take a step back for a minute because I think we,
we kind of dove into this one head first.
But why don't, why don't you explain kind of what happened
at the Grand Challenge and then what you're doing today, David,
because I think it sounds, it's a fascinating story.
Well, let me set the stage really for the Cyber Grand challenge.
So it was motivated by DARPA PM program manager
who had hacked and capture the flag contest.
So in defcon every year, the elite hackers get together and back
it out to see really who's the best hacking
team and what the program manager asked himself is,
can we teach computers to do that?
And so he got money to run this contest to build it up to do that.
And so what we built as well as our other competitors.
So there were seven in the final round was a machine.
And what the machine did is it ingested program binaries.
So we didn't have source code, we just had the executable that was compiled
and our goal was to find flaws
and then prevent those programs from being exploited.
And so there's really kind of three key technology.
One is every team employed some sort of fuzzing or symbolic execution.
So what they didn't do is run a S
a tool. They didn't run check marks to find new vulnerabilities
or
coverity or not.
They use dynamic testing because they wanted something
that they could prove there was a problem.
And then the second component would be,
they fix the vulnerability and they would rewrite the binary to do that.
And that's actually kind of a hard problem,
but we don't need to go into depth here.
The third thing that we had to do is once we fix the problem,
we had to automatically create in a regression test
and decide whether it was worth fielding that fix.
And so this is really the interesting strategy component.
And one of the reasons we did so well,
actually is if we created a fix that had like 500% performance overhead,
and we didn't think anyone was going to exploit the vulnerability or
the machine didn't think anyone was going to exploit the vulnerability.
We just wouldn't feel the patch
and I think that really reflects reality
where even though you have a vulnerability,
you have a patch,
you make a business,
this decision on whether to field it based upon data on, you know,
what is the functionality, what is the performance overhead?
What is the security impact?
And so it was really those three components,
finding bugs proving they're exploitable,
being able to patch them and assess the impact
of that patch and then a decision making engine
and, and now just to just to clarify, this was all done by your system, right?
Like humans didn't make these decisions, right?
Humans made zero decisions. So we had to install our system the night before.
And then what happened?
Cyber Grand Challenge was held at defcon 2016.
So we're in front of like 30,000 people
and DARPA flips on the power switch and it boots up the seven
competitors and then there's a couple other
machines that are doing things like scoring
and the way this works is the machines are trying to attack each other and they
have a round based system where every round you get a chance to attack and defend.
The reason they did that is they wanted to say, OK,
you have a chance to field a defense.
Let's see if that defense worked.
And so you'd field your defense and then it would give people
a chance to ret attack and see if they could get persistence
at the end of a round. DARPA would give everyone's patches to every other player.
So there was no like secrecy as far as how you were fixing a dress.
Oh
Nice.
-- Yeah. So people could just steal stuff. So
-- wait.
So your system also had the ability to take a binary patch
and essentially examine it and figure out
OK,
this is what this thing does and whether or not I want to use it or not based
on say performance metrics or we believe that this
type of flaw will be exploited or not.
We, in our system, we looked at our own patches.
We made a conscious decision to not look much at other people's patches.
And that's because we were being a little bit evil.
It turned out, DARPA
clarified a rule and we couldn't do that.
But when we release patches, we would actually put a zero day for Qu in them.
So if our competitors tried to run it under qu
we would own their system and could turn it off.
You know, you should never,
we were an untrusted patch, you know.
Well, that was, yeah, that was my first thought.
So, it was, uh, it was clarified, you weren't supposed to do that.
So, we removed that the last day before the contest because of that.
We never designed a system that we really spent much time on other people's patches.
And the other thing I'm curious about.
So what classes of flaws were you able to automated find? Like was it just buffer
or was it more like logic bugs?
Yeah, for, for most of the cyber Grand challenge, it was really memory safety.
So there was like invalid reads and things where you could leak secrets.
So could you leak a crypto
secret was one set and then,
you know,
they would divide them into like reading a
single byte or reading from anywhere in memory
and then anything that would result in control flow hijack.
So they were looking at kind of the bugs that they cared about most, really,
most prevalent in C C++
and non safe languages.
So basically the, the, the ones we read about in the news,
the ones you read about in the news, the ones that are on the airplanes,
the destroyers.
All right. That's cool. So, so let's continue this story because I I'm loving it. So
the challenge happens, you guys win obviously at the very end. Right. And so I guess
what now?
-- Well,
-- that was actually kind of a time for reflection. So we were like, yeah, we won.
DARPA spent
$60 million showing the world that autonomous cyber is possible.
And it turns out Darpa's mission is to simply demonstrate the art of the possible.
They're not really someone who's going to take that forward.
Right.
So we had about
eight months where we were
wandering in the wind as a company, what should we be doing?
Finally, another organization in the dod called the Defense Innovation Unit said,
you know, we really should take this,
this technology and help use it to protect ships, planes,
everything the dod cares about.
And so that was really the start of our commercialization was taking
the CGC check that worked in this kind of artificial environment,
DARPA created
and starting to port it. So it worked on real operating systems like Linux
real programs that weren't artificially created by DARPA.
-- And so we've been on that path really since about 2017,
-- which is not,
that's not very long.
I mean,
and that's, it's crazy to think about.
I mean, this is like this is brand freaking new technology, right?
It is and it's a brand new paradigm as well.
And so there's a set of people who get it, they see the CGC and they're like,
that's the vision I want to have,
I want to have something that can automatically detect a flaw, fix it,
feel that patch and do it in under a minute as opposed to the current process where
it takes hours, years or even decades in the dod.
Literally, if you think about it, those ships, they're out at sea for a long time,
they don't get software updates while they're out at sea.
So that's the vision and that's, that's what we're trying to bring,
but incrementally piece by piece.
But there is, you know,
quite a bit of education we have to do because we're creating a new market category.
Like why not just use static analysis is a common question. We have
no one who asked that has ever actually used static analysis. I think
I thought that too. So
what I've seen is actually kind of interesting
often in practice,
you have the security people who are like we know our stuff needs to be more secure.
But then you have the developer who's like my job is to push out
software features and I'm already checking the box on a tool to check security.
So there's really this kind of interesting question
of incentives like what incentive does it develop?
Have
to do anything else?
Yeah. No.
As me and Josh have discussed at length in the past, you know,
developers get yelled at when they don't get their features in but you know,
security flaws, whatever, that's the thing that happens.
Yeah.
And
it's a really interesting problem. One of the things that we hope will happen is
a side effect of our analysis.
So we're using techniques like fuzzing and symbolic execution
is we're automatically building a regression test suite.
We use this in the cyber ground challenge. That's how we assessed patches.
And we're hoping that we won't just be another security tool,
but we will help them build the regression test,
which is something we know they don't like to do
and can help automate. But that's still kind of like up in the air.
You've got my, my brain is starting to, some wheels are spinning, but there's,
there's kind of two pieces to this, right?
There's the offensive aspect of it where you're actually looking for problems.
But then there's also kind of that defensive view of let's write
tests and make sure this is doing what we expected to do.
Yeah, absolutely. That's perfectly right. In fact, maybe is too abstract.
But the way I think of things like fuzzing is they're just testing a program, right?
And they're just
typically we say we,
we want better coverage as we're doing things like fuzzing or symbolics,
which is just saying we want a better test suite
and we just assume the better we get our test suite,
we'll run into the vulnerabilities.
Well,
the problem and the problem I've run into there
is I back when I was doing CV assignments,
I'd literally have people send me like here's
100 fuzzing test cases that crashed the program.
And I'm like,
that's absolutely fantastic.
Now,
you need to go do your homework and sort that out
and figure out what the root cause is because I'm not.
Yeah, absolutely. Like root cause analysis is still a challenge.
And I think you got it something more than that,
which is also you want to assess the severity.
So if you just fuzz and it crashes, you need to understand what that means.
And in the cyber Grand challenge, what they had us do is create
what they call a proof of vulnerability.
And they use that term, I think because they didn't want to call it. An exploit
is bad. Pr to say
the US is funding exploit development with the university researchers.
But really what they were trying to do is walk
this line of saying I can prove to anyone reasonable
insecurity that I can control the computer while not going
so far as to have to worry about weaponizing it.
So in the CGC, just for the technically minded, we had to show that we can control
the CPU and get it to execute arbitrary instructions,
but it didn't matter what instructions we got it to execute.
Ah So when you were attacking the other competitors,
it wasn't like you weren't literally pointing them.
You were just showing that I found a bug that could do something bad,
-- but you didn't have to actually do the something bad we
-- had to, yeah,
we had to show that we could gain control of their
CPU but we didn't have to like execute random code.
And part of that is just part of that is just the
metric of the game as soon as you allow arbitrary code execution.
Then
for example, one of the things we could do with our cio
exploit is we could turn off their machine, we could wipe out their machine
and it would not be in the spirit of the game
like, you know,
the backdoor battle.
Uh
No, hold sparred is better left for Defcon,
right?
That, that sounds like the what is the the robot,
the Bat Wars show that used to be on where like one
-- would totally destroy the other, right. Yeah.
-- Yeah.
It'd be fun to do that, to totally, to totally destroy the other person.
So I think like root cause analysis is an important part.
Um
As you said, being able to triage, I think also providing people more information.
One of the cool things in the product that we have is
we also give a person a command line on how to reproduce.
Oh, very cool. Kind of a silly thing.
No, not
a thing because
no, like working at product security at Red Hat.
That was, how much time did we have people spending trying to reproduce these flaws?
-- It was, it was a huge part of the job.
-- So no, that is no, that is.
-- So that is such a critical component.
-- Yeah, I'm glad you're saying.
So it's, it's something that I,
to me it's like huge because I'm like,
if I'm going to debug a test case is so much better than someone just telling me
there's a problem in this code because then I have to figure out what the code.
Yeah, definitely. So I think that's what we're trying to do for it.
Now, I got to say there's some limitations, right? So as we said,
DARPA was about memory safety.
And so that's the first generation of the tool. So it's mostly C C++
and looking for memory safety vulnerabilities,
you can also find any assertion violation.
So I think you may be aware of Java property testing.
It's heavily you lose in elastic search, I think.
Right. Right.
So I think
the idea there is
you're not just looking for security bugs.
What you're going to do is you're going to write an assert,
you're going to assert that your program should have a property like, you know,
this should never be null or
you should have never have a SQL query of this form.
And then the goal of the,
the fuzz and symbolic execution is try to violate that property.
I always love the comments in C code where you'd have
the case statement and it says you should never get here.
We did.
Yeah. That paradigm of assert false like this should never happen just
Yeah.
And that's, that's exactly what asserts for and then you get there and it's like,
I don't know how we did this.
-- But yeah. No, I'm, I'm familiar with that
-- as we're taking this technology.
I mean, we actually have to run the program,
we have to prove there's a vulnerability, we have to show how to reproduce it.
So we're asking people to do a little bit more when they want to
use mayhem than just run a spell check over their program like static analysis,
right?
That you see that's OK though,
I think because I have been dealing with static
analysis for longer than I can remember now.
And I've yet to come across a single static analysis report
that I looked at and said this is a really good report
at, at best. It's like, well, it doesn't totally suck.
And that's about the best I've seen so far. And I get it though.
It's, it's hard, right?
Static analysis is really hard and you guys are,
it sounds like you're skipping over the really,
really hard problem and moving towards something that's just sort of hard, right?
Which is kind of binary analysis and just beating the crap out of this stuff.
And well, it it's dynamic analysis essentially, right?
Yeah, it's a type of dynamic analysis.
I try to be careful because like I read the Gardener reports and then as an academic,
I'm not really sure what they're saying and they say there's
something called DAST and DS T is not what we do.
Sorry. What's dat
dynamic application, security testing.
-- And,
-- and there's also SAS T which is static application, security testing.
And I
A which as far as I can tell is an LD preload. Um I don't know.
It's
so, yeah, what we're doing is dynamic.
We're running the program, we're learning every time we execute the program.
And I mean, fundamentally both fuzzing and symbolic execution,
you you guess an input, you run the program, you watch how it executes
and you learn from that to generate another input.
I can't help but wonder if part of this is tied to.
I guess the word I would use is intent, right? If you have
a binary
and you have a test case that allows you to control code execution, then you know
that you have a security flaw, right? I mean, there's just there's no question
whereas with, you know, static analysis, well,
we have a flaw and it may or may not affect
the flow of the program and control of the program.
But it's, you know,
you haven't actually tried it out,
you haven't really confirmed it, right?
And that that was something always,
I saw a lot with these static analysis tools is OK?
There's definitely something
-- not right here, but what kind of not right? Is it?
-- I agree with you.
And I think also this is just my personal heretical opinion but
the incentive structure.
When you build a static analysis tool is the salesman has to come in and
be able to run on any code base and point out at least one flaw.
Right.
Like that is just the business thing you have to do. And so
there's actually not really, there's an incentive to like remove false positives,
but
there's also an incentive to always find a problem.
I think when you look at our techniques, it's quite different.
Our incentive is simply can we generate tests for the program?
And I feel like that's a much saner metric.
-- So
-- I guess the thing coming to mind now that I
would imagine a number of audience members are wondering is we,
we talked about some fuzzing.
We've talked about fuzzing quite a lot.
How are you different from fuzzing with what you're doing?
Well, that's actually a good question.
So we are big fans of fuzzing and a lot of what we're doing is making fuzzing faster.
So that's one side of it.
So for example, if you take a fl and you run a fl
which is uh
advance.
Oh man, anyone who Fuzzs needs to know a FL, it's uh American fuzzy lop,
which I don't think describes any better.
It's kind of the standard
that people would use.
That's open source. It's well known. It's well documented, has a very long
list of successful uses. It's easy to get started
and
what you end up doing with,
with a FL is you end up having to compile
your program and make sure it reads from a file.
And then what A FL does is it fills in the
file and it tries to learn from executions through instrumentation,
how to generate files that get better and better coverage.
And then it's just been found to find
lots of bugs and security vulnerabilities this way.
So that's what A FL does. And it's a great product.
Like
by all means, if you're looking for great open source available,
uh things go download a FL.
So what are the things that we do? So first, a FL can be a little bit hard to use.
For example, if I have Apache orgen
X, it's not reading from a file, it's reading from a network socket.
And so a lot of our work has actually been trying to bring down
the expertise needed to get started. And so we'll take in engine
X,
we'll take an Apache as is and we'll be able to fuzz that network port.
The US are doing nothing, which is the normal build.
I think another thing when you look at a FL is I'm sure it's fine for your,
for your audience.
Like what it's doing is it's forking and exacting the process, right?
It's launching a new process every time it reads an input.
And
if you look at it,
it can only do that up to like 16
cores before you start getting a performance degradation.
So on the one hand, we know like the more we run it, the better results we get.
But on hand, you have kind of this bottleneck,
right? And so we've spent a lot of time trying to remove that bottleneck and got it.
So things are much, much faster.
So that's kind of the the side of the second part of it though
is we don't just use fuzzing in the cyber grand challenge.
We used a portfolio of techniques.
And what I meant by that is we use a couple of
different things all running at once that are feeding off each other.
And one of the big ones where we got patents was called symbolic execution,
symbolic execution.
What it does is
as you watch the program execute on an input,
it builds up a mathematical formula of what's necessary to take that path like model
checking and then it tries to come up
with an input that would violate that mathematical
model.
And so we've turned reasoning about a program into reasoning about mathematics
and we take advantage of things like SMT and SAT solvers.
So this is what all my work as a professor at
CMU had been is how do we make this efficient?
How do we make this good?
And
we ran both together. And so you kind of have on the one hand fuzz
which just quickly execute a program again and
again with heuristics and then symbolic executors,
which are more like the turtle in this race
where they're slow, but they're very methodical.
They make sure they never duplicate state space and we
use both together and then lots of tricky optimizations,
you know, like everyone kind of went in with these two techniques.
And then the question is how well can you execute with these two techniques?
So do you get like 100%
coverage of all the code paths?
No, no, we don't. This is a great question. So no,
one of the things that was really frustrating for me is
I ran symbolic execution and fuzzing on the program called clear.
So clear is the dumbest program you'll ever see it simply
clears your screen and we are getting like 33% coverage.
And I was like, why are we only get 33% coverage?
And then I'd ran it, run it on Pearl and I was getting 67% coverage
and this is just running at five minutes, right?
So I was completely mystified what's going on here.
And the reason is what we're doing is we're testing a particular input source and
clear has different code paths that are only
executed when you vary the environment variables.
Ah
Yeah, I was just, I would just check and it doesn't take any command line options.
-- So I was like, yeah, wait like what, why not?
-- 100? Yeah.
So we would vary 111 environment variable not another because
really what you're talking about in all of these,
it's more of like a testing paradigm, right?
Like you're taking one thing and you're iterating
and trying to explore all the combinations,
going to the next thing, trying to explore all the combinations.
And so what you're trying to do is maximize code coverage.
And if someone hands us code coverage, we can
every case I've seen improve it.
But saying 100% I mean, you have to realize there may be dead code,
unreachable code code that is outside your configuration just like clear.
And this has also been one of the hard parts when you go to market like, you know,
static analysis looks at all the code
and therefore can find all security vulnerabilities.
I just don't believe it. I would rather have something that looks at less code
and is actionable.
Has zero false positives than something that purports to look
at all the code but has a huge amount.
What you just said about the zero false positives is huge because that
I mean me and Josh being on the receiving end of these reports
and the false positive rate was I would say anywhere from like
very low to
99.9%.
Like I literally received reports where people like
this product doesn't store credit card information correctly.
And I'm like, wait, what we take credit cards to this product now.
Wait, that doesn't sound right like what
you know, and they literally were just cutting and pasting
reports from, I guess,
ecommerce sites or something.
And so that, that false positive rate, I mean, Josh,
how many times did we spend hours or days chasing,
you know, phantoms?
I do it every day where I get a phone book of a report
and then I have to refute some or all of it
and yet
hearing no false positives is that is the dream
and that's what these techniques deliver.
Zero false positives is always reproducible. But
you know, the very first hacker was this guy named Turing, right?
He was trying to break the German code.
I've heard of that guy before.
Yeah. Isn't it interesting how the first computer scientist is a hacker or at least
one of the first
like he has, you know, we go,
we go into computer science courses and we all hear about
undecidable and how you can't even decide whether a program terminates or not,
right?
-- If we remember this from CS 101. Yeah.
-- The stomping the halting problem, right?
Yeah.
And the artifact of this in our world of
programs and try to check them for vulnerabilities is
you can either have false positives and check everything or
you can have no false positives and not check everything.
And I think
really the world was kind of fooled by these initial products.
I mean, they came out actually as like bug detectors and co quality detectors like
coity
and then got relabeled as security tools
when the security budget suddenly materialized.
Yeah, that's true.
You know, their, their entire,
their entire life was trying to prove the absence of something
when,
what we're trying to do in security is prove
the presence of something we want to prove.
Is it a problem
again? Very philosophical. But you got to think of it.
Are you trying to prove the absence of the presence of something? Right.
Well, no, that, that's, I don't think it's philosophical at all.
I think that's exactly the right way to look at this is you, you know,
you can't prove a negative as they say.
And
yeah, you're right. That's exactly what they're doing. Cool.
So, so let's do this, David. We're, we're approaching the end of our time together.
So I'll give you the floor for a few minutes.
Yeah. So,
I mean, I was, I'm a tenured computer science professor at CMU.
That's a pretty nice gig, right? Like I have a lifetime appointment.
I'm moving out to do a start up giving up on that
because I think this idea that we can,
that we can check the world software for exploitable bugs that
we can make it actionable is something that the world needs
to.
And so we're building a product for this.
As you said,
there's tools like a FL that are open source that are also along these lines
that it's good when there's a community if I was the only one saying it,
I'd be the crazy nut.
But I think we're seeing
enough people out there who want tools that
provide actionable results that can test programs,
check the code that's actually going to execute the
thing that's actually going to run on your machine.
I think the full promise of these techniques in the long term is you can
check compiled code which means I no
longer need developer participation to check it.
I think today in the products that are shipping, including including ours,
they tend to do best when you have developer participation
just from a usability perspective.
But I do want to get to that world where we can be fully autonomous,
but also where I can check other people's code
for security vulnerabilities.
Like, you know, I've been able to download code from various vendors,
never had access to the developer and find new zero days.
I think that's the world we want not because it's offensive,
but now I can hold those people responsible for their code quality.
And so that's what our company is trying,
trying to get to is that world where it's fully autonomous, we can find problems,
fix them, test them, give you
an accurate view of the performance impact,
but also kind of get to this world where deep software
testing is the norm and everyone can check everyone else.
And that's how we know everyone's playing it safe.
That's awesome. I
I cannot wait for that future because I think today if you look at the state of things,
it, it doesn't look so bright.
So
here's I, I hope it works out, man.
So I guess if people want to get a hold of you guys, where should we send them?
Uh go to our website for All secure.com, forallsecure.com.
We chose that name because it kind of reflects what I just said.
We think security is for everyone
and we're kind of math geek.
So the for all symbol, the universal quantifier is our logo.
That's very cool. All right. And I'll put links to all this in the show notes.
So, yeah, I guess. Awesome. Thank you so much, David. Thank you, Kurt.
This has been a fantastic episode.
You can go to open source security podcast.com,
hit up the show notes so you can use the Pound
Os S podcast hashtag to find us on social media.
-- Yeah, Kurt and David have fabulous rest of your days.
-- Thanks everybody. Thank
you.
Awesome. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.