Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
This is the Running in Place episode with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- What? Running in place? Yeah,
treadmills
also a reference to Alice in Wonderland.
Right. The Red Queen. You have to run as fast as you can just to stay in place.
And that's
honestly how the last few weeks have felt.
That is my life right now. I'm, I'm running in place and falling behind.
It's frustrating.
The,
the one thing I've always noticed with that is
when those weeks or months happen is that a
lot of the stuff that falls by the wayside
turns out you didn't really actually have to do.
I have been culling tasks for years.
Like I did recently spend two hours outside on a step ladder,
chipping ice out of my gutters because they were solidly full
of ice in the front of the house because it,
you know, the sun hits it, it melts in the evening
-- but, and then just freezes overnight.
-- Right?
-- That sounds like an incredibly dangerous task.
-- It's actually really easy.
You just a hammer and a screwdriver and you smash it up
in the little pieces and pull it out of the gutter.
-- Yeah.
-- You're not filling me with confidence
that
I own a really good ladder.
Like I, I spent good money on a good ladder.
That's not wobbly like it, trust me because, yeah,
I don't want to be up on a wobbly ladder and fall 10 ft and break my
-- everything 10
-- feet. My roof is probably 40 ft in the air.
-- Oh, yeah. No, my house is relatively.
-- I would definitely not
do that. Yeah. No, no.
With 40 ft, I'd hire somebody
or, you know, install one of those electric heaters for your gutter to keep it.
I just let my gutters fill with ice and I YOLO it
-- so it's fine.
-- Yeah.
-- But then you get ice stands and you get your roof pushes up and
-- it's fine. It's fine.
Everything's fine. Kirk,
it's fine.
It's all fine.
But, yeah. No. So I recently got a treadmill and it was actually really
interesting experience. What always gets me.
Now when I buy big kind of complicated machines that I'm also expected
to partially assemble myself is how much easier and better it's gotten.
Partly because, you know, they just, they don't want to hear from you.
-- I
-- mean, that's pretty fair.
So
I will,
I will prewarn the listeners that Kurt decided we should discuss his treadmill,
endeavors as the security topic of the week.
And I'm as enthralled as you are as to how this is going to
work out because he doesn't tell me how this is going to go.
-- So, here we are,
-- there's a lot of things we,
in the security industry could learn from these people,
but there's also a lot of things we just,
how do I put it nicely we can't do or what we do do. But,
you know, like there's a lot of passing the buck for sure in this,
in the security world or in the treadmill world.
-- That is fair.
-- Yeah, because like, it's right now it is my favorite.
I love the important precautions. This treadmill came with. There's
a,
there's 31 of them.
I'm not going to, I'm not even going to come close to reading all of them,
but only 31 only 31.
But I mean,
it's things like it is the responsibility of the owner to ensure that
all users of this treadmill are adequately
informed of all warnings and precautions.
I mean, that seems pretty fair, but there's 31 of these and then there's things like
use the treadmill only as described in this manual,
which leads me to wonder what have people done with and to
and on their treadmills that weren't sort of normal treadmill activities.
-- Let's say,
-- haven't you seen this
of
people with treadmills on the internet?
-- There's some hilariously awesome videos
-- like doing the
ball bounce things and stuff like that.
The ok, go video, right. That ok go treadmill video.
There's, there's that one but then there's also,
I've seen people where they put like,
food on it and they hold their mouth open while the food.
But it's pretty sweet. There's some cool videos. I'm trying to think.
There's some other really funny ones.
I've seen where people tried to put a bicycle on it and they
-- like,
-- of course, like two treadmills for that.
I mean, I guess you'd have to one run in reverse because they
just
put it.
Well, no, no, no. But most treadmills aren't long enough to put a bike on.
Well, no, because they put it on,
they get on the bike and then they fall off immediately.
I mean, that's the only reason the videos on youtube, if it works, if it worked,
no one would care.
Well, I imagine a unicycle you'd have more luck, shorter wheelbase.
I don't know. Like,
I have no idea.
But the point is, I mean,
there's also the Survivor bias of things like treadmills where you
hear about the really dumb stuff that people got hurt doing.
So, these silly legal things.
Well,
like this keep Children under age of 13 and pets away from the treadmill at all times.
That seems fair.
But like the things in my basement I'm supposed to, like, put, you know,
like construction fencing around it or something.
-- No, like
-- none of this is real.
It's, I don't just,
so when you try to sue them someday they can say
it was in the phone book of instructions we gave you.
You didn't follow them so, too bad.
-- It's not our
-- problem,
which is something in the software industry we've been
doing forever and getting away with it seems,
I mean,
until people, you know, freak out about whatever the given flavor of the week is.
Yeah, that's pretty common.
And then, but the best part is as long as you can weather the storm for a week,
most people move on to the next thing and then you're fine again.
Yeah. It's kind of just how it's worked.
But in fairness they did do something that we talked about earlier.
That is pretty awesome. Which is when I was assembling the treadmill.
It comes obviously with a bunch of like nuts and bolts and screws and stuff
fasteners basically.
And they're on like this heavy piece of cardboard that's been like shrink wracked,
laminated and all the parts.
There's like, step one,
step one is labeled on the cardboard with like a line
around it with the parts for step one and then like,
step two, same thing.
There's like,
you know, the eight bolts, the eight thing.
And yeah, and I was just like, because I'm looking at it, I'm like, oh,
like there's a lot of like, I'm gonna have to find the pieces and then I'm like, oh, no,
it says step one, step two.
I look at the manual. It's like OK. This is awesome.
This straight up is just, and it literally,
yeah, the whole thing took me about, I don't know about an hour to assemble
in total by myself, right?
It would have been way faster with two people, you know,
somebody to hold it while I'm trying to like fit the
Yeah.
No, it was,
I I've literally had more trouble assembling IKEA furniture than this thing,
right?
Because I do furniture has that bad habit of using those
wooden pigs that you got to be really careful tapping in.
If you overdrive them, you know, you, you've just buggered up the whole thing.
Yeah, I've been there.
Yeah. And you can't fix it once you split particle board.
This is an interesting problem and I see this in security all the time where
there's, you know, there's the old argument of you can have security or usability
and usability will always
-- win because security. Well, that's
-- what people want.
Exactly.
That's what they're buying your product for, not for security in most cases.
And I think this kind of put together industry. So
I remember probably 20 or 30 years ago
when put together stuff was kind of becoming the new thing
and it was a nightmare. It was really bad. So I remember I, when I was in
high school I was probably 1617 give or take.
I went and worked at a store that sold, it was like a,
like a department style store where they had all different things.
And I was in the hardware department and furniture was part of that group.
And so the put together furniture was our group's responsibility to do.
And I remember the lady who was in charge of it would
bless her heart. She would start putting it together.
And inevitably, every time be like whoever was working, she'd say you finish this.
I give up and it was,
and the instructions were so bad.
I remember usually we'd look at the picture and we just
do our best to put things in the right place.
So it looked like the picture and it was,
if anyone actually tried to use this furniture,
it would have collapsed immediately because it was a bunch of
high school kids who had no idea what they were doing,
you know, not putting it together correctly.
-- Plus
-- you're putting something together that's
been partially put together and we're,
you know, we
skipped
or
like
that's what always gets me with Lego. Right.
When my one kid is assembling Lego, he'll like, oh, this doesn't work.
-- I immediately flip back eight pages and start from there.
-- Exactly.
That's exactly right.
A friend of mine, you know,
she made her little street sweeper and she's like the little Lego
man doesn't fit in and she's getting all annoyed and I like,
look at it and I look at the picture and I look at it and I look at the picture
and then I like,
move the little steering wheel forwards where it is on the picture and I'm, like,
-- poop and he goes
-- in defense of the Children.
I do that all the time too.
You get to a step and it's just like this part doesn't fit.
And then you, like, look at, you,
look at the picture and it's like something is subtly different.
But, and then you're like, yeah, you flip back like 5,
10 pages and start doing your forensic investigation.
-- Right.
And although I feel like even LEGO,
I don't feel like it's as difficult as it used to be.
When
-- was young, the
-- instructions are way better.
And what I actually,
and this is going to show my age and my get off my lawn is almost all the sets.
-- Now come with that bs orange crowbar piece.
-- Oh my goodness.
That is the most amazing tool I've ever used. It. Lets you take the Lego pieces apart.
You can use your damn teeth like the rest of us.
I, I get,
don't laugh like I have my old Lego that my parents have in
their basement has teeth marks all over the pieces because of me.
Right. Yeah, exactly. I'm like I was some sort of animal. No, man,
this is, this is what progress looks like and this is even I, I
I'm going to frame this in the context of security.
No, I will give you that orange piece makes lifting pieces a million times. I
mean, and you think you look at a lot of security
and I feel like we're still prying pieces off with our,
-- with our teeth instead of
-- that's assuming they weren't glued on
by the vendor.
Yeah, sometimes, sometimes.
And I mean, so part of this too though, and this is,
this is actually something I'm dealing with right now and I was,
I was complaining to you before I hit record is I am running into so many
security teams that either have this mindset from
probably the mid two thousands or like,
they, they watched a movie and they wrote down the threats and it's,
I want to help you, but this isn't real.
I
get this all the time,
you know, because the CS A is 100% cloud based and we get these audit questions.
Number one,
there's a lot of companies that no matter what you are as a vendor,
they basically make the assumption you're
somehow getting and processing their data.
And we're like, right, we're just not, that's not what we do. We don't do that.
And they're like, but you still have to fill out these questions and I'm like,
but they don't make any sense in this context.
We don't back up your data because we don't
have it.
-- Yep. Yep. I see that,
-- you know, what do I say? Or
do
so actually fund
enough. I see both sides of that where I will see someone looking to use
Sass and they send a question that's
clearly for something running on their hardware.
Or I'll see people wanting to run something on their
hardware and they send a questionnaire that's clearly for Sass.
And it's like none of these questions matter because
I'm not running this computer. Like, is it just encrypted? I don't know. You tell me
your,
your computer.
I
mean, I know I have TLS to Google and beyond that, I here's their documentation.
So actually you remind me too. I, I was talking, I freaking, I was talking to a friend
that they'd gotten, they were, they were complaining to me over a beer.
They got one of these questionnaires
and there were questions about the data center and like,
how far is it from the nearest body of water?
And what's the elevation and all this? And they're like,
it's freaking Amazon.
And they said that the customer they were working with was adamant.
They answered the questions and they basically said, I don't know what to do.
I'm trying to think like, cause Amazon really,
China, they really keep the locations of their data centers kind of on the down low.
And what's interesting,
like they just recently opened up a new set of
data centers in Central Canada and by central Canada,
they mean like eastern Canada,
but they basically explicitly said,
like they looked at ice storms because these things are out in Quebec and Ontario.
That's the thing.
And they're like,
we have at least one physical path that's
100% underground between our data centers for five
stuff like that.
That makes sense though. That's important.
And they talked about literally like we looked at floods, we looked at snowstorms,
we looked at angry moose, whatever, right?
Like they, because Amazon probably has,
if I had to guess a team of 10 to 20 people who think about angry moose,
it's a legitimate concern.
Like, if you have an angry moose on your campus in Canada, that's a serious problem.
-- It sounds really funny, but like moose are actually quite dangerous.
-- Well,
yeah,
like the thing to keep in mind is basically a
moose is about as big as your car and meaner
mean, you know, it's an easier comparison probably is like,
let's say you build a data center where polar bears live.
You would have to be concerned about that.
You can't go outside if there's a polar bear outside.
Well, and even better now we have these things called cinnamon bears,
which are a mixture of polar bear and brown bear.
-- Yeah,
-- that sounds great.
Basically all the articles agree. Just, just leave them alone.
I would leave any bear alone. I see, regardless of whether black
bears are like they're, they're cuddly friendly, you can feed them and pet them.
No, I live in a place that has black bears
and I do not go near the black bears.
I luckily they're, they're generally black bears are very skittish.
And if they see you, they run away.
If they didn't,
I would run away.
Plain and simple.
But, but anyway, anyway, they have valid concerns and they're, at the same time,
let's say I put data in Amazon's cloud.
I don't even know what data center it's in.
-- Right. Most of the time.
-- Well, you can, you can sort of force it to a region,
a
region, Canada one or us East two. Which,
but we
-- think is like Ohio,
-- nobody knows where that is. And how many buildings do they have?
I don't know.
Well, it's not so much how many buildings they,
but the thing to remember is like an Amazon
availability zone is like multiple is my understanding.
I could be wrong but it's multiple discrete,
what we would traditionally call a data center campus.
It's like multiples of those because, you know, a tornado hits one and, well,
whoops, we lost one but we got two more.
-- We're
-- ok.
Stop
guessing what Amazon's doing. Let's reel it back to the context of more to the point.
We don't have to guess because they filled out a bunch of sock
two reports and all this other stuff saying that they like engineered,
they over engineered the bejesus out of this and I'm inclined to trust them,
you know, it's like cars, right?
What steel alloy does your car frame use?
Was it chewing gum or whatever steel, that's good.
I assume it's the good one,
the National Insurance Institute or whatever it's called,
tested it. And since they're selling me insurance on my car,
I assume it passed.
Well, funny story,
remember there was that Japanese scandal a few years ago
where this major steel company was faking steel testing results.
And so there's all this steel floating around that may or may not be what it says it is,
But in general, you know.
Yeah. No, you're right.
There's testing and there's regulation for this that works.
There's always going to be
off events, but you can't plan for them. So don't try.
And there's nothing more infuriating to me than people who
try to include Black Swan events and their threat models.
Like if it is a Black Swan event, it doesn't belong in a threat model.
And actually this is, it's funny, I mentioned this.
So there's my mythic Star Trek talk, I've been working on right forever,
which has been canceled from all the events it was going to be at.
But whatever it doesn't matter.
I just,
I've been working on the slides and I just added
a slide for the episode where I call it,
Picard has a fiddle duel with the devil.
And there's, there's an episode which one was that
it's called, I forget the name of it.
There's a character named Ara who is supposedly like the devil
who's collecting on a bargain a society made 1000 years ago
and she turns out to be a scam artist, but like, I'm using this as an example of like,
does your threat model include the devil?
Well, I hope not, you know, like, because how do you possibly plan for that?
And what does it mean? You know? You know what I'm saying?
-- Well,
-- and again, you know, we go back to taking reasonable precautions. Yeah, so
back to the treadmill thing.
So it's, you know, it's funny to me because, yeah, a lot of this is obvious legalese,
like keeping your pets and under 13
year old Children away from it.
Although somehow magically the day they turn 13 it'll be ok and safe for them to use.
-- I,
-- for whatever reason, 13 is a magic age in the legal world.
It seems because it's the same deal with online.
Your kids aren't allowed to have any online, anything till they turn 13.
And then all of a sudden, like, open the floodgates. Everyone.
-- Uh,
-- my kids have lots of online stuff.
Well, they're not supposed to Xbox.
That's different. Actually, Microsoft has a nice program for that.
There's a lot of these services though that if,
if they ask for a birthday and you're under 13, they're just like, no, can't do it.
But then what I love is you can hit back, change a birthday and they're like, oh,
good job, everyone.
Congratulations. You're 13 now.
And it's like everyone knows what's going on here but everyone,
it's not.
And actually, I mean,
this is one of the problems I think is these
younger kids will try to sign up for a service.
They're told you have to be 13. So they enter a wrong birth date in many instances.
They're just entering like I'm 45 now, you know, I'm not, you know,
whatever that is more dangerous like that.
That's a great example.
And like we do this in security or we say, oh no, you can't do that.
And so people just find a way to go around us and now we've fallen out of their ability
to actually help and monitor and they've gone off
grid and that's far more dangerous in every instance.
Well, yeah, I mean, I can't even imagine how many people have removed, you know,
safety, software, security, software, disabled bits of it.
-- Yeah. To just get their job done.
-- Right.
I mean, my, again, I, I pick on Se Linux every time if Se Linux
gets in my way, I turn it off and I hope
hopefully remember to turn it back on later. But I don't know.
I don't know.
I, to me it's funny, the whole idea of multi, true,
multi user systems to me is you're doing it wrong.
You should containerize or lambda or as a service
now now.
And, well,
-- but we have that now
-- 15 years ago that didn't exist but
it's not 15 years ago anymore.
Like
-- it,
-- it's not
tell that
to the people I've been talking to for the last two weeks.
It's like everybody is like, how do you back up your user devices?
And I'm like, I, I don't
like
-- every, all our data is in the cloud or
-- it should be seriously,
well,
more of the point like, for example,
on a phone or tablet to get your data onto the local device and locally manipulate it.
I mean, it's nontrivial like I could do it.
But I mean, if you get me a Google worksheet,
I'd have to do all sorts of shenanigans to actually get it onto my phone and
-- only have it on my phone and manipulate it on my phone and
-- that would be
stupid.
Exactly. So the answer is no, no normal user is ever going to do that.
I always love that when someone will send me like AAA Excel spreadsheet.
And I'll just say I'm, I'm not going to look at this. You have to send me a Google sheet.
They're like, what?
Like, seriously, I'm not going to look at this, like the odds of me messing with this,
sending it back to you and you incorporating the correct changes.
0%.
If you want me to collaborate, you're going to send me a Google Sheet or Microsoft,
you know, office online or whatever.
I don't care, but not this.
And you know,
it's a game changer there telling people there is a work offline button now,
right?
Like, and,
and I get it because a lot of people want their
Excel or whatever things so they can work on it.
Well,
in past when they were on a plane or whatever,
whatever man everywhere has internet now.
Well now, but again, like five years ago,
-- maybe five years ago, but like
-- for real, but more to the point,
there's an offline button now and you can just fuck all your data off.
And what I discovered shockingly the the Google change merging.
It's kind of like Google hire smart engineers or
something because the change merging actually shockingly good.
Like because I, I did some major offline edits on a document,
forgot to like I had my laptop closed, brought home,
started working on it on my desktop and I'm like, where's all my changes?
Like my brain didn't even remember that I'd done this offline.
And then I was like, oh no.
And then so I, I literally opened my laptop log in wait like 20 seconds.
And then I'm like, oh everything's fine now, just magically synced.
So and I think that's part of it. Like I try to
stay abreast of what cloud services have and offer
and kind of what the cool new stuff is
-- and even I forget like that this offline thing is an option.
-- Yeah. Yeah, I
hear you.
And so again, for normal people to even know that that's a thing.
-- Yeah,
-- it's definitely a challenge and even for security things, I mean, this is,
this is one thing actually I try to be sensitive about is
there's so much change happening all the time.
And, like, even I'll admit, I don't know everything. I learn new things every day.
Unquestionably. But it's, it is hard right now.
If you're a security team trying to keep up with the various, you know,
threats and risks and everything going on around you, it's, it's a crazy time.
-- Well,
-- plus then you have all the legacy systems where it's like, yeah,
the world has been right.
Well, except for this one part that's 20 years
-- and mission critical because it does payroll
-- you, you, we need it.
You can't turn it off. No, I love that.
Like I was so proud,
one older system got turned off and it's stayed off and the plan to replace it
-- got mixed and I was just so happy and
-- sometimes that's the right way to do it
is if something will accidentally go away, you can work around it somehow.
And then
amazingly,
the system that couldn't be turned off was turned off and the world didn't end.
Yeah. The classic scream test methodology.
Yes.
I, I always love that in the security universe where it's like, oh, you can't do that,
the world will end and then people do it.
And it's like, well, everything's cool guys.
And now what?
Well, and, but the challenge is you might also on the flip side,
you might be doing something that ends up creating systemic risk and
the world
does
-- sort of end.
-- That is true. There, there can be challenges there.
-- We
-- don't
-- always know which is
-- which. Well, I mean, that's our job
and
it's one of those things like, yeah, in hindsight.
-- Oh, that should have been an obvious problem.
-- It isn't always.
But, I mean, in all seriousness, like this is one of the challenges I think is when,
when the security team is just obsessed with no,
then you end up in a situation where you become an obstacle to progress
and you're worked around as a different problem to the one you're ignoring.
-- The problem
-- is incentives, right?
Because every time the security team says yes and then something goes wrong,
-- the security team gets beaten with a stick
-- actually.
Do you know what? Now that you say that I, I'm sure there's counterexamples to this.
But generally speaking,
when I've seen a security team try to be reasonable and something does go wrong.
I've never seen them like,
harshly punished as long as they deal with the failure appropriately.
Right. Well, and that's the problem.
A lot of organizations are more about blame than about fixing the actual problem.
So it's just
from my local incentive,
my local maximum is to say no and not spend a lot of time and effort
trying to make it better because that's something I really try hard to do is when,
you know, people come to me with a security thing.
I'm like, ok, well,
I actually want to understand what it is you're trying to do
and then let's figure out a good way to do it.
Right. A lot of them, you know, initially are kind of shocked.
They're like, I'm like, I want to help you and they're like, what, you know, that,
that's sort of suspicious where you're offering, you know,
a, a stray dog, some food and the stray dogs, like, I want to bite you,
but it smells like food,
but I don't trust you and I want to bite you.
And so many people have just, how many times did somebody in it,
let alone security actually try and help them.
I've had a lot of bad experiences.
I mean, I'm not gonna lie and, and I was a lot of bad experiences.
I'm not going to pretend I'm innocent in any of this.
Like my current Sega trying to get this Xbox up and running.
It's so awesome.
-- Like I just want to spend some money so we can play games
-- and you know what makes
me sad is Microsoft does a better job at this than almost anyone else I've ever seen.
And
-- it is terrible.
-- I
agree.
I can't even imagine the nightmare that is other things like Steam is amazing.
I love Steam and now that I'm dealing with Xbox, it's just like, wow, this is
like Microsoft, I just, I know my son is a child
but I want the account to be under his name. That's it. That's what I want.
Try signing up for any of these other services with a child.
And you'll see, like,
obviously if your kids are running steam you've lied about their age.
-- Oh, really?
-- Ok.
Yeah. Exactly. Exactly.
Because in fact, my kids used my Steam account for a really long time.
And so it's always funny now because I'll look at my,
what it was the list of games played
and it's like, I don't even know what these are
-- but whatever, whatever.
-- I think there's a lot for us still to make
dress on.
And the good news is though I, one thing that frustrates me is like,
there's a lot of other industries that have gotten objectively better.
Like IKEA furniture,
I remember what assembling IKEA furniture was like 2025 years ago compared to now.
And like this treadmill, this treadmill was easy, literally like an hour of my time
just putting it together, you know,
cutting the pieces off of the laminated cardboard one step at a time and
there were no pieces missing. The counts were correct. Like, yeah, it was lovely.
-- Well,
-- and you know,
so part of this too is my suspicion is whoever helped design this assembly program.
I don't know what to even call it.
You need the right incentives because obviously the incentive is you want people to
get your product and not need to call you for help to assemble it.
Well, here's one thing that's interesting.
So the manual is model number blah blah blah 0.0.
And then there's this giant piece of
yellow paper and they're saying important customer notice
the model number of your treadmill is blah, blah, blah, blah blah 0.3.
So they're iterating
the heck out of this thing like this is the fourth iteration,
I assume they had a 0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 I
think.
And so things have clearly changed.
There's one step where it's like, you know,
if this piece has two screws already mounted in it,
take them out and I'm like looking at it and
there's like two screws in this thing and I'm like,
oh, ok, take them out.
And so, you know,
it's clear that they've iterated and they've done the value engineering
of kind of either making the parts cheaper or somehow reducing
the parts count or I don't know what the heck doing
because this manual works for this newer version of the treadmill.
And what's interesting though is that they had these steps where it's like,
you know,
if you see this just kind of ignore it or take it out or throw it away or whatever.
Yeah, they kind of knew that was coming.
Maybe there could be a lot of reasons that happened.
I mean,
they might have reprinted portions of the manual too because
you think if you only have to reprint page three,
it's going to be a lot easier to just reprint page three than like all of it.
So it's, it's what's fascinating to me though is that like,
I look at the security industry and it's the
cloud definitely has been making things a lot better,
right?
Like the number of cloud services now where I can just
do enabling single sign on now for a lot of cloud services
is like in Zendesk, it was like go to this one page and and turn it on and yeah, that's,
that's awesome, right?
It's like with Slack,
I think I had to click a link in an email to prove that I own that domain kind of thing,
right?
Like literally, it was so
so easy
and I think about what it was like, you know, 5, 10 years ago, oh God,
I don't even want to think about what it was like five or 10 years ago.
No, it was, it was terrible.
But then you look at the the software world and most of these
things trying to enable single sign on in a piece of software.
No, I hear you.
And I guess that's like, look, that's the overall message here is it's all about
if I was a user,
what does that mean? Right. What is my experience look like? How can I make it better?
And this is true of if you're building security
features or even if you're building security process,
put yourself in the other position
and say, what does this look like? And then how can I make it?
-- So obviously, the, the less callbacks the customer,
-- well, even simpler,
if users can't use your stuff, they're not going to use your stuff or,
or they waste your time asking for clarification,
which is not good either.
And obviously in many business settings, you can't not use something
because you're an employee at the company and you
need your laptop tied into email or whatever.
All right. So we've been, we've been going on and on about this.
But you, you told me at the beginning you have a funny story to tell.
And before you run out of time,
I want to hear it because I'm concerned you won't tell
-- me otherwise
-- I go shopping like once a week now,
you know, I'm wearing my P PE and everything
and I was at a red light
on a major road and there's this silver car kind of
coming southbound on this major road kind of lurching along.
And I'm like, wow, that person is drunk, like
they can't drive in a straight line for more than 4 ft without suddenly stopping.
And then,
you know, I'm just like, wow,
and then I take a closer look and like the, the, the pass or the driver's side,
front end is smashed in at the corner and I'm like, ok, like their cars all beat up
and then I noticed the tires, the one tire pointed in at 15 degrees.
Oh, that seems normal.
Yeah, this is a major road.
Like this person has been driving on this road for a while anyways, they,
they get through the green light, their green light and I, like,
pull behind them and I'm like,
honking at them and, like, kind of waving my arm to get them to stop because like
this person literally she can't drive her car like more
than about eight or 9 ft without it lurching because
the axle is broken.
So I pull over in front of her to like force her to physically stop.
And I call the police and the police are like, oh, ok.
Yeah, we'll send, you know,
we put a call out and actually a cop showed up like less than five minutes later
and you know, I see in the rear view mirror,
I see him talk to her and then he comes up to me,
he starts talking to me and then he looks back at me.
He's like, 00 wow. Yeah, that looks way worse from the front than from the side.
And he's like, yeah,
so because one of the questions they asked me is
like there is there a damage sticker on the car?
You know, like when you get in an accident, your car is beat up,
you have that sticker on it saying like my car got this damage.
So, like, don't worry about it. I reported to the police. We cool.
So, you know that it's like they didn't commit a hit and run or whatever.
All right. Cool. Right.
So, anyways there's no damage to her.
So I'm like, yeah, this must be like new and I, whatever she hit, like,
she hit it pretty hard because,
I mean, to break an axle on a car, you know, those things are made out of metal
anyways, the accident had happened,
she said a half an hour ago and she'd been driving like this for half an hour.
And he's like, yeah, she, she's agreed like she was now saying that, oh,
I'm just trying to pull over on this one road over here to wait for a tow truck.
Right.
So, yeah, I assume, you know, rather than get a ticket, she's like, oh, I meant to,
you know, I was trying to pull over
and it just blew my mind that this person had been
driving their car around for like half an hour with a broken axle,
eight or 9 ft at a time lurching into the other lane.
I imagine if you're driving around with a broken axle,
like you've gone from probably bad damage to catastrophic damage.
Yeah, I know the car is probably a write off
at the front end is going to have to be replaced which, you know,
it's a Subaru. So it's
not going to be cheap
and it just, it blew my mind that I get, that you're in an accident, you get shook up.
But if your car can't drive more than eight
or 9 ft without lurching to one side violently,
like you got to stop and call a tow truck people and,
and I see this in security people do some sort of, oh, no, no, no.
It's normal. Like we just turn the system off and on every seven
minutes.
Yeah. Yeah, that's, that's a good story.
-- Like I,
-- I just, I don't know what to make of, you know, like this person, I just, what,
I just don't, yeah,
I just can't fathom this kind of this thought process where something is that
-- terribly broken and they're just trying to live with it.
-- I can explain this.
This is a very human condition
and I will throw security people under the bus. Here is,
there was a period of time
where
we had, I, I worked at a company, everyone had their own computers.
They were expected to take care of them
and then at some point,
yeah, whatever.
At some point the,
basically an inventory was taken of operating
systems and computers and everything going on.
It was part of some compliance program that was needed for.
I don't even remember what anymore.
It's been so long the security people by far had
applied fewer updates than anyone else in the company.
But this is, it's very typical. Right. I'm a security person.
I don't need to worry about that. I know what, what I'm doing.
And I think this is very typical of people where people love to be.
Like, well, I'm special.
I don't need to worry about that because I'm, I'm not like everyone else. And it's,
yeah, you are like,
the rules need to apply to, you just like they apply to me because if they don't,
then society collapses
talking about society collapsing is probably less funny right now.
-- But you know what I mean? Like it
-- is a great,
-- we've gone through worse
-- maybe. But I think it's human nature.
And I think the, the key to this though
is not shame and yelling,
which is what like security is historically
trying to do it is compassion and understanding
of saying, ok, so you did this thing.
Here's how we can help you fix it.
Like you have to go do this now. You stupid idiot.
Well, yeah, that's I was, I was telling her I'm like, lady,
you need to call a tow truck.
Like you can't, you can't drive on that like it's broken,
like not a little bit broken.
It's like broken, broken, like your car's doing ballet
-- and
-- sometimes all people need is another person to give them a little nudge and,
and then they do the right thing.
Yeah.
In this case, that's the reason I had to block her is because she kept trying to go.
Now, I will say my personal stance on a lot of this is often
when I see a situation like that,
I'm not overly inclined to get involved generally because it can, it can go bad
in terrible ways.
-- Like, you're lucky. I
-- live in Canada. That's much less of a concern.
-- Yeah,
-- there's, there's less guns and stuff but, like,
even ignoring that kind of stuff, I have seen people, like,
get the crap beat out of them doing stuff like what you just did.
I stayed in my car, the doors were locked, like, yeah, no, I get it.
But at the same time, I also felt like this is going to crash into somebody and, well,
I could have stopped it.
Well, I, I commend you and I think we need more people who will do those little things.
Like another great example I saw when I was at the Home Depot
coming out, loading my car,
these two guys are loading their truck and then they peel
off their nitro gloves and throw them on the ground.
Now that's just littering. Don't do that.
And I, I yell at them and I'm like, hey, you know,
pick that up and put in the garbage and he looked at me and I'm like,
put it in the garbage
and they did pick it up and throw it in the back of their truck.
So it might have ended up in the garbage. But
I, I mean, I think we need more people who will speak up and say, you know, look,
stop spitting on the ground or stop whatever it is you're doing, that's ridiculous.
And just not hard to change the behavior and make the world a much better place.
Maybe I'm going to end this episode before we get into that discussion because I,
I feel unprepared
to discuss that and I have a feeling you
and I have fundamental differences in our opinions here.
So that's ok though. Right? I'm calling it. That is a marvelous story though.
Kurt, thank you for sharing it. So, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Head up the show notes, use
Pound
Oss
Podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye
bye.