Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- I have a marvelous story to tell you.
So this weekend,
I did a lot of work preparing a garden around the house and
we ironically had planned this long before the current state of world affairs.
I had to do a lot of digging
-- and a lot of tilling and just the usual preparation of the ground.
-- Sure.
-- I, I've never gardened.
-- It's harder than it seems.
I have tried to dig up some tree stumps and bush stumps in my backyard.
And I, the decision I
-- was, I'm going to hire a guy with a baby backhoe.
-- Yes. Dumps are the worst thing ever.
But anyway,
so I was digging a hole to move a plant because I had a plant in
where the garden is going to go and I wanted to move it and I'm digging
and guess what I found in the bottom of the hole, a rock. No, the, my internet line.
-- I was like, I'm really glad.
-- Did you find both ends of it or
just not two? Just one.
Yes. That was my first. I was like, oh my goodness, did I break this?
And so I, of course, like,
ran inside and started running speed test and stuff to make sure, like,
my internet connection was good and it was, and everything's fine,
but it was the most terrifying moment I've had in a very long time.
I'm guessing, like, mine,
they have like the little baby board directional drill
that they pushed it through your yard with.
No, they, they, like, ran a little trench but it's only, it's only maybe
-- six inches to a foot deep. Like, it's not deep.
-- Yeah.
No, my, my line is like, maybe a,
about a foot ish underground and it's like a tiny scrawny, little white line.
It's
like when you sneeze on it you're going to break it.
So, anyway,
-- that was my, I don't know if I'd call it valuable lesson.
-- Stupid question.
But what do you think the time to repair would be ignoring the current situation?
I mean, it sounds to me like, because you, with one of those big American providers,
right?
And aren't they, like, comically evil and terrible?
-- They're,
-- they're generally slow.
I bet it would be on the order of a week or more to get a new line run?
-- I
-- wonder if you could get a private guy to come because, like,
I know a guy who does cable installs and he
actually is trained on fiber joins because it's honestly,
if you have all the equipment and you know what you're doing,
it's like a 20 minute job.
-- Right.
-- I mean,
yes. And if you don't have any of that stuff, it's impossible.
My suspicion is it's illegal to, you could probably mess with the stuff in my house.
But I bet messing with the box in the yard would be illegal.
Well, I didn't say messing with the box. I meant just like rejoining it.
Oh, just splicing it. I mean, I don't see why you couldn't pay someone to splice it.
-- I don't know if that would even be worth it.
-- Well, you wouldn't, you know what?
-- Because you wouldn't have any
-- slack. I could make slack.
So,
actually when there's a lot of slack on the side
of the house on this table and at that point,
like craves, I just, if I could find someone to join it,
like I'd dig it up by hand and pull, you know,
just to make it work because no internet right
now would be literally the worst thing ever.
You can't work well.
And, I mean, in fairness, you know, I've been working from home for 20 some years.
It would be terrible. You figure there's work, there's watching various TV shows.
They like everything I would and
I could tether a cell phone or whatever, but it would not be the same.
Especially like I have fast internet. I'm used to my gigabit up and down. I need it.
Well, Yeah, for the longest time I had, you know,
we have two infrastructure players here.
We have the cable company and the phone company.
And for the longest time I had one from each because I worked from home,
you know, and there were times where it would go down for half an hour,
an hour and being able to switch to the other one and
not have that hour of downtime because it would only ever happen.
Of course, when I was working on something that needed to be done right away.
-- But
-- now it same time, you know what this got me and I was thinking about that is, oh,
I don't have any backup solution.
And I actually the cable company. Yeah, you do, you have your phone, I've got that.
But I'm saying like the cable company has a line run to my house.
So like I could theoretically call them and go pick
up equipment and make that work if I needed to,
which could be an alternative.
But then at the same time, I also was thinking,
so let's say so the cable company when I canceled my service through them said, oh,
we're going to run fiber optic to the neighborhood.
I'm like, that's
call me when it's done. Like, I don't see how that helped me now.
But,
but anyway, like, let's say they do run it and they want to run fiber to my house.
How are they going to run the line without chopping the other one because
I don't think there's any wire or anything in this fiber optic line that you can,
like, scan for, you know, with the magic machines.
Yeah, because I know,
like all our gas lines here have the little wire tied to
the side of it so they can run a tone down.
It.
It turns out at my last house,
my gas line came out of my house at a 45 degree angle and then went straight back.
So, like, you know, where the,
like where the meter is on the back of the house. My assumption was like, it just went
straight out to the alleyway where the main gas line was and it's like the guy's like,
yeah, no, it,
it goes off at 45 degrees and then it goes straight
out and it actually went where the back gate was.
And I'm like, I would, that's 10 ft away from where I would have guessed where it is.
Well, and that's, I mean, you never know how any of this is, run it.
-- It's, it's madness and a mystery for
-- sure.
So, what I do now is, is I either find out where it is or I call, click uh, before you dig,
well, you know, call, you set up the website.
-- Yeah.
-- Call those people no matter what.
Well, this is, even before I'm doing anything, I just want to know where it is.
So that if I do need to know where it is,
I have it and I don't have to wait for them to come out and do it.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, definitely.
I got caught up on my vaccines last year, you know, because my tetanus shot was like,
20 years out of date.
Oh, wow. Well, you're supposed to get one every 10 years.
So, like, 10 years is more than enough time to, like,
just completely forget about it.
-- And then, you know, so I pulled my vaccine records and I'm kind of like, huh?
-- Ok.
So my doctor actually has really good about that because
I just got a whole bunch of vaccines last year.
I was in there like, oh, you're, you know, you're way overdue on all these.
And I don't know if they were like,
happened to be checking in on people or if I just got lucky that the nurse looked it up.
But, yeah, they, like, they loaded me up with stuff because I'm like, great.
I'll take whatever. I don't care.
I don't want, like, freaking rabies or something.
-- Hook me up.
-- Yeah.
And I mean, it's one of those things where if you do it in advance, great.
And it's, you know,
because I remember when we got the
meningitis vaccine because there was a meningitis
locally because it was spreading and they didn't know how
probably, you know, people looking each other at raves
obviously.
But, yeah, I remember, you know, getting that, you know,
meningitis is one of those things where you don't,
you basically can't get vaccinated for it
unless there's an outbreak because it's just,
it's rare enough that, like, we don't bother.
-- Yeah. I don't think I have that one. You
-- know, it's like d
cor,
all right.
Unless you go to the travel clinic and get
it because we don't have cholera in North America.
Like, that's not a problem in most of where we live thankfully,
because we have toilets now.
So everything's
-- and toilet
-- paper for
now for now. I mean, all right.
Anyway, so anyway, let's, that's enough.
Well, one bit of quick news turns out I was right. Microsoft bought
corp.com.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, so this,
this news doesn't surprise me in any way because I think they are dumb to not buy it.
-- Well,
-- just the cost and hassle alone of dealing with all those support calls.
Well, in the world doesn't need any more chaos right now.
So the part of me that, that would love to see what would happen if,
if like a bad guy bought it is unfortunately still there.
But yeah, I think given the circumstances of the planet this is good.
Yeah. So, I mean, that's kind of nice. They did the boring thing
and I'm, you know, it's,
I'm gonna say it's probably one of those things
where it was comically cheap comparative to even hiring,
like, three more support people.
-- Almost.
-- Definitely. Yeah. I bet it was cheaper than a couple of people without.
And I bet it would have cost them tens to hundreds of people
to,
with the, the fallout of this problem.
So, actually, it's funny, it's funny you bring that up.
I have, I have a similar problem going on at work right now where there's basically,
there's a customer saying we need this feature and we're like,
this feature is ridiculous.
This is just to appease like a security
team that doesn't know what they're talking about.
And the customers like we know we know these security people are morons,
but like we need this because they won't go away at this point.
And I even, I went to the developers kind of begging and I was like, look guys,
if this is going to take more than let's say, 10 hours, it's not worth it.
I've probably lost more than four hours of my life at this point.
I remember pushing for a team to fix
a cross site scripting vulnerability because I'm like,
these
people keep freaking out about it
and it will be honestly way less hassle and
effort to just fix it than to keep telling them
-- why we haven't fixed it yet,
-- right? Because that's the thing.
I mean, usually what ends up happening is we get a complaint,
then either the support person or the sales rep gets involved and then I get involved
and it's like this is,
and we've got like five people on the phone
for and while I can say like this is not an issue, this is not a real security problem.
And the people are saying we know,
but our security team makes us call you and talk to
you because we have to get a statement from you.
I always wonder what would happen
if companies could actually accurately track kind
of how much money was spent on an activity or an issue,
like dealing with this one customer complaint or whatever,
because I'm guessing the numbers are quite shockingly high.
Once you figure out like including overhead and everything,
-- I should
-- start hacking that.
I think that would be a valuable metric actually because
-- it would, it
-- would, well, there's not just how much time you spend on it,
but then the opportunity cost of, well,
I was dealing with this silliness rather than doing something more productive.
Well,
and all the other people involved and even the
customer involved because like at the same time their,
their people standing up, the services are saying, yeah,
we know our security people are ridiculous.
And I mean, in all seriousness,
I think part of this problem as well is that there's a lot of
organizations where the security teams just are
like unchecked maniacs and they can,
they can just say,
can't deploy this unless this is fixed and there's like, well, what do we do now?
I mean,
it's kind of madness.
Well,
they're probably running on policies and procedures that
were put in place like 20 years ago.
And I mean,
this whole work from home thing is a great example of that the local government,
not everybody has laptops, like a bunch of people have desktops or whatever.
And so part of their work from home strategy
was literally they sent out a questionnaire saying,
you know, do you have a windows seven or better PC at home?
And I'm like, wait, what?
And so they're expecting people to work off their personal gear.
What's the alternative?
I mean, and I get that because in fact,
I know of some organizations or some friends I have that I was talking
to that were saying that they're not able to get hardware for the new employee
and obviously their, their new employees are working from home.
So they're basically saying
your options are essentially either don't start working yet,
which for most people isn't an option.
-- Yeah, or go source a chromebook.
-- Yeah, or yeah, or, or find something to work off of.
And of course, look,
almost anyone in the tech field has one or more computers at home.
So like it
an issue, however, the problem then becomes.
So you've got your internal corporate standards for desktop security.
Well, what now
I'm using some guy's gaming machine, right?
My reply to that would be like cloud,
you move your trust perimeter to the cloud and assume that these
horrifically virus ridden nasty malware infected machines will be accessing it.
And that's cool because you can do things like, not to name drop vendors, but like,
you can do that Citrix terminal thing where they can't even cut and paste.
You know, worst case scenario they're taking, like, screenshots,
didn't we talk about Citrix a few weeks ago?
Yeah, we did. You know, like, it's funny.
Right, because, like, the cloud security lines were 100% cloud based.
So literally business as usual. Yeah. Right. Right.
Edmonton public school boards is all in on Google.
And so, like,
literally most of the kids actually have their user name and password memorized.
And so, like, the schools basically reminded of our kids accounts.
I logged them in on their ipads. That was it. There was no step to it.
It was kind of funny because I also set up a profile for Felix on, you know,
chrome for his school thing and get him, like, have him log in,
takes two seconds and then all of a sudden the chrome turns to this, like,
hideous orange and red and,
and I'm like, what? And there's like all these weird icons popping up.
-- I'm like, oh, this is his desktop from school?
-- Ah. Oh, I see.
-- I see,
-- because I was kind of wondering, I'm like, yeah, man.
Like, where's I'm gonna have to hunt down, like,
where Google classroom and whatever is and all that.
And it's like, no, like, just boom there's,
his desktop is a web browser and it's everything he needs.
Yeah, the chrome user experience is remarkably good.
And I mean, I, I discovered this exact same thing, right. I am a chromebook.
I do lots of stuff on it. At one point. My kids need to log into Google for, for school.
And I was like, here just take this right.
Go, go off in the corner and use my chromebook. I don't care.
And, yeah, they logged in and I was like,
this is nothing like when I use chrome it's so different because of course,
they're all locked down.
And the most annoying thing is they can only print a school printers,
they can't print to the printers in my house. So it's like, ah, this sucks. Right.
We, we worked around it basically. We, we can save to PDF.
So I had him save it to PDF and then I just, like, you know,
sneaker net it to the printer.
Yeah.
So, what,
what gets me is like for the organizations that
they weren't necessarily even prepared for this specifically,
but just in general they've embraced the cloud and they've embraced.
Yeah.
You can have like,
a totally locked down corporate desktop and then a
zero Day comes around and we're all screwed,
you know, or a new virus comes out or something.
Right. Like, that's the thing, right.
-- Having a lockdown corporate desktop doesn't make it secure magically,
-- I have a lot.
I can talk about on this topic.
But I mean,
fundamentally from what I've seen is most of this
technology that's being used to lock us down,
there's kind of two sides to this.
And
now,
like we talked to Tony Meehan a couple
episodes ago and there's the magic Endpoint response
software now that just looks for badness and then it tries to stop the badness.
I feel like that is the future because it's,
it's trying to be smart and then there's the, oh,
we're just going to lock your desktop so you can't do anything dangerous.
And, like, so my favorite example of this is when I was in college,
I worked at a paper mill in the summers.
It's how I earned my money to basically pay for beer at college. And
they had, of course, all the computers everywhere because, like,
everything has computers.
I mean, this was in what the,
the late nineties and there were still computers
everywhere and the computer that was in,
like, the little room we'd sit in that was air conditioned because the paper mill is,
like, freaking boiling hot.
There's this little room we could sit in, had a computer and the computer had all,
like, the readouts of all the,
everything on the machine and we were supposed to pay attention to it
and they were like, yeah, we used to play, uh, Solitaire on this but they,
they took it away.
I'm like, oh, I can probably fix that and, yeah, like 10 seconds later, of course,
I was past whatever crappy song
-- where they were using to lock everyone out. You
-- know, a funny story.
I remember at the Chaos computer conference in 1999
a guy had a Windows machine set up.
It was a Windows NT machine. I forget if, I think it was a 351 must have been anyways.
And he had it so locked down that you could actually do stuff on it,
but you couldn't mess with it and nobody was able to, like, mess with it.
Now, granted, most of the people there weren't, you know, windows experts.
They were more uni
type people.
But I specifically remember this guy somehow did some horrifically art
set of group policy objects to this laptop that he actually
had it so locked down that it was quote unquote secure.
But what gets me about all that is then, you know, nine times out of 10,
the person's like, but I need to do X to get my job done and they're like, yeah, tough.
You can't. Exactly.
My favorite thing is, you know, back in the day when USB ports were new.
Well, what's the easiest way to secure access to your USB ports, glue hot glue?
I remember I dealt with this company that actually made like USB
software security for Windows where you
can basically whitelist devices and stuff.
And it was like, I was like, wow, that's,
that's better than hot glue. But
also it's a
-- lot more expensive than hot glue.
-- It is.
And it actually doesn't work as well either because
you can just spoof the ideas now and stuff.
Right.
-- There's all kinds of shenanigans you can do
-- well back
in the day it worked because like this was like,
you know, 20 years ago
it was still magic.
And, and now for those of you listening, if you just fun fact,
a Raspberry Pie Zero has like a programmatic USB port on it.
So you can essentially spoof and do anything you want with USB. So like get hacking.
Yeah, you can make those like mice that send their own keyboard commands and stuff.
-- Everything
-- that's like the people made the little dongle that you
plug it into a computer and it would just say like,
oh, I'm the, I'm the whole internet.
Everyone route all your traffic over me and then computers would just start sending
all kinds of crazy network traffic to the Raspberry Pi Zero that got locked.
So anyway, I'll look at it for the show
notes. Uh
Right. Right.
So anyway, we are talking about locking down desktops and right, as soon as so,
but here's the thing.
So I think
to 10 years ago
people would say I need this to do my job and the security team would say too bad.
So sad. But I don't, I don't see that anymore.
Right now people say I need this to do my job and they open it up
and now it's like, well,
what's the even freaking purpose of this crappy software you put on?
Like I can do everything I need to do to get around it.
And one thing I think where the chromebook really gets it right is the
chromebook is less about locking it down and more about when you log out,
you are logged out
and it has that power wash option.
So like I feel comfortable using like I have a chromebook here that use once in
a while and I feel safe knowing that like when I log out of that thing,
there's nothing left on there.
So even if it were physically stolen and you know,
somebody imaged the SSD in there and did all that magic
that there's nothing that would come back to bite me.
So I'm fine with like handing it off to my
kids because if my kids like short of them somehow
getting some like resident virus that has a whole pile
of zero days to get through chrome and stay put.
I'm just not worried if they can basically do whatever they do
on that thing and it's not going to mess it up.
And that's, you see, that's the other thing that's,
that's classic problem with Windows,
right is people would have a Windows machine at home, especially Windows 9598 XP.
You'd have an account, everybody logged in to use. Right.
And so Bobby would go, you know, play his online game, get a virus and then, you know,
his dad would have to deal with that virus because it's in
the computer now because there's only that one trust level effectively running,
you know, with something like chromebook, it's essentially containerized.
So, you know, my kids stuff is just a completely 100% separated from mine, you know,
short of breaking out into the US and really hosing it.
Google puts a lot, like, they just shipped another security update, what,
23 days ago,
because there is something going around that where
you can potentially get out of chrome and
so they fixed it, you know, and I did the update on my computers,
which I hate doing because I have like 50 tabs open and, you know,
it's like reload chrome and I'm like, yeah.
Yeah. And I'm going to go, like, watch TV for half an hour.
Well, this is actually, I love it about the chromebook because you click,
restart it restarts and literally it pops up exactly where it left off.
It's marvelous. I love it so much.
And actually, yeah, I had that because Firefox just had a rotten security issue and,
yeah, I,
I had like 100 tabs open and I just declared tab bankruptcy and closed everything.
Yeah, I
don't even know what I had.
I assumed someone will yell at me eventually if
I don't do something I'm supposed to do.
So it's fine.
No, this whole keeping state and backup when my mother was first playing Minecraft,
you know, trying to hang out with the kids on Minecraft.
She's like, how do I save it? And I'm like, it just does.
And my mom was like, what, why I'm like, the computer just saves it because, like,
obviously you would want your work to be saved.
And she's like, yeah. and I'm like,
she's like, wait, why couldn't our old computers do this? And I'm like,
they could, but they just didn't because software programs are hateful people. So,
so actually, it's hilarious. You bring this up a couple days ago.
My wife and I were talking to our kids about back in the day when you would be like,
working on a paper in Microsoft Word and you'd
accidentally delete everything and it was gone forever.
And they said, why don't you just go back and document history and recover it?
I said there was no such thing.
Like this is why you'd have like four floppy disks and they're like, well,
what's a floppy disk?
But, you know,
you'd have like four floppy disks with like various backups of your term paper.
Well, you'd be emailing it to yourself once Gmail came out.
-- And I'm like, that's actually your best bet.
-- I remember that.
You know, like now
you can collaborate on documents.
They're magically saved in the cloud.
There's like, there's almost no way to lose this.
Like, until you delete it and empty the trash can. It's, it's there somewhere.
And even with that, like, if you,
if it's a corporate thing with Google Vault or whatever it's called now it's,
it's there somewhere.
Like
it's, it's an insane amount of work to accidentally lose a term paper
now.
So.
Oh,
my goodness. I don't miss those days.
-- So, anyway,
-- well, this, this whole, like, desktop security lockdown thing.
I mean, to me it's the other aspect of this is it shouldn't matter because again,
we're moving to that, bring your own device
thing because like, I'm not going to carry two cell phones. That's ridiculous.
And I'm also not giving you access to put like that
crazy software on my phone that can then wipe it.
Like, because there's been multiple people,
especially students talking about that,
how they want to access their school remotely university level mostly, you know,
they get this software that's like, like warning this thing can wipe your phone,
you know, do you get these permissions?
And it's kind of like I don't want to because again, I've looked into, you know,
deploying the software and I came to the conclusion
that I wouldn't have left on my devices.
So I feel like it would be a hard sell if you know, director of it is like,
yeah, we're going to do this but like, it's not going on my devices.
I had that conversation with someone. Not, this wasn't even that long ago.
They were, they were talking about, oh, you know, this is what we're looking into.
And I said, if this is me
would literally say no. And they said, well, then you can't work from your phone.
I said that actually would make my life a lot
better and it would make your life a lot worse.
So,
-- local
-- optimization for the win,
right?
I mean, seriously, because like, if I didn't have work on my phone,
-- that sounds pretty nice actually, like I'm
-- OK with that.
Although in hindsight, I should uninstall slack someday. But it's
anyway, anyway, there are, it's one of those things, right?
There's advantages to having slack on my phone and there's disadvantages. But
another story,
what I'm really curious about is after this whole work from home mass experiment is,
do you think it's going to stick?
I have been thinking about this a lot and I see.
So there's a couple angles to this that, that I envision. And
so there's the people who get to work from home that
like working from home that is a huge benefit to them.
And like you and I are an example of people who enjoy working from home.
I know people who do not enjoy working from home,
they need like the human interaction and they liked being in a place with people.
And I think that's OK too. And there's always going to be a certain degree of that.
Well, and there's certain kinds of work too, especially like creative,
collaborative work.
-- Absolutely.
-- You can't do that over a video link.
Like you have to be in the room playing with objects, taping them together,
whatever.
-- Right.
-- Yeah, I totally agree. I think there's always instances where it makes sense
now at the same time. So an example being there's a large insurance company in town
that is like, you know,
like they obviously have lots of people that
have to work their answer phones deal with.
You know, people want to submit claims against their insurance.
People have questions about policies, they're not paying their, you know,
whatever, there's a million reasons,
the parking lot's empty and they have
-- this enormous building just sitting there
-- blank.
Well, that's what, you know,
I'm thinking about like the cost of commercial real estate costs and he, you know,
-- and all that stuff and look
-- man, my guess is they haven't ever
migrated this work to being
at home because quite frankly,
this is the sort of job where the supervisors are kind of that, that
they like lording it over people because I know
some people that have been in these jobs and they
100% of them hated their supervisors.
I think this is one of those situations where the incentive is to maintain that level
of control because what you're going to see is the company is going to be like,
wait a minute, what's a supervisor doing now?
Like, you're not walking around yelling at people all day, like,
why are we paying you money?
And so my suspicion is there's a lot of these,
these organizations and departments that had kind of perverse incentives
where the people had an anti incentive in terms of
keeping people in an office because it felt it gave
them a certain amount of power and ability that they,
it's gone now.
Well, from everything I've read with every organization,
the number one metric essentially for success is what's your head count?
Fundamentally is what it pretty much always boils down to.
Yes, been articles about, you know,
the surveillance software being bought by companies to, you know,
put on people's computers to make sure they're doing their job, you know,
extreme example of this being. What was it?
Yahoo fired everybody who worked on a VPN and because apparently they
were checking their VPN logs and like some of these people,
like there's been zero traffic for like six months or whatever, right?
And I get it like you will, obviously, but I mean,
to me that really speaks to a fundamental failure in the business
and the management of so you hired this person to do something
and what they were doing was so poorly defined or untracked that
they literally just didn't do it and got away with that.
That's pretty broken.
And I don't think the answer is to put software on their computers to track that they
actually doing it. It's to, more to the point was that job even necessary.
It's like the old story of what is your incentive actually?
Where, you know, in India they paid people to bring in dead cobras.
So people just started raising cobras. Right.
-- Well, it's
-- a lot easier than catching them.
Yeah. Seriously.
That's exactly opposite.
Or my favorite was hearing these horror stories from
people in telemarketing companies where they were basically told,
like, no call can last over eight minutes.
-- So at eight minutes they just hung up.
-- Yeah, I remember those days.
I remember when that happened. I remember all those text
things where all of a sudden, yeah, tech support people just started hanging up.
And what, and what I love now is my previous phone carrier.
They must have some automated system because the guy asked, like,
so have I solved your problem?
And I'm like, and he just got,
and I kind of did this intentionally just to see what would happen.
But I basically refused to say yes or no.
I just kind of made an uncommitted grunt and he
just kept asking the poor guy like he just,
he's like, sir, I need to know, you know what I mean?
-- Like, he really had to get a yes or a no out of me.
-- I feel bad for a lot of these people.
And in fact,
like, for example, when,
when I take an Uber.
I basically, unless like that, I felt like my life was in danger,
which has only happened once in Uber and it wasn't Canada, in fact, but, like,
I give him five stars because I know if you don't give this person five stars, like,
he'd be like, yeah, it was ok.
It's a 2.5 star ride.
But if I don't give the five stars they're going to
lose their job and then their kid doesn't get to,
which is ridiculous, right?
-- Like that's not ok because
-- that's one thing I really wonder with, you know,
people having to work sort of under their own direction more.
I mean, I'm reading these articles where these guys are talking about, you know, oh,
my boss gave me
piece of work and, you know, based on previous experience,
I said it would take me two or three days to finish and, you know,
it was done in two hours because I
had two hours of completely 100% uninterrupted work.
Actually,
it's funny you bring that up too.
So I think one of the unexpected outcomes of all these people working from
home is so one of the things I do at work is people,
for example,
run security scanners and they send me the results
of their scan without ever having looked at it,
which again, kind of comes back to the scanner podcast we talked about,
we'll say last week.
But anyway, we like,
we had this discussion and so these people are running these scans,
they send me the scan, of course, they don't look at them and then I send them back.
I'm like, OK, here's what's going on.
This is what's happening and 99% of the time like, ok, great. Thanks for that.
And that's it right. There are no questions asked.
They're clearly now paying attention.
And so they're saying, OK, well, uh I don't, I don't believe you, I prove, prove this.
And I'm like, what do you mean? Prove it? Like, what do you want me to freaking do?
And they're saying, well, I, I want you to prove this.
And I'm like, that doesn't even make sense.
You're like saying like, prove Air is air like that. What?
Well,
my favorite is when they're asking you to prove a
negative because like I remember we had a Jackson data
thing
and I went through the code and I'm like, well, we, we never make that call. Cool.
And then I confirmed it with the developers.
Like, yeah, we never use that and we never will.
But then I was told we had to fix it
anyways because the customer could turn that feature on.
And I'm like,
the only way they can turn that feature on is
by like rewriting a big chunk of the product.
That's exactly the same problem I have as Jackson da,
people say we want you to fix this. I said like we can't. And here's why
they said we don't care, fix it.
I'm like, you can tell me that all you want and like,
it's not going to make it happen any sooner.
-- Well, here's the funny thing. They did a scan of a production system. Correct.
-- Sure.
-- Some are production, some are whatever,
-- some
-- of
-- them are production for sure.
-- Well, the world has not ended. That thing's running well.
-- Right.
Is it a risk?
-- Kind maybe sort of, but realistically, no,
-- it's, there's literally no risk
so well,
then it definitely falls into bucket of acceptable risk.
And, well, here's the thing, if they were really adamant about it,
they would turn it off.
Well,
it's funny actually you say that because
I've been in conversations where the security team
says we can't run this and the other team says this is literally mission critical.
It stays up
and then the security teams like, oh, no,
we're telling you have to turn it off and they're like, no, like you don't,
you can't win this one.
If we turn this off, you don't get paid. Like,
yeah, like I worked at a place where they had this,
they had this accounting package and it's
construction industry.
So like when I learned about how that accounting software works because, you know,
every contract has different like holdbacks and, you know,
like they do all the work and then there's like 10% held back that's paid out.
Like six months later when they make sure, you know,
the whole thing didn't burn down or whatever.
And anyways point is it's this like horrendously custom piece
of software written locally because it's got to be legal locally
and it has to kind of fit the local culture and everything.
And I was running on this so machine with, you know,
VT 100 or whatever terminals and they, we upgraded, you know, so like
there, you know, we got like a dozen windows,
95 machines and then they upgraded to like an actual proper school box.
And like
it was just,
it was comically horrific because like the password to log in was
the company name spelled backwards with like every second letter capitalized.
And it had like a dedicated modem and its own
dedicated phone line and its own dedicated phone number.
So the company could like,
remotely log into it and update the software and fix stuff.
Which yeah.
No, no, I,
I support that because that thing printed out a huge pile of paychecks every Friday.
And like, I
remember one time it went down on Thursday and
they're like, Kurt, can you fix it? I'm like, no,
I'm not touching the, I'm not touching the machine that like pays, you know,
several 100 people. No, like you call the company and you make them fix it
right? And it is.
But I just, yeah, I had this dot matrix printer with like just these boxes of,
you know, the checks and anyways.
I mean, yeah, it's like there's nothing I could have done or said, or I wanted to,
to be clear where it's like, no, I'm not touching that.
Like, you, this thing has to work. It's outsourced to this company. Like that's them
because they're like, oh, Kirk,
could we save a few bucks by building our own PC to run this?
And I'm like, yes. But then paychecks might not run one week
and we don't want that. And they're like, yeah. Yeah, you're right.
I mean, this is a topic for another day because we're basically out of time today.
But I think something to consider is if you look at
kind of the state of affairs happening in most organizations,
obviously, I would say many organizations are running
in a sort of panic mode for a variety of reasons. And
how often is security getting involved and how often
is security just being blatantly overruled because they're like,
no, you're being like crazy person.
We don't want to talk to you. And,
I mean,
I've seen both sides of this where I see
security teams that are involved and they're very reasonable
and they're actually partners and I see security teams
that it's like you're acting like a crazy person.
-- We don't care, go away like we're done with you
-- now. Yeah, they're the, no police.
I think this is when you're in this sort of crisis because there's like,
there's the security crisis.
We're like, oh, we've been hacked. We need your help.
Security, please help right now and then security's like, oh, I'm important.
I can do whatever I want. Like, this isn't one of those, right.
This is one of those things where security is a partner in the crisis.
-- Not like the fixer
-- right now.
We have, you know, something going on where like, business has to go on.
The security team can say no, but
-- we have to do our jobs.
-- Security team should never say no.
-- That is my, that is my honest opinion.
-- I think they should be
able to say no, but it should be, in my opinion,
the security team has failed at their job if they end up in
a situation where they have to say no much like a parent.
That's probably fair. All I do is say no as a parent, Kurt.
-- But
-- you know, there's the difference between the no and like the no,
I'm actually like banning this, right?
That's fair. That's fair.
And I would say like, if you as a security team, if you're having to say no to people,
you need to maybe do some like root level analysis
of like stuff has gone wrong a long time ago.
I, well, and look, if you say no, too much,
they just stop asking like it's the same thing with kids, right?
Kids figure it out, man. If mom and dad just say no to everything.
Just don't ask, texting and driving.
Let's not even get into that one. All right. Anyway, anyway, we're out of time.
I'm going to call this one. This was, this makes me amused because
I don't think we talked about any of the things we previously discussed,
talking about for this episode.
So I love it more content for next time.
Anyway, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to
Osar Security podcast.com. Head up our show notes. You can use the Pound
Oss podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too,
-- thanks
-- everybody and please use your turn signals
-- seriously and don't,
don't text and drive.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.