Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Seyfort and
hang on one second,
my partner in punctuality, Josh Pressers.
All that's really clever because we're gonna talk about leap seconds.
But before we do
my Google Wi Fi finally died,
-- like, physically or emotionally
-- dead dead.
Well, it died emotionally a long time ago, I think.
Well, no, no, no, because I've, I've like, I've had router hardware that like,
physically died.
Like the, the chip obviously is like, you touch it and it's like,
oh, like I burnt my finger
and then I've had routers that just needed
too much emotional support and they just could not go on with life.
It, it was dropping a lot of packets.
And so it was,
I forget what day it was. But anyway, I, I needed a replacement.
So I went to Costco and just bought the middle priced
TP link, whatever. I don't even know the brand. What model it is, doesn't matter.
And I install it.
And the first thing was like, holy crap. This is fast.
And then I was talking to a friend and he
basically pointed out your Google wifi was 10 years old,
you're experiencing 10 years of network improvements.
And I'm like, oh,
I guess I am.
-- Well,
-- it's, it's actually,
it's funny yesterday we were downloading a game to my son's laptop on Steam and the,
uh, you know, the download went faster, faster, faster and then peaked at about 15.
And I'm like, that's like, is my wi fi messed up. No, it's just
the, uh, the SSD on his laptop. Is that slow?
There
you go.
It's,
although that slow is like 100 and some megabits
per second sustained for a couple of gigabytes.
Where in hindsight, I'm like, that's actually not that bad for, you know,
a mid-tier laptop.
But, uh, it's, it's funny to me now that my Wi Fi is still faster than my son's like,
laptop hard drive.
Yeah. And I will say I have Wi Fi six now and I have one computer that can do Wi Fi six.
Holy crap. It's fast.
That's actually I'm,
I'm looking forward to Wi Fi six because I will
get rid of the physical wires in my house.
I think you could. The latency is about the same as my Ethernet. Like we're talking a
couple percent difference
-- and the speed is nearly a gigabit over Wi Fi. Like, it is crazy
-- fast.
It's never the speed I care about because as long as I can get 50 to 100 megabits,
you can do everything
right. It's fine.
You know, for once in a while. Yeah.
Having Gigabit is really nice but by and large 50 to 100 megabits is fine.
But the problem is if you get jitter
or, you know, drops or, you know, like
you,
I call it digital banjo,
you know,
when the people's audio on a video call just starts getting all twangy and weird.
Right. Like digital banjo
and, and that's unacceptable. Like I need
-- what?
-- Yeah.
Right. Right. So, anyway,
I have
new wireless hardware now and because I needed it right away,
I did no research and I just assumed Costco, would it lead me wrong?
And they did,
they have that one year. We just don't care. Here's your money back.
So they generally don't sell garbage and if they
do you just return and get your money.
Yeah. I mean, I have to use a terrible app to configure it
and that makes me sad. But whatever I can live with it.
Do you not remember the Google wifi app that then got replaced by the Google Home app?
No, I agree. And I love now when I test my wire, my Wi Fi speed, you know what?
-- It tells me why my Wi Fi speed is. It's good. It doesn't give me a number anymore.
-- Wow.
-- What a great number.
-- There's no more number
anyway,
whatever,
whatever it doesn't matter. I have internet. That's all that matters.
Life is good.
Right. So, we should talk about leap seconds instead
first. Of all. I wanted to actually take a step back. What's a second?
No,
-- no,
-- seriously. What's the second? Because
-- it's how like a cesium atom vibrates like a bazillion times or whatever.
-- Exactly.
But the,
the previous, the traditional definition was 1
86,004 100th of a day
of a solar day.
And this is, and this is the problem where things get tricky because
vibrations of a caesium atom are like absolute
like that is just a physical constant.
Like it's like saying 10 atoms of iron, well, either it's 10 atoms of iron or it's not,
the problem is saying one solar day
that's not at all constant,
not even a little bit.
Um And I was reading about this and I
knew that gravity of other celestial bodies affects us.
What I didn't realize is, for example, humidity temperature,
there's a whole bunch of factors that affect
essentially where water is in the atmosphere.
And so obviously, there's more water in the atmosphere, there's more mass
to the periphery,
I guess would be the word of the earth and it slows down the rotation up a tiny,
tiny bit.
Whereas if it's, you know, all sort of closer like, well, you know,
cons conservation of rotational momentum when you bring your arms in,
when you're spinning and you spin faster.
Right.
And so I think this is kind of where things started to go sideways.
-- Right is we went from now,
-- if, if you really want to cook your brain.
Remember that Japanese earthquake that caused the Fukushima disaster?
That earthquake shortened the earth day by 1.8 microseconds.
Yeah, exactly.
So, there's all sorts of events like,
let's be real. If, if the, if the uh polar,
both poles uh ice caps melt that's gonna really
redistribute water on the planet to some degree.
Um,
-- mostly because of the heat but whatever.
-- So, anyway, all right, that's enough.
We know what a second is cesium
-- atom, right? Measuring other stuff
-- is dumb. That's what it is now.
So, but the problem is now we're measuring it in an absolute terms and it's divorced
from the earth rotating around the sun and we still
need the earth rotating around the sun to sort of reflect
reality, I guess, would be the word
like
that.
I mean, it's,
the drift is not going to happen anytime soon and it's not going to affect most of us
that much.
But, you know,
somebody pointed out like if you are taking a GPS signal and it's off by half a second,
that's basically like from here to the moon.
Not, probably not that far, but it's, it's a long ways.
Speed of light in a half a second is
you're gonna be off distance.
And, and I did read fun fact, if we didn't have any leap seconds
in 80,000 years, I think the, what we'd be off by a couple of hours, it was,
and the earth's rotation is slowing, right?
We've got the moon orbiting around us causing tidal drake.
Um So back when the dinosaurs were around, it was like, what a 20 hour day give or take.
And
so anyway,
so the problem is ok. So we kind of have to keep
the seconds and the time in sync with the earth kind of going around the
sun and so on and so forth. Um
Because there are people for which this matters.
You know, if you're operating a satellite constellation,
those satellites move pretty damn far in a second.
Right. Well, and we should clarify the importance of having two distinct
computing systems, having the exact same time to a very small margin of error.
Right. That's what we're shooting for here.
This isn't like if my computer and Kurt's computer
are off by 10 seconds from each other, it really doesn't matter.
But if you're doing high frequency trading on the stock market
-- that
-- probably
-- matters like you're gone.
Right. Anyway. All right,
-- we have to remember. This is a security podcast.
-- Yeah.
So for some people it doesn't matter.
So,
so what's interesting is traditionally we've done leap seconds and
leap seconds are a pain in the ass because,
and I didn't realize this, they, they can't really predict them that far in advance.
That's right.
It's completely bananas because like AAA group of scientists is like, well,
we need a leap second now.
So we're gonna add one. It's like, wait, what, like, that's how that works. Yeah.
And they try to give six months warning but it's not like a leap year where, you know,
we, we have a calendar going out a few millennia and we know
when those are. That's right.
Although it's funny because people, you know,
mess it up because it's every four years, not every 100 years, but it is every
1,002,000
because it's not exactly a quarter, like it's a little tiny bit more.
So you do a leap second.
And of course,
somebody wrote software that assumed there were 60 seconds in a minute
and or worse
that time only ever moves forwards,
which typically it does in my experience
and so time sometimes moves backwards.
And for example, back in what was it?
4017, you know,
cloud flare RR DNS software kind of went and tipped
over because time is not supposed to go backwards.
They calculate an offset and,
and it literally was one character change adding instead of equals equals,
it was less than, or equal to.
So essentially making
the point is this, this isn't some hypothetical like, oh, what if it happens?
Will something bad happen?
Well, nothing terrible will happen but stuff will break.
Well, I mean, how do you define? Terrible?
Like if, if Microsoft's cloud goes down, that's pretty bad.
Well, but it's not like a nuclear reactor is gonna go kaboom.
But for example, you know, if enough high frequency trading systems poop out
that we could have a bad couple of months, economically speaking.
Well, and didn't, a couple of years ago,
Azure, like, just completely went down because of the,
that
was, um, yeah, Microsoft with,
I chuckled that because I wasn't using it and it was funny,
but I'm sure for any of the customers and for the poor people working there,
-- it was a
-- bad day. It was a certificate issue where
it was a 300 the certificate was good for one year and, well,
except that year there was an extra day.
Ah, that's what it was.
So,
and, and that again, that speaks to things like LS and crypto.
Let's just keep re
rolling these certificates every 30 60 90 days, like, constantly so that
-- it just doesn't ever become a problem.
-- Right.
Well, and that's how it works now.
I mean, that wasn't exactly how it worked.
I still run across a lot of sites that
obviously spent a lot of money on their certificates.
It's kind of weird.
Why do they do that?
And, and, ok,
I want to add this little bit in
because obviously this is not particularly security oriented,
but there are security themes in time.
And I think things like certificates are very important.
Like, if you've ever had your clock off by several hours,
it's very common for TLS, connections not to work
because TLS, like you check the times, when was this signed?
When did this key come out? When did the other, what time does a computer think it is?
And so things get weird,
especially in the security universe when time isn't quite correct.
And a leap second is a marvelous denial of service attack,
which is actually the reason we're talking about it because
what was it
basically said?
-- Can we stop doing leap seconds because it messes up
-- our stuff.
It messes up everybody's stuff and, and,
and here's the thing when you think about it,
if you're writing code that deals with time and you almost certainly are.
Maybe a leap second affects you. Maybe it doesn't. But if it does affect you,
number one, you're going to find out the hard way.
And number two, if you're gonna engineer against it,
it's hard because you don't like a lot of test cases and stuff.
Right. It's, it's tricky.
Yes. So there is a really clever solution to avoiding this cost.
Well, we should first say what, what is the current way? Leap seconds work?
They literally, you, you, if you're watching a digital clock,
it would be the equivalent of like 1259 59
1259 60.
That's right.
Uh
What comes after 11 o'clock
in my brain? I was saying zero, but I'm like zero is not right. Like what?
That's right. That's right. But yes, you have a,
a usually you go 59 to 0. And when there is a leap like you have 5960 0.
So there's literally a second,
no one was expecting
that it added to time stamps.
And you can imagine a
lot of software falls apart because
it is a
very
uncommon event.
Just a simple,
like how many times have you looked through a log file using a red jacks?
That's essentially good for 00 to 59.
Yeah. All right. Right. Because that's how time works. Usually most of the time,
the time. That's a good one. So the one of the alternatives is to do a leap
smear.
Yes.
-- And this is what Google does, which is quite
-- clever.
And what a leap smear is, is you basically say, OK, we're going to
smear that leap second over a period of, I think it's
tens. It's about like 10 or 17 or something hours.
And so basically you just extend every second by,
it's, it's the Superman attack.
You know, I only steal a penny from each transaction, but I do it a million times a day.
And that's exactly what this is.
You, you, you add or steal a tiny, tiny amount of time from each second for like,
say 10 hours.
Well, basically nobody's going to notice unless they're operating satellites.
Well, and the really cool part about this is if there's, there's a link
I'll put in the show notes where the Google folks talk about this,
the amount of time they add to each second
still falls within the accepted margin of error from, like, the NPNTP consortium,
whoever, like, big time is in the world controlling all of this.
Yeah.
And that's, that's exactly right because, I mean, we've all had the, well,
I've had the case of, you know, where I turn my computer on RUN NTP.
And it's like, nope, it doesn't work and it's like why it's because it's,
the clock is off by an hour and it's like, that's too much of a jump.
And then, yeah, within the NTP spec itself,
you can't just suddenly jump like half a second or a
second because obviously something went kind of wrong at that point.
And you should probably have a human investigate.
I,
I like leap smears because basically it says
we've got this problem which if we force everybody to engineer for it,
that's
literally millions of people, years of work
-- to properly engineer for it.
-- You say that?
But I bet you programming for a leap second
is easier than creating the code to produce the leap
smear.
But the thing is you only have to do the leap
-- smear once in the NTP world. And then
-- just,
-- what do you mean once in the NTP
-- world, your NTP servers do the leap
smear and your
just consume the NTP time.
I see what you're saying.
Oh, so you're saying just at some point in the future,
they magically pick up the missing second.
Well, for example, what if time dot Near stock up starts doing leap,
uh leap
smears
doesn't care.
This is the classic sort of cloud argument of we can make
1000 customers do it or we can just have one big entity,
do it and kind of resell it.
Or in this case,
NTP services are typically free.
See you, there's a couple of vendors of time equipment that you know,
take a GPS signal, you know, from an aerial on the roof of your data center.
And like you have a little box in your um in your data center.
So you effectively have a stratum kind of 1.5 time server.
Let me, let me explain this back to you because I think I get what you're saying,
but I want to make sure.
So you're saying all of the, we'll say time clients
just have no concept of
a
and you have the time server which understands there is a leap second coming.
And instead of having 1259 59 or 1259 60 they just slowly smear it out.
And then obviously,
when the clients update their time sometime after the leap second occurs,
they're gonna basically jump a second in the future,
but a second in the future is like no
big deal because that happens all the time anyway.
-- Right.
-- Yeah.
Well,
or more to the point if they're getting updates during the leap
smear because like your NTP client doesn't like it connects on a,
-- on a, on a more than once a day to the time server
-- when the smear is happening.
If you time it right,
the, the time the NTP server is going to report back is basically going to still be
the time the time we'll put that in quotes until the leap second occurs. And then
it's the correct second after that moment.
And the thing is if a client is checking during the smear, it kind of slowly upgrades
and if it's not checking during the
smear time, like it doesn't, it only checks once a day.
It's hard coded, for example, it's just for the sake of argument then.
Well, yeah, you're drifting one second over a day is not totally un.
Right. Right. Exactly.
And this solves the leap backwards problem and that's a big part of it too.
That's true.
I think that leap backwards thing because if you tell most programmers, hey,
you gotta make sure time can also go backwards a second once in a while.
They're gonna look at you with like,
oh man, that sounds brutal to account. It's such OK.
So, and this is now you claim you have a third option
and before I, I want to set the,
this has not been very security oriented at all.
I think the, the discussion of corner cases,
especially in the context of like the security universe makes sense.
But I first want to hear your secret. Third option.
-- You won't tell me about
-- why do we need leap
seconds.
-- We just went, we just spent like five minutes
-- talking what I'm
saying because of the
sort itself. So it's simple. We get Elon Musk to throw an asteroid at the earth.
It
up and
slow
down.
And there's
a second
part,
there's a second part to this. And this is the clever part.
We colonize Mars because a solar day on Mars is one day and 37 minutes.
And so everybody either gets an extra 37 minutes in bed
in the morning or a 37 minute nap in the afternoon.
Thus, we will have a schism in society of the snoozers versus the nappers.
-- But hear me out because everybody's well rested. I don't think it'll
-- matter.
I'm glad no one can see me right now.
Oh,
-- come on. You got to admit this is a good plan
-- anyway. All right.
-- So I, I want to now use the rest of our remaining
-- time
point of this is the leap smear is the best and really only solution we have other than
messing with the clocks.
I
feel dumber after listening to that.
So anyway,
I feel dumber for having said it.
I
think the more interesting discussion is part of it.
I think time is very interesting and it's its own unique challenges.
But I'm most interested in the,
you claim it's not a corner case because it affects everyone,
but it is a corner case in the context of it's hard to test for,
it's not particularly reliable.
So you can't
know it's coming and account for that.
And I think, especially like in the security world,
most security bugs are the unexpected.
Right?
And I think this clearly falls within that category and it,
it makes you think about like,
how do you plan for the unexpected? You know what I mean?
So, uh on a related
problem is time zones,
time zones can change with very short notice.
I remember there was um, a change to the Argentinian.
They are Brazil.
Some South American company basically decided with like a couple of
weeks notice to change when daylight savings was going to happen.
And everybody's like,
just that's such a pain because now we got, I, I remember Red Hat, remember they,
we did like basically an emergency critical time zone update,
you know, because I was like, why is this time zone update, you know,
marked as basically critical?
And it's like, because all the computers in this country
are gonna be off by an hour if they don't update it, you know,
Red hat was really good about time zone updates because I,
so I used to live in Indiana.
-- It
-- breaks so much
stuff. Right.
Well, I,
so I lived in Indiana back when Indiana didn't observe daylight savings time.
And then Indiana started observing daylight savings time
and put itself on the eastern time zone,
-- we thought it was a good idea at the time,
-- so be in sync with Eastern,
right?
I thought it was a good idea. And then we started following daylight savings.
I like this is the dumbest idea in the whole world. That's another story.
And that this was also before we had like a lot of shared calendars.
So you can imagine the chaos that ensued trying to schedule meetings and all.
And anyway, Microsoft
was very bad about updating their time zone.
And so I remember we switched to time zones and everyone was like, oh,
you just have to change your time zone to Eastern Standard Time now.
And like that was the solution. That was the Microsoft solution.
-- But
-- that's not your time zone.
I know,
I know it's not.
And,
and this is one of those weird corner cases where
for the vast majority of people it didn't matter.
But like if I was looking at computer logs
and I set my time zone to Eastern,
but my time zone really has to be like Indiana because before this certain day
there is no daylight savings and after this certain day there is daylight savings.
So, you know what I mean?
Again,
it's that weird corner case situation that really doesn't affect
-- very many people
-- just every computer admin in Indiana.
-- Yeah.
-- Right. But,
but it is something like when you are in a field that you have to care about, like,
exactly when something happened, like, for example, doing security forensics,
it makes a huge difference.
-- Well,
-- what about all the people doing science
in labs,
recording their
lab things going on? Obviously, I'm not a very scientific person.
Um,
but to me, the bigger argument and the bigger problem is, is
how should we solve these problems?
And the traditional way we solve these problems is like, well, it's your problem.
You go solve it.
But
people like Google and Facebook have kind of looked at this and gone.
Yeah,
like kind of getting all the NTP servers to do a leap smear
is obviously just getting the political buy in from that is like,
I don't even want to think about it.
But if every major NTP server on the planet does this, then the,
the pro basically just goes away for almost everybody who's not some like
I'm not gonna say corner case because like operating
satellites and hyper concentrating is actually pretty common.
And I'm sure there's some more cases where even being out by
a few milliseconds can be problematic for the vast majority of us.
It doesn't freaking matter, right?
And,
and look when you are one of those kind of corner cases where you're worried about,
you know, microseconds or nanoseconds,
you can account for a leap second
and deal with it
as you would expect.
But for the vast majority of non high frequency trading situations,
I don't think it really matters.
Like, from my perspective on my computers,
-- I don't care if my computer's off by five minutes, it really doesn't affect me
-- again.
This goes back to the security thing of like,
do we kind of force everybody to take them?
Well, a great example is when, um, there's a new potential for default,
like a great example being remember when Red
hat and everybody ship stuff with Telnet turned on
and then we started introducing open SSH and how long or not
even Open Ssh back then it was just ssh before you know,
the license went crazy and we got open SSH.
So
there was a period of time where we had both Telnet and SSH
and clearly SSH is the better solution on a whole pile of things.
But it took how many years
for some of these vendors to turn off telnet
and how many arguments and how much persuading,
you know,
it's ridiculous where it should have just like at
some point they finally pulled the band aid.
But for over those years,
there were
hundreds of thousands of people who went into etc id.com and you know,
added a pound sign and restarted IED and went on with their day.
But
that's like one or two minutes of my time and it's something I can mess up.
And it's again, this speaks to the, you know,
do we make a million people spend an hour fixing it
or do we make a small team of people do a whole bunch of painful, hard work
and
it's fixed for everybody.
Well, not only that the magic of NTP is
like, no one's paying for it, no one's, you know what I mean?
It's not like one of those services.
You could be like vendor,
I'm going to write you a big fat check and I want you to solve this problem for me.
Well, I,
I was actually kind of wondering about
that because there are NTP appliance vendors,
like again with the GPS signal and stuff
and
you know, do they maybe add a smear mode where you're basically just like,
I don't want my data center to have to deal with this.
So like I want to click that button and just have it work.
I mean,
it'd be cool if they did,
-- but I bet they don't.
-- Well, that actually sounds like one of the few
useful features that you could be. Like we have this feature that like
we made, we made leap seconds go away.
Don't ask, but it'll be fine, you know, and as a server admin, I'd be like,
I don't have to deal with leap seconds ever again.
-- Yeah, I'll buy your product.
-- Yeah. II, I can understand that.
-- I
-- feel like this leap smear thing is going to be a,
there's gonna be people who just dig their feet in and scream,
of course.
And then in five or 10 years it's gonna happen
because especially with IOT stuff and a whole bunch of other stuff like
it probably won't fail, fail. But,
ah, man, I just, it's one of those things where
I would rather programmers not have to deal with it because
-- the majority of them aren't that good at it.
-- I, I, I agree. I agree completely.
I mean, I,
and we have to put the, you know, what is it, the, the page of myths.
-- Programmers believe about time in the show notes because,
-- oh,
yeah,
that's really good.
There's a whole pile of stuff where even I was like, what?
No time's not supposed to do that.
Like, there's always a Tuesday after a Monday it turns out there's,
that's usually true but not always true.
It, it has happened a couple of times because what was, was, wait, when did
there was the island nation
in
the Pacific that skipped, did they skip from Sunday to Tuesday?
Is that what they did?
Yeah, they skipped a day to move over the Dateline to be more in sync with their US
economic counterparts.
Exactly.
Yeah.
There's some funny videos on youtube where people, like,
scrolled their apple calendar back to, like, the year 8, 200 or something
and it just starts freaking out.
But, yeah, like, back in the early days of calendars they had to just, like,
didn't they skip, like, half a year once because it was so messed up?
Yeah.
The Gregorian calendar and stuff got out of sync and, like, it was basically,
like July and snowing, but not because of global warming.
Right.
I don't think snow in July is ever going to be a problem again.
Have you, have you paid attention to any of the temperature graphs?
Oh, I know. I know.
But it's just,
we're going to get more like we had the rainiest June on record basically here.
Yeah.
It was actually, it was funny, We were really wet in June and now we're like,
ridiculously dry.
It's so weird.
-- Anyway,
-- so like, I think this is a great example of the leap second was a solution.
And, and you got to remember this is going back to the 19 seventies,
right? Like it's not, you know, this is, this isn't something like that, you know.
Oh, why were those people so dumb? And why did they do this?
Well, it's because they lived in caves and they painted with their fingers.
It was the 19 seventies. And how else would you solve it in the 19 seventies? Right?
There was no big concept of like NTP servers and everything, right?
-- Well,
-- well, not just that, look, there's,
this is also an interesting problem because you
have to understand in the context of progress
before the seventies, before atomic clocks and before redefining
the length of a second,
none of this made sense
and, and it was close enough whatever.
And now you have all of this incredibly
sensitive equipment you need incredibly accurate time.
And of course, the scientists are like, oh, we'll just add a second, right.
That works.
And in the context of highly specialized equipment run by highly
specialized people and there's like 10 of them on the planet.
Adding a second isn't a big deal because you can account for that.
But now we have literally billions of devices on the planet
that have highly accurate time sources, which has never existed before.
And now you look at something like a leap second and it's like, well,
-- this is a dumb idea
-- and worse is not just a
leap second forwards but a leap second backwards because again,
time is not supposed to stop or go backwards.
Like that's just
if, if a programmer makes that assumption,
I am not gonna blame them for mishandling a leap second because that is
-- like, that's a totally reasonable assumption.
-- That's right. And,
and I think
this is one of the funny stories of security is a lot of the security we created
was for a small number of people who were very knowledgeable in the, in the,
the space focusing on a very small number of devices.
And now everyone has a ridiculously accurate time source in
their pocket that can also take pictures and play music.
Like
if,
if you would have told people in the seventies this was going to happen,
they would have been like,
no, there's no way like absolutely not.
And that's kind of where we're at.
And so I think this is like, this is part of the story of security.
Same thing with time.
It is time pun intended
to like, really look at some like, why are we doing this doesn't make sense?
Is there something better we can do that is less disruptive
and we rarely do that in security.
And I'm glad people are doing it with time.
I think the problem is if the world changes at, like, 5 to 10% per year,
people don't
notice and that they don't pay attention to it.
But then you think back over 10 or 20 years and it's like what just happened,
right, like, straight up
when I think back to,
like,
well, you know, talking with my Children about screen time and it's kind of like,
well, it wasn't a problem for me because we didn't have screens. Like, we just,
we just didn't have screens or internet, like, it didn't exist.
You know what my favorite is, is when you explain to kids that, like,
when you wanted to watch a TV show, you had to go to the TV at a certain time,
like, be sitting there,
go
to the bathroom
staring at it
and, and you'd show up a few minutes early.
So you had to watch whatever crap was on before your show
and they're like, what they like, they don't even understand what that means.
-- It's hilarious the
-- other day.
So, we were basically, I motioned to Felix to make the, this motion.
Ok, Josh can see it on the video, right? So, what, what am I telling you to do?
You're spinning your hand? Is it? Hurry up? I mean, is this some Canadian signal?
-- I'm in a car, I'm in a car making this motion at
-- you rolling a window down a big car.
Right. Exactly. And my son had no,
I had to explain to my son. I'm like, because, like, why would he know? Exactly.
He's never seen one because I wanted him to, you know, sh goodbye at my mother and,
and I'm like, and I, and Felix is like, I'm like, Felix,
roll your hand roll and he's like, what?
And he's like, kind of shake his hand. I'm like, no, no.
Like you're rolling down a window and he, like, looks at me and I'm like, oh, yeah,
you, you have no idea what I'm saying.
Do you? They've never done that or, or now
I love it when old people are like, oh, kids today don't know how to use a rotary phone.
And I'm like, thank goodness they don't, those things were terrible.
I know. Right. Actually, it's funny too because my kids are always like, I, I,
when they got their cell phones
and now let's clarify when you say cell phones. Do you mean smartphones?
Yeah,
of course.
I mean, they,
they got their SIM cards, they got actual phone numbers, right?
Because this was during the pandemic and we're like, everything's a mess.
We want to get you guys some phones now.
That way, just if like, everything goes sideways,
we have some communications and all this stuff and we go into the, the store,
we were like, we need to add two lines to the, the plane and like,
what area code do you want?
Do you want the same one you have? And I'm like,
can they pick any area code?
And the lady was like, yeah, like do 12 and the kids were like, why, why do we want that?
I'm like, because it's the best area code and my kids were like,
I don't get it. Why, why is 212 so good?
-- Right.
-- It's the shortest,
right?
And I was like, I, I then I do explain a rotary phone to them,
explain how you used it to dial and why 212
was such an important area code with a rotary phone.
And they're like, we don't care, dad, we'll just take the same area code you have.
But I'm like, no, I failed as a parent.
Well, I was just, I was buying some Zoom phones for the CS A and it's like
just unlimited calling within the US. And Canada is the bare minimum feature set.
They'll sell you
like, and I remember when that was a big deal to add that onto your phone
and not
cheap. I mean, anyway, no, I'm not. We're not turning this into
talking about old phones. But,
well, this is a perfect example of like where the phone companies, you know,
used to make a lot of money on local calls or billing long distance and realized
at some point, like,
especially once they move to a packet network instead of a stream based network.
Here's the ugly secret.
Do you know what the number one cost and hassle for most phone companies is,
is billing to the point where actually most of it's outsourced to random company.
Like there's this Israeli company that does
phone billing for a lot of major telecoms
because phone billing is apparently such a nightmare that they just outsource it.
I believe that.
And that's a perfect example here of like
the phone companies instead of fixing it themselves.
They were just like, hey, these smart guys over in Europe or Israel or this,
I'm sure there must be a company in America doing it.
Boom, done.
Pay them to do it
and they probably handle leap seconds. Whereas
I'm guessing if you build by the minute or bill by
the second most phone companies would not handle leap seconds.
So the way that's generally done,
I wonder, I, I bet a lot of them don't actually,
I bet I would not be surprised at all if
calls that end on the leap second don't get billed.
Well, no, no, no.
But here's the problem if you have a call start and a call duration in seconds,
that call
-- start and duration no longer match up with the call, end time.
-- It's close enough.
It won't matter. I, I bet the software's not that smart
anyway, we're running out of time. All right. So I guess
my, my, my close on this is just
corner cases, amuse me. And
it is an interesting thought experiment to discuss a weird corner case
in the context of like, what would I do in this environment?
And I think in the case of time, it's obvious that you want to make the problem,
just go away for normal people because it creates a mess for them.
And, and I think that makes sense in this context.
And I also get why economically speaking,
I can tilt at windmills and try and get the NTP consortium
to do the right thing which is to do leap smears.
But in the meantime,
I'm probably going to have to fix my own software and that's
just kind of how a lot of this ends up working.
Do we? Do we know? Is there a leap second coming up?
I have no
idea.
I don't know either.
But if you look at the Wikipedia page,
like they're a reasonably regular occurrence.
-- Well, they,
-- they come and go right, like sometimes there's long spans without them.
It's very strange. So,
anyway, anyway, we'll see.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Head up the show notes, Uy
Pounds
Podcast hashtag hit to the spot on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the.