Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode
40 with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- Kurt,
-- do you know what's special about the number 40?
That's how old I turn this year. No, nothing, nothing is special about 40.
That's the beauty of it. We are monkeys with 10 fingers. So we always say
numbers that end in zero have meaning but they don't.
So
they're also used to avoid by 10,
which is only important because we are monkeys with 10 fingers.
See,
-- that's right.
-- Anyway, it's awesome.
Right.
Very good.
So, I am going to start this show with a bit of a rant
and then I'm gonna tie it into
a discussion.
We had a couple of days ago about security teams and not shipping software.
All right. So,
so my son comes home from school yesterday
and has an assignment from his teacher of
no screen time all weekend.
And they're supposed to be talking about, uh,
addiction or drugs and alcohol or whatever.
I can kind of understand where this is gonna go because like
every kid is gonna fail and they had a terrible weekend,
whatever.
And it's like, oh, but that's how addiction works everybody.
And it got me thinking
that
food addiction
uh
sure.
-- But, but here's the point
-- we all have to eat fundamentally.
We,
yes, that, yes, you're actually on to exactly where I'm going with. This is that
it's occurred to me
that asking someone to not use screens
is insane in this day and age because these have become
part of society in our lives. Like an example is
when,
when we wanted to look up some information,
how do you do that?
You grab a screen and you go to Google and now when I was a kid, if we did that,
we would go to the encyclopedia and spend, you know, like,
like two hours trying to maybe find something that we've never actually found.
You know what I mean?
Is, this is like, it, it is a part of life now that you cannot escape.
I would view this as telling someone you can't use electricity all weekend long.
We'd be like, that's dumb.
No.
You know, now if it was with the caveat,
you can't plug anything into the wall for the weekend.
I'd be like, ok, cool. I can live with that,
you know, because I can use my phone in a batter.
Yeah.
And that's
bills.
Right. Exactly. That's just it. Right.
In fact, I was just, I, I,
I've got to get my taxes done and I was just on my computer printing stuff off.
I'm like, that's how it works. Right. That is,
-- in fact, I was thinking this is a nuisance.
-- I
submit it electronically.
Yeah.
But I have to print stuff and then bring it to
the accountant and they type everything back into the computer.
I know this is insane.
Whatever, whatever is how it is. I don't care.
And, and I do miss the days when this like,
envelopes would come to me in the mail and then I would bring everything in,
in a big folder and be like, there you go.
And now I print everything and then put it in the big folder and whatever.
But anyway, so here's my point, right? Is
there are certain expectations that have been laid down,
especially around like screens and computers and,
and now like telling a kid no video games or TV or whatever.
OK. We can maybe work on that because that like you won't, you won't die maybe.
But
so, so here's where I want to take this though
is you and I were talking about the days when
a security team could stop ship software for their organization,
which whether that was even true back then we, we can argue one way or the other.
But,
and here's the point is
in the world today,
I think, expecting to stop ship something as a security team is
kind of absurd.
I don't think it's something that's a reasonable expectation anymore.
And in all seriousness, you should have been involved from the start
and never even find yourself in this position. But regardless the point is
that
I feel like there's a lot of people who
they don't realize the world has changed
and so their expectations and what they think is ok,
hasn't caught up with that.
And it's totally like a teacher telling kids no screen time
feels to me like
a security team today that says, oh,
I'm gonna stop ship because you didn't fix this bug.
And it's like you're both living 20 years ago.
Well, and I think a big aspect of this is too, is like, the reality is
even terrible, serious bugs and flaws. Like a great example of the Samsung seven.
I mean, they actually, these things caught fire,
they
caught fire.
Well, they could have been exploding and then catching fire
have been slightly worse.
But, yeah, I mean, literally these devices catch fire.
If you bend them, they catch fire,
done deal. I mean, and you know, it, what they, they, they sort of quasi
fixed it once and found out. Oops. No, we didn't
because the fix had a flaw. And, I mean,
you know, that's an example of where they should have stopped shipping it,
done a recall and sorted it out. But, you know, they sort of did that but not quite.
And,
yeah, I mean,
ok, you know, the world went on.
Nobody really seems to have cared that much and quite honestly, what really got me is
I was listening to the radio in the car the other
day and they were actually talking up the Samsung the,
the eight,
what is it? The Galaxy Eight
comes out being like an amazing phone. It's
got more stuff in it and bigger screen or, I don't know, whatever. Right. And
so it's pretty clear that the whole Samsung Seven debacle and they even made
fun of the Samsung seven for catching fire and stuff and they're like,
this one doesn't catch fire, but
nobody really cares.
You know, it's, I don't, I, I really,
I don't think it's impacted or it's going to impact sales much.
I mean, look at Apple with their infamous, like you're holding it wrong phone.
I do remember that and,
you know, maybe,
maybe all these people who've been talking about brand for so long
were wrong.
I think part of it people will forgive quite a bit,
you know,
and more to the point like I can't. Ok. So let's say I decide to
be angry at Apple and ditch all their stuff
that's gonna cost me several $1000
to get rid of like to replace all my stuff, you know. So
yeah, unless they start like,
well I was gonna say eating kittens but even that, you know,
is it really that bad?
There's a lot of cats in the world, you know, overpopulation of cats.
-- But anyways, not that I'm advocating the eating of kittens
-- to be clear
from security teams,
stop shipping to eating cats.
A
level
of
sanity.
The thing is right. I mean, here's the reality
there.
I, I took that security economics course and they,
they point out bluntly there are so many things that are legitimately huge risks
to killing companies and to killing products or to costing lots of money.
But these, like, well,
it's a security flaw that maybe gets exploited and maybe something
bad happens and maybe it ends up in the press,
right?
We're talking at
that point, such a, a small risk. Statistically,
you just don't need to care
which the security part of me is like screaming in a padded room when he hears that.
But the business side of me is like, yeah, no, cool.
Like if we ship this, we can make money and then if we have money,
maybe we can go back and fix this
and that ties into this whole, like,
I love the idea of proactive security, but for example,
the Linux kernel has how many tens of millions of lines of code.
So we're stuck with that.
Um And so then it boils down to fast reactive security of like, ok, you know, like
how fast can you do a tire recall and swap all the tires on your car?
You know,
II I agree with you 100%
in, in all of this.
And you know what else it reminds me of actually, is,
what was it you who was telling me that in order
for there to be an airline disaster at this point,
there has to be like six things that go horribly wrong.
And if you
look like five happen, everything's usually ok.
And that's
kind of
-- something like where the pilot intentionally crashes it because they're
-- suicidal
ignoring that.
That's not an accident,
right?
Which, which kind of brings me then to
stuff, they fixed it.
A lot of airlines have a two man role and even
if one of the copilots or whatever has to leave,
they send in a stewardess or whatever.
-- I mean,
-- ok, that, that's fair. I suppose that's true.
That does mean
it, it's more difficult. But so. Right.
So we're, we're getting to security now and that view of the almighty security team
and,
yeah, even
like five or six, probably terrible things would need to happen before
that, that bug that us, you know,
tinfoil had security people were freaking out about
it becomes legitimately a problem.
Right. I mean,
-- let's
-- face it
when you, I mean,
the reality is there are some security flaws that do end up being used in,
like drive by ad download attacks and stuff and,
you know, there's your, uh, what is it? Your Adobe Flash, your Java.
What's the third one?
Uh, IE
ie more. Yeah. Well, actually, no. Yeah.
Sadly, yeah, older versions of IE, newer versions seem to be better,
you know,
and and so the reality is there are legitimately like attacks that are bad or,
um, well, I mean, slammer but, hey, you know,
nobody had passwords on their databases.
So it's,
it's kind of hard to get excited about that.
Um,
but yeah, I mean,
or like that struts worm that is going around
in struts to the Romo code execution thing,
right.
You know,
but that's also, it's kind of old,
you know, and that's the thing, right? So we're dealing with a world where? Ok.
Yeah, we have a really severe flaw,
but we also have a patch and everybody's ignoring it.
They're
ignoring it or if they just don't know.
I,
well, some people definitely have, like, really poor infosec
and are just not aware of anything going on,
obviously, like,
they're small and medium businesses and that are probably outsource this to, like,
manage service providers who
just don't have the expertise for this. But
the reality is too, I mean, is, do you want to take again back to this, like, ok.
So if we, like, upgrade the software on this thing, well,
the last time we did that we broke it.
So we just don't do that anymore unless we absolutely have to.
Versus
this. Well, they say there's this risk and if somebody, and then there's all those
fallacies that people believe, like, oh, you know,
the internet is full of so many systems nobody would ever target us directly.
Well, it sort of true, but also worms,
you know, that just touch everything.
Um
So
yeah, I mean, really what it boils down to, I guess is that risk analysis, which,
you know, the majority of people don't do because
even I, when I try to do these risk analysis
analyses, sorry,
um
What data am I basing these risk analyses off of? And the answer is,
so
you just, you just reminded me something
really funny.
So, so for those of you who don't know, I,
I've moved to from Red Hat to Elastic and I'm doing
various security things for them there. And
one of the things is,
is there's a machine learning product that's designed to do some
kind of security analysis and using like actual machine learning,
not just grub
and, and you know, finding threats and whatnot anyway, I'm, I'm helping one of the,
the marketing guys put together a demo and he said like, what am I,
what am I looking for?
Like, help me, help me look for something cool.
And I said uh why don't you look for 404 errors with no refer in the header, right?
So basically people do, right?
He did that and he's like,
what am I looking at? This? Looks terrible. And I'm like, that's the internet dude.
Like that's, that's what's happening all the time everywhere.
And yeah, there's like attempts for, for like PHP login weird forums and,
and wordpress stuff.
It just like all this crazy and,
and the guy was horrified. I'm like, this is, this is just what it is, man.
Like anywhere you are, this is what your web server is doing now because like,
like people are just like spamming the internet
with everything.
Yeah, it's crazy.
Even
like, you know, all my sites are behind cloud flare and they block a lot of stuff
but even then, you know, yeah, I was gonna do a 404 clean up.
So, yeah, went for 404 and it was like, wow, there's so much of this car,
like there's still people scanning for.
Um,
oh, I don't remember the name of it now. I won't, I want to say Front Page.
-- Remember Microsoft front Page
-- I have and there's
probably a ton of it out there still.
Well, the I
six vulnerability that has now an exploit
and they're not going to fix it, nor should they, in my opinion, it's out of support.
-- Right.
-- Quit running that. Why are you doing that? What's wrong with you?
Windows XP in 95 are stolen. You
know?
I know. I know.
But, you know, typically they're not hope.
Well, typically, hopefully they're not running internet facing servers.
They probably are.
Yeah.
But, yeah, I mean, so that's, that's, you know, it's how many people, like,
check the brakes on their car
periodically or
-- even the oil in their car.
-- I never do. In fact, I had a problem with my brakes one day.
Like, I, I turned on the brakes and the car pulled real hard to the right.
And I thought this is
weird.
So, anyway, I bring it in.
They're like, yeah, uh,
your breaks are like falling off your car because my car was kind of old.
I'm like, you guys just fixed the brakes a year ago.
The mechanic, like, uh, yeah,
we don't know what happened but they're falling off like we fix them, you know.
So, I don't know.
I, I must have run something over or hit a pothole or whatever, but it's like, yeah,
-- that's,
-- they forgot to put a screw in.
I, I don't know,
they didn't give me a discount,
so I'm gonna assume it wasn't them trying to pretend that everything was cool.
Like that's,
in fact, that's what I was waiting for.
I was waiting for them to offer some sort of discount
or free parts and I'd be like you guys screwed up.
But no, no, they didn't do that. So,
anyway, anyway, we should, we should move on to happy topics now.
Maybe,
maybe spyware.
Yeah,
I, yeah,
well, spyware is whatever. Spyware. Spyware.
But, yeah, apparently your,
one of your happy fun Telcos is actually forcing it on people,
I guess. And Verizon wants to put, uh, something called Appl
on Android phones,
which is
I,
-- what is that flash?
-- I, I don't know. It's something that
monitors your activity apparently.
And it, it sounds like it's one of those just spy on people and then sell
their browsing habits and whatnot to, to somebody for marketing data, right?
Whatever you wanna call that
you could call it spyware, I would call it spyware. Whatever. Here's, there's,
there's kind of three things that come to mind when I think of this immediately is,
uh first of all,
why on earth would a company think this is a good idea? This is insane
because 1% of the users will fall for it and it's a revenue stream,
not a 1% credit. It's going to be like 8080 80% or more, I guarantee. And that's,
well, well, that, that's the second point now is the fact that
I,
I see this story and there's all these
people talking about rooting their phones and selling
car.
I'm like,
nobody's going to do that.
Normal.
People won't even hear about this and they're just gonna go to Verizon and they're
gonna get the phone that's free when they sign up for a 12 year contract.
And,
and that's what they're gonna use.
And so they don't even know this is happening to them.
And I'm sure in that phone book they signed,
it has one bullet point talking about Verizon
stealing all of their browsing habits off their phone
-- and, and that's the thing like,
-- isn't that a moot point now with the new FCC
Rs?
That's another story we can.
But here's the deal. Right.
Here's the deal,
I guess at the end of the day is why on earth can they even do this to these phones?
You'd think that these phone manufacturers would
want to exert some level of control.
Like an Apple. Does this where Apple is?
Like, no, you're not gonna put it with a bunch of crap on our phone.
Like this is an iphone. We do it our way
-- and in all seriousness they do it.
-- Right.
Well, here's the thing though.
Apple is bargaining from a position of strength.
How many different Android phone makers are there?
There's like, I don't know.
Yeah,
I know. What was it? LG was talking about?
Android phones and the fact that they have, like, they make a penny
on them,
like,
legitimately, their profit margin is not, like, not a percent but a pen.
It's probably bigger than that. I mean,
there was an article about this.
It
was ok. That could be the end result.
But I bet you two, these companies like LG,
they make a bunch of other parts that go into it.
I bet it's like movie accounting
where every movie loses money.
I'm sure
they're, they're granted
they're not making tons of money on these phones.
It's not like the iphone is selling for 8, 900 bucks,
you know, 300 parts in costs.
Um,
but anyways, so that's part of the challenge. Right? Is, is,
oh, you know,
I
mean,
maybe apart from like Samsung because they're kind of
hot right now with the S eight or whatever,
the Samsung eight,
you know, like LG, like, I name an LG phone model.
Uh, the Nexus five X.
Ok.
Ok. Well, ok. Yeah, exactly. Like,
you know, there's, if you don't carry one brand of Android,
I don't think too many people are gonna, like,
-- walk out of the store whereas with Apple, they will,
-- I mean, that, that is fair and I,
I mean, this is why I would only buy an Android phone from Google. And even, even then
all of this madness has me seriously thinking about
an iphone just because there's a level of sanity
and
peace of mind
-- that will come with this
-- sort of, I mean,
there are problems like I recently discovered,
did a iphone update to 10.3 or whatever
and it reset the whole Hey Siri thing,
you know, which
I did like, I remember that podcast we're doing a few weeks ago where I was like blah,
blah, blah, blah, hey Siri.
And then my phone's like,
you
know,
and I'm like, damn it, I disabled that and then I did an O update. So it got Reen
and so,
you know, iphones aren't perfect like there are, you know,
now I'm kind of wondering like all the other security settings I made
uh the restrictions are still there. Thank goodness those stay between updates.
But
you know, the um things like Hey, Siri, you know, popped back in and it's like,
that's really freaking annoying.
-- I,
-- I'm sure my phone does the same things I just haven't noticed or paid it well,
I never use any of that stuff either.
I,
yeah,
anyway, anyway, so
-- it's,
-- I think a lot of it
again, kind of like the security thing. It really boils down to a lot of like
these sec, these, well, and when I say these security issues, they're,
they're only security issues to people that truly
understand them unless it's something like really egregious,
like,
you know, uh, like the, um,
you know, where, like, kids data is being, like,
directly leaked online in a way that's understandable.
Right? Because the majority of security problems are not easily understood.
They're kind of, you know,
there's nuances to them.
Right.
And so even, even security people don't always agree
on what is, or isn't a thing? It's madness.
Yeah.
And so with that, I mean, the reality is,
I don't think these security incidents and vulnerabilities actually
do much if any real damage to these brands and
to these products in the minds of the consumer.
Um,
you know, you,
you basically have to have something really epically
stupid and understandable to kill a brand.
Like, uh,
well, like that airline that, you know,
crashed into the swamp in Florida because
they were carrying oxygen containers online,
you know, like improper cargo or whatever.
Uh,
was it easy?
Not easy? Jet.
Yeah, I know who you mean.
And you know that, and, but here's
the, or, or even better, you know, um, Malaysian Airlines, right.
They, was it, they lost two, or was it three planes in this, like,
not a good track record?
Granted they hit like the, you know, the trifecta lottery winnings.
Um,
and so technically they went out of business but
-- they just rebranded
-- and that's how it always works,
man.
I mean, everybody does that
you just, you rebrand
all done, put a
new coat of paint on that 747 and
was
to say
there's some consulting company I heard of that was doing
uh it was, it had something to do with, with one of the,
the public sector certifications
and
I was,
I was trying to look them up and I feel like
I couldn't find anything about the history of this company.
And so anyway, I finally talked to somebody like, oh yeah, they,
they used to be so and so, and they change your name.
I'm like, oh yeah, yeah, those guys were terrible,
but it totally works. Right. It totally works it
anyway.
And I guess in, in, in this note, we should talk about uh ISP spying,
which is probably less of a story than it than it really is. But
I,
well, no, here's, here's,
here's the deal. All right. Is
that the in the US, the,
the Congress or whatever? Some, some, one of the lawmaker groups. I forget which one
they basically rolled back some customer protections on
ISP selling their data to third party advertisers.
And, but here's the deal is
this, this rule has been in place for like four months.
So
I I'm all for customer privacy. But I think it's, it, there's probably less,
there should be less uproar than there is perhaps
because this is one of those things that,
that needs to be fixed.
Of course, it won't be because like the government is completely dysfunctional.
But
that's another story
and, and it's like,
it's only been there four months. I'm
the world didn't end before it's not gonna end again.
And so all these people talking about like running, you know, VPN S and,
and all this other crazy
is,
is probably a bit over the top and it kind of comes back to that third party firmware.
Bit of our last story
is normal. People aren't gonna run VPN S because they, they can't.
-- And could you imagine the poor V
-- P?
I've actually met a few normal people that do have
like Nord VPN or whatever installed on their machine.
They pay their three bucks a month. Seriously.
Uh, but these, yeah, I mean, it's, it's, but it's, it's the,
if you actually go to some of these better VPN providers,
it literally is like 40 bucks or 50 bucks a year.
And, oh, you're on a Mac click this, if you're on windows click this and it just works.
So, they know, because
they wanna sell their stuff. Right. So, they've actually gotten user friendly,
you know, I use, uh, Tour
Guard and, I mean,
um,
I use it on Linux of all things or? Sorry, I use it on free BS D actually,
um, because I'm a weirdo and even for them it was trivial.
They're like, oh, you're, they actually have set up scripts for free BS D,
you know, and I'm like, it's like download this.
Here's the, you know, here's the config files for like,
uh well, they basically have like 200 different pools of servers like globally,
right?
And I use the Canadian ones
and uh
you know,
and I just modified their script so that I
hard coded my password and user name into it,
right?
So that it just automatically starts when the machine boots.
So all of your traffic goes over a VPN.
Uh All of my traffic on my backup network link goes over
VPN because I, I it's sort of a quasi
anonymous slash,
you know, that's not K
-- uh thing for what I want to look at stuff, maybe whatever
-- things,
right? We just say look at stuff.
Yeah,
nothing in particular.
But speaking of I SPS and privacy, I mean, there was that one,
I have to find the link for you later, but there was that one ISP that was inserting,
I wanna say people's account number or MAC address.
Or something like that really ridiculous into outgoing http headers.
That would not surprise me in any, you know.
Um,
and I think part of the, the, I
think really what it boils down to is
people sort of are kind of aware that they're being tracked but
they don't like their face being rubbed in it.
So, you know, my all time favorite is everybody's like, oh, you know, blah, blah,
blah, tracking, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I'm like, cool. Do you have a cell phone? They're like, of course, I do.
And I'm like, well, so like, yeah, you're being tracked like, uh no, I'm not. I
where do you think they get the traffic data from?
Like the information on how bad and messed up the roads are?
Where do you think that comes from? And they're like, uh,
or I'm like the, you know, Google now,
Google Maps shows approximately how busy a business is
like in real time. Now,
if you go to
Google.
Exactly. And it's because cell phones, right? And,
well, and technically speaking there, you know, the ISP is quasi
anonymize the data and send it over to Google or whoever's willing to buy it.
But, you know, so that, that data are, I mean,
the reality is these companies are gonna monetize any data they can
and people's
location and travel and habits like that,
especially, you know, aggregated in bulk is a hugely valuable thing.
And I, and I mean, I do love it because when I go to maps.google.com now and, like,
look up a business and they're like,
you know, they show that little graph of, like, how busy the business is,
like at various hours of the day and stuff.
And then they say, like, approximately how busy it is right now.
I mean, that is wonderful.
You know, that's actually really useful because I will then,
you know, avoid a store until it's less busy.
You don't have a much better experience
or, you know, for planning dinner reservations.
That actually makes life a lot easier, you know.
Right.
Like, oh, if I want to book a seven o'clock table, I'm gonna have to do it like,
it looks like about two weeks out,
you know.
And so, you know, when it's done
properly, the product is amazing.
And then, but the question becomes, you know, how is,
how are people being protected?
Right. It's,
it always reminds me of when they
were trying that really hyper targeted advertising,
you know, and they were sending out pregnancy
related stuff to, you know, people who didn't even know they were pregnant yet,
right? Because
they found out, for example, you know, when women get pregnant, their,
their choice in soaps and a bunch of other
stuff changes because of their sensitivity to fragrances.
Right?
And so, you know,
uh there was one case of where this like, girl, I think in Texas or something,
you know, got this, like, ad and her parents freaked out.
And so what they do now is they,
they, they mask the ads, right.
They put the, like, they, they basically send you like, 50 innocuous ads plus,
like the five that are, you know, pregnancy related or whatever.
So it looks less targeted and it's less obvious. And so,
you know, it's, it's,
that's my concern. Right? Is like, you could,
I'm guessing based on
travel data you could easily like out a whole bunch of people that are in the closet,
you know, based on what bars they go to or based on,
you know, whatever. Right. And,
and that is where things become concerned or, you know,
what if your insurance company buys this data and it is like, yeah,
we're jacking up your premiums because you spend a lot of time at the bar or whatever,
you know.
And that's one, in fact, that's one of the reasons there's the, what are the,
the DNA testing?
We
-- just got that in Canada.
-- And I'm, my wife thinks they sound neat.
I'm like, I will not do that because someday, um,
my insurance company is gonna get a hold of that and,
and nothing good will come of them having access to that data.
No, it's, and I mean, I guess what, what that comes down to is
when, when I think of these kind of problems,
it's really been
kind of regulation.
That's
been the, the lowest common denominator
historically speaking, because I don't think we can trust these organizations
to be stewards of this data.
Well, they need to monetize it. That's the thing. Their business is fundamentally
and that's what pisses me off about where people are.
Like, oh, well, the real problem is that we have these ISP monopolies.
No, because even if you had like 1000 I SPS to choose from,
they would all still be trying to monetize this data.
Yeah. Yeah, it'd be terrible, man.
You know, like every social network on the planet is,
well, not every, every single website on the planet is showing ads and these ads have
tracking data.
-- That's just
-- how
the internet is.
That's crazy, man.
All right. So what about this uh smart TV running flash?
Have you read that story, Kurt?
Yeah. So yes, I, yeah, T V's running flash.
Uh And I actually, I want to apologize last episode.
Uh You might remember, I think I mixed it up with the dishwashers running flash.
-- We
-- joked. No, here's the thing
about dishwashers running flash.
That
was
about it.
Hey, guess what? Everybody, your TV probably has flash well done.
Yeah.
Well, and what's even more? It's OK. Honestly, the TV has a web browser
and the TV has flash. I can,
I can sort of excuse that.
For one simple fact,
there's a lot of cute little old flash games online that
would be kind of fun to play on a big TV,
OK. Like desktop power defense or whatever, right. But having said that
the fact that you can apparently
in the TV signal, like in the broadcast TV, signal that these things process,
you can send stuff and it will open a URL in the web browser in the background.
Right.
Well,
and not only that the, the digital
signal, digital broadcasting signal
is unencrypted
and, and why would it be? Right. It's, it's not authenticated anyway.
So essentially if someone
-- management
-- that's true.
But if, if someone essentially has a transmitter
and you use an antenna,
you're probably doomed. And, and so what,
so you're forgetting?
Drones,
-- screw.
-- Look,
a
drone,
ignoring, drones, the, the flower van that's been outside for a week.
Right. Like those guys.
And, and here's the thing.
Everyone doesn't understand though either about the way a lot of these TV. S work is
if you have a digital TV, today,
did you ever notice you can usually push a button and it'll bring
up a little menu showing you all the shows on the various channels.
-- I'll take your word for it. I don't have cable TV.
-- No, no, this isn't cable.
This is broadcast.
I don't have, I don't, well, I don't do broadcast.
Well,
-- I do Netflix,
-- I
have a myth machine
which, which does my broadcast, but which, which doesn't do this.
And I'm going to assume isn't running flash since I didn't put it on it.
But
that's another story.
Anyway, here's the deal is most of these TV s are
listening
all the time because they're getting the updated channel info off of the channels.
So you can't say like,
oh my TV is off or I never turn on the digital receiver or whatever.
Like if you set this up
and, and I should say a lot of them probably just set themselves up.
It's going to pick up
a digital television signal coming through the air.
And so, like, there's basically nothing you can do here.
Yeah. No, I remember I had to set up a Samsung TV for somebody. Uh,
and then I hit that privacy notification and I was like, what? Oh, ok.
That's interesting. And I started scrolling through it and I'm like,
yeah, I'm sitting in green,
it was like 500 screen Fs
and,
yeah, I mean,
I, you know, I, I, it's funny you mentioned turning it off doesn't, actually,
I'm actually just sitting here trying to think of
what I own, but when I turn it off it actually turns off
off off.
The only thing I,
well, I was gonna say I have some flashlights
and, and I'm sure even then,
and that's it. Like I can't think of anything.
Oh, my, well, no, my alarm clock has a nine volt battery in it. That's right.
Uh,
so even my alarm clock, like a $20 alarm clock,
although that's hopefully safe from hacking because it's stupid.
That a challenge.
Um But yeah, no,
realistically, you know, it's sold, it's not, you know.
But, yeah, I mean, realistically I'm just thinking everything I have,
especially anything that connects to a network doesn't
have a concept of like actual off,
off.
No, nothing does anymore.
Nothing turns off because it always does magic in the background.
Yeah. And I mean,
-- yeah, so,
-- so anyway, here's the deal though. Ok, here's the deal is number one,
don't put freaking flash on your smart TV because flash is a huge problem.
Let's face it. You look at like flash running in something like chrome,
they sandbox this thing to death. Do you think these smart TV S have sandboxes?
-- You know, they don't
-- uh
don't a bunch of smart TV S run.
Maybe
they're probably running Android having
-- said that
-- right?
I mean, just,
you know, they're not running a latest version of Android.
Oh OK.
Um And well, the thing is I know for flash, I think it broke 1000 CV S some time ago.
-- 1207 1200
-- you said?
Uh Yeah, I just, well, and that's on the search term,
Adobe flash player like that's pretty,
not a lot of false positives.
Wow,
-- that's,
-- you know,
-- that does not surprise me. Hey, at
-- least they're fixing flaws.
But again, it goes back to that technical debt issue of like,
you know, at this point, you obviously can't, well,
unless you rewrite flash from scratch in a memory safe language.
-- No,
-- that's, that's never gonna happen. Dude.
Like actually I just read a tweet earlier today about this that
someone pointed out that saying use a memory safe language is the equivalent
of telling people just stop being poor as the solution to their problem.
I just added this to the show notes, but there's that announcement from the Tor
project
talking about just that choosing a memory safe language to rewrite torn.
And then they went with Rust cause Rust apparently has good sea binding.
So they can sort of like transition over.
And I would say so for
a very teeny tiny eensy
weensy
percentage of software projects where security actually matters and tor
being like one of the three,
then it is an actual answer.
But yeah, for the rest of the world, no, just it's useless.
Yeah, I know.
Well, it's think about it if you can't stop ship,
rewrite the whole thing in a different language is like
10 times 100 times worse than not shipping
because that's gonna cost you a lot of money.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, that's,
that's true. That kind of comes back to that stop shift discussion we had is
even even bad shipped software makes more money than software.
That is perfect and never ships.
Yeah.
So
I, you know, I mean, I, I would personally, for myself,
I would only ever use memory safe languages because I'm lazy and
I just don't want to write languages that require a lot of,
you
know,
I
know what you mean,
detail oriented stuff because I'm terrible at that.
Um,
and more to the point, like, to me it's, I just,
I want to use more advanced tools now and I get
that there's a place in a time for ce C++ whatever.
Right.
There's just certain stuff where you, you just have to do it that way right now.
Yeah.
Yeah, there is.
Although, wait, what is, uh, hang on a sec? What language is?
Uh, ok. Hang on a second.
Hm.
What is this thing written in?
Uh, it's written in c,
um, the, uh, the Google, Os Fuxia.
Yeah.
Well, you could, you could
-- go or
-- something. How do you write an operating system in go,
I don't know.
But
if it can spit out a binary, I mean, theoretically, why not?
Well, it's complicated. I mean, bootstrapping
-- theory, it should be possible in practice. Yeah. No, nobody would do it
-- because
this is one of the next things on, on the show note list here we put together is
Fuchsia is a new operating system. Apparently. Google is working on
and
I, I guess here's, here's the question
is if anyone can do this,
it's Google.
But can they,
well, they have, but more to the point is it
viable?
No, no, this is not production ready.
This is a long way to go before they're gonna be using it
in something. And so the question is really,
do you think
it's gonna happen?
I,
here's the brutal reality is Google operates servers out of scale. Where
for the sake of argument, if you can save a dollar a year on every server
for them, that's hundreds of millions of dollars.
So,
for them at that scale, you know what
just think about, like if they, if they
don't, if it reduces their global reboot count by one
because they do some clever because it's a micro kernel, right? So, uh
OK, so long story short, there's basically two theories, I guess,
or two camps of like operating system design,
there's the monolithic kernel, like Linux Windows,
whatever where you basically just have a ginormous blob
of software that runs the computer suite mostly.
And then the micro kernel guys are sort of like, well,
let's be a little more clever about this.
So the idea being you have this really tiny
kernel that is the actual like sort of minimum core of the system.
And fundamentally all it does is just pass messages around,
you know,
and then everything else is like kind of plugs into it.
And so
in theory, you can like
unplug those things and plug new things in,
you know, on the fly even whereas with a monolithic kernel,
well, you can sort of do that now with things like um
uh oh
what the heck is it called uh
case splice or what's the other one
K patch.
Yeah.
Yeah. Which basically involve like sort of
patching the binary by like shoving a bunch of, well, essentially jumps in to,
you know,
scissor out part of the binary you don't want and put part of the, you know,
a new binary in.
But with micro kernels, obviously this is a lot more uh supported.
So from that perspective, like if they come up with, say a, a truly, you know,
uh a secure core that then, you know,
all these other bits can be unplugged and plugged
in and they don't have to do reboots.
You know,
even if a reboot only takes their machine like
two or three seconds multiply that by like,
you know, tens of millions of machines,
that's a significant amount of downtime,
-- you know, lost product. Is
-- it true? Well, I would imagine
that without some of the overhead of Linux,
you could also have higher density.
But here's,
here's part
of the, the question is
adding all the features you need to actually run an operating system is nontrivial.
And it's the one of those things that a phd student thinks is neat and easy and fun.
But when it comes down to it, we kind of come back to that whole stop ship thing is
there are
just certain real world requirements that
win
when it comes down to doing it right and getting it done.
And, and I think like the Linux kernel is a great example of a,
a million decisions between doing it right.
And getting it done
and granted they, they do a lot. Right. Don't get me wrong.
But there's also a lot of like, let's just get it done.
Yeah.
Well, and what, what's interesting to me though is,
uh and actually Linux is a good example.
Linux tries to be a lot of things to a lot of different people.
Right.
It runs on everything from smartphones to supercomputers,
to network devices with no
like no console or anything, right?
Um
Whereas Google uh and this is of course,
a huge assumption that like my assumption would be that they're looking at this as a,
you know, something to run their servers,
you know, the dose
and G uh Google computer engine and all that stuff.
So there they would have a much more constrained problem space, you know,
they literally control the hardware to a degree
that almost nobody else controls in their environment,
right?
Because they're actually working with Intel and making their own switches and,
you know, doing all this custom stuff.
Um Secondly, their workloads, right?
They obviously, you know,
-- have much better well defined workloads than most people
-- think about this a lot.
And in fact,
this is something somewhere where Java kind of gets some of
this right as well if you don't have to really,
I mean, you kind of do, I know it's complicated, but
the idea is you just kind of write a thing and then it works.
-- Yeah. Right. Once
-- run
anywhere. No, it's not. But, you know, that's
well, and
Linux is sort of that run time now, like, within reason
most Linux
workloads can run on, you know,
at least a variety of near Linuxes without too much of a horror show, you know,
compared to say, like Windows versus Linux, which even now it is becoming, you know,
-- possible because Windows has a Linux subsystem
-- which is crazy.
So
I love it,
dude.
I
know
clearly, you know,
that's what gets me is, is, yeah. Can you imagine 20 years ago if we'd been like,
oh yeah, don't worry about it.
This is gonna be awesome and it'll be Windows o you know,
Microsoft will ship it on Windows eventually,
right? Nobody, you know, they all would have put you in a padded room.
Um
But yeah, back to this, I mean, assuming
that assuming
Fuxi for example, like if you could define the workload as like
you essentially have to run, you know, containers that like have a
glib C basically
and then just basically talk to the network, talk to the disk, talk to memory,
-- talk to the CP
-- U.
I mean, it's not unreasonable and and there's always talk of this with,
oh what do they call the, the micro
Os thing?
That's always that there's been so many
research papers about like uh micro kernels,
I think it is,
-- is it or rump
-- kernels
the
kernels.
No. Is it?
Oh,
I forget the name anyway.
You get the idea. Right.
-- Yeah. Oh, man. Yeah. Oh, it's on
-- the tip of my.
Don't you love it when you just,
it's not coming back.
Old
man. Getting old is the worst decision I ever made.
Uh, they're known as rump kernels.
I keep thinking rump kernel and I know they have another name. That's less bizarre.
That makes sense.
But anyway.
oh, these guys. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, because the whole idea was you would like,
literally take like a little bit of kernel compile your application
that
you have your application.
Right.
Yeah,
I think there's potential here, but it's still very,
it's very much a research project. And
part of me wonders if we're ever even going to get there
just because
it's easy to write a research project.
It's a lot more work to actually get the job done.
And this is
Linux
does it though. Like, Linux actually works, you know, it as ugly as it is
and as much as we don't wanna, we, it's that friend.
We wanna pretend we don't know, like it's getting the work done
well. And I've read, um, I forget which phone company it is,
but they actually have,
um,
it was open stack, I believe, running on their, you know,
massive phone switch server, do hicky rack thing in a jigger.
And it was actually handling like DH CP requests by spinning up
a container to process the DH P request and then killing it.
And it was doing this whole thing within
-- like 40 milliseconds or something
-- cleaners are designed to start
up very quickly and be destroyed just as fast.
So that's, that's fine.
Yeah. And
I
suspect Unic kernels
running on hardware are not ever gonna happen,
but maybe some sort of quasi
-- Unic kernel style container,
-- you
don't
need
-- it in a container. It's just running an application and
-- more to the point
actually, it's, it's even obsolete because you would just go cus
and why would you even care about the Os? Right? It's just abstracted away from you.
There's your Python runtime
the right way to kind of start thinking about a lot of this is, is who cares?
And now someone like Google might care
because like you said,
if they can save a dollar per server, that's, that's real money.
But for, for people like us,
big deal, right?
Whoopee. It's, it's Os X or it's Windows or it's Linux or it's BS D like who cares?
It doesn't matter.
Yeah. All, all I really care at this point is like, how's the battery life?
How fast? No, like how long, how fast
this is like blowing my mind.
So, so I got, I got a Macbook for work, the one without the, the F keys.
It's got the stupid
whatever. I, you know, it's a funny thing. I, I didn't realize how little I use.
Escape anyway, because
for, for people, old school folks, uh, escape is
really just control, uh,
bracket.
And that's what I use.
And, like, I don't even realize I never touched the real escape key and then, like,
I lose a real escape key.
I'm like, oh, I, I didn't even realize it was gone. Like, everything is fine.
But, uh, anyway,
you can, it, it has USB C for charging, you can charge the thing,
I guess off a five volt USB C it has like magic inside of it to, to charge the battery.
It takes like 100 hours but it can be done.
Which is crazy. That's like madness man. Like madness
standards, right? Standards work.
Anyway, I don't remember how we got there. Uh Right. Oh, let's just keep moving.
Uh Bitcoin, let's fork Bitcoin.
Yeah. Well, I mean,
-- everybody's doing it.
-- I mean, see that's,
yeah, well, you, hey Ethereum did it.
They, you know, did their roll back of a transaction due to the flaw in this theorem,
you know.
Um I mean, that's the, you know,
you know what this really reminds me of is like
like I PV allocation back in the day where like I
actually knew a guy who at the age of like
20 went and got like two or three portable C classes
and then ended up I think he sold them.
But um he basically managed to be an ISP at his house with like basically a dedicated,
you know, Isdn line
and get a couple of
this
isn't what
-- this would be like him.
-- And it's just, well, no, no.
But in the sense of it's just the wild west, like every,
it is to everybody what they want it to be,
but at some point for it to be useful,
it kind of has to steady down and like become stable.
It's not even just that though.
I mean, the fork is an interesting story because what it really comes down to is
the size of a block in Bitcoin is
basically at its limit.
And so it's,
it's like
a megabyte or something.
I know it's, it's too small basically.
And
there's, there's kind of a couple of different ways to look at this.
Now, I don't know how much Bitcoin you've done, but when I run the Bitcoin client
and just run it right,
just where it's essentially part of the
network and it's receiving new information,
whatever. I'm not mining, just running
it consumes like two megabits of traffic constant right up and down,
which is, that's pretty significant in all seriousness.
And so the issue though is that
the people forking
want bigger blocks because obviously
the blocks are so small now and it takes a
really long time for your transactions to be verified correctly.
And, and so
if you're lucky, it can be days depending upon a variety of circumstances.
So anyway, I understand the people who think they need to fork it.
And part of me also understands
the,
the people who think we need to keep this
small because this is like getting out of hand
and it's, this is a tough one, man. I don't know what the answer is going to be.
And I guess
the beauty of this is
the market is going to decide,
right?
Like there's always these people who are like, oh, I'm free market, blah, blah,
blah, you know, until something you don't like happens and then you're like, oh,
we should, we should stop doing that.
Let's go get those people.
And, and
this is one of those instances where like the,
the invisible hand is the only thing
-- that, is there
-- a
-- stupid
-- question though, is it the market at large or is it the
Bitcoin?
Well, the mines,
the market at large, I
mean, let's face it.
Ok.
So that's,
yeah,
it's going to be the miners who basically decide what is
going to happen to the future of Bitcoin in this instance.
And, and I, I mean, I have no idea what it's going to be
but here's what it kind of comes down to is
so the new fork I think is called Bitcoin Unlimited.
And it's currently being viewed as an alt coin.
And if it stays.
So for those of you who don't know, and I know way more about this than I should,
I don't even know why I,
for some reason I decided it'd be fun to learn about
Bitcoin a couple of years back and I bought like,
some mining gear and like, II, I spent way too much time on this.
But anyway, the point is, uh, there's Bitcoin, which is like the granddaddy
and then there's what they call alt coins,
which are things like Ethereum falls into them
and there's pure coin and dog coin and,
like, more than I can even remember.
And anyway, the idea
was
no, they made fun of Kanye with one of them and I forget what it was called.
That, that, that I think, I think that one is gone because I believe they were sued.
But anyway, the, the, the, the point is
these alt coins are viewed as kind of second class citizens
and their value is tied directly to Bitcoin in most instances.
And so if Bitcoin and Limited
is an alt coin, its value will be pegged against Bitcoin property.
Whereas if it's seen as a Bitcoin competitor,
then it's gonna get weird.
So we have a free floating, well, we have the current thing with, you know,
uh currencies globally in the real world.
Like there are company or companies, there are countries sorry
that have literally pegged their currency to the US dollar in some cases
at one time. These are generally not,
we'll say giant economies, well, except one, but I think they fix that.
Uh, you know, and
I, I don't,
I'm really interested to see what's gonna happen to this because I view this as like,
this is the invisible hand
that like this is
economics at its rawest because there is nobody in charge,
right? Nobody is in charge. We're gonna find out how this ends when it ends.
There's nothing else to do. But wait.
And part of me also, I mean, the, the greedy part of me kind of hopes that, uh, Bitcoin
doesn't fork properly because that would dilute the
value of the Bitcoin I have so there.
But anyway, anyway,
yeah.
No, it's,
it's, it's, it's interesting to see
-- true consensus protocols is fascinating.
-- I agree. I agree. It's crazy, man.
You know, it's something I think we lack in the security world is we don't,
I don't think there's any consensus, not even on, like, even, even in terms of like,
like my favorite all time thing is like, what's a security vulnerability?
There's
not even
on
this.
I'm strongly in the no camp
and,
uh, I like the new C so we got, I talk to her all the time about,
I think antivirus is dumb.
She's like antivirus is good. I'm like, we'll just agree to disagree here because
II, I think it's both the most terrible thing on the planet,
but also absolutely necessary for some people.
You know,
-- me, you know,
-- anyway, let's,
there's a certain class of people that if you don't have antivirus on their systems,
you're gonna like, then they only have like days for
weeks
with one more story.
And this one
I love for so many reasons. Do you wanna, why don't you explain it? Kurt?
Which one? The, the next one in line?
Oh God. That thing is terrifying.
It kind
of
makes sense
for.
I have no issue with the events happening here. So
no,
so, ok, well,
depending on how you look at the story,
it's about what I guess we would call dual
-- use technology.
-- So this
guy
start there.
Yeah.
So this, this guy wrote a remote access tool called NANO
core. And ostensibly according to him,
it is, you know, it's supposed to be like a legitimate, you know, remote access tool.
So you can like
remotely administer control, whatever a machine log keystrokes,
look at the log files, blah, blah, blah, blah blah.
And of course,
that's the exact same stuff that like most malware does, right? I mean, you know,
and so he got arrested
and charged, you know,
for essentially being an accomplice for a whole bunch of hackers.
Now, obviously this set the community up in an uproar.
Um and it's a little more subtle than that because apparently he went on to
was it hack or hacker forums.net dot com or something?
Um
to like advertise this thing.
Not
only that.
So here's the only thing that happened is I went to the way II I spent
some time researching this to make sure I wouldn't make a fool of myself when,
when I did this.
But uh
this guy got arrested
and I have no problem with that.
And here's why
is I went to the way back machine and I loaded up the NANO
core dot IO website.
And now
if you're looking to acquire a legitimate remote administration tool,
let's see if you're interested in features such as stable remote surveillance.
OK? No big deal, remote desktop. OK. Fine.
Remote webcam and audio feeds.
What?
Um dude school
and they shouldn't
like, look, look here, we have uh reverse proxy connection, Sox five SOX four,
http ssl, reverse proxy.
When you're doing remote administration, why would you need that?
Um I could sort of, well, so that you can uh send their traffic through you to,
to inspect it
seriously.
Now
your devil is pretty weak here. Uh
So we'll keep going. There is talks about here. It never drops your clients. It's OK.
Fine. Uh
This is clearly
an application with, with nefarious use.
I would say it's definitely towards the dark
and I don't think
this guy
positioned himself in a way that gives him a plausible story that you know,
it is dual use.
Don't get me wrong. It totally is.
But
I don't think in this case
that's how it was being positioned. I think this was clearly meant to be
a
we'll say questionable use
-- device or, or tool.
-- Well, there's a question if
I, you know, I'm reasonably certain,
um,
I
mean, I know certain professions have like, a duty to report
if somebody says they're going to commit a crime. Right.
And, I mean, for example, I know what, like, for example,
uh,
you know, in general, in most jurisdictions, if you go to a gun store
and say I would like to buy a gun and they go, ok, cool. You know, just offhand.
Why are you buying this? And you go because I'm planning to rob a bank
-- reasonably certain they're not supposed to sell you that
-- or
imagine if there was a gun store whose ads were,
you can rob people 20% faster with this gun.
Like,
do you know what
I mean? That's kind of what this is, this is set up as
you can commit crimes much easier with this tool.
And
I
in, in the story, obviously, the lawyer and the, the, the,
the gentleman in question are positioning themselves and themselves as victims
and
in any court case, that's what you do.
You make sure the guy goes out and tells a sob story and explains how he's the victim
and that's just part of the way it works. And in fact, I don't,
so
I understand why this is being done. My one concern,
I don't feel bad.
-- My
-- biggest concern is that it starts to slide potentially, you know,
that dial of
um,
culpability and, you know,
well, guilt
literally, uh you know,
to, because I go, you know, I checked on github
and if you go to that link, um there's like, what was it?
You can't just say that link hurt. No one knows what that means.
Yeah. Oh, so sorry if you go to, ah, here we go. If you go to github
and you plug in reverse shell into the search bar
329 repository results,
you know,
and um
uh
some of these are, you know, quite clearly,
um
legit
and some of these, OK, like, uh let's see, 12345, the fifth result,
Hercules is a special payload generator that can bypass antivirus software.
Interesting.
Yeah. And it's written in go, which is, that's nice.
Uh And then on the flip side,
there's other ones that are like a little bit more legitimate, like say a Python,
reverse DNS shell, you know, that'll send stuff over DNS which,
and I've actually talked about these in the past because you can use them to,
here's the deal though, if I do this
and I put it on
github
and if someone uses my tool to hack, let's say one of the major US parties, right?
Whatever
I would expect a visit from the authorities,
I won't say yes, there can be ex
ex
circumstances here.
But I think fundamentally if you're going to play this game,
you have to be ready for what's going to come.
And I agree like it's, it can be questionable ethically
as to whether this is ok or not. Ok.
It's like, you know, gun manufacturers know their,
their guns kill people but they still make them.
-- But like,
-- well, part of it is, you know, some of these people are doing this for
purposes.
It's a complicated area. I'm not going to disagree with you. But I think in this case
I don't feel bad for this guy.
Well,
it's funny because I remember and this is years ago and I'll have to find the link but
I wanna say University of Calgary, uh part of their comps,
I think they were gonna have a course on writing
and, oh my God, the amount of controversy caused
and of course they went to all sorts of, you know,
like they're going to be air gapped computers, not online, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
And all I can remember thinking was like, who cares?
There's like millions of viruses coming out every year. And this is like a decade ago
that you
think the criminals are gonna go and learn and then
steal grammar's fine,
the whole Satan thing, security analysis tool
to do. And honestly, like, it didn't do anything. All that exciting.
And now those things are
standard commercial products that are actually, in some cases require, like,
doesn't PC I require it.
Don't
know.
I'm pretty sure the payment card industry standard
requires some level of network scanning on a somewhat regular basis.
Yeah, they, they they have continuous monitoring
to a degree which that can be part of it. It's
no, I know. It's, it's complicated anyway.
It's from 2003. I know it's really old.
Uh,
no, Satan is even older than 2003. Man. Satan's from like the nineties
University of Calgary.
-- The
-- virus.
Satan is like 95
than before.
Oh, yeah. No, that's, he got, didn't he get fired? I
remember now. It's been so long.
Yeah.
So, I mean, you know,
and it just makes me laugh now because honestly these things are like,
yeah, I mean, even if you wrote like a really terrible virus,
-- it's like literally a
-- drop in the bucket.
It is. It is. It's,
and, and I guess
we can wrap everything back up into
the one thing we keep talking about over and over and over again is the fact that
all of this stuff put together,
the only solution is to be able to respond quickly to your environment
because we're never gonna write secure code.
We're never gonna have TV. S that aren't terrible, right.
We're never gonna have phone companies that don't want to spy on us.
We're never gonna have antivirus free or, or
vent
that too, right? Virus and antivirus free computers.
It's, it's a matter of if you are an organization that can't move quickly, you, you,
you've already lost.
I mean, that's just the end of the story
period
and I would expand that.
It's not just the organizations that write and create these things,
-- it's the organizations that
-- consume
exactly both ends.
You know, if you can't, if you don't know what's on your network and you can't,
for example, firewall it or,
um,
you know,
somehow deal with it to some degree if it's found to be completely vulnerable,
you know.
Uh, like, for example, let's say the smart TV S are on your corporate network,
you know, maybe they should be on their own V
land that's monitored. Right.
I mean, if you can't do that you've lost
smart
TV.
Of course, there are. Right. I mean,
you know, for video conferencing or whatnot.
So,
I, I think that's the reality is we have to move,
you know? Well, it's think about the real world. Right.
We, we try crime prevention but the reality is
something bad happens down 911, they show up. Hopefully.
Exactly correct. It's all about fast response. It's not about prevention
-- because prevention doesn't work. Oh,
-- great example.
85.
Oh,
good.
We should, maybe next week we'll discuss that. That's like,
well, you know what, we'll discuss it next week.
Hopefully we'll know
more of the aftermath.
Well, it's a pretty simple story and they did arrest him.
I haven't heard they arrested anyone yet. I, I haven't made it that far but all
next week, next week, next week.
All right. Cool.
Everyone. Thank you for listening. I appreciate it.
If you want
links. To any of the crazy stories. You can go to open
source Security podcast.com.
You can hit us up with Pound Os S podcast
on Twitter for the hashtag we have a Facebook group
and we love answering questions,
talk about stuff if you see any cool news stories by all means, send them our way.
Uh
Yeah, if, if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic day.
Thank you everyone for listening. And until next time,
I hope everybody enjoys spring and all the water it brings to their basement.
Goodbye, Kurt.