Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers. So,
-- what's new and exciting
-- summer's back?
-- Did it ever leave?
Kind of we had like kind of a week or two of not great weather.
Ah,
that's because you live in the Arctic circle.
I think the rest of us have been boiling to death for the most part.
Yeah, we got that stuff now. Fun fact about terrible weather.
I went to a Renaissance fair over the weekend
and I cos
played as Waldo,
many people found me and it was like boiling hot and I thought I was going to die.
And then I spent the next day being pretty much,
it felt like I was extremely hungover.
-- I assume I was very dehydrated even though I drank an enormous amount of liquids.
-- I,
that's one of my memories from Schutz
Fest. And uh I lived in a small town in Germany called
Biberach,
which literally means Beaver.
And they have a Schutz Fest, which is the shooting festival
in, uh usually about June. Now it's moved to July.
So it doesn't interfere with school and
they have like a traditional marching band from the schools, like,
like with the drums and the medieval costumes
that just so hot. Like all that medieval costume.
Even the replica stuff is just, it's like six layers of fabric.
Yeah. Yeah. I saw people wearing, like, night
night suits with metal and obviously you can't just wear metal on skin.
You have to put a thing on under it.
And
I just kept thinking I would have died. There's no way I could have done that
-- just even
-- later. Hosen.
Like, I have a pair of nice later hose and, and man, it gets
like,
they're just, they don't breathe.
Yeah. I'm sure I have no doubt.
That's why I went as Waldo because I put on a t-shirt with some stripes on it and a hat
and I'd wear my hat for like, five minutes just for pictures and stuff.
And then I was like, I'm going to pass out. I take this hat off.
Yeah. And, yeah. Yeah, I couldn't do it.
Yeah. No, people really do. Underestimate. It's, I also find it's,
it's heat plus the sun. I always underestimate that.
Yeah.
Well, well,
so something I actually learned also over the weekend I
didn't realize is when the temperature is measured for the weather
that's measured in the shade.
-- So when you're in the sun it's probably like 20 plus degrees
-- hotter.
Well, I mean, again, we did the math.
Remember I have those solar heaters from my pool. They're 2 ft by 10 ft.
-- There's six of them. So that's 100 and 20 square feet.
-- I thought you lived in Canada.
-- Should you be using meters?
-- No, because we buy stuff from America
anyway. So it's 100 and 20 square feet
and it raises the temperature of my pool by about 1 to 2
°C per hour. It's a 9000 L.
So that's basically
not about 18 million calories an hour coming from 100 and 20 square feet.
Right.
You do the math in, in a single afternoon, if that,
that's enough calories to feed a human for their entire life.
How many hamburgers is that like all of them?
But the point is like, I know the sun is strong and carries a lot of energy.
But, you know, now that I'm actually
harnessing the power of the sun to heat my little pool, it's like holy cow, like two
°C an hour, 9000 L of water.
It's a
lot of heat.
It's a,
and, and, and that is not a super efficient system.
Like, it's just black plastic with water running through it.
Yeah, you're probably only capturing like, 10 or 20% of the energy.
Now, I wonder anyway, we, we have a topic, our topic is not pools or the sun.
Well, it's like that. It's data,
it's
-- data.
-- It actually, it is. It is. Ok. It's
valy related. All right. So, let me, let me kick this off. There was a tweet
that I saw
shortly after we recorded the last episode
and I really like this. It's from uh the user name that says Brian in Pittsburgh.
It says the elephant in the room is that we do not have controls, effectiveness,
data controls being like security controls.
Right. Livingston said this is quoting an article
we have shared understanding of what good practices are.
I agree with that,
but the data is yet to come in as to which
ones are bloodletting and leeches and which ones are penicillin.
And I love this. I really like this topic because I have a background in data.
And
I mean, you know, me, like
people get sick of having me say, like, show me your data, show me your data,
-- show
-- me
-- your
data. We don't have any data and we're embarrassed
and that's why people get sick.
But anyway, so I wanted to tie that
then into while I was doing my research for the show that there
were a couple historical events that came to mind around bloodletting and Lee
specifically.
And I,
I actually came across the uh an article written called the
six most common type of bias when working with data.
And I thought this is really good and we should go through some of this
and
it, it's just six things that shouldn't.
Well, I should, I say it shouldn't take us long. We'll see
we don't have a timer right now, but
we'll do our best.
Uh So anyway, let's just let's just start the list.
I think this is a good conversation. Number one is confirmation bias,
right?
And this is the one where I'll just give an example of confirmation bias,
which is where we kind of
we see things we want to see, I guess is how I would describe it.
But like here's, here's our example.
I saw it on Facebook. It was shared by John, right?
Sound familiar social media, blah, blah, blah
and social media obviously is amplifying
the things we want to see.
And so I think social media is literally confirmation bias.
Well and not just that but like social media
is literally amplifying the stuff that you look at.
Like a great example is youtube.
I hate the youtube algorithm because I will click on one video where I'm like, oh,
that looks kind of interesting.
And then it's like, no, I really didn't want to spend the next 17 hours looking at,
you know, listening to air traffic control videos.
I just was curious about this one.
Can you
OK. Do I unlike this video? Don't show me this channel. Like
I accidentally uh every time I accidentally click on a movie preview
and then my
thing is flooded and it's like
I'm antisocial, I don't go to the movies.
I just want to see like one movie preview every four months
mostly for my kids. That's right. Related to this is the batter meh
effect.
Which one is that it's the difference between something actually happening
a lot and something you're starting to detect a lot.
-- Like when you buy a new car and you see them everywhere.
-- Exactly. Right.
That's exactly it.
What is a security example
of confirmation bias?
Oh, you know, two fa works
and it does because here I'll tell you a story.
We've rolled now rolled out hard work E two fa across the CS A and we've had zero hacks.
Now,
let's ignore the fact we had zero hacks that we knew
of before we rolled out the two fa you know,
I,
I'm sure the two fa that, you know, the anti tiger rock is working.
-- All right,
-- we're gonna keep going.
Uh, number two on the list is selection bias. This is my absolute favorite one.
And I think this one exemplifies security perfectly. And selection bias is when
you just have a, a sample, obviously, you can't sample everything.
So you have to sample a subset.
And what happens is oftentimes you'll, you'll accidentally select a
very small subset of something that then skews in one direction or another.
It's not the problem that it's a small subset because you can interview like
what is it like 2000 adults in America and actually get a reasonably representative
opinion of on something.
So, an example of a security selection bias is
I'm asking about password security.
And for example, I'm not even aware of another security measure.
-- Somebody might be using.
-- I have a better one.
I, I would say, let's say I'm doing a survey
and I say,
would you use a two factor token?
And if I survey only security people I'm gonna get like, probably 80 plus percent.
Yes.
But if I survey
the overall population, I suspect you're gonna get like 20%.
-- Yes,
-- you're
-- gonna
-- get about 10%. That actually know what it is. 10%.
That will just say yes. No,
that's fair. Remember that Google video of like, what is the address bar? They went
and interviewing people like what is this thing here?
And most people don't know. And that's like, why would they like it drives me nuts.
So people make such a big deal out of this.
And I'm like, well on mobile,
it doesn't even show it to me by default unless I like look for it.
Tech in general
suffers from selection bias because we think everyone knows what we know
and they don't. That's just the reality of it. All right. Let's keep going.
Number three historical bi.
This is one of my favorites where we kind of use the
things that happened in the past to kind of dictate what we do today.
And, and I'll read the example because I think this is really good. It says in
2013 neural network models transformed the way machines, blah blah, blah,
blah technology allows they they giant sets of written texts, Wikipedia,
Google news, reddit, whatever, right?
And
when you source the
text from a data set,
you end up amplifying a bias that's contained in that data set, right?
So for example, if you, if you train
on the example they give here is machine learning model.
Train at Wikipedia produce gender bias analogies like man, doctor, woman, nurse,
man, commander, woman school teacher, things like that.
And that's where the historical biases
of, of society, right?
Because I mean, I I don't like putting people in these buckets.
-- But if you look historically, that's what happened.
-- Yeah, of course.
I mean, there's, you know, all these stories about a
male nurse. Like what
I think we can see some of this insecurity
and especially in technology because if you look at
some of the old, old just way we did things like for example, I bet you if you took data
and you had I PV four and I PV six data sets,
the I PV four data set is going to vastly outweigh the I PV
six data set just because I PV six was barely used a decade ago.
You know,
I don't want to say it's still barely used, but it's
you're often not exposed.
Like there's huge I PV six networks sitting behind 6 to 4 carrier grade
N A
like every mobile phone it's getting better.
But on the flip side too I don't actually want my mobile phone on the proper internet.
I want to use it as a client only. So I'm actually ok with that, you know, I don't want
real internet for my phone.
And again, that comes back to it, I think it gets even more subtle and it's,
it's not just the data, but it's what we even think of as data.
So, like a great example of this is,
I see people we don't actually really have
a proper definition of what is a vulnerability.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, that's a great one too.
How are we supposed to measure vulnerabilities in software? Oh, wait,
could you define software for me? Josh, I'm serious.
Can you, like in the next 10 words, define software for me,
I would define software in the same way
they define pornography back in the early days.
I can't tell you what it is. It is, but I know it when I see it.
Yeah, exactly. Right.
Like, OK, well, software software. What about hardware?
Well, hardware runs software. OK. What about like business processes?
Well, that kind of software, it's like it's instructions for humans to follow.
Does it have to be a computation machine? Because, well, remember we used to call
humans used to be what we called computers,
you know.
So if we can't even define the word software and vulnerability correctly,
how are we supposed to measure vulnerabilities in software?
All right. That's a whole another conversation.
And we're not going to talk about that today because we have finite time.
If you start going down these rabbit holes, it, it gets worse.
Right. Well, let's, let's go to the next favorite one. Survivorship Bias. Right.
This is kind of my favorite one here is like, oh,
we didn't wear seat belts when I was a kid and I turned out fine.
Well, yes, you did.
But the, you know,
millions of other people who died in horrific car accidents did not.
And I think we see this, especially in the world of security where
it's like, oh, I didn't run antivirus. I'm fine.
And like, ok,
how many small and medium businesses are getting
-- sacked by cyberattacks?
-- We don't
know,
we know it's more than zero and probably less than 100%
somewhere in there.
-- Right.
-- Like,
what an enlightening statistic Kurt. Thank you.
But at least I'm willing to admit my ignorance.
Most people I read reports all the time that, like, talk about
something that's really hard to measure and only kind of pops up or bubbles up.
-- Like, how many cyber attacks don't even get noticed.
-- I mean, right.
Like, so one of my favorites here is
when I was younger I would tell people.
Well, I've never, I've ever been hacked now that I'm older.
I think I'm not saying this out loud ever because, like, it won't be true someday.
I also don't want to be a target but more importantly is it's far more likely
that I just haven't noticed I've been hacked. Right.
But I feel like I was special because I could say, oh, it didn't happen to me.
This is actually what I liked about ransomware is
all of a sudden all these attacks were public,
especially the bigger ones, you know, where they're going to release the data.
And we actually started to, like,
I suspect prior to ransomware there was probably
about as much shenanigans going on. It just we didn't know.
Yeah. Right.
Well, in, in ransomware, it's just so in your face you can't,
you can't pretend it didn't happen.
I mean, how many, how many of us don't? No one needs to tell me this for sure.
But like how many of us work somewhere? We're like something got popped.
We were like,
we'll just turn that off and pretend everything's fine
and we did like no other forensic work.
We
stuck our fingers in our ears.
I was like, everything is awesome.
Yeah.
-- For us
-- it's like hoof and mouth disease. Shoot shovel Barry. We fix the problem.
We're not going to talk about it anymore.
Yeah. Yeah. Anyway, anyway. All right. All right. We'll keep going here.
Uh Number five says availability bias.
This one, I actually like a lot.
This one is explained as.
Have you ever find yourself wondering if crime has increased in your neighborhood?
Because you've been, you've seen a broken car window
right where you see,
like these little clues and this one is the one I want to talk about the most.
And I've been rushing us to get here
because this particular one availability bias, like
heartbleed log for Jay,
whatever the hype Du Jour
is going on right now is the most important
and serious security event that has ever happened.
And then in six months we can't remember the name of it.
No, that's it. Yep. I mean,
I had to fill out so many stupid surveys of like,
how are you dealing with Lawford Chain?
My answer is like we're not because we don't Java.
No, that's like that's my response. Like we don't Java.
I have a, a better example of this is if you look at like the,
the usage and interest in certain security tools during log for J,
like if you look at the uh like in, in good public data source is the github
stars graph
of Sift and Gripe, right?
Which are sift creates s bombs, gripes, cancer vulnerabilities.
And obviously you can imagine there was enormous interest
in these tools during Lock Jake because it was
uh Sift did a really good job of like digging into
the jars to find log for J hidden in there.
And
obviously, like if you look at the Get up Stars graph,
it takes an enormous jump during log
for J and I'll put a link in the show now.
So it's a really cool uh website that graphs this for you.
So it's got this huge jump, right?
And then obviously after a little while it tapers
off and just turns into normal growth again.
And I mean, this is exactly it, right.
This is,
this is literally an example of availability bias where all of a sudden it's like,
oh my goodness, it's super important.
And obviously, if everyone kept thinking this mattered,
the graph would continue up like a rocket ship,
but that's not what's going to happen because we think
it's important and then it ends and then we're like,
eh, whatever next thing.
Well, and that's part of it too is. And next thing like covid's important. Well,
now we got monkeypox.
Fantastic.
Oh my God.
Like,
yes,
I,
I'm seriously looking at buying long sleeve shirts and
pants and not wearing shorts and short sleeve shirts.
Like I, I, what am I
-- anyway?
-- You know,
the problem is we also don't have any way to weight
the data.
Yeah, I think that's part of it is we, we look at all this and it's very difficult to say
what is the larger trend? Well, and I think especially insecurity.
Does this matter to you,
let alone, does this matter to the world?
And we can't even really answer. Does this matter to you very well?
Because based on some of those survey questions, I got like,
they clearly don't like they're not doing, you know,
they don't know what's going on.
-- They literally were asking and,
-- and
I don't think anyone knew what was going on.
I mean, that's kind of part of how this works, right?
It
is one of the challenges when you don't have data, you end up with nothing but biases.
I mean, I would argue that we,
we have security data, we have security biases for the most part.
And I think things like log for J show that
well, and a great example is the data we do have tends to be controlled by companies,
some of which don't want there to be security data.
So they have a, you know, a very small number of vulnerabilities,
even though they have a lot of patches that they say like install now or else.
Yep. That's right. That's right.
-- Oops,
-- it's, it's complicated for sure, for sure. I will say.
So I know we're, we complain a lot on this show,
but I do feel like this is starting to get a little better.
I think there is more
the fact that we're recognizing this is the first step and we
have a long way to go before we can fix it.
But just people acknowledging this,
I feel like is really important and I can't underestimate that.
Well, I think to be blunt, we're still at the frame or the uh the stage of
it's like, what's the name, what's the name?
And I'm going to butcher this name. I apologize.
Ignaz Semmelweis who, you know,
was the guy that pioneered hand washing for doctors and was ridiculed and you know.
Yeah.
Yeah. We're kind of still at that stage.
We are uh actually my other favorite example of that I put in the show notes and I was,
we were going to get to this at the end was
Jon Snow
and the cholera epidemic in London,
which the guy's name is actually Jon Snow.
And I remember I accidentally learned of this guy on a documentary during the
Game of Thrones phenomenon before it was like ground into the dirt and murdered.
But
I was like, oh, that's funny, Jon Snow.
But anyway, like what it came down to this guy used data to figure out
-- C was coming from a
-- pump. Well, not just data but visualization of data.
-- That was, that
-- he did,
he did a map. It was amazing.
He did, he made a map and he created quadrants and he figured out like,
where are people getting sick?
Like what is the central point of all this sickness?
-- And
-- he went to like every house and asked where they got their water. And
that's right.
He did research while the, the scientists and I'm putting scientists in there
said it was, what was it? It was poisonous air or something.
It was no ill humors
or something like that. I
forgot
like
they made that up. That wasn't a thing.
Like my favorite is they invented radio and they're like
ether.
Right. Because you can't transmit a wave without a medium
and electricity doesn't move through air.
Because if you've ever held, like, you know,
you can spark two wires together and the electricity will go through
a little bit of air but not a lot of air.
So, obviously,
well,
you know, radio waves go through either.
Well, no, it's more complicated than that, but,
like, they just made stuff up.
I
mean,
well, ok, look, however, I will say
if you look at the history of science making crap up is generally step less,
but I think you also need to be aware that making crap up isn't where you stop.
Like you need to go test the hypothesis
and then figure out what's going on and, and when Ether was defined,
a lot of experiments happened that disproved it even though everyone was certain,
it's real.
It's like it's the dark matter of our day, right? Like
some day it's all strings, we'll be like, oh ha ha.
Remember we thought dark matter was real and it was just Cheerios or something.
And we're like, oh, yes.
Anyway. All right, one more, one more. And then we'll move on
number six outlier bias.
Uh This one is averages are a great place to hide uncomfortable truths.
And I like this. So the example of outlier bias is,
let's say you are tracking here.
I'm just gonna read this because this is a really good explanation.
It says the start up wants to be sure
that their marketing site feels quick and responsive.
They decide to track their average latency time to
make sure that their site continues to load quickly.
After a few months of roughly consistent average latency values,
they start to see decline in engagement on some of their most important pages.
When they investigate
further, they realized that the latency on those pages has skyrocketed,
the average latency time site wide continued to paint a rosy image.
But those particular pages had outliers that obviously were bad.
That's why things like 99th percentile and 95th
percentile are so critical and also your maximum.
We had a page that took 16 seconds to render. And I'm like,
hey, how did that even happen? Like how did it not get killed and just not render
like seriously, I'm like,
from what I know of our stack that just shouldn't be possible.
Right? Well, something happened.
So yeah, it was like a cosmic glitch, but I'm like 16 seconds and
like the client still waited like wow.
-- Uh
-- I waited a long time when it's something I want.
Well, no, no, I mean like physical client, not you.
-- I don't care about the human meat
-- bake. Oh man, no, web browsers wait like forever.
It's terrible. How bad.
So I, I have a great, I have a good example of this actually.
So when I was at elastic, elastic has
observable
and application, performance monitoring capabilities.
And I didn't understand this before I, I learned from the A PM and observable people.
So what you really want to do
is you want to throw out the average,
like in the bell curve, throw out the middle,
you want to look at the things on the two edges.
You wanna look at the things that are being serviced like
ridiculously fast because that's almost definitely some sort of weird bug.
And you want to look at the things that are being really, really, really slow
because those are the places that the interesting stuff is happening.
And I feel like in the world of security,
it's kind of a similar idea where
we have all this data, we can look at these bell curves and, and throw away the middle,
right?
Like what are on the edges and what are the
things we can do there that can be effective?
-- Well,
-- a perfect example, things with a 0.0 CV SS score, huh?
-- Well, those are mostly from Oracle, right?
-- And so like, what's the deal, you know?
Well, so the reason Oracle does that actually,
I know this because I've talked to them about it.
They obviously there's lots of vulnerability management systems in
the world and usually it's giant companies running them.
And Oracle is a favorite
vendor of giant companies
and so
they would release advisories and they wouldn't assign CV SS scores and then
the vulnerability management tools would pick up their advisories and be like,
oh my goodness, they oracle just fixed a critical issue.
You know, everyone sounded an alarm
and it's just that the thing they ship contains that package
and they might not be using it.
And so now they just give it a 0.0 that says, yes, we ship it.
No, we don't use it, like, stop bothering us.
Totally. Fair.
-- Yeah,
-- I think it's brilliant. Like I love
it.
I kind of wish we had done more of that at Red Hat because there was so much of that,
this problem has existed for a long time.
And I would argue this is one of those outliers, right? Like this is
this falls under the outlier bias category I think.
And this is like what vex is meant to do, right?
The vulnerability exchange format where you can
start specifying like this doesn't affect me
for this reason or this isn't as severe as it's noted for this reason.
And that's like that's a powerful thing.
So now we can kind of pull some of these edge cases into the middle once
we have some of this data and now we can look at the new edge cases,
right? Because there's going to be new things.
I feel like part of the challenge is is data visualization is hard to begin with,
right?
Like I have a stack of books up there, the Tufty books
and data visualization when you have good data is hard data visualization
and understanding it when you have bad data is basically impossible.
-- And I suspect
-- not just that
if you have a malicious
entity
creating the day because what's the Mark Twain quote lies,
damned lies and statistics, right?
Like you can use statistics to lie if you know what you're doing.
-- Well,
-- and I was about to say,
like we can use the statistics to basically make a warm comfy Sainty
blanket. That's like
-- things are not great, but they're ok. Right. That
-- too. Yeah. II,
I mean, I've seen that many times.
I mean,
-- that's like the Enron story is that
-- the average
time a vendor needs to respond to security events.
Well, but wait like half of these are totally minor and they closed them out in a day
which pulls down, you know, their, their 95th percentile
where it's like, oh yeah, it took us like seven years to fix log for Jay. But
yeah, I mean, that's,
that's the average again, right?
When we're, we're hiding in the average 99% of things I respond to.
I respond to in an hour.
I want to end with a tweet from Bob Lord who is uh he was the what?
-- So of the DNC, the Democratic National Committee
-- that has got to be not a fun job.
I can't imagine that job, but that's another story.
So anyway, so the, the FTC,
the United States Federal Trade Commission puts out a tweet that says using public
Wi Fi if the network isn't secure and you log into an unencrypted site,
other users on the network and see what you see and send,
they could hijack your session and log in as you learn how to protect yourself.
And then it's a link to some terrible document.
And then Bob replies,
what exactly are modern browsers doing to create a
condition so unsafe that you have to warn consumers,
what do the browser makers have to change for browsers
to be safe by design and safe by default,
such that you can retire this advice?
Is there a punch list? We can
-- you
-- fun fact, Google actually fixed this for us.
What was it two summers ago when they changed their? So I'd argue it's fixed now.
Yeah. Well, no, what happened is Google changed like they do this rejiggering.
I forget there's like a name for this event where they rejigger,
how they do their search engine optimization rankings.
And two summers ago they made HTTP S matter
and guess what happened within about three months.
Let's, well,
now let's encrypt was key to that
without let's encrypt that couldn't have happened.
Let's encrypt enabled it. But
here's the thing, this is what frustrates me about security. We always,
there's a,
a supply side and a demand side and people really only ever talk about the supply
side because the demand side is boiling the ocean and we've given up on that.
These are all biases, right?
Like it's easy for my confirmation bias on the,
on the supply side because that's where me and my friends like.
But people forget that Google can boil the ocean by oh,
guess what our web browser is now instead of saying
secure is going to say
insecure, that's
all
crap. I need to go fix my website right now,
you know, or oh, my search engine rankings are going to drop like a stone.
If I don't do http S
we're like this is now
a project
and that's the thing is
there are some vendors like
Apple is a good example of having boiled the
o for a few things. Apple has pushed a few standards forwards
but
yeah, like nobody else could have really done that.
Cool.
So between Microsoft Apple Google, you know, with them doing the, the,
the Fido alliance and all that stuff like, yeah,
Fido is finally going to come here because the the demand side will happen.
And that's the thing that always drove me nuts is
if there is demand for something,
there will be a supply.
My case in point being like the global illegal drug trade, right?
This stuff is crazy illegal
in a lot of countries and yet.
Well,
yeah,
you know, yeah,
it amuses me when governments think the solution to a problem is to outlaw it.
Like no, you just made a new problem now instead of the one you just outlawed,
we legalized it and, you know,
there's a tax stamp on it.
Now, when you buy marijuana in Canada and as far as I can tell, nothing changed
of drug enforcement officers went down.
-- We were
-- honestly,
we kind of haven't been doing that for the last three or four decades.
Well,
-- there you go. Then
-- this is a good example of like everything is HTTP S
oh,
ok.
Like the
like, I don't care how insecure the network you use is if it's HTTP S set up properly,
if the attacker can get in there, there are state
-- level actor.
-- But now remember too,
so I think there's some other pieces to this. This is historical bias.
I think that the FTC put together because if you look back 1020 years ago,
wifi was new
and not only that a lot of the protocols on the internet were unencrypted.
You know, you had SMTP, you'd have IRC you'd connect to, you connect to FTP site,
you connect to
mail server. Like none of this stuff was encrypted.
It used to be a vendor choice criteria at the CS A is do they do HTTP S like by default,
that used to be a big deal 10 years ago. And now, of course, it's like,
I
-- don't think I could even find a real, but
-- the point is
the world has gone to HTTP S for everything. And so like literally all of our
all of our email.
Now, all of our communications, all of our,
this freaking podcast is being recorded over http, s like,
it's just,
it's ubiquitous whereas a decade ago it wasn't and there were lots of unencrypted
protocols.
It's funny you mentioned email specifically because
I was actually looking at our logs.
We have a log for how much encrypted and unencrypted email we get and receive
at the CS A and this is encrypted and encrypted at the network level.
-- Right.
-- Right. Like server to server, you're talking, right.
So Google to
whatever else.
-- And it's like, well, over 95%.
-- Oh, really? It's that high.
I wouldn't have expected it to be that high. But that's fantastic.
You can immediately knock out all the major providers like outlook.com,
gmail.com, hotmail.com. Right. They're all, they're all encrypted,
all the real corporate stuff.
Like if you're a corporation with more than 100
people and your email server is not encrypted like
you need new it people.
Like, I'm sorry, there's no nice way to say it.
And as far as I can tell,
we're just kind of dealing with the dribs and drabs of people
who run their own mail servers that haven't set up encryption.
Alright. We're, we're running out of time.
So I, I think I, I love this idea and this is something I'll think about now for a while,
but I,
I think one of our challenges as a security industry is just to start to start
recognizing we have bias to start collecting data
and to start doing something with the data.
And I don't think we're there yet. I think we still make up a lot of crap.
And this is one of my complaints.
It gives me hope that people are starting
to ask questions and people are starting to recognize
that
a lot of what we do
-- isn't necessarily right.
-- Well, and that's the thing.
I, I'm ok with people making up stuff but don't pretend it's correct.
I mean, you know what, I'm ok. II, I think I agree with that.
Like I'm now firmly at the point where I'm making stuff.
Like I literally am building these threat models because I don't have data.
But if I have a threat model,
at least I have something I can poke with a stick and visually show to people
and, and also more importantly not to make sure we're talking about the same thing.
Yeah, I, I think that's a good point too.
The CWE board, we just apparently
rejiggered our definition of vulnerability and weakness that, I mean, that's,
that seems kind of critical for something
that's called the common weakness enumeration.
Wait, the CWE board redefined vulnerability.
Well,
they have a glossary where they define it
and we changed the definition to be actually,
in my opinion a lot better.
-- And does this now line up with other
-- before it specifically mentioned like
that it had like vulnerabilities had to be in software.
And it's like, well, what about services?
OK.
So for example, here's the current definition,
vulnerability in occurrence of a weakness or
multiple weaknesses within a product in which the
weakness can be used by a party to cause the product to modify our access,
unintended data into a proper execution
or perform incorrect actions that were not specifically
granted to the party who uses the weakness.
OK. Well, product, what about services?
The focus there is product,
right? And so there's that problem with it.
But then there's also to modify our access, unintended data, interrupt,
proper execution or performing correct actions
that leaves a whole host of shenanigans unlisted
like,
right? And so it's just, it's a bad definition of the word vulnerability.
I agree, you know, and then we have weakness,
which sort of Venn diagram overlaps a bit with it.
But
again, it talks about a type of
and first of all, a weakness, a mistake.
Well, no, they could be intentional backdoors but ignoring that
improper conditions could contribute to the
improper conditions while they may not be proper,
could contribute to the introduction of vulnerabilities within that product.
Again, product not service.
This term applies to mistakes regardless of whether they occur
in implementation design or other phases of product life cycle.
Again, mistake.
-- No, these things aren't always mistakes like weaknesses back doors.
-- OK?
Now you say that
I remember I, I I'll have to see if it's on a public list or something.
But I remember at one point there was someone asked a question, like,
should backdoors get Cwes?
And Iii, I vaguely recall being like, yes, yes, they should.
And a whole bunch of other people, like, oh, no, those don't get Cwes at all.
Like backdoors aren't weaknesses CV. S you mean?
No, it was,
it was ac we question but I know cbes also don't sign the back doors and this was,
this was all related.
It was part of the miter soup.
And I remember being like, who cares if it's intentional?
I
-- don't want
-- it, do I It's like, can an attacker use this?
And is it actionable data that I can actually make use of? Yes. Yes.
Then give me the damn data.
II
I remember that I was just like
I was shaking my head like I don't even want to be on
this planet anymore after that one because it was like this just,
this is,
this is such a pedantic argument
-- based on a historical bias that like
-- it's
again,
this is one of the reasons I quit the CV board.
It was just, I was tired of sitting in the swamp
-- anyway.
-- All right, we, we should, we should end this one, I guess. Uh
Yeah. III I
love these kind of conversations, man. I think it's fun to talk about data.
I think it's fun to learn new things about data and,
and now I have to think about
what I can do with this list because I have a strong suspicion I
could get a couple of conference talks and blog posts out of this.
You know, I, I just,
what always gets me is when I used to go to RS A is every year was a different flavor.
Like one, like I remember I'm old enough to remember when it went from like
from firewalls and state firewalls to intrusion
detection.
And then the next year was intrusion
prevention.
And I'm like, yeah, because if we can detect this stuff can't, should we be
dunking the connection and like blocking it? Like
that seems self evident.
You know,
that's another
and, and I love this every year. It's like this flavor Du
Jour of Rs A, you know, what was it? Three years ago? It was machine learning.
I don't, how did that pan out for us? I forgot
it's doing great. I mean, every machine learning is awesome.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, I assume this year is going to be supply chain. Actually.
You know what makes me sad? I was thinking about this this morning
we did an episode on self-driving cars a couple of
years ago and how they're going to revolutionize the world.
And I feel like the self driving car research,
like it's an upside down you where like it was like, it started getting better.
We're like, oh my goodness, it's so close and now we're like, oh, crap.
Like we can't even get this thing to stop running into stuff
like that.
You know,
that recent testing video where the Tesla car just slams over the fake child just,
I didn't even try to stop.
Oh, I know my, my kids sent me that and I was like, uh,
anyway,
yy,
but someday, someday I, I want to,
I, I hope I, I want the day to come when I never drive a car again.
And I don't mean like getting on the train because I love that too.
But I live in America where our trains are terrible.
So my, my hold out now is
self driving cars.
But anyway, anyway, all right, I'm going to call this one. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
our
security podcast.com. Head up the show,
Not Su
Podos
Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the