Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and getting one day older every day with the rest of us, Josh Pressers.
I do age
at the time of t equals one second per second.
-- Maybe
-- you should try going faster.
That is
true.
I remember, I, I think I read this on Reddit or something one time
about how
building a time machine that goes forward in time is quite easy to do actually.
And
so I remember,
I, I think it was my, when my kids were young,
it was very dad joke of let's build the time machine and they're like, oh,
how exciting.
And I'm like, yes,
our time machine will go forward in time at a rate of one second per second.
It
is a cardboard box
and then they were less impressed.
Yeah.
So the topic this week is everybody is getting older and especially open source.
People are getting older.
Yes, there's a news story that was, I think it, it showed up to me
on,
but it's called what the Graying of Open Source. It's on the register
and, and SJVN wrote it. Who's like a, a
ironically, a gray beard news journalist at this point.
Well, who else is going to do it?
I don't know. That's a good question. See, that's part of the challenge, right?
Is like
when it comes to being a domain specific knowledge expert, statistically,
it's going to be the older people,
I
guess.
-- I, so here's the thing,
-- statistically I'm saying,
statistically obviously there's outliers.
You have young chess grandmasters who know everything there
is to know about opening theory or statistically,
if you want somebody to have a lot of knowledge,
well,
to get that knowledge requires a really brutal combination of time and effort.
I don't think that's the point of this discussion or, or story though. So let me read
this
in particular. I'm just going to read the opening
from, from the story.
It says a youth and open source panel was
held at the United Nation open source program office
OS
O for good conference.
Now, the, the UN
proceedings
are all.
There is a video of it. I had it open and I watched it. I'll see if I can find it.
I'll put it in the show notes. But anyway, so the
opo for good conference in the UN building in Manhattan,
there is only one little problem with it to quote ruth
IKEA,
I'm sorry for probably mispronouncing your last name. A
young Nigerian open source project manager.
We need more young people here because I see a lot of old people here
like
that.
I'm staring at an old person.
I am also staring at myself and you. So two old people in my window. But look, yes.
And,
and so this is something I have done more thinking
about since reading this story than is probably healthy.
And there have been a bunch of threads on Mastodon. I've looked at
mhm.
Toma De Pierre had a really good comment where he basically pointed out that look,
you know, a lot of young people don't have time or money
to work on something like open source. It's a very privileged thing to get to do
well to,
to basically be a for most of the world to basically be able to
do any activity that doesn't directly put food in your mouth is a luxury
and, and not only that but an activity that requires a computer and internet and a
little bit of knowledge about programming and
things like that. Like that's already the the bar to entry now is quite high.
Well, and I think there's more pieces to this than even that.
You, you can say we need more young people in open
source. But
I
don't
know if that's the right thing to say
like, what is the problem? Right?
You can say the problem is there aren't enough young people in open source
and
maybe there isn't, let's say there isn't, let's say that's an issue.
So now we have to think about why is that is it because the old people won't leave?
Is it because young people don't care?
Is it because young people don't have the resources to do this?
They're, they're like millions of guesses.
We were talking about this and I invented the word invite
ability
and looking at some open source projects, they are very inviting like they are,
you know, hey, um here's how you can participate in their read me.
Like they literally say, like you can go do this or that or whatever or
curl is a great example.
Like every time there's a new committer, he celebrates it on Mastodon.
Yes. Right. Yes.
So I think I,
I think the problem is there's probably about 50 to 100 factors in total here
that are all,
some of them are tightly coupled and some of them are not coupled at all
or,
and like essentially some of them correlate but are
not causative and some of them are highly causative,
right?
And so like to throw a technical one,
a lot of software has been written
a lot of very complicated software. A lot of it's been enhanced and grown
and it's, it's not easy anymore.
Like we've, we've written all the easy software kind of
also not fun.
So this is something I was thinking about actually is let's pick
on XZ just because it's top of mind for many people,
right?
If I was a new person looking to do something I found interesting I
have a suspicion I would not land on something like the XZ project.
I think that's a great example because there are literally a handful of
people in the world that are probably very excited about compression algorithms.
Like there are competitions and there are,
there's actually a pretty solid movement here
and it's from within that community that,
well,
that's basically your pool of possible
applicants because it is highly specialized.
Here's where I think what you bring up is
is I think exactly it.
I'm a new person.
I'm doing
compression algorithm research.
Do I want to go and dig around in someone else's 30 year old C code
and try to maintain it?
Or would I rather do my own thing? Except
if I try to do my own thing,
no one's gonna use it because they never heard of me and there's already this other
library and they're gonna yell at me and tell me I shouldn't be doing it.
-- Yeah,
-- you're doing it wrong. It's a bad library. You blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Right.
-- Right.
-- And I have a suspicion. Part of this story
is that if I'm a like when you and I were getting into open source, it was all brand new,
everything was new. Every, it was Greenfield
everywhere we talk about getting young people involved in open source.
But what we really mean in many of these
conversations is we want young people to take over maintenance
of this thing
that is probably poorly written
and badly documented and hard to work with
because we're worried that the current person working
on it who is overworked and underpaid and
everything
like
because they might stop someday.
And you know what this feels like to me,
there is a concept in enterprise software called Sustaining Engineering
where you have a piece of enterprise software and you
have a bunch of developers working on the next version,
but you have companies paying you quite a lot
of money often to maintain a certain version,
right?
And so you hire a sustaining engineering group whose only job
is keeping the old version alive
and nobody wants that job. Like if you hire someone into your se group,
they're there to hopefully move into the development group, generally speaking,
right?
Like it is not fun, it's usually terrible work.
And the only way anyone is going to do it is if you pay them often a lot of money,
the on ramp to coming into a lot of
things. Now, a lot of technology is quite steep.
And as a young person,
do you want to go on a steep on ramp to something that is maybe not dead but is a dead end.
Like pearl, like pearls, not dead, it'll never die just like
coal, just like FORTRAN, they'll always be around,
but they're kind of dead ends in the
sense of like they're not growing significantly.
-- Ok? I have another way to think about this.
-- Well, but my point is
I want to get on a steep,
on ramp to something that is a dead end or something that's new and interesting.
-- Well,
-- everyone wants new and interesting. Like, that's just human condition.
How many of us have 700 unfinished projects in our workshop areas
because we started it and then we decided to start
something new because it was more shiny and interesting.
Right. Like it's, it's human nature. It's very, it's very common to do that.
Now when we were young,
when open source was young,
a lot of the efforts going on were to create a functional computer,
right?
Linux didn't work very well.
We needed encryption libraries, we needed compression libraries,
we needed graphics libraries.
I think the interest in a lot of these tools was to just get a functional computer.
We're past the point of needing functions, computers.
It was because like some of the open source I participated in was scratching my
itch of like I needed this to work or I needed this to function.
So literally
to have a working computer,
it had to be done. Now it's
well, it's good enough, right?
So here's the other piece of this.
I think that isn't, was not discussed anywhere I've seen
and I ignoring the
young people don't have it. It's like the Maslow hierarchy of needs, right?
Like open source is way at the top. Yeah.
Now
there are a lot of things going on in the world of tech and humans, right?
Like one of my favorite examples
is if you look at the world of like Twitch streaming and video games,
the mods people are creating
the, the hacks they're making around video games. Like I, I have a great example.
There,
there's two things that I've been playing that have consumed the entirety
of my video game experience for probably the last three months.
What is called a super metroid Zelda Randomizer.
And the second is a super metroid map randomizer.
What people have done
is these, these random folks, they are not old people mind you that have done this.
They have taken these old video games
and they have hacked them up
and they've created like there, there's, there's websites I will put, I, no,
I'm not putting links to the websites.
I don't want them to get taken down by Nintendo,
but
look it up,
figure it out.
But
like the thing is you basically, I,
I say I want to play this game that has these
rules and you can click all kinds of buttons that are
like these are the tricks I'm capable of doing in the
game because you watch like the really good players do these things
like wall climb versus no wall climb or jump, sorry, wall jump,
wall jump. Yeah, I wish I can do that. You should do the crap these other people can do.
It's amazing. But anyway. Right.
And I can
set it up to my skill level because I'm bad and I, I just like playing it.
Like, I'm not playing in tournaments or anything like that.
But the point is there is a ton
of interesting innovation happening from young people.
It's just not happening
-- in the open source world. I think. I
-- think it's more diffuse because you're right.
Like, I'm just looking at this Hearts of Iron four.
Guess how many mod packs there are on the Steam Store? I bet. Hundreds. No.
Keep going.
Oh, really?
2691 entries.
-- Yeah,
-- that's amazing.
Like I knew it was a lot,
-- but
-- that is open source for a lot of young people now is stuff like this.
And so I think the, the,
the, the funny thing
that I also think about this story
is my guess is the real reason
people are concerned about open source needing fresh blood
is because
-- a lot of companies rely on that free open source.
-- Oh, absolutely.
And, and that's another thing is back 20 years ago
when you were in the open source world, you were dealing with
people, right?
Because companies,
so few companies were using this that you could literally count them on one hand.
Scary. And only hippies used open
source like,
and a lot of the companies using it were
using Red Hat because like to get it working was
no, like even getting red
installed. Which had a good installer
was right. Like you laugh, I laugh and then we cry a little bit and have like a flash
bang,
you know, to Kickstarter
-- or sorry. Kickstart.
-- I can't see my disc controller for some reason.
Or like, why, why, what, why are my cylinder count? What?
That's not my cylinder count?
Oh, I know. Right.
Nowadays, like
we, we're seeing this where, you know, it,
it's a person but they're seeing things like
this is like a critical bug for Microsoft teams and we
need you to fix FFM PEG to do this thing.
And then my favorite thing was on the hacker news discussion
where basically some people were tearing into FFM peg saying,
look,
you made a breaking change to a default which
then broke teams that's kind of your fault.
And the response was like,
hang on a minute
like FFM Peg wrote this open source thing.
They changed the default behavior which is not ideal, but hey,
they get to do that. It's their right.
And
you know, and Microsoft's consuming it, they could have tweaked it to
not do that.
Like I literally just wrote the create users rewrote
the create user script for a thing I use
because I don't like the one they have because
it's interactive and I want to be automated.
I'm not going to go upstream and complain and be like blah, blah, blah,
it doesn't do what I want.
No, I'm just gonna fix it.
And so like they literally Microsoft was like you
need to fit like and it was already fixed.
They just had to literally add one flag
and then Microsoft just
left the conversation and never like no, thank you.
Well, kind of a thank you but not genuine.
And like no, they could have bought a support contract.
They could have given them money. I think Microsoft maybe has a few dollars extra.
-- Not poor little Microsoft. Yeah,
-- they basically came in yelled it's broken, fix it.
Oh, it's already fixed. OK. We'll consume that fix. Thank you. Bye. And it's like,
well, that was nice of that.
-- I'm sure that's part of the story.
-- Well, but as a young person, I think
we grew up with open source that was people,
young people are growing up with open source
that is being strip mined by corporations.
-- There is a lot of that. And the other thing is
-- back in the day
when a company used open source, you didn't see it
as directly.
Oh, they would never admit it.
Yeah, like they kind of like in super fine white print on white paper,
they'd have like may contain traces of open source.
You know, you can, you can,
you can write this mailing address to get like a CD with the stuff on it.
But nowadays like if a cloud provider provides a Mongo DB as a service, well,
clearly they're providing
Mongo DB as a service and poor Mongo DB is like, well,
we would like to be able to pay the rent and eat.
So now we're going to change our license to be whatever it was.
And I think that's the other part of it is open
source is no longer what it was 20 years ago,
especially with the consumption of it.
Like, companies are openly consumed
-- and selling it now as a service.
-- Sure. Sure. Right.
Well, and, and so that's the point.
Right is, I think there are without question,
thousands of open source projects that have died that existed,
we'll say 3040 years ago in the open source world.
Just because for whatever reason
-- they didn't work out.
-- What
-- do
-- you mean by die?
Like there's
like they're gone or they're still there,
the open source never goes away but like no one is working on it.
Right. We'll say
abandoned projects. Let's call them
that probably don't build anymore because you need to use like Red Hat Linux
three
with a custom config on arm or on spark arm.
-- We didn't even have that back then. But anyway.
-- Right.
And now
I think there's a lot more attention because of the things you're
talking about where you've got all these large companies using open source,
open source is critical infrastructure.
And I think the reality is that
if you want
to keep this stuff maintained and going,
you have to give people a reason to do it
beyond you should do it because we need you to do it,
please, please do this work for free some young person because we need it.
This is an example of
if you need someone to do it,
pay them money to do it.
Like that is one of that is probably the only
solution at this point for a lot of this stuff,
right?
Like PC RE two, we talked about that a little while ago
where
the, the maintainer was like, I don't, I can't do this anymore.
And what now?
Right.
So anyway, but at the same time,
I think this is an example of young people have things they work on,
young people have things they want to do just because they're
not working on the things we think they should work on,
makes it wrong.
I just had a thought, I think there's another
aspect of this that you and I are ignoring because we're old, which is
open source, used to be infrastructural type software.
And now
because we have all that mostly sorted out,
like getting a web server nowadays is easy.
Like you just download one of the good ones. There's lots,
the same thing with mail servers, same thing with
whatever. There's so many options now.
And now
a lot of like younger people can work on building
like they build things that are like an end point.
Like what,
what traditionally would have been a command line utility except
it's a website that does this really cool thing.
And that's why I think part of that too is,
but you can't consume that as an open source component
easily in the traditional way, right?
Whereas if you traditionally release the open source,
I would then bundle that into my dependency chain or whatever and have a thing that,
you know, converts PDF to html or vice versa, whatever.
But if it's a website,
I can maybe consume it as an API but then I'm dependent on
you running that for it to be available for it to continue working.
-- Whereas if
-- I don't think we're talking about the same things, if I'm a normal person,
what kind of website am I going to build that
is scratching my itch for other people to use?
I don't think there's very many,
there's a lot of them on hacker news and quite a few of them that I use
like a great one. Jason
editor
online.com. It is a wonderful little Jason editor online
and it went from being
it's, but it's got a really nice comparing.
It's got some really nice features and it's just, you know, it's,
it's just super convenient,
right?
Like I wrote that ridiculous. Like what is it RFC 933 three.com.
And you go there and it spits out the RFC 33 date.
Like
that's it.
Yeah,
it's just a handy little thing because I literally it was
easier to do that than to have like a Java library,
do it or javascript library do it rather,
I think it was called that. Um
But anyways, the point is like
the way people build and release their open sources change
because now they can do it as a website.
Whereas you and I
Josh, 20 years ago, if you wanted to build something as a web service,
the answer is you couldn't.
No, it was just really hard because you had to get a, a Colo
machine somewhere
and you had to run your own web server.
And now for like three bucks a month, you can run, uh, VPs somewhere
that can actually handle quite a bit of load.
Yes. Right. Like, yes.
Yeah. So, I think maybe that's part of what's changed too is the, the,
the way people do open source has changed and it's not as,
it's not consumable in the traditional sense as a software library.
It's a service or an API or
like I've literally seen people chaining together websites
like they would in the past chain together a shell command with pipe
and effectively getting the same thing.
But obviously, you know, you're a lot more reliant on that website still working.
Versus, you know, if you have a shell command installed locally, it's,
it's not going to go away or break one day.
Well, it might break one day. But, you know,
and I think that's part of it is that the world has changed, like
it it has.
So, I think maybe the right discussion here
isn't about the graying of open source.
It's about,
why don't we see more of the organizations relying on open sources,
core infrastructure.
And this is true of corporations and governments and lots of other groups.
Why aren't we seeing them stepping up to the plate
to properly fund and maintain open source?
-- I know the answer to that. Well,
-- we all do.
-- It's because they don't have to.
-- I know.
Right.
Why should I pay you if you'll do it for free
-- or
-- more to the point? Why would I care if it works well enough?
Like, remember when we used to think, oh,
companies won't like data breaches because their share price will
go down and they'll suffer for it turns out no,
I mean, what was it AT&T just lost call records on, let me check my notes.
Oh, everybody. Right. Or Ticketmaster, I got my email from Ticketmaster.
I'm pretty sure everybody in North America has gotten that email.
I don't think I have a Ticketmaster account. So
I'm, I'm still waiting for an email though.
Yeah. But I mean, like,
you know, you want to go to a show, you have to deal with Ticketmaster at some point.
I probably have an account.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Here's my, I, I,
how do we make open source
more inviting? And I think the answer is open source.
Like, I think part of the challenge is people are doing open source,
just not in the way the companies want them to,
which is like you pointed out doing like the sustaining engineering
on old infrastructure code that like some big company is relying upon
and that's too bad because I see a lot of young
people building a lot of interesting and creative services and,
and look, I,
I wanna stress at this point and all of the data that exists
shows young people are getting screwed over by society at every possible turn.
Be it wages or inflation or prices or homeownership education?
You think our Children are going to own homes? That's so cute.
Well, no, that's just one of the ways they're getting screwed over.
Like they've got it rough. Right. They have it.
But harder than most of us old people can possibly understand.
We will never understand because it's not affecting us.
And so
while young people are doing many things,
I also recognize it is not without struggles and trials and tribulations.
Like
-- they've got a lot to deal with. Can
-- I quote my child?
So my, my one son was playing the game of life with the neighbor's kid
and I heard her say
I'm just gonna have a cat and find Children by the side of the road and feels like,
yeah, me too.
Like my son Felix is he wants to own maybe one or two cats like that is his life goal for
like,
yeah,
that sucks. Like people, young people should be filled with optimism
and a sense of purpose.
And the thing I love is veterinarians in North America are getting more and
more expensive because all the private equity
groups are buying the vets and dentists
because, like, where else are they going to park their money and get a return on it?
That's true, I suppose.
Right.
And like I looked at that pet insurance
thing with that 56 page contract that doesn't cover
anything other than the cat getting in a
fight and getting like accidental teeth damage somehow.
Yeah.
But like
it's just, it's,
yeah.
No, it's, I think it's a lot of this is boiling down to corporations want free effort.
Like the, obviously,
I mean, to the point of some of them, you know,
the infamous tales of certain large employers in the US that have, like,
here's how to get food stamps on the bulletin boards in the
back of their store because they don't pay a living wage.
Exactly. Completely insane.
Like, why would their, it,
people pay some open source person to do something that they
kind of get for free.
And I think to quote, I guess Thomas de,
to some degree, it's, that doesn't sound like a me problem.
That sounds like a you problem. Yes.
And look, I think that's the correct answer here. I think
this is one of those things where if you let the
status quo be the status quo nothing is going to change.
And open the where we are at today
with open source is absolutely that
we are existing
at a state of perpetual status quo that I
don't think is beneficial to the open source developers.
-- The
-- hm
I would say I have noticed certain patterns which is open source
people like literally killing themselves to try and sustain these things.
Like
I remember
and we asked for XML hash doss
hash dos
and the guy was like, yeah, I don't have time to work on this for a few months.
Like, and we're like, I'm like, I respect that like,
because
we're not paying you like, what am I supposed to like, I can't make demands.
And so we did it because we needed that thing solved quickly
and it wasn't nearly as bad as we thought it would be.
That is the pushback
that it, it is funny because I remember back in the day
when we wanted to make someone go away in open source is kind of the fu get out of here.
We'd say patch is welcome, right? That was the,
that was the,
oh, bless your soul, right? Of open source.
Like just learn how our code works and how we submit code and the
culture of our code and the style of our code and do it perfectly.
I'm OK with that.
I'm OK with that as being the answer of if you are an open source maintainer,
you can say like if you want this fixed, you're going to fix it because I'm not.
Can I give you a quick analogy if a group of kids
are playing baseball and another kid comes up to them and says,
can I play, they get to play baseball or they, they can go away.
That's how it works with Children and baseball and other games. And I think,
yeah, I think it's not that we need to be meaner, but we need to be firmer and say,
look here,
like one thing I'm trying to use more is the contributor covenant and I'm saying,
look, here are the rules that we are going to play by.
We're going to be
like, nice to each other. We are not going to be mean to each other.
We're gonna behave like reasonable human beings or else you can leave and by,
you can leave.
I mean, I'm gonna boot you.
Here's I think what I want to end this on
and I'm going to
park
the story with the young. If you watch Streamers on Twitch,
I've actually never watched Twitch.
I've actually, I just realized I've never been to Twitch. Is it Twitch dot What is it?
-- Twitch
-- dot TV.
Amazon owns it ironically.
But anyway, you watch the Streamers and so funny enough, I,
I watch Streamers play the Randomizer.
I also play, it's just, they're really good at it. So it, it reminds me of how like
people,
they might play a sport themselves but then
they'll still watch the professionals do it.
It's 100% that, because it's like I suck at this and I'm like,
I wish I could do the things these people do and I can't.
But anyway,
you watch these streamers and when they have someone
in their Twitch chat that's misbehaving in some way,
they just ban them. Like
they'll, they'll time them out, they'll ban them like whatever.
Like there is no discussion, right? They're just like b
hammer comes out, I'm done with this crap.
They figure
it out. Open source has not figured that out.
Like we don't get out the band hammer, we don't discourage behaviors.
And the thing is like
when you look at these Twitch Chats,
generally speaking,
the people in them are,
we'll say
polite and, and interesting and nice.
Then one person shows up like that one toxic person.
And I think it's like the Nazi Bar story, right?
Where like these, these streamers, they don't deal with it like boom, you're done.
And I think
i it works right. I feel like it works. They figured it out,
I think.
Well,
I remember we had this discussion about the open source license definition of
open source licenses where number five says
no discrimination against persons or groups,
the license must not discriminate against any person or group of persons.
And my take on that was that, yeah, like the license can't say you know, no,
no people with a skin tone of darker than whatever bear paint sample.
No people named Kurt may use my project.
But on the flip side,
that doesn't mean I can't ban them from my
github or my mailing list. And like, I
don't have to let them into my house to listen
to their ideas about how I should rewrite this.
And I've seen that happen. Right.
We've, we've both seen that happen where somebody says, like,
I think you should fix the project by doing this.
And they're like, yeah, for like the 17th time now, we, we,
we looked at that a lot like five years ago
and here's the 10 reasons why that won't work.
And
I really think,
I don't want to say the open source projects needs to be more discriminatory,
but I think like your Twitch thing,
they need to be a lot firmer with
what are the expectations and enforcement of those expectations
and not like, oh, let's give them a 3rd, 4th, 5th chance. It's like, no,
there's enough nice reasonable people out there that do want to participate,
but they're probably avoiding a lot of this now because they did participate.
They saw a gross person come in and knock at the boot and they're like,
because I, I've seen, that's why I'm not,
that's why I will have nothing ever in my life to do with
the Open BS D project because they have some horrifically toxic people that,
like, threatened me.
And I'm guessing that there are people that read those email threads and went, oh,
-- look,
-- here's, here's how I'll end it. It's not about open source needs young people.
I think it's, the situation is open source needs to learn from the young people. Like
-- that's a lot, they know
-- there's a lot more kindness with young people. Nowadays,
we expect them to come play by our rules.
We should go play by theirs because I think their rules
are better and they figured a lot of this stuff out,
younger people are definitely a lot kinder like
the fact that school bullying is a thing
like that is not tolerated anymore like it was 23
years ago.
Oh
my goodness, thank goodness.
Yeah.
So I guess, yeah, let's be nicer like the younger people.
No,
like statistically look at like you look at like giving rates to
charity and stuff by like a percentage of income and everything.
Yeah,
old people
are like be like the youth.
I wish I was youth anyway.
Thank you.
Thank you for listening. Go to Fitzer Security podcast.com.
I would have bought so much Bitcoin.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to
Security podcast.com.
Hit up the show
T
Podos
Podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.