Hello and welcome to episode 107 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
All Kurt. I'm going to call 2018 as the year of the Linux
desktop.
I'm inclined to agree
for real,
for real. Like it's been
a
year forever.
Right.
And, and I feel like we made it, we finally made it, but ironically,
we didn't make it for the reasons anyone thought we know
-- we
-- were
because the year the Linux desktop is
going to exist because of chromebooks and windows
and android
phone.
I consider that less desktop
than chromebooks. I mean, a phone is a phone whereas a chromebook is a computer,
a desktop.
And I think that's part of the thing.
The desktop thing is a dying metaphor
shipments
are,
everybody's got a smartphone.
Now.
Did I buy? I don't even remember the last time I bought a computer.
It's, it's been a while, I
think
for my kids,
my kids play games on a windows machine, but that's it.
Uh But anyway, anyway, we should explain this.
So, and, and why is the security podcast talking about a desktop.
So this is a bunch of bizarrely related things come together.
So, chromebooks have been around for a while and they're insanely inexpensive.
In fact, I have one
and it's what I use when I travel and it works
perfectly and I have no issues with it and it's obviously ultra
secure compared to any laptop
except maybe some of the windows stuff. But that's another story.
But anyway, anyway,
so
you
have to, you have to work to make it secure. It doesn't come out of the box that way.
Typically
that's fair. That's fair. You know,
unless you work for
which nobody does.
I've tried walking down the biases and these things. It's, it's,
it's a nontrivial task and I
know some of
-- the
-- new ones are OK.
Some of the new ones come locked down by default and
you have to actually unlock the stuff if you want it.
But anyway, anyway, so chromebooks
are basically desktops. They're, they're basically web browsers
and
you now have the ability on a select number of chromebooks.
I'm very exciting because at the end of July mine gets it
is you have the ability to run native Linux
apps in the chromebook. And I guess it's using some magic container technology.
But this is super exciting because now I have like an ultra portable,
ultra secure device
that is essentially my Linux desktop and it's,
I, I
don't even know what to say.
It's awesome.
Yeah.
Well,
the other thing that I like about chromebooks
is similar to Apple is that they keep state
sort of natively,
like, you don't have to set up something to do data replication and all sorts of
stuff to get your data,
not just backed up, but like in real time synchronized to another device. So that
God forbid you like,
want to edit a thing on your phone and put your phone
in your pocket and then immediately start editing it on your laptop
and not have to do some like black magic in between to get it to work.
Well, not only that, I mean, one of the things I love about it is, is part of that story.
So my chromebook cost me $250 dirt cheap.
And, and I have the opinion of like,
let's say I go through airport security and they take my
computer away from me and they give it back to me
that's going to go in the garbage can as soon as I walk away from the TS a checkpoint.
Right. And I won't think twice
about
getting all my stuff back because it's all magic. Right? It's super cool like that.
I really dig it.
And so that's one of the beauties of traveling with that versus traveling with,
you know, a multi $1000 laptop.
Yeah. No, I just checked my laptop is from 2012
and I haven't bothered upgrading it because everything's in the cloud it's
like
ancient man.
Well, that's the thing.
I'm looking at the hardware specs for some of
these newer tablets and phones and chromebooks and it's like
they are pretty solid machines. Like, generally speaking at least four gigs of ra M
ac pui, I don't know what that means anymore.
Like, I know, I think it's,
the newer Apple phones have like two fast cores and four slow cores for
stuff to
-- save battery. And I don't know,
-- I've got so
and my chromebook, I have four fast cars, two slow cars and so it's a six
car chip which is weird, but whatever it works, I don't care.
I
don't
think
-- so.
-- Yeah.
No, I'm just, I'm looking at the hardware specs and all this stuff and like honestly,
it all boils down to, yeah, it'll, it'll let me like watch video.
It'll let me
do all my office type work
and even play some minimal games. So, yeah,
you know, these things are under 500 bucks.
Uh Yeah,
seriously, man.
And they all run Linux
year of Linux desktop.
Well, actually we should also point out why we jokingly said Windows is these days.
If you have a Windows desktop,
you can use what's called the Linux subsystem.
And you can like literally run Linux applications
on Windows and it works pretty well actually.
Oh, it works great because I needed an SSH client on my Windows machine.
So I went to the Apple or to the Microsoft store typed in SSH.
And the first result was ubuntu. So I'm like, yeah, whatever. Sure
Ubuntu has a copy of Open SSH, which is actually what I want.
I don't want some wonky home brew written copy of SSH,
you know.
Um And so I, I, yeah, I clicked it and like 10 minutes later after a reboot, I'm
running Linux in a container and the beauty is, it runs like an app like there's
it
when you type in Reboot, it says I can't do that because there's no process one,
there's no system to like I, I am a container.
I was instantiated, not like a computer but like a container.
And I love that I can just click the X in the corner and it, it's gone
and when I reopen it, like
whatever state was on disk is saved,
right? So it's not like
it works for losing state or anything.
And yeah, it's just, it's incredibly easy and simple and
yeah, I mean,
it's, it's honestly, I, I'm not going to bother installing, you know,
I used to install sin the tool chain on my windows machine.
So I'd have like said and a
and grab and all that stuff.
Yeah. Now, no, I just
click on the ubuntu icon and,
and go to slash MNT slash C mount C,
you know, it natively mounts your C drive and all your local drives and just,
you can monkey around with your stuff.
-- No problem. Yep.
-- Yep. I, I wonder how many listeners we just lost
in the last three minutes.
But, you know, in context, I remember back in the day and by back in the day, I mean,
like 10 years ago,
I would force myself for two weeks every summer to use Linux on my desktop
and get it fully working, sound everything and, like, really try hard to use Linux
and
invariably I just was like, oh, man,
this is just such a chore and I would give up and go back to,
you know,
Mac Os or Windows.
Um, and, and, and, and Linux in a virtual machine,
you know,
so I've been running Linux on my desktop probably for 20 years.
And it, it, it has reached the point now where it's a
non event.
And I remember back in the day when I was going to install the new version of something
usually Fedora or Red Hat Linux
that were that long ago,
like I remember I would set aside a weekend
to get it working and I needed it.
Right. It wasn't just, oh, I'll screw it up for a weekend.
Like, no,
I actually needed to work my behind off for a whole weekend to get my desktop working.
Oh, no, I, I ran Linux on the desktop slackware one point.
Oh, and some other things because what else was there?
But what I'm just realizing too is
if I run Linux,
I can't really easily run windows or Mac O SI can run windows in a VM,
but I can't really run Mac Os at all.
Whereas if I'm running Mac Os or Windows, I can trivially run Linux
now.
Yes, that, that is a very good point.
It's, although, you know, man, I find like, II,
I purposely make myself switch between different kinds of
desktops just so I can keep it kind of fresh
and honestly like on, on Mac O si just open a shell and I use my web browser.
It's basically as good as Linux.
I mean, honestly, I don't notice a difference.
I removed my virtual machines that I had for my previous job and
yeah, Mac
Os command
shell. Uh I did have to install a newer version of GP G.
That was basically the only thing I needed
and home brew obviously to get all the
news said
because the Mac Os said does not
-- home
-- brew
-- line
-- returns.
The
Mac
Os utilities are
they're
broken,
they're straight up broken. Like,
like go read the man page for
said on Mac Os and what you need to do to handle line returns.
And compared to like GNU said where it's trivial.
Yeah. No, it's
Yeah. No.
Yeah,
but that's probably because they're using like some
1965 version of AT&T set or something.
But I guess here's, here's the thing I keep thinking of here is, you know,
why we can even have this conversation, man.
It's because like open source one
down
and what I really love is, is
in the container space. Linux one,
right. Is there, is there any,
is anybody even making a really serious attempt to
have containers that are not based on Linux?
And the answer is, well, yeah, there's a, there's a couple of BS D things and what not.
But they,
yeah, they're like those weirdos living out in the woods with sharp sticks.
You know, they, they mean, well, but you probably want to avoid them.
You're gonna,
don't, don't poke the bear cart.
Just,
just don't
anyway. Anyway. Anyway. All right. That's cool.
But it's, I don't know, I'm excited.
I think there's some, some fun stuff going on and I'm always happy to talk about it.
-- But, but you have some other stories.
-- Yeah.
-- So, so
-- something that you wanted to discuss,
but I've kind of wondered why nobody wrote about this before is, um,
thermal imaging cameras.
And so when you type in a password, um,
obviously you generally touch the keys on your keyboard
and that would transfer some heat. And so, uh,
thermal imaging cameras now are, are quite affordable.
Like I was just looking online.
Uh, there's a really nifty one that plugs into the bottom of your phone,
either Apple or Android
200 bucks, apparently quite a nice,
uh,
infrared camera.
You know,
there's a couple of branded phones like a
Caterpillar actually makes a brand of phones,
you know, the heavy equipment
guys that paint all their stuff. Caterpillar yellow.
And they have a couple of, like, ruggedized
phones for
construction type people, I guess.
I don't know, but they have thermal cameras built into them. Which,
yeah, that'd be kind of useful.
You know, if you're looking at an engine or, like you said, you're,
where do I insulate my house?
Right.
There's, I'm sure there's countless uses
for it. I'm thinking especially with like pins, you know, on a pin pad.
It's, it's, well,
usually everybody has four digits.
Uh you can have six, but then you run the risk of that not working in Europe or America
with older equipment.
Um, because I used to have a six digit pin and it works almost all the time
for my debit card.
A six digit pin. I don't think I've ever heard of a six digit pin for a debit card.
Yeah. So you, you can get,
uh, you can definitely get up to a six digit pin on most cards.
But like I said, if you encounter an older payment terminal,
you might have a bad day,
not in the US.
Like we don't use pins.
It's so bad.
But, um, but yeah,
like I'm surprised this hasn't kind of
come out sooner because apparently there's enough
heat left on these keyboards for a good 45 seconds to a minute to,
you know, basically get the person's um,
password and what I noticed I was actually watching
a tech tips and he is in their server room and he's logging into a server
and they actually blurred out his hands and
the keyboard while he's typing in the password.
And I was like, oh, yeah, because you could, you know,
have the youtube video go through at like quarter speed or whatever
and you'd clearly be able to see what key is hitting.
Sure.
Yeah.
And this is one thing that gets me,
especially around two factor authentication is that,
you know, especially in office environments, it's just,
it's people can watch you type
unless you're like in an office
room facing a backing into a wall or something. You know,
it's like when people discover the cameras are good enough now
to easily take a picture of a key and you know,
you can figure out what the bidding, the cut pattern is.
-- Your,
-- your fingerprints, man, right? You can take pictures of fingerprints. Now
most,
let's be brutally honest,
any decent phone nowadays has at least a 10 megapixel camera,
right? I remember buying a one megapixel camera for like 500 bucks back in the day,
you know,
it was,
did it take
pretty much? I think I'm, I'm restricted to
-- 16
-- megabyte
SD cards.
But um yeah, I mean, the reality is like modern phones,
some of them have upwards of 20 or 30 megapixel cameras.
And
yeah, like if you're doing that, what is it that um the, the,
that
the, the thing that the, you know,
where they hold their fingers up in the peace symbol.
Whenever they take a photo, it's like this iconic thing,
I think that the Japanese do or something.
And yeah,
like you're holding your fingers up to the picture and
apparently these cameras are good enough now that you can like
literally see us. I, you know, enhance, enhance.
Oh you have the killer's fingerprint,
you know,
but like legitimately, you know, and, and that's the thing that gets me right is
it,
we always go back to, you know, security through obscurity never works.
Um Largely because most security through obscurity,
you can't change what it is you're hiding, right?
So with passwords, you can argue that you can change your password quickly.
So it's not so terrible, but like, yeah, something like your fingerprint.
Uh Well, you can technically change your fingerprint, but it's going to hurt
a lot.
And so I think any security that kind of relies on something
never being physically seen by an attacker. A great example being like a key,
you know, I think we need to start
thinking about these things because II, I know people,
like I've seen people that wear their key ring on their belt
and you could easily take a picture of
most of that thing and, and get the bidding of most of the keys.
I would argue keys are different
because
let's face it. There are
janitor with a master key on his key ring.
Yeah. But even with that man, do you know how easy it is to pick basically every line on
the planet today? I mean, with a bump key, you can pick it in literally four seconds.
I mean, keys are to keep honest people out, they are not to keep evildoers out.
And I think that's kind of the difference with passwords is passwords
are meant to keep evil doers out and honest people out.
Right. And, and
I
really, if we kind of think about
passwords, like we think about keys,
a password is really to keep the honest people out,
but you need two factor on now if you want to keep the evil doers out.
Right? I mean, that's probably the right way.
Part of the challenge is if you have just a password,
then you really do need things like account lockouts for bad logins or, you know,
like slowdowns like, ok, it's, I'm gonna make you wait 10 seconds,
I'm gonna make you wait 20 seconds.
And that's great with like a physical device, like a phone.
But
that really sucks if I'm trying to log into like
my gmail
and some Russian dude hammered it and now I can't log in for like half a day,
right? Because that's, that's,
that's actually one of the cwe identifiers is like
overly aggressive account lockout because I've literally seen systems
where you get three bad logins and the system
locks you out completely and you have to,
like, get the admin to let you back in
which, you know, for some crazy high security environment maybe.
But, like,
you can't put that online because then everybody will be locked out in half an hour.
Yeah.
My,
my bank does that where if I type my password in wrong more than three times I
have to then provide them with an obscene amount of information to prove it to me.
And it, it, it sucks.
But I guess, and that one I can probably let go and it doesn't happen very often.
It's, it's usually,
for some reason I end up accidentally hitting
buttons while I'm pasting the password from,
from the password manager.
Yeah. Or at least they don't have the cut and paste disabled in javascript. Right.
Oh, my goodness.
II, I, yeah,
I'm actually going to be campaigning this year probably to make that like a flaw.
Like if you block, cut and paste, that's a flaw. Don't do that.
-- I agree. That should, that should get a CV E unquestionably like it.
-- Well, and a CV,
-- get them both.
-- And then the other big hardware news. Well, not really big news again.
It's been for a while, but like,
if you buy an evil replacement screen for your smartphone, like,
obviously it can see what you're typing
because, like, the screen is also the keyboard. Right?
And you can also impersonate them too. Right.
Because the, the, the screen sends the signals to the,
to the computer saying, you know, they tap over here, they tap over here,
they swipe this, right?
And so it sounds like, you know, for example, Apple is dealing with this by
e essentially uh my understanding is the parts will, you know,
they'll have like a little encryption thing in them
that proves that they're part of the legitimate supply chain
and not some like off brand third party whatever piece,
right? Because
when you think about it, right, if you have somebody like
replace the screen on your phone, like you have no idea where that screen came from.
That, that is true.
-- Like
-- is it a legit Apple screen or is it some third party thing or is it, who knows?
Right.
And now man, this one, I get torn over because
I'm sensitive to the concept of right to repair
where if, if my phone does break,
I should be able to get it fixed wherever I want to. But and the other side of it,
there is something to be said about some of this kind of dodgy gear.
It's like Apple getting more and more restrictive with the
cables that you can use to plug your phone in,
right?
Because the the the lightning cables do have
again like a little encryption do hicky in them
like I have cables that used to work and then I
did an I OS update and then they stopped working.
See, that's lame, man. I'm sorry. That's lame.
And, well, it is.
But at the flip side you have these people
buying like really garbage cables and frying their phone.
Like that guy again.
Back to the Google guy that did those USB C cable testing and like fried his laptop
-- from a bad cable.
-- Yeah. But look if, if you fry your iphone on a bad cable,
are, are they gonna, I assume they can tell,
-- are they going to replace it?
-- If it's Apple care?
Possibly if you're off Apple care, then that's your problem.
And more to the point you're what if it burns your house down?
Right?
-- Because there's been pictures of some of these phones
-- that, like,
don't buy cheap stuff.
Well, the problem is though, I don't know.
How do I know that the expensive cable I'm buying is legit or not. And that's true.
You don't like? I know that the cheap stuff is probably not legit
but the expensive stuff like monster cables, those are expensive,
aren't they legit?
I thought they were gold plated for your safety.
-- Did you ever see the website where some guy did a test of monster
-- cables?
The
coat
hanger.
Nobody could tell the difference.
I'm not even a little surprised and obviously digital is even funnier
but whatever
in fairness,
I have had digital cables that were of such
poor quality or mangled that they actually were bad.
But like these things have been like, chewed on.
Basically,
I remember one time I bought a bunch of cheap cables
of ebay and like half of them just wouldn't work.
They would,
they would plug in and it would start charging for
like two seconds and then it would just stop charging.
And so I, I threw them away and then I bought nice cables
-- and I've never,
-- yeah, like a great example. Um,
in the car, you know, you have your old timey, we call them a power plug.
Now what they used to be for cigarette lighters, kids.
And so you have that little round thing that has the USB plugs on the end, right?
It's like basically a little physical adapter.
And I bought like a super cheap one thinking like, don't do, who cares? Right.
It's just like a chunk of, it's basically a couple of bits of metal.
There's nothing in there. Really.
No. And uh so I found one where uh my phone won't charge off that one.
Like it provides power and it'll run like a dash cam.
But like you plug an iphone into it and the iphone's like, just like, no, I'm just,
this thing is garbage.
I don't know what's going on. I'm not going to charge.
And then I, I bought a nicer one, like uh
it's a fancy one with like USB ports and the port, uh the, the,
the round ports and it's got like an on off
switch and it shows you how much voltage it's drawing.
It's pretty neat.
And that one works fine.
Yeah, I get it because I don't want to, like, save $3 and fry my phone. But
let's be honest, unless you go to the Apple store and buy the Apple cables, then
you have no idea.
And in the Android ecosystem, like, where do you get provably good USB C cables?
Uh, I go to Amazon and by the Amazon basics and I have the
assumption,
I assume they've done some level of quality control on their cable.
That's
fair
-- and
-- that's all. And again, it just goes back to having a brand to protect, right?
That's honestly as a consumer, that's about the only thing I can do.
This is a very similar problem to security
because
I don't know which cables are good.
Just like if I need a security product,
I have no way to know which security product is good.
And so
there might be some places I can rely on,
on advice because maybe they make good decisions or they have a brand,
they're looking to protect.
But I mean,
fundamentally at the end of the day,
like let's think about using open source libraries and github,
I have zero way to tell which one is the most secure.
Just like if I'm buying cables, I really don't know which is the best
and more to the point too, most software is so complex to objectively say,
well, like, it's like whenever somebody does ratings of software,
I'm just like, yeah, nine out of 10. What does that mean?
Like, I get for games you can kind of rate games,
like it has good gameplay or it sucks with gameplay or it's got beautiful graphics,
terrible graphics.
These are somewhat,
you know, they,
they're somewhat easy to understand the measurement and
to kind of validate the measurement but to,
like, look at a piece of software and say like, yeah, it's a nine out of 10 for a,
for an image library
-- and,
-- and, and that's fair. And you think like power cables
and,
and power supplies would be very easy to
-- measure if somebody was
-- technically they're supposed to be
tested and like, either ul, like underwriters laboratory listed or
most of them don't have that though.
Well, uh, two problems. No,
number one, they will have it,
but it will be self tested and certified by the manufacturer.
Not by a testing lab,
right?
Because they went to a, a self testing regime because it's a lot cheaper and faster.
And, yeah, number two is,
they just don't have any of those markings and it's just like buyer beware.
Good luck with that.
Yeah, I've, I had a bunch of power supplies for USB that had no markings and II,
I forget what happened.
One of them did something weird and I just, I've thrown them all away now
and I've given up and I purposely just buy things that I know I can trust because
my assumption is if it says UL on it, it's gone through some level of testing,
assuming they just didn't put the markings on.
I'm assuming it went through some level of testing.
But again, you're right. I, I have no way to truly prove it.
Right.
Yeah.
And see, this is where I think some of the, you know,
some of the people have been talking about things like
Blockchain for supply chain management where you can actually trace like
that fish from the fish farm to your plate or
that specific component from like
where it was made and what went into it to your end
thing.
And I think longer term that will definitely
happen for some of the more expensive stuff.
But yeah, for like a $1 cable. That's
-- right. Yeah, that's going to be tough.
-- Right. Exactly.
Exactly. And, and
man, you think about what goes into even a $1 cable, I mean, there's wire in it,
there's connectors in it.
There's the plastic, there's
that guy
that made a toaster,
remember that guy that made a toaster,
a
toaster? He didn't make a, he, he barely made a wire.
That's what he
did.
Well, technically he made something that toasted bread once and then caught fire,
whatever
anyway.
-- But
-- no, the point is it was basically impossible to build.
Right.
Right. But that doesn't see, at the same time, I think that's ridiculous.
Way to think about it. I mean,
we live in a society where people have different things. They do.
I don't grow my own food.
Right.
You don't grow.
-- But
-- did you see the picture of the,
of the $4 toaster he bought and took apart and there was, like,
over 100 components in it.
I, right. Right. Because that's how
the modern society works.
Yeah.
So, I guess the moral of the story is where, um,
he shielded gloves, like, so wear winter gloves whenever you're typing passwords.
No, don't do that. That's ridiculous.
Look, here's what, here's what the moral of the story is. The moral of the story is.
We are surrounded by risk every day
and we have to make decisions about where we want to put,
invest our risk dollars and where not to
worrying about the heat signature on your keyboard.
If someone wants to attack you on that level, they're going to get you no matter what.
That's just one of the possible ways they can get in.
Right.
And so the reality is if that's the risk you're worried about,
you better be like some spy in a hostile foreign nation
because if you're not, you're probably wasting your resources.
This is where, like, two factor
a
solves this problem 100%.
Right.
And
not on two factor
off.
I was glancing through the user list in a slack,
uh, that we'd set up
and I noticed one of them had next to their name.
Two fa enabled and I was like, oh, Slack Sports two fa, I didn't even know that.
So I went and enabled it on my account. But
yeah, that just goes to show even me with my whole, oh, use two fa everybody used to fa,
I,
I still don't because honestly half the time I'm not
even aware it's supported in some of these newer services.
I, I had no idea I could do that either
and I blame Slack for not forcing us to use it.
I would agree.
-- I mean, for real, they
-- appear to have that switch.
You can flip to like force two fa across the org.
Oh, nice,
nice, nice.
But um,
yeah,
even you and I are guilty of not taking simple steps that are extremely easy and
extremely.
Ok. No, we don't want to say guilty because
now that I know a Slack allows two factor off, I'm going to go enable it.
Like, as soon as we stop talking,
I didn't know about this before. So you can't say I'm guilty. Right.
Then that's, I mean,
in all seriousness this,
we should probably we could stand to do.
I would say part of it is we have the expectation that there isn't always two fa like,
and that's the fault of all these companies
because they should have supported this sooner.
No,
no, it's not about that. It's about the words we use right?
When you tell someone they're guilty of not doing it,
you're now placing the blame on them
or, or like, for example, I, I had someone I know the other day said if you can use git,
you can use GP G
and I
understand,
I know.
Well, that's another story but I understand the intention of saying that,
that it is complicated and you're a smart person if you're using it.
So you should be smart enough to set up GP G
and he's not wrong.
But what he actually said was if you don't know how GP G works, you're dumb.
Right?
And it's, I think this is something I'm becoming really sensitive to insecurity is
we're really good at saying things that, that don't have ill intent
but to a, a number of humans who hear our words,
they realize we're effectively
demeaning them,
not on purpose, but we are. And that's a huge problem for this industry.
But we won't, we don't need to get into that today because
that's
a,
true because
there's similar, you know,
the similar thing with like car mechanics talking down to people or whatever.
Right.
And when you find a car mechanic that doesn't talk down to you, you tend to keep them,
-- you know. Yeah,
-- exactly. That's exactly right.
And it's the same deal with security and I just, I keep thinking about there,
there's all these parallels and all these analogies and
this, these problems exist in almost every other industry as well.
And so I, I often wonder,
will we, will it ever get better? And I have a feeling the answer is no,
I, I'm more hopeful because II I am seeing across the industry,
I think people are beginning to,
to become more aware of the fact that security is not just a technical problem,
it's a people problem, it's a social problem.
Yeah. There, there is some of that.
Well, there's that famous quote, you know, you can't solve social problems
very well with technology and, and I think it goes the other way,
speaking down to these people, yeah, that definitely will not help.
And I think there's an awareness that we,
we need to work with these people and not just bully them
and, and part of it is I love the cloud for that, right?
Because you, you can't bully users anymore because they're like, fine.
I'm going over to this service. That doesn't sound right.
Exactly. Exactly.
Indeed. And, and that's probably a topic for another day.
So I think, I think we should call it, man. It's, it's a good end.
So awesome. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, use our pounds
as podcast hashtag to hit us on social media.
And yeah, Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.