Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner trying to figure out what the hell's going on. Josh
Reser.
I,
no, I gave up trying to understand what's going on a very long time ago.
I, I think for me, it's,
I've actually become much more selective of what I'm trying to figure out.
I think that's fair actually.
-- Yeah.
-- And I think part of that is that that comes with age
because not only do I have the potential to
understand what actually going on in certain situations,
but I actually understand now for myself,
understanding which ones are valuable and which ones are not valuable. Like
I was actually just going to write an article about SB
and Se Linux and maybe having like some sort of manifesting of
like this library touches these files and listens to these parts.
And I realized
no,
that that's why we did containers, right?
We just shove a single privileged level into a container
and if we need a different privileged level,
use a different container and talk over the network basically,
right? And so I'm going to write that article
and basically say this is why
a, my idea is bad and b why my idea, even if it was good would never work.
And based on the fact that here we are, I'm right.
Well, and that feels like it falls in line with the cloud security alliances,
kind of pushed towards, you know, 00 trust.
And I mean, zero trust is fundamentally just heavy resource,
uh
what not, not exclusion.
Um What do you
think that
I'm going to correct you? I think you're actually thinking of SDP software
perimeter, which is a subset of zero trust,
which is zero trust is the overall idea. And SDP is one way to get there.
-- OK? I accept
-- that
it also ties into SDP and ZT AC
T A
-- zero
-- trust and I forget what the A stands for.
Sweet.
I'm glad that's recorded
to
Alpha.
Nope.
Oh,
here we go. Here we go. Oh
sweet zero trust architecture.
It's one of those like systems or,
you know, it's a useless word.
Might as well be Z TT zero trust.
-- Anyway,
-- before we, before we start accidentally talking about zero trust,
we're here to talk about zero day, which is
maybe more exciting. I don't know.
So I remember when zero days were, you know,
two or three times a year massive thing.
And now it's like, well, what does this report say?
I
want to clarify before we start? So, Kurt and I are going to say zero day a lot.
And some people call this O day. I feel like it's an age divide.
I feel like the young hip kids call it O day and us old fogies call it zero day.
So if you prefer O day, just think O day, every time we say zero day.
So there you go,
Josh. And I are. In fact old.
Did you see that Twitter thing? What's like was the first Linux you used ubuntu?
And I'm like,
no
Ubuntu didn't exist
actually. What was the first Linux? I used, technically it was Red Hat Linux,
but I, a friend installed it. I didn't like it.
I installed Slackware and then I used that for a very long time.
Which one? The, the, the 52 disc image Slackware, 1.1.
-- No, I, my first slackware came off a CD. I know that
-- because,
well, La di da,
I purposely, I,
I bought a CD drive to install slackware and then I bought
a book that had the Slackware CD in the back of it.
So
I made 52 floppy disk copies off a friend's set
of slackware that he downloaded because he had a 9,
600 odd dial up link.
Did I, I did install
some Linuxes off of floppy disks because I had some
computers in the house that didn't have CD drives,
but it was extremely painful and I only did
it a couple of times because it was terrible
-- floppy disks were and are terrible
-- and you needed 7 million of them.
Like, even now, I think Debian's what, like 60 C DS or something.
I mean,
anyway, Zero Day Google Project Zero
released a blog post that they titled
The More, you know, the More you don't know.
Well, wait, they actually spell out Project Zero.
What do you mean?
Spells it out as Google Project zero.blogspot.com. So, therefore,
Zero Day, at least according to Google, that's the way to say it
or they would have said Google Project O day,
you know what, just tweet at Kurt,
which is right.
That's easier. I'm not having this discussion. I literally don't care.
We'll run a poll. I don't care. I literally don't care.
Anyway,
see, this is what's wrong with security.
We obsess over these ridiculous pointless details that don't even matter at all.
You're even a little bit
but whatever. OK.
So they release this report, the more, you know, the more you don't know. And
the, the I guess the headline, the lead as,
as they would say in the industry for this report is there
is a graph of the in the wild zero days detected by year
and the graph kind of looks a little bit like a U from 2015 to 2020
then 2021 is an enormous spike,
more than double
the next highest like it is significant. And so the obvious question becomes
-- why
-- I suspect part of it is better detection.
I suspect a lot of it is
a combination honestly of actually more zero days in use,
but they're in use for a shorter period because of better detection
maybe.
-- I mean, so, ok, well,
-- because like, like citizen labs,
like the stuff citizen labs are doing, you know,
like here's the real,
if you monitor, let's say the top 1000 journalists globally for shenanigans,
you're absolutely gonna run zero days now. It's not a
like, it's like nso group and all that, you know, the
like the, what is it? The is it the Pegasus spyware?
The one that was found in potentially like the British government,
the French government,
you know,
like this is no longer a oh it's a movie plot threat.
It's like, no, no, somebody went out paid for that and dropped it on a government.
So, so Google asks these questions.
They, in fact,
directly beneath this graph and obviously I'll put a link
to this in the show notes for anyone interested.
They say is software getting worse? Are Attackers using more?
Zero days has our ability to detect and disclose zero days increased. And
I mean, that is a question. So you like, let's just start, is software getting worse?
I, I don't think it is. However,
maybe
I would say that
software in our security
mitigations we're building into software
haven't gotten drastically better in the last couple of years.
I think they probably spiked three or four years. Ago,
I would say it's not that software is getting worse.
It's that software is not as improving as quickly
as the volume and size of software is increasing.
So even if you do
twice as good a job on security, if you generate four times as much software,
you'll have twice as many vulnerabilities. And
I think that's where we are,
especially with things like just the size of these libraries and what these like,
like you look at the N PM ecosystem or
you look at all.
I just think of every Microsoft Tuesday now or every I Os and Apple update and it's
like how many gigabytes of stuff?
Oh, did you see that last oracle patch? Tuesday? It was like 100 and 50 CV ES.
That's,
it's always been 100 and 50 CV S quarterly.
-- It's always 100 and 50 to 200 CV S quarterly.
-- Is
-- it always
-- that much?
Well, OK, that could be, I, I don't pay that close of attention.
-- It's been like that for years.
-- So anyway, no, no, I, I want,
I want to dwell on what you just said because
I think it's really important and I think it,
it feels like I'll call it relativistic security
where we often like to think about problems in this kind of stationary position.
And the reality is
all of the software world around us is growing, the Attackers are growing this,
what we're doing with it is growing like everything is growing.
But I think some of our security process and ideas are stagnant and
when you're in an environment that's growing and you're not growing too,
you're actually shrinking compared to the overall environment.
I mean, that's why we've had to do the global security database.
You know,
a perfect example if you go to the common weaknesses and exposures database,
which is essentially a list of software and hard now also hardware
in the last year or two of like flaws like buffer overflow,
buffer underflow,
there's basically zero representation for Blockchain and smart contracts.
Now you go to R
dot News and look at their leader board
and there's at least a couple times a month, you know,
a $100 million plus hack
like and the, and the fun part is most of these vulnerabilities are,
are sort of quasi known but just not well known in the,
in the Blockchain world or the smart contract world.
So they get to
make all these mistakes again
except here they matter because like $611 million goes missing.
Yes. Yes. OK. So anyway, I don't want to dwell on this point. I think
I'm happy to say that the state of security is
it's very relative and I think we're not
expanding our mitigation technologies fast enough.
And I'm skeptical many people would disagree with that.
It's not just the mitigations, but it's the, the actual response.
It doesn't matter. Well, No, no, it does matter.
Because if you have twice as much stuff, basically, your,
your cattle herd got twice as big
-- and you're still phoning the vet to come by once a month.
-- Are,
are you suggesting though that like you mentioned something about monthly?
Are you saying that like monthly, patching is
insufficient in this universe or are you suggesting something else?
I am saying that patching is now like having a roof on your house.
It's, it's just something you have to do as a bare minimum to keep the rain off.
-- I don't think that's controversial.
-- Like basically if you can't patch,
if you can't patch, you probably don't have inventory management.
And if you don't have inventory management,
how can you possibly secure all this stuff?
So to me, patching is now like brushing your teeth
daily. It's the bare minimum. Not. Oh, good. You patched.
Ok.
Yeah, this is III I don't think anyone's going to disagree.
I want to move on to the meat of this discussion because I don't think this is.
So
there's the question are Attackers using more zero
day exploits and I have a suspicion.
The answer is yes.
Well, and there's a simple metric for this, the value of them,
what people pay for them.
That's exactly what I was gonna say. There, there's a book by
Nico Nicole Plot.
This is how they tell me the world will end.
I, I know I talked about this at length and I, I gush over this book all the time,
but it really is that good.
And if you haven't read it, you should read it
because it goes in depth
on this whole, like exploit black market.
And it's fascinating and terrifying.
Well,
-- I
-- like when I worked at eyesight partners and
we were the first company to start buying exploits.
And it's funny because we bought the exploits and
immediately went to the vendors and told them because,
like, we, we didn't want to sit on them. We weren't like the NSO group making spyware.
We just wanted to get stuff fixed,
but by buying them and telling our
customers first and hopefully there's a mitigation,
you know, our customers love us and pay us more money
-- and, and that is covered in depth in this book at the beginning
-- of it.
And like
that is a very good metric of what does the market price this exploit at
is like, what is the value
and not only are exploits worth a lot more money now,
but,
well, like, as we've seen, you know,
the NSO group is churning them out at a pretty quick rate.
Well, no, they're not churning them out. They're buying them at a pretty quick rate.
Well, yeah, that's what I mean, like, they're, they're,
they're going from like a guy found or a person found an exploit to,
it's actually being used to compromise journalists, phones and governments.
Yeah. Right. They weaponized it
-- to an amazing degree.
-- Well, not just weaponized it but they deployed it.
They took the risk of attacking the government.
Right. Like you and I would never do that because we're not,
it's just, that's too risky. It's insane. Right. And what would the benefit be?
I would end up in the river
and I don't mean swimming in the river.
Yeah.
So
again, I don't think this is a controversial point in any way, which of course,
I think adds to this number to a degree.
But
the thing Google calls out in this report and the thing that
I also suspect is true is that we are getting better at detecting
many of these zero days. And I think there's a variety of reasons for this.
And now the one thing, the 11 of the
most interesting things they call out in here is
they mentioned the vendors who self identified the zero days
and there were only two on their list, Microsoft and Google.
And this does not surprise me in any way because both of those companies have
security teams bigger than the total employee count
at most other companies on the planet.
Well, I would, I would like to think Apple is doing this but Apple of course,
is always doing the soft shoe a um what is it?
They'll credit it to an anonymous researcher and say,
quote, Apple is aware of a report that this issue may have been actively exploited,
period.
End quote.
Right. They're super
-- weird about this.
-- They're waffly. But
I, I think a big part of it too is, is as we get other mitigations
and as more importantly,
like I said, if you monitor to the top 1000 journalists globally,
there's 100% chance one of them, uh,
probably more than one of them is going to be
attacked using a zero day in the next year.
-- Yeah. Oh, the next month, I bet.
-- Well, it's just now we know where to go hunting.
And what really blows my mind is I'm looking at these Apple advisors for last month.
There's about five of them that have this, you know, waffle talk about zero days
and there's the usual suspects. Ok. There's like, you know, the I OS 15.41
running on iphones and ipads. Ok. People attack that.
I get that and there's one for, I watch,
like, watch Os.
So people are actually attacking pe, yeah, I know. Right. Watch Os 8.1
released October 25th, 2021. Yeah, like, but I guess people wear watches,
I mean, yeah, they're every, they're everywhere now.
I mean, and not only that, it's not just that they're everywhere,
everyone has them everywhere they go.
Like an easy example is so my son has an Apple watch and he uses it for exercise.
Tracking primarily is his, his goal in having it.
And so,
like,
he'll leave his phone at home and just go out with his
watch because it can do what the magic it needs to do.
And so, even though if you were just watching his phone, you'd see it at home.
But if you're watching the watch now
-- you've got, you've got some details, you know,
-- and it's got a microphone,
like the watch has a microphone.
It could be recording it and I don't know how much storage is on the watch,
but I assume enough to record a low bit rate MP3 for a couple of weeks.
Yeah, probably.
I know he can store over an hour's worth of music on it because the thing also you
can like upload your music just to the watch
and then stream the watch to your Bluetooth headphones.
It's like this is,
-- it, it's wizardry, it's
-- a computer,
-- it's a
-- computer. I mean, you can even get one with the cell phone chips that built in.
-- It's
-- a better computer than I probably had 20 years ago.
-- Like the screen
-- is far better. I love the screen on this thing.
-- So,
-- so the next really interesting data point that's in here
is
of the 58 0 days, 39 67% for, for people who aren't good at math like me
were memory corruption vulnerabilities.
And it was 17 years after free six out of bounds,
read and write four buffer overflows, four integer overflows.
And this is one of those things like
we have been
and by we, I mean, like, the security industry has been harping about memory safety
as long as I can remember and we clearly have not solved it and
I know we've done some amazing things to make it harder to exploit this,
but it clearly isn't enough.
Well, the problem is fundamentally if you're using C or C++ or whatever,
if you're using a not memory safe language,
then there is 100% chance you have a memory corruption bug in your throat.
Yeah, probably more than one
like and it's, and, and that's it. That that's my TED talk. Thank you for coming.
And even if you use a memory safe language like Python or Rust or, or pearl,
the underlying platform has flaws sometimes, right?
Like Python has had memory corruption bugs. So as per
you know us now, but the beauty here is
I can fix Python
and boom. I fixed it for everybody using Python who upgrades.
Whereas if you're looking at specific applications,
well, now you need to patch like a billion specific applications,
you know.
And so I this speaks to remember your talk about, you know, moving security,
the the oas pop 10 list, essentially it's all handled by
sort of three or four classes of issues that are handled by
frameworks and just use a framework to fix all of them.
And I mean, this is even true of memory safety.
I think like a lot of web browsers, for example, are still written in C++ and
C++.
Obviously, we're seeing it,
it's notorious for having memory corruption issues
and this is where there's things like rust
that don't suffer from these problems.
And in fact, there's,
I think I'm seeing more and more efforts in the wild where organizations
are trying
to move things over to rust. Of course, this is going to take time,
but I have a strong suspicion.
It's, it's the only way forward is we can't, humans can't manage the memory.
It's just it, it can't be done. There's,
we've tried it for 50 years, it hasn't worked.
But what's interesting is you can't rewrite all the code.
But what you can do, for example,
like the Linux kernel is a great example of if we could do device drivers in rust.
Well, device drivers are a lot of the attack surface.
You know, file systems are a lot of the attack surface.
That's the stuff Attackers can talk too easily.
And if you can secure that,
then you don't have to rewrite the whole kernel and
Rust just kind of the bits that Attackers talk to.
And same thing with web browsers,
you just brought up a really interesting point is there's
an effort going on right now.
It's part of the open SSF it's not like widely distributed at the moment.
It, it may be more widely after this episode goes out. I don't remember for sure. But
the point is
they're, they're starting to look at like, what can we maybe rewrite and Rust?
And they're taking a very pragmatic approach of saying things like these
are the libraries we're seeing are being attacked on a regular basis
that are written in c what if we start with some of
these and rewrite them in Rust like the portion of them?
Because one of the, the, the reason Rust is obsessed over by,
by security nerds just for everyone listening who might not know
is it's trivial to write code and Rust and then call it from C and so you can
basically just start like replacing shared libraries with Rust
and you get all these benefits of memory management,
but it's also usable by the larger C program.
Whereas many of the other languages, while technically possible to do that,
it's very difficult.
Generally speaking,
well, it lets you do a gradual cut over.
And that's
like if you try and do a, a single cutover,
you're 100% gonna fail because you're gonna encounter at least
one bug that breaks something bad enough that it's unusable.
Whereas this, you can gradually start flipping it over.
The other thing I find fascinating is because
we've talked about this in smart contracts where
one idea for smart contract security is that you write the
smart contract in say two or three totally different languages,
ideally, or if it's the same language, you write it differently
and then you essentially have the contract vote and, you know,
two out of three have to agree.
So that way, if an attacker finds a vulnerability in one
in contract version A,
it's unlikely that that input will also trigger a vulnerability
in contracts B and C because they're written differently.
Right.
And so because there's some contracts out there that are only a
couple 100 lines of code that are handling billions of dollars.
Yes, absolutely.
And so
I, I suspect that will never take off.
It's just too much work and it's too technically sophisticated
and you know what's gonna happen?
Someone's just gonna write like a stupid auto converter
that's gonna auto convert the bugs between language.
You know what I mean?
Well,
you
know,
part of what they talk about is in the research they did is the more differently,
you write the code, the more robust it is right that the,
the two have nothing in common and ideally you
have like two different teams with two different languages
-- but, you know,
-- no one's going to do that. But anyway,
but that's not gonna happen.
It's just not gonna,
what I'm saying is this is not a realistic solution
outside the Blockchain world and even within the Blockchain world,
it's not gonna happen
anyway.
But
it's something where if you tell me
you can start replacing your C code in little Drips.
Oh, I, I can do that
and I think that's part of it is these technologies have to not just do security,
but they actually have to have like a deployment
strategy of how are we going to actually
like, like EV cars are a good example. EV cars are relatively simple in that.
Ok, you buy an EV car, you have to install a charge circuit in your garage. That's it.
There's no step three.
Like for example,
I just ran a new circuit and remembered that my electrical panels full.
So if I buy an EV car, I will have to buy a new electrical panel and
you know, get my entire electrical service upgraded.
But ok, so anyway,
here's
the
point is it's, it's, I know what the path to success is.
Ok.
Yes. But, but there's a big, but here
there has to be an economic incentive for a business to do this.
And I think that's one of the challenges is generally speaking,
if you look at the economic incentives of security,
they don't exist.
There is
you,
you could potentially make the argument that let's
say Google takes the android down this path and
they start replacing tons and tons and tons of
pieces with rust and then they can claim,
oh, we're more secure than I OS.
And that might be true.
And maybe that would get apple to kind of, you know, start a, a,
some sort of arms race in terms of who's more secure.
But
I think generally speaking,
the vast majority of organizations are never going
to find themselves in a situation like that.
Well, to put it bluntly,
your security has to be absolutely terrible for me to switch for security reasons.
Like I am firmly entrenched in the Apple world and Apple is inc, like
they're nice but abusive in some ways and,
but they're gonna have to be incredibly abusive for me to leave
that Apple world because I've tried the Android world and it's worse
-- for me and my kids. Yep.
-- Yep. Now, now on that point
on, on this particular,
I am glad I get to transition in almost a reasonable way.
One of the questions they ask is do some vendors have no known in the
wild Zero days because they've never been
found or because they don't publicly disclose.
And that's a really good,
I would say yes to both in that there are software vendors that are small enough,
nobody cares to target them.
But if they were targeted, it would probably take a few hours to find a zero.
If they're not targeted, then they don't have an in the wild Zero day.
But there are vendors small enough that
in the wild zero day, but they don't have the capabilities to know.
Well, every PHP library ever, every wordpress plug in ever.
Right. Right now. And on that note,
there are also going to be companies that learn about a zero day
and they silently fix it
and they never tell anyone what they found because they're
concerned about the reputational damage it would do to them.
Well,
the legal issues.
Right. They're worried about their customers suing them or, or getting all snarky.
And, I mean, we can confidently say yes, 100% because
we have found out after the fact, like,
look at the way ubiquity handled their breach.
Right. There's companies that have tried to cover this up.
And so I think it's,
and, and more to the point, nobody can argue with us because there's no data.
There's, or rather there's not a lot of data.
There's a few people who tried to cover up and got caught with their pants down.
But in general, by definition, if these companies do that, there's no data.
Well, and even if they get caught,
what really happens,
usually not much.
Yeah.
You know,
I'm just reminded every time I watch the lock picking lawyer where he's like,
you know, if you want to break into something, just here's the set of, like I said,
he sells a set of what it's like seven or 12,
it's the most common keys for like everything.
You know, he's like, instead of, you know, just like, because there's like a what,
10 or 20% chance you'll just click, click or was it like Honda?
I think it was Honda. They all used for the radio frequency fobs.
They all use the same code.
I
remember something.
There was something weird about that that made
it really easy to crack the Honda radio
security, whatever that's called. But no, II, I think
it's an interesting point is there's no incentive
generally speaking for companies to disclose now.
-- Sorry,
-- Honda doesn't use a rolling code.
-- Uh ok.
-- Just record it and replay it. That's what
it was right
now.
We're seeing things like, for example, in the United States, the sec,
the Security and Exchange Commission is starting to
tell companies if you have a breach,
you must report it.
It's not an option.
And so like that,
I think is an interesting aspect of this because now
there is a cost to not reporting a breach.
And the, you know what, you know,
what the best way to not report a breach is don't get breached.
So they're, they're gonna see organizations willing to invest
in security,
not as some insane cost center, but as
like something you have to do.
That's part of the cost of doing business, which I guess is kind of a cost center.
But you get the idea right?
There's an obvious return on that investment.
Yeah, I mean, every sec
10-K filing has that mine safety report, like even Red Hat,
you know, and it just says it doesn't apply to us because we don't own a mine.
But like mine safety was bad enough that every company
to this day still has to report on mine safety
in their
10-K filings.
And, and I have
a I would be very interested to see
like vulnerability disclosure fall under this umbrella
where if you have a vulnerable,
I mean,
granted this is going to be difficult because you think about like we just
mentioned oracles 100 and 50 CV E like how do you report that?
You know,
the filing is gonna be a phone book
maybe, I mean, and maybe that's like an old
phone book, not a not a modern phone book. Those things are skinny nowadays.
But,
and, and II, I don't, I don't know the answer. Right. This is
we're in new territory here,
but I think we can all agree that the way things are working today is unacceptable.
Well, there's also a new elephant in the room
and I'm gonna go there. It's the whole Russia thing because
Russia is grumpy
and
Russia could do a lot of damage to us by say, taking down some power grids now.
Like it's not gonna be the end of the world, but
like I remember the Northeast blackout like that
has a significant economic cost and impact.
Right. Right. To the tunes of billions or tens of billions of dollars.
And,
well, that's,
you know, we're not going to see a Cyber Pearl Harbor like we used to predict,
you know,
with like what North Korean cargo planes dropping paratroopers over the Midwest,
like in um,
you know, Wolverines. What's that damn movie called? Oh,
Red Dawn,
I've never seen,
you know, I've seen like seven movies. And does it have spaceships in it? No.
Does it have wizards in it? No, I haven't seen it
-- anyways.
-- But,
and that's part of the thing is like it, like, again,
we've gone from zero days being like, oh, yeah,
that's a thing that could possibly happen to,
like, you look at the crypto world and
sim swapping to gain access to people's accounts
that that happens all the time now, you know, uh people sending out fake Tresor.
I think it was Tresor
hardware Waltz with like another USB chip soldered in
that. That's like there are the pictures online.
You know, what happened is somebody breached treasure and,
-- and got their customer list and started mailing out wallets to people
-- wild man.
That's wild.
I mean, nothing surprises me, whatever it is what it is. Um
So anyway,
that's kind of the gist of this report.
I think we've hit on the, the things I wanted to discuss that were very interesting.
Now, I want to bring up one last point before we, we are out of time, but I don't care.
I bring it up anyway.
So the, the NSA, there's a joint report that just came out with the what CIA, the NSA,
the FBI,
a bunch of other
security agencies spread across the world. Like New Zealand's in here.
There's the U K's in
here.
Yeah. Right. Right. Can
Canada's in here
and
they, they just say the 2021 top routinely exploited vulnerabilities.
And I, I love these sort of reports,
not because I think it's going to necessarily change anyone's
behavior drastically.
But I think it's helping surface all of this to the top and it,
it makes it harder for us to ignore them.
But the,
the interesting part of all this and I'll link to the report in the show notes,
but nearly every one of these vulnerabilities they point out
have a 2021 year in the CV ID,
which I think is that is telling to me
because it means the Attackers are definitely paying
attention to what's going on and they're definitely
focusing on the newer vulnerabilities rather than some
of the super old crusty horrible stuff.
And
the reason I think that's important is
there there,
I think used to be this prevailing attitude
in the security industry where it was like,
oh, you've probably got some time to patch this.
Like, the Attackers take a couple of months to develop the exploits.
And I think that's probably less true than it used to be.
I just remember like back in eyesight and I defense we had a guy
who every patch Tuesday they picked what
they thought was the top vulnerability and they
basically put him in a room with a pizza and a couple of computers
and then he walked out of there 24 hours later with a proof of concept
pretty much every month.
Yeah. And you think
a decade ago,
you, you'd have to work for someone, like, you know, I defense
and they'd pay you probably well under what you're worth
to do this sort of work.
And now if you can do that,
you could create an exploit and then you could go to
one of these exploit brokers and probably make a year's pay
from one of them.
I mean,
that's,
that's something, you know,
I, I think I,
I keep coming back to the fact that either you're patching
in a reasonable time frame being days or weeks or effectively,
you're not patching.
You know, it's like people who say, oh, I'm,
I'm dieting and they cut their caloric intake by 10 calories like, no, you're not.
Don't mock me, Kurt
anyway. Well, it's ok. Ok.
So here's the parting thought I have on that because I think it's easy to say, oh,
you need to patch and no one's going to disagree with that.
You should definitely be patching.
You should definitely have some sort of patch cadence. However,
I think
we need to create an environment
that is less hostile to the blue team in this context where like, for example,
Google Chrome had a sandbox and when it came out,
it neutered an enormous number of vulnerabilities.
And it's obvious now that the Attackers have
figured out how to get around the sandbox
with,
we'll say a,
a certain amount of ease just given
this particular report we've been talking about.
Yes, thank you.
And I think we, we need
another level and I don't like the technology doesn't exist.
I can't say what it's gonna look like because I don't know,
I don't think it's sand boxing because we're doing that
now and it's less effective than it should be.
But we need some revolutionary thinking in the security industry
to bring us to the next place because as defense,
we need to get ahead of this
and cut the knees off of the Attackers. And that is what we really need to do.
We don't need to just say, oh,
just go pat your stuff because I think that's oversimplifying the problem.
-- I'm going to say, I don't think that's possible.
-- Well, it's not possible yet.
Someone has to invent it. Go invent the future. People come on, get with it. But,
well, but,
but it's an arms race. Right.
And I think I,
I suspect that defense will never be so good that
the Attackers can't win with a reasonable amount of effort.
Oh, no, no, no, they never will be.
I think the Attackers are too far ahead right now and we need to do some catching up.
Oh, it's too easy. Yes, it is.
Well, but, and that's why I'm actually going to disagree. Subtly.
I don't think patching
is something we should beat people up for,
to me patching again.
It's like putting a roof on your house and actually making it waterproof.
It's just, it's part of your basic
it
strategy. Like having electricity
or having keyboards.
Well, you should also have patch management. Like that's just,
-- it's not
-- a, I agree. I agree.
But we need the defense of technologies to buy the patcher more runway.
That's all I'm really saying here.
I don't think they have enough runway,
like they can't get the plane off the ground right now.
Well, and I, I hate to say it, but obviously I'm biased.
I work with the Cloud Security Alliance, but I think a lot of that goes to
outsourcing this stuff to the cloud where, for example,
you have Amazon and Microsoft doing hardware
security co processors on their equipment because
they
can't just take down their virtualization stack to patch it
and, and maybe, maybe that's part of the answer.
-- Like maybe it is, well,
-- especially I think for smaller organizations because,
you know, well, I'm just reminded of all the, uh, restaurants I go to,
they're kind of, uh, I don't know what phrase to use.
It's younger people like hipster people running these
and they're invariably it's a square payment terminal
and they've also got the square
payment terminal integrated with their online store
and everything and it just works and it's perfect and beautiful and it,
I,
I agree.
Versus, you know, these people that try to cobble together their own garbage.
No, the answer is you just pay square.
Yeah,
I, I agree. I agree. I, I think,
and, and maybe that's it. I don't know. I guess this is one of those instances.
We're just gonna have to wait and see what the future is. It, it,
it's interesting. I'll say that.
Well,
I think there's one important piece is
that the level of technology and competency needed
to keep the Attackers out
and even respond to them once, you know,
they're in is growing like the level of sophistication needed
to run a modern network versus like 20 years ago.
And I think like many things, it's just, it's getting out of,
it's not even being priced out,
but it's just not possible for these smaller businesses to even find that talent,
those people all have jobs.
Yeah, it's, it's the relativistic security problem.
I mean, that's, that's what this is, it, it's all expanding
and we're not.
-- Yeah. And
-- I think part of the solution here is to radically,
like, outsource your problem as much as possible.
Like that's what I've done at the CS A
and it works
for not for everybody. Right.
Let's be like if you're on an oil platform in the middle of the North Sea,
I don't know that that's going to work very well for you. But
I, I don't see any
realistic solution for a lot of these
small and medium businesses moving forwards maybe.
I mean, you're, you're framing it in the context of what we have today and,
and II I don't disagree with you though.
I think it's, it's an easy solution to some of these problems.
So, anyway, we're out of time. I'm calling it. This has been, man, this one.
It feels like we started talking seven seconds ago. It's, I love it.
All right. Anyway, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not at Susie Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag Do hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.