Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in thinking about long term things. Josh Pressers.
I do think about long term things more often than I probably should.
I'll admit I have a, I,
I won't say it's impressive but I have a disaster recovery plan for
when I am the disaster and everyone else has to recover from it.
It was funny because I got ac pu upgrade.
Uh, and I had the store do it because last time I did ac pu upgrade, I dropped it
and bent the pins and that was a $200 lesson learned.
Oh, you didn't,
-- you didn't bend the pins back and use it.
-- The pins on a modern CPU are pretty tiny
and these were pretty mashed over.
So, you did? Good, huh?
I, I, well, and I dropped it at like a 45 degree angle. So it just anyway, the point is
so I paid the store and of course the store is like, you know,
you only need your bit locker key. Do you have that? I'm like, yeah, of course, I do.
I have it like, printed in this and they're like, oh, ok.
And it's funny because I had to sign this really,
like multiple initial thing disclaimer for like,
they're not going to back up my data.
I'm like, damn. Right. You're not backing up my data. That's my data. I'm keeping it.
It's encrypted. I don't want you touching it.
But it's funny because I had to sign all and they're like, is this,
I'm like a back blaze and like, oh, ok.
-- You know, I mean,
-- but how do they know you're not just some new,
who has no idea what's going on?
-- Because I
-- initialed the form that says if they screw. Well, the thing is,
it's, it's to protect them. Right.
If they mess up my computer while they're working on it,
I initialed a thing saying, like, I don't have backups and that's, or they,
I didn't pay them to back it up before they worked on it.
-- Really? Right.
-- Oh, I see. That's what they were trying to do.
They were trying to scare you into buying a backup service from them, weren't they?
Well, maybe, I
don't know, don't care.
I just would have brought it in without a hard drive and then, like, here you go.
And I mentioned that to them.
I'm like, actually I would have removed the, the M two drive,
but then I'd have to remove the video card which, like,
there's so many screws to take out. That's true. Some of those do that.
Yeah, because my, my
PC has two video cards. So one video card
-- covers up the M two slot,
-- right?
-- Because you claim you're doing a, I
-- work, I am. It, it's quite funny.
-- I
-- suspect you're mining Cryptocurrency
-- like a net negative loss
-- monkey NFTS Kurt.
I think those are illegal now.
But
I think they're illegal. They're just stupid.
Yeah. So,
yeah, it's, uh,
it's,
it's nice though because I have 16 cores now and
this machine should last me probably two more years.
So you can play Minecraft like a
boss.
Yeah.
Well, see,
the thing is all the Ryzen 5000 CP US are
on sale everywhere because it's the end of the era.
So, either I buy it now on sale or I pay antique prices next year.
What comes next, Ryzen 7000 AM five?
Oh, ok. Right. And they're, they're great. They're affordable. They're solid.
-- But they don't run in this AM four board.
-- Oh,
-- I
-- see.
I couldn't tell you what my board has on my desktop.
I would assume it's, if it's less than a year old or if it's more than a year old,
it's probably AM four.
It's
about a year old.
-- I don't
-- m five
then.
Probably not because I'm a cheap skate. So I doubt I would buy the expensive stuff.
Oh,
it's not that much more expensive.
It would have been there, you know. Anyways.
But, yeah, thinking long term.
So wordpress released a thing where they're basically going to, for $38,000.
I know, like, run your website for 100 years all in DNS, running the website,
everything.
Well, well, well, it's not 100% clear on the DNS side because, ok,
so somebody pointed out wordpress does own dot blog the TLD,
which makes sense. For example, like wordpress can't.
-- Well, for example, we have that GSD dot id, which is over $2000 a year,
-- right?
I'm sure you have to use a TLD they approve of because I mean,
it says on their website it's a century long domain registration.
A domain is blah, blah, blah, planned
you an opportunity to secure your domain for a full century.
Yeah, I assume it's like thought blog because they control the pricing on that,
right?
-- Of course,
-- because.com could
one day be 1000 bucks a month
or a year, whatever.
Sure. Whatever. I'm just gonna start this out by saying
there is no way
-- wordpress is going to be around in 100 years. All right,
-- see. And
ok, let me interrupt you for a second. What's older Canada or the New York Times?
-- I have
-- no idea. The New York Times is about 16 years older than Canada as a country.
Look 1851.
I'm pretty sure the New York Times in 1851
didn't anticipate being around in 100 and 50 years.
I bet they did. I bet they did
there are industries that I would be comfortable
saying will exist for 100 years now,
in a, in 100 years from now, will the New York Times exist?
And I would say no, because I think
the world of print media has changed drastically in 100 years. Will Ford exist.
-- Maybe, I don't know, it's hard to say
-- Ford's a financing company now. So, yes,
they're a financial firm with that happens to make cars too
unless people stop buying cars.
-- Yeah,
-- but they'll go into some other debt financing.
Maybe it's possible.
But anyway, anyway, OK.
G
capital. And
here is what I love.
Here's the thing I thought when I saw this and I'll just start there. Right.
Ignoring the fact that I just said wordpress won't be around in 100 years,
which I still suspect is true.
But
when I saw this, it reminded me of,
remember when we were young and there
was the obsession with cryogenically freezing yourself.
-- Yep.
-- Still a thing.
-- It is still a
-- thing. I was actually watching a documentary on
and it's actually cheap now. It's like 200 grand. I mean,
sure
out
of your head. I think it's more if you want your whole body, just your head.
I don't know.
-- But the point is, well, think
-- about it, like a head is a lot smaller than the body.
-- Like,
-- well, but
here's the thing,
like how many,
there are an enormous number of those cryogenic freezing companies that went
out of business and no one knows what happened to the people.
-- They had frozen.
-- Technically, they're not people because they're dead.
I don't know.
You get the idea.
And I think
it is easy to say we're going to be around for a
bazillion years because every company thinks that it wants to be obviously.
And I think as humans, it's easy to be like, oh,
I'll pay this company and they'll thaw my frozen corpse out in,
in 500 years and cure whatever horrible disease killed me or whatever.
And
-- not very many of those are working out.
-- Right.
Well, it's interesting to me is in Canada,
we actually have some laws around lifetime membership stuff
and I know there's like a specific exemption for cemeteries
where they can essentially sell a thing. And
with the promise of this long term,
I don't want to say lifetime membership. But,
well, you know what I mean? Right.
Like this long term,
like you buy this plot and we'll own this land and maintain it and whatever.
Because if you look at K law,
my understanding is that the vast majority of leases
and contractual agreements are limited to 99 years.
-- I mean,
-- so
that's another good example of
things like cemeteries are valid until they're not.
So one of my favorite things I learned,
if you go to the east coast of the United States,
like Boston is an example, there's like cemeteries you can go tour, right,
and you walk around and they've got all the headstones and
you can see like famous people and all that stuff.
And at one point I made a comment about how
it was remarkable how the headstones were lined up. Very nice.
Even though there was a tree that probably wasn't there.
And the guy was like, oh, no, no,
these were like a, a shambled mess, like 50 years ago. We everyone like
tied up.
Yeah, they just basically stuck them in a nice straight row and we're like, there,
the headstones are in a row now.
Like no one knows where anyone has actually been
in that cemetery.
And I feel like a lot of this 100
year plan,
like this long term stuff is basically that like wordpress
says they're going to run your site for 100 years.
But it's gonna be like, oh,
we have to go pull all these headstones out of this pile in
the corner and we'll just line them up and make them look pretty.
Ok. Everybody, it's fine.
Well, you know, just take a static, it's like sea.org,
it's just a static blob in an S3 bucket
that I haven't updated in 15 or 20 years.
The DNS record and the MX record are the only two that matter, right?
Like, keep that DNS paid for and keep the MX record alive
and see this is the thing, people, I actually have a friend
who basically through no fault of her own forgot like she didn't renew her DNS.
Yeah, people do that all the time.
And so it has been an utter nightmare because for example,
if you want to change your name with the website, sure, no problem.
You want to change your birthday
probably. Ok. But you want to change your email address.
Well, you can't because that's key to your account
and,
and especially if you don't have control of that email address anymore.
Even if it's completely bouncing. Like this, it a spammer grabbed the domain.
I tried to buy it back. Didn't work,
you know. And so it's just gone. It's like seafood.com, I did not register it.
And then like a month after I registered seafood do work, somebody grabs sea.com
and now so for going on
20 fiveish whatever years,
like
it's just, it's this like weird dead
thing on the internet.
-- Like it just doesn't work. Yeah,
-- I know.
And so the same thing happened with, with me because I own breast.net and I,
I did it by breast.com and in fact, now it's for sale and it was for sale a long time ago.
I wonder how much they want for it.
Not that I'd pay for it. But
-- anyway, but like,
-- yeah, it drives me nuts because like the,
the domain name is like that is my number 10 my God.
I will get yelled at so much at work if I let Claude
career lines.org ever lapse
-- right. There will be so much yelling.
-- That would be a bad thing.
Didn't, then did that happen to like Hotmail or something?
And someone, like, bought it just to
fix their email and gave it to Microsoft?
So, I mean, and that's the thing you can, you can, you can
register your domain name up to 10 years out in the future.
-- And that's the rule I can't, doesn't let you do that.
-- I don't do more than 10
-- because I do it every year.
-- Well, you can't do more than 10.
-- Well,
-- but, but the point is I, I actually, I do it on purpose.
I only, I do one year at a time domain registration.
That way, I won't forget
because
I have 10 years to forget
that
every
year and that's fine.
Except I get a nag mail from my registrar.
Hey, you better do this, like you better do this right now.
And so I feel like it gives me that,
that sense of urgency.
-- I need to not forget and
-- seems like there's a lot of business stuff where, you know,
things need to be done once a year.
And I mean, this goes back to a lot of our discussions about security and how,
if you don't do something on the regular, you forget how,
like if you don't do something at least once a week,
you're gonna forget how to do it every year when I mow the lawn.
I'm like, uh, how does this work again?
You know, and I'm like, bashing my mower up against stuff and, you know,
by midsummer I've kind of remembered my mowing pattern.
I think the thing is
what I don't quite understand is what business or, or,
or organization or individual has $38,000 kind
of lying around to avoid this problem.
That is,
you know what I mean?
Like, like if I could buy a life, like if I could buy a 99 or 100 year,
uh safe deposit box at the bank, I
-- would consider that
-- some banks
will probably be around
-- well
-- and more to the point they're regulated.
So even if they're not around their next,
next next incarnation will still be around,
-- you know.
-- So. Ok. Ok, we, we uh this one is gonna be so hard to stay on track.
What I'm trying to figure out is what is the market here who has $38,000
and kind of wants to set it and forget it and not have to worry about it.
Ok.
-- I think there's a market for this because I think,
-- well,
obviously they're doing it well, at least one person will buy it.
-- There's a rocket for pet rocks though.
-- I think a lot of people will, I mean,
look,
look at all of the foundations and charitable trust and all that stuff that exists,
right?
But you need,
like you need a scary amount of money to set up like
a proper charitable trust and foundation that survives for hundreds of years.
And those exist. Like, there's, there's what the Carnegie Foundation
and things like that. Those are really old now.
Just go watch public TV for a while and you'll get a list of them.
I watch a lot of public television,
Arthur Foundation. I'm like, what,
now?
My favorite is when the Coke Foundation donates to Science Channel
science shows. And I'm like,
that one's weird
but
good for you.
Good.
Yes,
it's fine oil. The planet loves oil. Everybody keep burning it.
So anyway,
there's,
there's a lot in between.
Right.
When you go from having like gazillions of dollars to set
up your crazy trust fund to people who basically die with nothing
-- or less than nothing. Well,
-- that's true.
But there's that, that slice in the middle
and I think
it is human nature to want to believe we will be remembered in perpetuity.
And there is almost certainly a group of people that will believe that
if I pay Wordpress $38,000 now that no one will forget who I am
and my offspring in 100 years will pay more.
I, I don't know, I don't know what the end game of that is like,
what happens after the 100 years does like?
And then they just delete your website,
-- but
-- you re up it like whatever inflationary triggered rate
you're going to be logged dead in 100 years.
Yeah.
Well, and that's why I love it.
It's, it says, like, literally, it says crafting legacies one century at a time.
Right.
So, I think you're right, they're going for that sort of
-- artisanal. Like,
-- I think it is like, right, nobody
will look at your website.
I can't afford a foundation but I can pay for this website. So
-- that's my suspicion.
-- You know what? Actually, now that you mention it.
Yeah, it, for some people, $38,000 for a conversation starter worth it. No, really.
-- But
-- you know what? You know what I love?
Here's a better question. Will the internet archive exist in 100 years?
I hope so.
I could see them getting sued out of existence by some media company.
That's what scares me right now.
And, well, they're, they're being sued by everybody right now.
They have an adversary that would love to see them die
just like kind of like those people that were like,
well,
maybe Elon Musk bought Twitter so that essentially a bunch of business
interests could kill off Twitter because they don't like it because it's
like, no Twitter historically
that
was used to pants and to like, really embarrass a lot of
that is significant
interest. I
ascribe almost always to the Hanlon's theory of stupidity over anything else that
I would
like
the guy.
I mean, the whole horse air
travel.
Just, yeah, just Google Elon Musk. Horse, air travel.
-- I, I'm not even gonna say
-- the rest of the,
don't know what this means.
We're gonna look
it
up.
It's gonna
air travel.
Yeah.
-- Or horse bribe. Maybe horse bribe is better.
-- Uh. Oh, interesting. Ok. Whatever.
-- Yeah, exactly. Right. Like the man is clearly not, that, that's
-- fair.
That's fair.
-- That's
-- not impressive.
Anyway,
also, horses are expensive, like, they're literally a free horse is not a gift
like a
puppy.
But
anyway,
-- I
-- feel
and maybe that's, I just again, I guess some rich person who, you know,
also would spend a quarter million dollars on
car again to have a conversation piece.
Right? So people have a lot of money and like you and I
-- spend how much on a cup of coffee?
-- That's very little because I'm a huge cheap skate.
-- So I purposely buy coffee in bulk and make it at home.
-- Ok.
Again, how much is that microphone you're speaking into?
The microphone is a different story.
It's totally justifiable.
-- It's just like this car.
-- It's not, it's not the, it's not the one I want.
We'll say that there's no good Lord someday.
But anyway, anyway,
so, I mean, it's, I,
but it kind of brings up this,
like if I could register a domain name like s.org or the Clouds
lines.org 100 years out, I totally would just to not have to worry about
missing that bill and like, oops,
but it is offset by like you were saying earlier about the whole,
having that sort of operational cadence of like, ok,
every year we do my birthday and DNS registration.
You know, like every year we have uh when is National Smoke Alarm Day?
-- That's in like spring, I wanna say, right. I,
-- the, the clock setting is what I use.
When you change your clocks, you change your batteries.
Uh oh, it's in October.
It's, and there's a test your smoke alarm day, which is probably not the worst idea.
I do like the modern smoke alarms. I have like a built in battery.
They last for 10 years and then they just chirp and beep until you get fed up and, like,
throw them away and buy new ones
because, like, 10 years is long enough that, like, I'm not, I don't remember, like,
I actually have taken to writing on the bottom now when I
put it in,
oh, mine come with, uh, the ones I have have a date, like,
stamped on the bottom of it when it was manufactured.
-- But
-- then it sat in a
store for six months or a year or two years.
Mine was installed very quickly after it was manufactured.
So
I
just,
it on mine.
Same with my fur,
my furnace filters. Actually, I've noticed now have a spot to write on them
for the date.
They've always had that curt,
have they?
Oh, I never noticed on the one inch ones
-- anyway.
-- Anyway.
Well, now that I'm buying those big five inch ones that are like,
-- cheap,
-- every furnace filter is made of cardboard.
-- You can write anywhere on it you like?
-- Well,
yeah.
No, I know
in principle, like, with a
given that I own sharpies, I can pretty much everything I can write on
-- of like, water.
-- I have so many sharp
because my kids keep taking them and I just keep buying more and
then every now and then they like appear and like there's 30 sharpies.
I was actually thinking about this the other day,
I had to buy more USB C cables because like I've run out
and I'm like,
-- thank you, thank you for reminding
-- me. No,
you can do this when we're done.
But
like these USB C cables someday I'm gonna like clean
my house and find 700 USB C cables because they probably
under the couch or something. Ok. Anyway, 100 year
we, we are so off topic on this but I think it's a weird topic.
-- It's hard to talk
-- about it. I suspect
the number of organizations and people that will
buy this 100 year thing on wordpress.com.
Like I would guess low single digits percentage of them will still
be around in 100 years in some way shape or form.
-- I mean,
-- none of us will. That's the intent, right? Is that the people who buy
-- organizations
-- or families
or there's
no,
I mean, look,
this is, I think
a good
thing to think about in the context of disaster recovery. Right.
-- When we talk
-- about reg just regular operational, like paying your water bill,
like I just got my phone bill and it's double
because apparently I forgot to pay my phone bill last month.
That happens. Sometimes I could swear I paid it online.
I got to double check my bill payment.
-- I guess
-- you got to do that too sometimes because I, I know I've had instances where
the bank sends a check to the company because they didn't sign
up with like the magic bill pay thing and they lost my,
the check disappeared one time. I'm like, what happens if it appears
they were like, well, we're going to cash it. I'm like, then what,
like
on your
account, I ended up, I got the check canceled it, cost me some money.
But I'm like, I'd rather just cancel it and not worry about it anyway. Ok.
So
this is the perfect example of stuff falls between
the cracks and then your phone gets turned off.
But, but in this case, you just pay $38,000.
-- Nothing can fall through the cracks assuming Wordpress
-- exists.
I mean, look, let's pretend Wordpress exists in 100 years. Right?
And this is where I think
we can put on.
I mean, is IB ma 100 years old? I bet they're close
and look, it, maybe they'll exist.
Maybe they won't, I don't think they will but that's another story. 1911.
Like I have a suspicion,
the web as we know it will cease to exist at some point in the future.
But that's a different story.
I want to talk about this in the context of
disaster recovery because I think security people like disaster recovery,
right.
Disaster recovery is, is a risk management tool.
Well,
it's one of the few boogeymen we have
because it does happen often enough and often makes
the news because quite a few of these companies
-- experience a disaster and then don't recover
-- who,
who has ever gone out of business because they didn't,
well, they weren't able to restore their data.
Like there's a company that hosting provider in Denmark
that just told all their customers,
like you better go to internet archive to get your websites
back because remember they got ransom word and it's all gone.
I don't remember that,
but that's probably a good example of
there are varying levels of disaster recovery,
right?
Someone like wordpress is going to have a vastly
superior disaster recovery program as opposed to you.
And I,
right,
you would hope so. I'm certain they do.
I'm certain they do from everything I've read
about wordpress and everything I know about wordpress.
They do a lot. Right.
They do a lot. Right. They're good. They're good and smart people.
Are you looking for the hosting provider that fails?
I'm looking for a list of, because I've seen a list of companies that, like,
had a disaster and then went out of business 6 to 18 months later.
In a lot of cases, the reason they go to business
is because they can no longer manage their cash flow.
They don't know who owes the money and they can't enforce it.
And of course, a lot of your customers, depending on what you do for a living,
probably aren't going to step up and be like, hey, we owe you money here.
It is for sure. No one does that right. They're going to keep a low profile and like,
you know, be like, I guess we got to find a new supplier for widgets
and look. Ok. So, so that's kind of the,
that's where I was going to go with all this I was hoping to get to is
if you look at wordpress 38 grand, right?
That's a lot of money today. 38 grand in 100 years.
Assuming we keep up with inflation the way we are, it will be a cup of coffee.
38 grand isn't going to be a lot of money. Probably the price of of what a
computer, maybe not even. I mean, it's hard to say, right?
You figure I look 100 years ago, a car costs like $500 and now a car costs $50,000.
That's
an interesting tact to take because for example,
also uh a house servant cost like X dollars,
but clothing was expensive and now clothing
is cheap and house servants are expensive.
Right. So
hard to.
So, uh here we go. The average rate of inflation over the last 100 years
in the US is 2.93%. So
3%
102.
What is that?
So, whatever that is in like
1.0293 to the power of 100 is about 18. so 38,000 divided by 18, about two grand in
100 years,
-- assuming the current rate of inflation and all that.
-- Right. Right. Right.
And, and that Wordpress is still there.
And
so from,
from a disaster recovery perspective of someone alive today
wanting to keep something alive for 100 years,
-- it's a pretty good investment in that regard. Right.
-- Well, it also
potentially, you know, I suspect the problem is more the organizational, you know,
institutional knowledge and stuff and,
and handing that off to Wordpress and just having them deal with all that stuff.
-- And
-- so that's where it starts getting more bizarre, I think is so, in 100 years,
what happens if you have some sort of next of kin?
Well, that's just it. Right. Right. Right. What happens then
I assume before then they start
making you to re up but you're dead.
Well, but somebody's gonna have, like, there's gonna be some
email address on that website or something or some log in to update it.
Or, you know,
-- like there'll be some ongoing contractual
-- gmail is deleting
Gmail accounts that are two years inactive now.
So the email will
just,
and it's fine.
-- But
-- I mean,
even myself,
I have a company I'm incorporated and I
have a 25 year relationship with my accountant.
Right. Like these, this 2550 year relationship
between businesses and individuals is not abnormal. It's pretty normal, actually
practical.
It is practical.
-- And
-- I mean, in theory, you know,
my son Felix will take over the mantle of doing it stuff and
you know, so like siefried and sons, I don't know,
-- I
-- have instructions for my family for my demise to take care of the,
the my domain because there are emails there too.
My accountant is his last name and associates and it
-- was his dad and now I'm with his son.
-- Sure.
Sure. Like, I mean, that's fair.
It's plausible.
Look, there's one other important piece to this,
I think where we're gonna run ourselves out of time before we get to it.
Unless I, I'm just gonna make us talk about it. We are standing on the precipice
of massive disruptive change coming to the planet.
And I don't mean
just like the internet being created disruptive change.
I mean, the fact you look at like we have climate change,
we have economic issues.
We have a generation of people that have been repressed
economically compared to their parents and grandparents.
-- They're not going to be able to afford
-- a house.
-- They, they can't afford cars right now. Like, it's true.
-- Oh, my God.
I actually, sorry, I got to interrupt,
over this weekend I was looking at cars online, used cars specifically.
My car is worth about 50% more than what I paid for it.
I
believe that
it's a,
and
here's what really got me in Canada, there's a thing called Go
Auto. They're terrible. They're terrible, terrible, terrible.
But they're like, nationwide and massive.
And for example,
they only have something like on the order of
just over 10,000 cars in their inventory right now.
-- Is that not a lot? I don't know,
-- 10,000 cars for a country of 40 million people.
-- Well, I assume you have other car dealerships, right?
-- But I mean,
go drive by them. The lots are not full of cars. Like they used to be like, there's
like straight up, you drive by, like, I live near dealership Row and like,
you drive down dealership Row, there's new cars
and, oh, that's the other thing that blew my mind.
Like, I drive a Kia optima like just a four door car with not enough cup holders,
but like a Kia Sport
ta for example, like, which is a totally bog standard SUV,
they're like 40 to $50,000 Canadian New now. And I'm like,
like in my brain,
a car that costs $50,000 has like a BMW or a Mercedes badge on the front of it.
Not
-- a random South Korean carmaker.
-- They used to.
-- Not anymore.
-- Right. And I,
like, I'll be blunt, I can't afford to buy a new car.
Like I literally,
I'm
not spending 50 grand on a new car. Are you insane?
And like a used car comparable to what I have would be 15 to $20,000 like
bonkers.
No, I know. I hear you, man.
I'm in the same boat. I don't like cars so I don't buy nice cars.
But yeah, it's, it's completely out of control for sure.
-- Yep. Yep.
-- Like there is because,
ok, look,
here's, here's the point, right? I'm getting us back on track.
This precipice of disruptive change is not going to end
in a way that is conducive to many of the existing
players in
the capitalist market,
right?
So like Wordpress has had massive success up to this point.
But I think
will they in 100 years? We don't know.
And I think this is really the question I think about is less so about like,
will wordpress exist in 100 years?
Will any internet companies exist in 100 years?
-- Will the internet exist in 100 years?
-- So, TCP/IP and htps will be around us like
10 digit phone numbers. Like that'll just still be a thing in 100 years.
Maybe we don't know that. I
-- mean,
-- I PV six will definitely still be kicking around.
We
don't
know
that I
can get off I PV
-- four, I mean,
-- probably,
but I PV four will probably still exist in 100 years at the rate we're going.
But you know what I mean?
Like this is, this is the things I keep thinking of is,
is thinking in terms of 100 years right now,
I feel like is a very
risky and unknown thing to do.
It's kind of like, again,
my disaster recovery example that we never actually
got into because we keep derailing ourselves.
But like
when I have a disaster recovery plan,
my disaster recovery plan is generally for one,
maybe two years of disaster recovery, right?
Because I know going past that
is a waste of my time and it really isn't going to matter
because in two years,
my company might be twice the size it is now, it might be bankrupt.
You know what I mean?
Well, and part of it a great example uh I love is a, I like all the things we wanted.
A I and thought a I would be good at like driving cars.
-- I know I'm so angry about that
-- turns out they're terrible.
But a
lot of things a I that nobody would have ever guessed like here I,
I keep abreast of all these new a
illm companies because there's some really cool stuff.
So for example, there's a new one out
and what they do is you take a picture of your plate.
And it does a calorie count.
So it does visual recognition of your food and roughly how much food is there
and what it is and gives you a rough calorie count of your plate,
which for a lot of people who are sort of trying to diet.
Well, when I go to a restaurant or something,
they don't all include their calorie counts or if I make it at home or whatever.
And so this is to me a, such a wonderful example of something that is so
unexpected and like, oh, wow, I never thought of that, but a 12th pitch of it is like,
oh, yeah, that's kind of a cool idea.
I would pay like a dollar a month for that,
which is easy, you know,
like there's all these A I things where it's actually really good
at these stupid little problems that actually solve real problems for people but
nobody ever anticipated.
Well, and that the technology goes like this. Like, it's
all this stuff that the web we thought it was going to do turns out no,
like people actually do just want to buy stuff online and like
the whole,
the internet will help educate people because blah,
blah information will be freeing people.
Like,
like nos,
-- like the truth is paywall, then the lies are free.
-- Kurt. Exactly.
Well, the propaganda is free or worse.
They're fucking being pushed because right, they,
they're willing to pay to make people read it,
um, like that whole fif when I found out about that 15 minute city thing.
I'm like, what now like,
and then the best part is they had a protest about the 15 minute cities locally
on the one street, White Avenue area. That is an actual walkable part of the city. I,
I love the idea. Like, I, I purposely built my life around the idea of a 15 minute city.
Did we talk about that? I don't remember if it was a podcast might have been
for anyone who doesn't know what we're talking about.
There's this concept,
some researchers created known as a 15 minute city being like,
yeah. Right. Like most, most cities will call it
where the idea is.
You should have like a doctor in a grocery store
and the things you need to live and survive a
15 minute walk from your house. Right.
Imagine, draw a circle around your, where you live 15 minute walk and you want like
the ability to survive within that circle.
But then
some insane right wing propaganda group said that the government's going to
make you stay within a 15 minute radius of your house.
And if you leave, they're gonna shoot you or something.
And it's like, oh my goodness, you people are like, you're so dumb,
it just hurts Steve
you about it. But anyway,
it, I, I love the idea. Like I want to live a 15 minute walk from everything.
Like I purposely, it's comical because my eye doctor and my,
the Pete Park lady who cuts my hair
and
there's my dentist and like an enormous number of things. I do.
I, I pick them because they're close to my house.
And then it's funny. It's like, oh, did you walk here?
I'm like, yes, because I can see my house from here. Like, that's why I had come here.
Yeah.
And it's great.
But, so I think part of it is the, the, and maybe, and this is part of hedging,
your bet is
we as a person or an organization,
maybe can't handle 100 years worth of change very gracefully.
But in theory, a company, like wordpress,
a tech company that has handled quite a bit of change
hopefully does a better job of that than we do.
-- I mean,
-- you look, they might be able to,
well,
it's just the classic sort of outsourcing of risk and expertise because,
I mean, that's why I have an accountant because I don't
account,
but they won't be your accountant in 100 years. Kurt
because you'll be dead.
There's well, true.
But like,
there's a ton of companies that use the same accounting firm for like 100 years.
Like that's,
-- there's a lot of that.
-- I, I won't.
That is probably true. And I'm sure there are 100 year old accounting firms
in the world. Like, I don't
deny that
there are 100 year old things that exist.
My,
my other favorite quote I read about this story when I was
reading it was what did the internet look like in 1923?
I was like, oh, that's a good one. Well done, sir.
And I get it, I get it.
I, I feel like anyone who looks at this should be skeptical
because I think wordpress is
they, they pulled apr stunt and it worked because like even we're talking about it.
So Bravo, to you wordpress
in Fairness,
Van
Bush's essay, as we may think did come out in 1945 which is almost 80 years ago.
But
whatever. So that as we may think is sort of one of the considered one of the,
the,
I don't want to say cornerstones, but one of the founding
thought experiments around the internet, so to speak.
No, I would say that's like claiming the wheel
is when we invented cars.
Well,
I'm not saying invented but kind of where we started thinking about these things.
The wheel is not when we invented cars.
That's what I'm saying.
Anyway,
we've been,
we've been rambling on about this for a long time and I guess
all in all, here's what I'll close with Bravo wordpress, forgetting everyone
to talk about you
and you've done literally nothing
-- to accomplish
-- that.
They serve something like 30% of the world's internet sites.
They do, but we take them for granted all the time.
Like the only time I feel like we ever talk
about wordpress is when there's some horrific security worm,
like ravaging the internet.
43.1%.
I believe that like, this,
this podcast is hosted off of wordpress because it's easy.
I pay them, like, $20 a year or something.
And I get a website out of it. Like, you can't beat that.
I, 43% of any market, especially the internet is,
-- that's a lot.
-- Well, it, ok.
No, no, not necessarily because they might host 43% of the websites.
But I bet they serve like 1% of the internet traffic.
-- I bet it's very low because it's random crap like
-- us. Hang on a sec.
Uh, Wordpress Power is 36.28% of the top million websites.
-- I bet
-- there are 10 websites in the top million that are 80% of the traffic.
Oh, yeah, there's a long sale.
It's proto
distribution. Absolutely.
But
still
almost, you know, 36% of the top million websites is a lot.
-- It,
-- it, it is an impressive company. I'm not gonna,
and I, I'm gonna pitch. There's a book I read called The Year Without Pants.
That is a,
this is literally the name of it because wordpress
was one of the first companies to have a,
a fully remote workforce for a long time.
And there is, this author basically took a job there as a manager
and worked there for like a year
and, well, maybe more than a year.
But then they wrote a book about their experience and
what it was like and how the company works.
And it is
a truly remarkable organization.
My favorite thing they do and they still do this
because I just talked to someone not long ago about it
when you get a job at. Well, it's,
it used to be called automatic. I don't know if it still is
the company behind wordpress.
Everyone start no matter what job you have, you spend like a month in support
like full stop.
Oh,
we talked about this like at the bakery they had their new lady who's
gonna be doing social media marketing stuff like working in the front of house.
I think it is hugely beneficial.
I mean, to be blunt,
that's why I have two video cards is so I can run A I workloads locally
and not speak about it hypothetically but speak about it from the sense of like,
yeah, six months ago, this was impossible
and now it's
a pain in the butt but it works
and it's steadily, you know what I mean?
Like and I've there is a real value to not
necessarily knowing all of the business or necessarily understanding it,
but at least having experienced it
and having maybe some empathy or compassion and thinking
about those 2nd and 3rd order effects of like,
oh, like
for example, like
banks
were like, oh automated tellers. That'll be great.
And then they realized, no, no, no, because the bank
can sell.
And so now when you go to the bank, they're always like, oh, we,
we've noticed you only have seven mortgages with us.
Would you like
a, uh,
an insurance
credit
card?
Right.
You know, same thing with Costco, right?
Like, I assume that they get a beating if they don't ask me to upgrade my membership.
And I'm like, I'm already an executive member. It can't upgrade. There's
no
like,
well, I get like 2% back and it pays for itself.
-- So I'm like, cool, I get all my pants there.
-- That's a weird correlation code.
But how many pants do you buy?
Like
probably two pairs a year from Costco
-- and then the rest from like Marks or Quarles? Because I'm a dad. Like
-- anyway, ok,
-- I literally dress like somebody who buys all their t-shirts at Costco because I
-- do,
I feel like every time I try to steer us on the track you
like grab the wheel and pull it as hard as you can into traffic.
That's my job.
I just,
I
think, I wish there was more of this long term type stuff.
But my fear is you get like a ba a back blaze situation where remember they just,
this week went from,
there's a bunch of people using our unlimited business
plans to just abuse the bejesus out of it.
We gotta, we gotta stop this because it's killing us. Right.
Google did this a few years ago where we
were paying Google for works suite and unlimited storage.
And then now it's two terabytes per user, which I'm like, ok.
-- Yeah,
-- I do remember that.
Yeah, I know when I was, when I was at Elastic, we definitely abused that.
Like all of our Zoom meetings went into a Google Drive
and we had like literally terabytes and terabytes of Zoom meetings.
I have to back up our youtube channel and it's like,
ok, Drake and drop,
you know,
because it doesn't fit and get unless I pay them
and S3 bucket will charge us like $2 a month.
-- That's what
-- glacier for.
You can put stuff in glacier for nothing until you have to take it out.
Which anyway, I'm gonna,
I'm going to bring this one home. It's time to be done.
I, I feel like
it is an interesting conversation piece that Wordpress has created.
And I do think there is a discussion point around like a digital legacy
which we did not really discuss today. But for example,
when our parents died,
I have an aunt who passed away not long ago and they gave me a
bunch of old like newspaper clippings and
scrapbooks and things she had put together.
I don't have this,
I don't know what to do with it really because I feel bad throwing it away.
But I also don't really want it
but like,
-- you know what I mean?
-- Is that content available on the internet?
Uh, most of it is, yes, it's mostly old newspapers.
But the point is like,
we can't give a box of pictures to anyone anymore and be like, here you go.
And so I don't think a website like,
like wordpress is doing is necessarily the answer
because from my perspective,
like my pictures I think are vastly more valuable than like my crappy website.
My website, I'm not gonna lie, breast.net is a work of art. But
other than that, no one, my kids have no idea what it is. They think it's dumb.
But if, if you looked at it, anyone listening would probably look at it and be like,
that's very nice.
Well done, sir.
But
the point is like, I do think that this digital legacy is an important topic that we,
no one really talks about
and
this isn't it?
-- But we see
-- and once OK, just to completely segue,
one thing I find fascinating about the downfall of
Twitter is all the people that have left Twitter but
downloaded all of their data from Twitter.
I did that and I personally did not, I started it and then I'm like, I don't care.
I deleted it and just deleted
and I realized
-- who cares
-- I did. I did. You know why?
Because I had some memes I had uploaded to Twitter that I knew I wanted.
And in fact,
I've I've now basically extracted them and put them into my meme folder on my phone.
-- So I have them for later. But
-- like, I really can't see that
personal Twitter data set outside of a very few corner cases being at
all.
No,
it's totally like family pictures of my vacation that I'm gonna
make people look at type stuff that no one really wants.
But,
but again,
all this digital content,
we have no way to preserve it.
Really like the internet archive is the only thing that exists today.
I don't think what Wordpress is doing is the answer.
But I think it's an interesting conversation
that we should have another day that is not today.
All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening to
Ramble on for 40 minutes.
Go to
or security
podcast.com. Find the show
Not
Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.