Hello and welcome to episode 99 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, do you know the email address of a good GDPR consultant? I could get a hold of Kurt.
Yes,
but I can't give it to you,
but I'm,
ah, ha ha
ha ha
ha.
I'm shocked at apparently how many recruiting
companies have my information in Europe.
And I'm a little puzzled because
I haven't ever worked in Europe
-- or tried to work in Europe.
-- Doesn't matter.
-- So, like,
-- welcome to
-- the world.
-- Did they just scrape linkedin? I don't know.
I,
I imagine there are countless reasons
that they have your information
and, and I guess this is, I mean, whatever,
it's good and funny enough this does tie in with,
with the topic for the day of consumer security is,
I mean, whether you're in Europe or not,
this is going to give consumers a certain level
of control over their data they've never had.
And I will ignore the political discussion around it.
But I mean,
I think fundamentally this is not going to be a bad thing at the end of the day.
I,
ok. I think it won't be a bad thing for consumers. I think it
is
going to be problematic for smaller firms, especially start ups,
largely because of the unknowns. Right. We, it hasn't settled down yet. Right.
We don't have precedent. We don't,
we don't actually know like how much and
how hard they're going to enforce certain things
and we don't.
But so here's kind of the one fundamental takeaway from all of this is
in the context of something like GDPR.
They're not there to get you right.
This isn't like some, some court case where there's a winner and there's a loser.
You,
you have what is essentially the people who want to make sure GDPR gets
enforced and then there's the people who have to deal with it and,
and the enforcers aren't looking to, like, put you out of business, right?
So you can talk to them and, and work through things.
Yeah. No, it's, I'm curious to see all those two lawsuits against, what was it?
Facebook. And I want to
-- Google
-- for like $8 billion or
$10 times everybody in Europe.
So
we'll see. I don't know. I mean, as I think I,
II, I forget I was talking to somebody and I said, um,
this is probably going to end up being like a 175 year old fine and
they have to write an apology note on the back of the lunch menu.
That's, that's how these things.
Well,
I imagine Google for $8 billion are gonna throw a few
dollars at their lawyers to prevent that from being a thing.
-- Right.
-- Like, just, just make sure this court case takes 20 years or more. Right?
Like,
but by then this, this, this trust fund we set up to pay for, this should
pretty
much
-- $8 billion.
-- Yeah.
Yeah, that's pretty wild.
So,
anyway, so you had an article about the FBI giving consumers?
I don't want to say advice.
My goodness.
I don't even know what to call it. So
there's apparently malware on 500,000 routers
that I think Talis found. I think it was the Cisco
Tali guys.
Anyway, that's where I saw the report first and, and basically the FBI told people
if you own like, one of these specific routers reboot it.
And I'm like,
man, that is just terrible advice because let's face it.
Most people probably don't know, they own one of these routers.
They don't have a good way to find out
and let's face it, telling them to read. Do they know how to reboot the router?
-- Well, you unplug it and plug it back in.
-- Do they know that? I mean,
I, I feel like
as a consumer,
if I was a normal person,
I would have no idea what to do
like ever. Right. What, what is, what is the purpose of this advice?
Why am I rebooting my router. Why does it matter? Does it affect me in any way?
And let's face it for the vast majority of them.
They,
they don't even know their router has been infected with malware and
it probably doesn't affect them in a super huge negative manner.
Right.
And not only that you're going to reboot the thing
and it's almost certainly going to get re hacked.
I, I actually just, uh, have been cleaning out some old, uh, it gear and, uh,
came across three of my wireless, old wireless routers.
A Cisco E 2300, 2500 and a,
I think, a
Dlin something or other.
And the Ciscos have like DDW RT on them because that's by
far the most recent thing that you can get for them.
And it's from like,
it's,
it's over five years old at this point. The software. Right.
And then
I think it was, the D
link has whatever D link software on it. And it's from like 2015
and there's no updates available,
you know, and that's just kind of the reality.
I'm, I'm sure it's fine.
Well, the channel, I think part of the problem is like most of these devices get,
what about maybe 1 to 3 years of support from the vendor if you're lucky,
you know, that seems to be
maybe, but
realistically a wireless router can run for 1020 years.
Well,
but here's the more important thing is even
if the manufacturer is supporting it for,
let's say, five years.
And I think that's generous in a lot of cases. But let's say it's five years.
-- How many normal people ever update their
-- firm.
Exactly. Yeah. Unless it happens automatically.
And then I'm thinking of, you know, like my, my, uh,
fiber link and my cable modem link.
You know, I have
a,
a modem from the ISP now that I think about it,
I've never updated them and I'm not even sure I can,
uh the ISP stuff should take care of itself.
It's, well, I don't know,
in Canada it's a little different because I do have the administrative login
to it and I can monkey with all the settings I want.
But
I, now that I think about it, I've never looked for an OS update.
Uh because quite honestly, my strategy is, is, well, you know,
um what is Google's thing beyond
uh beyond Corp
because the reality is like, it frustrates me,
the people that do spend a lot of time and effort securing their home network.
And I'm like, that's awesome. That's cool. You, do you,
do you ever take your laptop to a coffee shop?
And they're like, yeah, and I'm like, awesome. So, like, how do you, you know?
Right. Like,
yeah, exactly. So, I mean, at home it's just like everything is
essentially its own little
island fortress because
this, everything's mobile now I'm actually getting rid of.
I have one desktop computer that I'm getting rid of.
And so with, you know, basically everything I have now is mobile.
You know, and it moves around the house,
the coffee shop.
Yeah, for, as far as my, uh, my network gear goes. Yeah.
I mean, I bought a PF Sense firewall mostly because
the vendor does give updates to it.
It's like a general, you know, it's free BS D running firewall stuff.
So it'll basically get updates for a long, long time.
-- I thought
-- your firewall was gonna self destruct
at some point because of some Intel bug.
Right.
It's got that Intel chip that's got some wonky hardware issue that, yeah,
it's like the timing chip or something.
And so, yeah, if I,
if it runs for a long time and I reboot it, it just basically won't work and,
well, I mean, let's face it. That's also true of every other piece of hardware I own.
Right. It may not work someday.
It's a,
yeah,
you know, and I have a plan B, it's a Raspberry Pi with two network interfaces,
right. I'll just whip that in quickly and, you know, go buy another hardware device.
Um Although I'll probably just go with like a Google mesh router thing
and get rid of all my network gear and just go to that.
I, I bought a Google device because I was so this was maybe a month ago.
I was incredibly ill.
It was shortly after Rs a, in fact, and I was like, bedridden sick
and the internet died.
And so I, like, I hold myself down in the basement and I,
I start checking things out and I plug the laptop
directly into the cable modem and everything is fine.
I plug the router in and nothing works. I'm like, the router is dead.
And so I, like, I tried to do some magic to resurrect it. Nothing worked.
And so I'm like, I'm really sick and I don't care.
So I just went to Best Buy because I could drive there and I,
I probably made 20 people sick on this trip.
But whatever and, and I just bought the Google stuff because I'm like,
this is cheap and I know it'll be easy to set up and I just want to go back to bed
and, yeah,
it took me maybe 10 minutes to set it up
and it's been working great and I'm quite pleased with it
and, and maybe Google is spying
on,
you
know, given the fact that I, I don't,
I don't trust anyone anymore and I pretend all
of my computers are on the public internet.
So, like, whatever.
Yeah. So,
yeah, I, I, the whole beyond Corp thing, it's, you know,
I think that's just the reality of it now,
especially with mobile devices like phones and tablets.
Well, not only that man, like, I don't even trust my ISP.
Right though. Those people are, are dirt bags, let's face it.
Well, they,
you know, my ISP, I mean, in Canada they're not quite as dirt baggy.
But, you know, if I mistype an address and I'm using their DNS
very helpfully sends me to their error page,
you know, which is not what I wanted.
-- Right. Right.
-- Exactly.
Right. Did you mean this page of ads?
Yeah.
So the deal, so as I understand it, the deal with this FBI thing is,
is they took over the command and control servers for this malware.
And that's why they're saying everybody reboot your router because
I don't, they just reboot them then.
Uh that's a good question.
And there's been a lot of discussion in the industry about this, about, you know,
kind of like how active can we be for?
Yeah, like dealing with malware.
Like, I mean, it's one thing, you know, it's OK from a spam point of view, for example,
it's
definitely OK to say, hey, this IP address is spamming.
You know, if you want to blacklist it, go ahead and blacklist it. Right?
Because you're not touching the system in any way. Cool.
But you know, the minute you start to touch the system, even poking it with like
a scan or something, you, you really do open yourself up to some potential liability
and for all, you know, the system might.
I because I remember um oh jeez, what was his name?
Dave,
the guy at University of Washington that did a
lot of denial service stuff like 20 years ago.
Um,
and, and distributed denial service anyways, the point is he was like,
he was, like, back then he was like, the head it
Honcho to some degree for, like, University of Washington,
which has a very large medical center.
And so they would have like,
malware or spam or something coming out of a machine and they'd be like, you know,
and everybody's like, cool, just shut it down.
He's like, yeah, no, that's like ac a scanner,
we can't do that without potentially killing people or,
you know, this like $5 million piece of machine is no longer available.
And if you tell him it's not available because you killed its network access
because of some malware.
They're going to yell at you and then they're going to have a doctor yell at you,
you know.
So, yeah, I mean,
now in the case of these routers, it's
less likely that they're doing something life critical.
But, you know,
for all we know it's providing remote telemetry
access to like a remote oil field site.
Like we don't know.
No, I agree.
I, you don't know what's going on and I think rebooting them is, or, or, I mean, let's,
let's put our, our tinfoil hats on even, let's say
the FBI reboots all the routers.
What if one of them is in the middle of like a 911 call,
right?
Like, like there's I, I understand why you don't want to just magically do this
and realistically to the downside is one of those kind of classic, you know,
it's like people who don't cover their nose when they sneeze in public.
Yeah, it really sucks. And other people get sick but probably almost nobody dies.
Or if they do the,
the, the responsibility is quite diffuse, you know?
And so,
yeah, I mean,
it's really unlikely that rebooting 500,000 routers
is going to actually kill somebody.
But,
but right,
you end up in, it's one of those things that ends up in the news,
you know, it's like the self driving cars,
will they statistically be better than people?
Uh My understanding is right now,
we don't actually know somebody posted on reddit actually a really good
analysis of the number of accidents and whatnot per mile driven.
Um,
and I think maybe part of the problem right
now is we have actually relatively very little data,
right?
We only have several millions or tens of millions of miles of autonomously driven
cars.
And one could argue even that,
that they're not truly autonomous because like they're, they're,
these systems are built with the idea of not warning
the human to jump in when there's a problem,
but the human is somehow expected to do that
as we covered in the last episode. But, um,
yeah, I mean, we just don't really have enough data yet to truly say, are you know,
autonomously driven cars better than people.
But I think what we can safely say is, you know,
people have pretty much peaked at how good they're going to get with driving.
That's it. Right.
Like without, without computer assistant, like lane keeping and parallel,
like most people can't parallel park.
Like, every time I see one of those, like, here's the secret,
well, here's the secret to parallel parking and I'm like, that's not the secret.
-- That's just how you parallel park.
-- No,
the secret is, don't do it.
And in effect, so funny enough when,
when I got my driver's license because in the United States they give you this, like,
comically simple test
and the only thing I failed on was parallel parking. I
can't, I can't parallel park
in fairness.
I failed my first driving exam due to, I made an error while parallel parking.
It was in winter and there was enough snow on the road ramping
up to the sidewalk that I ended up like an inch on the sidewalk
because I just couldn't tell where the curb was. Right, because there's,
you know,
uh, our, our side roads here just are like, they, they try to blade them down.
So there's like, four inches or less of ice and snow.
But anyways, yeah, I mean, it, so
humans have peaked as far as driving ability goes without
computerized assistance.
Like lane keeping and like, oh my God, that thing in front of you just stop moving.
So I'm going to hit the brakes,
you know.
And so the reality is computers are going to get
better and better at it and will they surpass humans?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. And, and clearly not very long from now,
you know, um, especially like, you know, yesterday again,
driving and this lady next to me kept, like, was texting while, you know,
driving and making a left turn and it's just like, oh, good Lord, you know,
please let there be no pedestrians.
So,
yeah, the problem is whenever you take an active measure,
you know, and, and then the other problem becomes like, how active. Ok, is a reboot?
Ok.
Well, a reboot is probably non destructive and it's, you know, it's,
it's a good intention.
So, ok, we'll allow reboots. Well, what about a software update?
What about a software?
Uh What about removing a piece of functionality that probably almost nobody uses,
like, say UPNP
like, you know,
where do you draw that line of like, oh, well, maybe, you know,
this device will never get an update again.
Maybe we should just remotely brick them all
and force people to buy new devices.
You know, where do you draw that line?
-- Right.
-- It's tricky.
Well, what about people who have, say, cell phones or tablets that
the CS cellular carrier knows is compromised? What do you do with that?
Do you cut it off from the network? Do you break it? Do you
-- remember
-- when the
I, this
is like 20 years ago,
the ISP used to allow outgoing port 25 like you could run your own mail server at home,
obviously that stopped
and, you know, now they block outgoing to port 25 except on business accounts,
you know, and you certainly can't run a server locally.
Um They had the same problem with, um,
with
Samba traffic.
Uh And the problem was these infected
machines were generating so much traffic on their
local area networks.
And when I say local area network, I mean,
these machines were jacked straight into the internet.
So this is like the, is P's local area network
that they were bringing down entire neighborhoods, right?
Like the neighborhood node would get flooded with this traffic
and yeah, like an entire, you know, several square blocks would like,
basically their internet speed would go to like 0.1.
And so they started blocking that, you know, so my ISP
uh probably 1520 years ago, you know,
was blocking ports. Uh I want to say like 1 35 1 37 1 38 1 39.
And, and for what it's worth,
I totally agree with this sort of behavior and I know we kind of touched on
this when we argued net neutrality and you
totally convinced me that net neutrality is dumb.
But that's another story.
I,
I don't believe that really,
but uh I, I am not opposed to organizations taking certain actions against
known bad
devices and, or behavior just because I feel like,
you know what I would compare this to,
let's say you go into the hospital and you're like,
I have this cough and it won't go away and they say,
oh you have Ebola get in this bubble and stay in there, right?
You can't, you can't say I'm gonna go home. They
like, no, you're not get in the room, right?
And,
and I feel like some of this is kind of
like that where you have that public health aspect of it
and there's also secure ways to do this, right. VPN S are not
magic anymore. They're actually
available by default on. I think virtually every device.
Why are you, why is a VPN a solution?
What?
Well, for example,
if you do need to remotely access Samba on your machine at home or something goofy,
right?
Or,
or you can have your GP N
you know, like
D DNS style provider that then you know, you can connect it to it on the internet,
right?
Like these services cost like literally, I think three or $4 a month now.
Uh
Yeah, I mean, look,
you don't even need any of that. Let's face it.
The only reason people even set up a lot of this
stuff was for sharing files and there's so many services today.
I mean,
I think the cloud solves a lot of the problems we were trying to homebrew ourselves
and we've reached a point where you have to say, like, don't, don't do that.
I mean, it's like running an email server for less than a few 1000 people.
No,
I would argue running an email server for more than a few 1000 people.
Well,
at least at that point you get to certain
economies of scale where it might make sense.
But, you know,
I used to run my own mail servers and it was like a minimum one or two hours a week,
just dealing with spam and anti spam and all that junk.
You know,
it was a
part
that's over
with.
But, yeah, so I think,
yeah, you know, where do we draw that line of,
what sort of corrective action can we take or
do we just ideally have them notify everybody in,
in?
Of course,
you and I have heard about this, but I'm,
I'm 100% betting if we asked 100 people on the street,
one of them might know what a router is.
And actually, you know what's really funny about that? You even say? So,
uh, my dad calls me maybe a month ago. It was, it was just after, was it?
No, it was just before I got really sick
and he says my internet is really slow and I'm like, oh,
you have a virus probably again.
So I go over to his house and I check his computer seems to be fine.
And so I, I did some tests of the network where I had my own gear.
So, of course, I plugged things in and I'm testing and I said your router shot you.
If I take the router off, I was getting
like, whatever, I'm supposed to get 100 megabits, whatever.
And when I plug the router in, I was getting four
and I'm like,
something's wrong, you know, you need a new router
and this has been over a month
and I was there this weekend
and I said, did you get a new router? He said, oh, no, I just haven't had time.
And I'm thinking,
I wish I lived a life where my internet could
be four megabits and I don't care for a month.
You know,
-- it's
-- just
the majority of people like they,
-- they need it for
-- Netflix.
No, that's straight up it.
That's the only reason they need anything more than about a megabit per second.
And it's funny you say that because his Netflix looks really bad when he was playing.
I'm like, go get a router.
Yeah,
that's the only reason my partner's parents
upgraded their internet is because they're like,
why does our Netflix look so, you know, terrible compared to everyone else's.
And we're like,
because you have the $15 a month internet plan bit.
That's why
it was literally like one, it was, what was it?
It was like 0.3 or four and five megabits down or something like it was.
Yeah.
So,
so anyway, all right, we're in the weeds, we're in the weeds.
Normal people with security
there is.
I feel like there's no hope in educating them.
I think the FBI asking people to do this is a waste of their time.
I, I don't even know why they would do that. It, it is. No, it doesn't matter. Right.
It's not gonna work
and I don't know what the answer is like.
Should the I SPS have all the, you know,
on premises equipment and manage it remotely?
Uh, I'm not sure. I like that answer either.
Yeah. So I, I hate that answer.
Well, speaking of that cesspool, the whole dot app domain cesspool thing.
So, yeah.
So for those of you that don't know,
Google created a top level domain called dot app like dot A PP.
Um, for apps,
right? It's like the go to place for your apps. You know, I was on,
what was I doing? I was
on youtube or something. Anyways. Long story short,
uh, Fortnite,
very popular game right now amongst the young people.
And this guy straight up had a video on
youtube basically saying you can get Fortnite for Android,
which by the way, you can't
like, it does not exist
and he's like you download, go to this, uh,
it's like Fortnite something Android dot A PP, you know, install this thing,
you know, disable the warnings.
Yeah. You.
He's like, you might get a warning about an unsigned app, just bypass it this way,
blah, blah, blah.
And then he's like,
and then the app will take you to a website where you'll have to install
like two bonus apps that you have to like play a little bit before,
you know, it'll unlock Fortnite.
So it's basically,
it's an installer that then gets you to install like two random
other game apps. And, and the funniest thing is like, one was a clear rip off of um
like Clash of Clans or something. It was one of those, you know, like little
RT S sword Castle
jiggers
and he's like,
you might have to play for a little while or you
might have to play for a longer while before it,
like unlocks for you.
And it's like straight up,
I'm assuming it's like affiliate scams,
you know, like
where you get paid to get people to install the apps and use it
because I'm assuming,
or the app and
the
app,
people are hoping that the people will install the
app and actually enjoy it and keep it and
pay for microtransaction junk inside of it.
But you think they'd probably be smart enough to realize that that's,
that I imagine it's like one in a million
when it comes to that, you know, for installs actually being monetized.
Um
But yeah, I mean, this, this thing is on youtube, it's a clear scam,
like 100% scam and, you know.
Yeah, youtube has no problem with it. And
the dot App
domain is, you know, full of this garbage.
Uh, so the, the video you linked to on youtube appears to be gone.
I have a feeling.
Yeah, they, they, they must have taken it down.
Hm.
One down a million to go.
No, but again, we, we come back to
what did, what do normal people do about this kind of stuff?
How would a normal person know that's a scam? Right.
Yeah, exactly.
Well, it reminds me of the,
I believe dot Bank is a top level domain and the idea was like, oh,
only real banks can level for, can, you know,
can apply or get dot Bank. And I'm like, no, like
no,
there's like 100 and 80 countries and some of
them have some really lax rules around banking.
-- I wonder if we could start a bank and get a dot Bank.
-- Don.
I looked into it uh,
to start a bank depending on where you want to go and what kind of bank you want to be?
You're looking at about 10 to 100 rand.
-- Oh,
-- the bare minimal.
Really? That seems remarkably affordable.
Well, this isn't like you're doing it properly.
This is like,
this is like, I'm a car mechanic. I have like a hammer and a screwdriver
to, it's legit, yo
to,
it's legit.
Yes. And then we could offer 10% interest on investments
and no,
no,
no, 10% interest people. Here, here's how it works. You offer 10% interest.
People invest massively their money because they want
their 10% interest in days when you're anyone,
then you, you take that money and invest it in Bitcoin
and then you either become filthy rich or everything fails and then you
just declare bankruptcy and say you had no idea this wouldn't work.
Right. Totally checks up.
See, the reason I would never do this is it's,
is it's actually illegal to do this kind of stuff.
Whereas for example, having a Kickstarter and spending all the money on like
whatever lifestyle stuff is actually legal.
You, you're probably, you're sadly correct.
So,
you know,
that's the beauty of most white collar crime is there's
a whole bunch of stuff that isn't white collar crime.
It's perfectly legal. It's just really morally and ethically not so cool.
And we're again back to the place where, how do normal people know what's going on?
-- Simple
-- if it sounds too good to be true.
It is. Well, ok, there's that.
Yes, but here's whatever that doesn't work either.
So, so here's,
let's use banking as our example because it would be totally
illegal if you and I just did the insane thing I suggested
and
it is illegal and there are regulators
who help prevent this because.
Right. Right. I mean, let's face it.
If, if anyone could do this, everyone would do this. Right. Let's face.
I mean, that's just the reality of it.
Well, yeah. And I mean, Bernie Madoff did it and made
and that didn't end very well for him though.
And, and so here, here's the thing. Right.
And here's something I always think about.
I know we've talked about this more than once is,
can you regulate tech?
And the answer so far has been no.
And there's a variety of reasons for that.
Yeah, I think part of the problem too is how do we regulate tech?
Like, do we need to be prescriptive or, like, sort of descriptive or?
No, we can't be prescriptive.
I mean, that, that's why,
that's why the GDPR is so loosely defined because they know if they,
if they have specifics,
the first thing that happens is everyone just goes around them and now,
like the whole world of tech has shifted in crazy ways just to avoid GDPR.
Right.
Yeah, I, that's, yeah, I know, I've been thinking about this a lot and I, I
think realistically
it has to be demand driven because supply, nobody cares.
And until like a ton of people die as people are starting to point out,
you know, on Twitter and whatnot.
Right. And, and it's, it's multifaceted though there.
So, actually this is interesting, let's talk about this for a second.
So I see two ways. Right. There's number one,
there's economic incentives
where
it just, it, it is more economical to do something in a certain way.
And I think in, in the world of it, I don't know if we'll ever get there,
like an example of being cars. Right.
They don't build safer cars because it's economically viable.
They build safer cars because someone's telling them to do it.
-- But,
-- I mean, with, it has to be demand driven.
-- I mean, it's, it's,
-- uh, yes, well, sort of, sort of hang on
and we'll use cars as our example where
the automobile industry used to be really unsafe.
And when they said every car has to have seat belts, everyone was like,
oh my goodness, we can't possibly do that.
We're all going to go out of business.
And then
eventually
the, I don't even know which group it was that,
that told the cars they have to all have seat belts,
they did it.
I'm sure some may have gone out of business, but fundamentally speaking,
nobody really did.
And now,
now we have various safety features that are being,
I, I wouldn't even say they demand generated, right?
It's, it's more like you have organizations saying if you don't do this,
you can't sell cars
-- and, and like in our world who's doing that
-- well, and,
and part of the challenge with that,
well, part of the challenge is software and it is changing so much like,
uh 10 years ago we didn't have
or,
or
devices, man.
Well, yeah, I was just gonna say smartphones,
you know, we kind of had semi smartphones but nothing like what we have now.
And that's
in 10 years,
we've gone from zero to literally everybody having
a smartphone except for a few people with
-- phones. But
-- now, now here's, here's the other side of that.
So in the automobile industry,
literally
millions of people have been killed.
Right.
And, and before the safety, if we didn't have the safety measures, it would be much,
much higher than it is today.
And I, I read somewhere, I'll see if I can look this up.
I think it's actually, uh, you know what,
I think it's actually has to be worse than that.
It's, it's not even that millions of people were killed in automobile accidents.
It's that many, many more people were maimed and strangled
and,
and lived and I think in a way that's almost more powerful because, you know,
honestly dead people don't complain that much.
-- Well,
-- they have families and stuff,
their, their relatives and their friends do. Right.
But having somebody, you know who's been mangled in a car accident,
they're probably going to hold a grudge.
I, I feel like part of the challenge with it is that, you know,
luckily we very rarely kill and, or maim and mangle people.
Exactly. That's exactly it.
You know, which is good.
But the problem is, you know, it, I mean,
airline disasters are a great example of this because they're just so,
you know, horrendous, like several 100 people just died, you know, horrendously
that, yeah, we get it. That's a problem, you know. But like,
you know, we, we,
we already have instances of these A I and ML systems where it's like, clearly, oh,
you know, these things were, um, what was it, like,
incorrectly rating, um, parolees for the, the, the chance of them
reoffending whatever.
So these people are not being given parole
and they probably should have been given parole.
That, that's actually a pretty significant effect on these people's lives.
But how, how do we quantify that? How do we measure that? You know,
how do we do A B testing to actually see what the case is?
Well, look, let's face it.
That's a bad example because the vast majority of the public isn't gonna care.
Right.
Yeah. Well, and that too. Exactly. And,
and that's a lot of it like, oh, you know, some, a bunch of people didn't get
loans. So, what, because, you know, the risk profile said they were a bad risk.
Yeah, exactly. How do we, how do we sort of sell that as a problem to people?
You know,
it's really hard to say, you know,
statistically 0.0 0.0 0.31% of people who
are left handed were improperly denied loans.
Yeah, nobody cares. Except for maybe you,
I'm, I'm left handed. Yeah, that would be, that's a travesty.
I
have to care now.
Yeah,
I realistically think that,
I don't think software will ever make it bad enough that, like,
cars or like mining or air travel.
Well, that's, that's the question. Right.
I mean, that's really,
that's what it's going to come down to as far as consumer security is concerned.
Is,
are we ever going to hit a point where
people care enough
to make something change? And if, if I had to guess
I don't see anything in the next five years that's gonna drive that
we might see certain things and let's say like the
medical device community where like people will literally die.
But,
but even then
I don't know how much that's going to affect the greater ecosystem
that, that
we call software and cloud and, and mobile devices and all this stuff. Right.
I, I don't think it will because you look at all these data breaches.
I still shop at Home Depot.
I don't even care.
My credit card's been stolen so many times.
I just,
I have like alert fatigue on stolen credit cards and I just don't care anymore.
I mean, that's the reality of it and I'm a security guy.
Well, realistically, what can we do? So, as far as consumers though, I think, um
I think part of what might help is if people, you know,
I hate to say this but you know, replace their devices every 3 to 5 years.
But I mean, if the thing still works, why spend money on that
on, you know, this nebulous,
slightly lower risk profile because you're getting soft.
That's a really interesting question.
I wonder if you're say using an outdate android phone.
What, what the odds of actually getting infected by malware are
if you, if you're just using it? Right.
I don't mean like trying to download Fortnite for, for Android.
Which funny
that you say that I didn't really Fortnite wasn't on Android
and my kids were talking about putting it on Android.
So I need to actually go check that out after we, we stopped talking.
But um,
but anyway, like,
I wonder if you'd say just like checking email and maybe using Twitter
on an outdated device versus a brand new device.
I would say if you're using a,
a like sort of a brand name email provider who look quite,
-- you know, like
-- Gmail. All right, let's just say Gmail, right.
You know, if you're using Gmail or Outlook or something,
Outlook 365 or whatever it's called now,
you're probably no offense. But if a virus gets through to you then like,
yeah,
it's,
they have a suspicion
that the cost of buying a new device and let's face it.
Like, like cell phones are getting really expensive again.
They came down for a little while they're going back up. But anyway, my, my guess
and I'll, I don't know if I can quantify this.
I'll have to do some research to see if I can but my guess
is the, the cost of buying a new device and migrating your life over to it,
which, that, that has a huge cost as well.
-- So
-- for Apple, it's basically a dollar a day. Right?
You're looking at a new $1000 cell phone every three years.
And the cost of moving all your stuff over is almost zero because you just
assuming you use icloud, you log in, you're done
-- well.
-- ok. It may be in the Apple
system but, but here's the thing, if I keep using my old Apple device forever,
my guess
is
it is, it will cost me less than a dollar a day.
When, when, if I eventually get ped in some way versus buying a new one,
we're actually going to be for my kids for cell phone.
They're going to be sharing an old iphone se in an order box.
What's in an Otter box?
An auto, you know, it's one of those cases that's like IP 68 rated and like,
oh, the indestructible cases. Right.
Yeah, because like their kids and they're idiots.
Uh, love you guys though. But, um,
yeah, I mean, realistically because,
yeah, he's, the, the phone is gonna be locked down.
He'll be able to use it to make like phone calls and like, use messaging and that's it.
Right. And in that case, an old outdated phone is just fine.
Yeah.
All right.
It's actually cheaper than buying him a new phone.
I imagine it is.
Alright. So I guess in summary consumers still doomed
but it doesn't matter.
Yeah.
There we go.
Yeah. No, I to put it bluntly, you know,
I mean, unless you do something really crazy,
like send all your money to some Prince in Nigeria,
that's not the fault of your technology.
That's just normal.
Humans suck at everything. Behavior.
Like I'm just thinking like
the people I do know that have had to deal with this stuff. Yeah, it really does suck.
It's tens of hours of dealing with like identity theft and stuff. But
I mean, it's, it's honestly,
I'd rather deal with that than getting in a car accident and messing up my neck.
So anyway,
there we have.
All right, sweet. So, thanks Kurt. Thank you everybody for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Grab the show notes.
You can hit us up on social media with the Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag
if nothing else, Kurt have a fabulous rest of your day.
You too.
Thanks.