Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So I just got a new monitor and it is one of those ridiculously wide ones
and I am loving it
curved or flat. It's a little curved.
It's 32 inches wide, which is, I don't know what that is in metric, but it is,
it's two
inches
and
that's how we measure monitors here because all of the monitors.
Yeah. Well, because like the US market is 10 times bigger than Canada.
So when you list a monitor size,
like if I go to Costco dot C A and I look for stuff,
how big do you think the screen sizes are while they're listed in inches?
I don't know. Ok. Well, anyway, all the Canadian sites do that 32 inches wide.
Well, it's a 34 inch monitor, but it is 32 inches wide.
Is the like physical dimension of it.
Is that the diagonal or the actual width, width,
the width width is 32
and there's a slight curve.
So if, if I put the, if I measured along the curve,
I'm sure it's like 32.5 or something like that, but
it is 32 inches wide.
And I love it.
I didn't know if I would enjoy it or not, but my old monitor was acting up and I,
I told work, I'm like, I need a monitor, help me out and they said,
just pick out one you like and I was gonna get two and I saw this and thought,
let's do it right?
Why not? And
I love it.
I've honestly also gone to the one big high, high quality at least four K monitor,
right?
Like I have two desktops, each one is a four K monitor.
I can't go back to anything less.
And I kind of do wish I had the curve now because
from what I've seen especially well for stuff on the edge,
it, it does matter
a
little bit. I, I agree with that. It's less eye strained looking to the side.
But the, the most surprising thing I think is
I just like having the wi because I can basically have two
or three windows literally next to each other at all times.
And nothing's overlapping.
And my favorite part though.
So I've had two screens before obviously where you've got a seam down the middle.
I love having nothing in the middle because I can put a window
in the middle of the screen and then have like other
weird things off to the sides and it is absolutely lovely.
Well, see, and this is my hope is apparently,
uh Apple is working on augmented reality
and they get
that resolution matters.
And that's one of the reasons I hate to say it,
but I love Apple products is their screens, the quality on the ipads, the iphone.
They do have nice screens
like the resolution, the DP I and all that,
the colors and apparently the A R glasses they're
working on are very high res because apparently that's,
you know, that's become a thing now with all the other guys, uh, what is it?
I can't remember the names.
Offhand starts with A Q their,
their resolution isn't great and they've just sort of given up on it, you know,
in favor of other things.
And,
well, I'll be blunt, like the world itself is a very high res
place,
right? No, it is. And
it
is.
You know, I,
I'm thinking that's probably one of the things because I've used VR before
and honestly didn't much care for it unless it was like cartoony.
In which case, low
res works. But with augmented reality.
Yeah, I don't, I'm not sure cartoon shapes,
overlaid reality is going to work very well.
I don't know, man, I feel like
I don't think the technology is ready yet for humans,
but we'll see apparently Apple is about two years out from releasing something.
I am going to be very hesitant to get on that train.
Oh, Yeah, I bet it won't be awesome. But I bet it will be better than
what we have. Well, better be better than what we have.
I would trust Apple to not screw it up as bad as many of the others.
Like Google classes.
I think those still exist, don't they? I feel like they do.
I think they technically exist in the same way that you can buy, like,
pet rocks.
Like, yeah, you can probably go buy one somewhere.
I think they're still actually producing them.
And you can,
I believe I read that somewhere anyway. Anyway, that's not the,
we could rathole on this for hours.
I don't want to,
we're going to talk about encrypted V MS today because that's far more interesting,
I think.
And you're wrong you, if you're a company, you can get Google Glasses Enterprise.
But that, that's the thing. I'm a company, I
guess. Well, if you're going to buy 1000 of them. Sure. Do you have to buy 1000?
I don't know.
Do you think Google's gonna sell you one?
Maybe?
I don't know. Anyway.
But, yeah, no.
Encrypted V MS are definitely because, you know, coming from the cloud space,
here's the thing, right?
Everybody wants
to not have to run hardware anymore because hardware is a complete pain in the ass.
But at the same time, everybody wants magically, you know,
those security guarantees of like,
especially in a multi-tenant situation that the other tenants can't
touch you inappropriately or even in a single tenant,
you know, where you rent out the whole hardware for like, whatever,
10 bucks an hour extra
that, you know, you're,
you're safe even from like some shenanigans running in the data center.
Well, I don't think anyone pretends there's any safety in
this space today. We've all basically Jedi hand waved it away and said good enough.
Well, there is and there isn't in the sense of, I mean, I honestly,
I do trust Amazon and Google to not be,
you know,
making copies of the hard drives and showing the data on some random website,
like,
you know, just as I trust my bank, I gave them my money and I damn well,
better get it back.
Well, and I mean, this is the point of having
a contractual relationship is if they do something that damages you,
you have legal recourse to go after them.
But ideally,
I'd like to avoid that and just have the system secure in the first place.
Right. Oh, I agree.
I agree completely. It, it's kind of that whole defense in depth. So here's,
here's the reason we're talking about this is, is literally this morning,
we've completely changed all of our, our plans for the, the episode,
but like literally this morning,
we found a new story that said Google in their cloud
has an encrypted VM and they're using a technology called SEV
from A MD to be I think even more clear, it's not just an encryption VM,
but they call it confidential VMS because the reality is too,
is it's more than just encrypting the VM.
It's actually because what we want is
we want multi tenant situations where the tenants
hate each other and like, want to hack each other and can't.
Right. And so let's, let's, let's lay this all out and then we'll go from there.
So they're using a technology AMD created called SUV,
which is secure encrypted virtualization.
The idea behind this is
imagine you've got your current architecture of a
computer where you kind of have memory,
you have disk, you have ac pu in the middle, you have IO right?
And it just kind of all this data flows around and
in the event you have virtualization,
you kind of carve some of this up into little pieces.
But for example, the the non guest machine like like the host machine, right,
the underlying hardware, right?
Like the underlying machine,
it has the ability to say,
inspect all the memory or inspect the disk or look at the traffic
as it's coming in and out of the network or things like that,
right?
That's totally expected.
And so this is kind of where if you're in a virtualized machine, in theory,
you can't cross the boundary and look at what someone else is doing there, of course,
been some security issues involving this problem.
But some,
I mean, the the classic example here is of like the console makers, right?
Because the console makers tried to do a lot of this stuff ages ago
so that people couldn't, you know,
hack their consoles to play unlocked games or whatever, to a degree.
It's similar to that, but not exactly the same.
Well, they would be the starting steps of this kind of whole
mess.
What a MD has done is they've created this technology where imagine
your, your virtualized machine
has basically like encryption built into it. So the memory is encrypted.
And as the memory streams into the processor,
it becomes magically decrypted and then the processor does its work.
And then as soon as anything leaves the processor,
it becomes encrypted again as it's traversing the other pieces of hardware
you might have in the system.
And the idea is if you have low level access to hardware like the in the processor,
which in theory, I, I haven't read up on this technology in a while.
But when it came out, if you could say
get into the CPU,
you could inspect registers and things like that and see what was happening.
But that's obviously
a very sophisticated attack to be blunt, like if you're at the point where you know,
you've inserted custom microcode and hacked the CPU.
Yeah, you're, you're like state level.
And so the idea is, let's say I break into the host,
I can't read the memory because I can't access the
key that decrypt the memory and the memory is encrypted.
So where do the keys live? Like in a piece of security hardware?
Yeah, they have a, it's a secondary process
but you obviously have to get them in them in their security.
There's,
and there's some management interfaces and you have the ability for example,
to just say generate a random key and obviously you can never migrate
that machine somewhere else if it has a random key on the host,
yeah, you could, you could just copy the memory over like the old.
No, no, you can't because the key is trapped
in
a special secure processor
well,
but like you can still read the memory and interact
with it if you are running on that system,
right?
So you could choose on the system. Yeah.
So you could choose to then copy it out and move
it to another one like that old red hat product did
remember how it copied out blocks of memory. You can't do that
it. Well, no, no, let's just say no. OK.
So, so basically this, this changes the security equation from
the attacker always has access to your data to the attacker
would have to get at the key when it was loaded.
And if he misses that opportunity,
well, too bad.
And you,
and, and
in theory,
yes, exactly. But in theory, if you do this right, the key cannot be stolen. It is
impossible. Which is of course never true.
But the idea is so you have two virtual machines running
and even if say someone breaks from one virtual machine into another,
they cannot look at any of the data of what's going on.
Let's say you have a malicious cloud provider.
They are unable to even understand what your VM is doing.
They can look at how much CPU it's using, they can look at how much memory it's using,
but they literally have no idea what it is happening inside of that machine.
They cannot see it. Funny thing.
I spoke with an Amazon person and he basically said many years ago,
we honestly don't care or need to because just based on
very general traffic patterns of network CPU and ram usage,
we can basically tell legit from malicious workloads pretty darn reliably.
I believe that I think there's a lot of power
metadata and we often discount it in this particular
instance and not that even let's face it.
Amazon has so much stuff going on in their network.
I love that you do a port scan and you get
a nasty email from them like 30 seconds later saying,
why did you do a port scan?
Right? If you do it again? Yeah.
And I'm like, well, never doing a port scan for my corporate account again.
That's right. That's
that lesson.
Yep. Yep.
So, so anyway, the idea here is that
you have the ability to deploy these machines
that even your cloud provider can't pry the
lid off of and look inside of and I can understand a certain appeal to this.
And I think it is
probably the future of all cloud computing.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, that's where it's been moving, right.
Like, look at Amazon and Google and Microsoft.
So they have this storing data in their data centers, right?
And they obviously encrypt the discs themselves
and they also have, you know, very tight tracking of these discs. And if a disk is,
you know, damaged or whatever and
they, they destroy it,
they don't like ship a slightly broken disk back to Seagate or whatever and be like,
you know, can you swap the board on it and send it back, please?
Like, and, and you can even buy this, like, uh I know,
I remember back when Dell started offering this for servers where you pay a couple
extra 100 bucks
and basically the way disc arms worked is you said I want a new dis,
they sent you a new disk
and then you just destroyed the one you had, right?
So the one you had never left your control.
And so despite all that,
they still offer me disc encryption of my like application levels, right?
Because they know that I don't necessarily fully 100% trust them not to lose. Like,
I
don't know,
like a shipment of drives that were supposed
to be destroyed at the DC and accidentally
didn't get destroyed river. You know, even though, like, realistically
they're probably going to be a lot more on the ball about that than I ever will be.
Uh, probably, but it's also, again, it's defense in depth because
it would not shock me if truckloads of drives that were supposed
to get destroyed ended up on a secondary market somewhere once,
at least once.
So, yeah, I mean,
and that's what I love about this is we're already at the point where, you know,
most everybody has accepted cloud computing and made the, you know,
been willing to make the risk trade off of.
Yeah, I mean,
Amazon or Microsoft could go super evil and do something bad to you probably won't.
And well, now technically speaking, like Google, I don't want to say can't,
but it would be much, much, much harder, you know,
by several orders of magnitude of work.
Right. Right.
And that's great.
Like
that's, that's what we want to see in this industry is for
movement.
No, I absolutely. And, and this is, this is cool.
So the other thing I want to kind of maybe explain to try to set some of this.
So here's a question I have. So what is the difference between this and Intel's SGX?
Right? Because you got in
uh
no, I can't remember what SGX stands for Security
Guard
extension or something.
Yeah. Secure. Sure, why not? I don't remember.
So the,
the difference is actually quite large in reality.
So the idea being SGX is an enclave and the idea
is I want to kind of set aside a small piece,
a small place in my CPU
to run
trusted code
where
things are gonna happen inside of this enclave.
And absolutely nobody can peek inside of it.
And let's say you're going to do encryption in there, right?
You could potentially say load an encryption key,
do your encryption work and then take the results back and there's no way
anyone could unders like take the key out of the enclave. That's the intent, right?
You can imagine the the idea like this is a cool idea. It was actually we were talking
before we hit record and Kurt said, oh,
it's like T PM 2.00 I just found a slide deck that is
there's I knew SGX was basically T PM 2.0.
But I didn't realize like, but there is T PM 2.0
But,
but I mean, this is I didn't realize, for example,
Intel SGX only addresses up to 120 megabytes of memory.
Whereas
A
DSEV is like,
well,
they're not comparable is people, people like to compare these technologies,
they are not comparable in any way.
And the reason being SGX is meant to be I would say closer to TPM. Whereas SUV
is basically a new computing paradigm where the idea is you have your processor,
you have everything else happening outside the processor
and everything is happening in an encrypted manner.
Well, and here's my trick question,
what changes do I have to make to my application to make use of
AMD
CEV? And the answer as we both know is zero. Whereas Intel SGX,
you have to specifically call into SGX.
So, and that right there, I'm sorry.
But
if you have a, I don't care how awesome your security thing is.
If I have to rewrite my software versus
I don't, well,
like one of those is gonna get used a bit more
than the one that is going to require a rewrite.
Yeah.
Yeah. And, and that's what really drives me nuts about.
Some of these security technologies is like, it's like so cool, but it's like, oh,
but I have to like basically spend 6 to 12 months reengineering a big chunk of my app.
That's just not gonna happen.
Absolutely not.
Or at least not widely. Can you imagine trying to sell your boss on that?
Like,
let's just stall development out for half a year
versus this other technology where we just use it?
No, no. Well, again,
comparable though, right? They're just,
they're different use cases and I'm not going to say SGX doesn't have value.
It's just in this particular conversation. SGX is not a solution,
it has very limited value,
it has none in this context.
This is, this is like saying that I have to choose a screwdriver or a hammer.
It's like, well, what am I doing? You know,
am I hammering a nail because then I want the hammer,
am I screwing a screw into something that I want the screwdriver?
Well, but as I understand it,
you essentially everything you want to do with Intel SGX,
you kind of get by default in the,
in the AM DS EV.
Well, it's, it's not, no, no, no, that's not the right way to think of it.
So
you think of it like you're saying,
comparing SEV to T PM,
right? It
it's not the same.
So the idea behind sev is you have the ability to run discrete virtual machines in
a system and each of those virtual machines
are functionally separated by a layer of encryption
and you can't break through the layer because obviously it has a key.
So let's say, for example, I'm a malicious VM
and I find a way to read arbitrary memory off the computer, right?
I can read memory but I don't have the key. So I'm reading
Gobbledygook,
right? And without the key, I can't decrypt that memory into anything usable.
Now SGX is more of a, let's think of this as
I want to run
something
in the CPU in a secure manner, right?
Let's say I need to generate, let me think about this. Yeah, let's say I want to
decrypt some data
in,
in a manner that is similar to an HSM, right?
A hardware security module Well, see, and that's, that's my, my,
my understanding of T PM and Intel's SGX was essentially,
you, you get
very limited,
usually cryptographic related functionality. That's the idea.
And part of the problem, like, I didn't realize it was limited to 128 megs of memory.
I knew it was very computationally limited.
It is, but it's also very memory limited. So it's just, it's all related.
I mean, I don't know if, if there's a technical reason
they don't let you access like all the memory, for example, but I think the intent is,
it's meant to be very small,
single purpose use and they might have been worried that
people were going to do ridiculous things with it.
If you let them access, say all of the system memory, I,
I don't know exactly why that is.
But again,
they're completely different paradigms. One is a virtualization technology.
The other is just a secure enclave that
anything can access that's running on the CPU.
It has nothing to do with virtualization.
It doesn't necessarily make virtualization better or worse.
It's just, it's, it is what it is
and it's,
it's complicated and hard and weird and it's,
it's not the easiest thing in the world to understand.
But so now I will say
I need to do some more research on sev because I haven't,
I haven't looked at it in a while.
It's been a couple of years, but I will say that it is not a perfect technology. And
the, the last time I looked at it, the biggest problem it had was
it would basically imagine the, the, the magic decrypt
sits as a, like a ring outside the CPU. So you take say
like
ring,
negative one.
No, no, I mean, I don't mean that kind of ring. I mean,
imagine like a wall, right? Like a special wall with a gate.
And the,
the data is going to come from the memory and it's going to
pass through this this decryption wall and then it goes into the CPU.
And so what could happen though is if a, if an attacker has the ability to
like view uh For example, you could,
you could turn on like a debug mode in the CPU where you'd step through instructions
and you could just step through every instruction
and look at what the instructions are doing,
for example,
and then do things like reconstruct memory as it's being read and written.
So stupid question. So the contents of memory are encrypted. What about like the,
the CPU registers?
So the last time I looked at it,
that was not where basically this data came from the memory,
it was decrypted and then it landed in the caches,
for example, in the CPU, it was not encrypted.
And that obviously you can see right away with some
of the the various cash attacks against the CPU uh
in sev dash
es the VM register state is encrypted on each hypervisor transition so that
the hypervisor cannot see the data actively being used by the VM.
It's like A and D thought about this.
I'm just, I'm kind of blown away that they can encrypt the CPU registers in a way
that is
because like, what's the access time on those things now? Like a nanosecond?
No, it doesn't surprise me at all though.
I mean, well,
the fact that they can decrypt and encrypt the
data fast enough that it's not a performance hit.
That's pretty cool. It doesn't totally surprise me. It's probably there.
I'm sure they built their algorithm,
you know, in silicone with transistors literally in line, but even a, even a, like
a extra billionth of a second there adds up.
Yeah, I mean, you're not, I won't disagree with you. You're definitely not wrong.
But that's, this is, this is amazing.
They've also sorry, they've also got this thing called SEV dash SNP,
which is essentially there's they list sevseves and SEV SNP,
which is like the next next one.
And the list of capabilities on this SEV SNP is there's stuff
in here where if you told me this 10 years ago,
I'd be like, that's impossible to fix in ac pu because that's how CP US work.
No, like, really? Right. Like, well, that's what makes this so cool.
Like the fact, like, like encrypting your CPU registers 10 years ago,
I would have been like, you just can't do that.
It will kill performance. Well, in the first version of this couldn't do it.
And that's why.
But of course, everyone who looked at it,
that's the first thing they said was you have
to encrypt the registers because if you don't,
this has much less value.
This is why, like I just, I know CP because honestly, I
really paid attention to CPU and computational improvements in the last decade
because computers are just fast nowadays.
There hasn't been a lot of exciting work going on. But this, this is exciting.
Like I remember the Gigahertz Wars
and man, that was a great time to be alive.
Like literally going from like one gigahertz two gigahertz
or like, well, I remember going from a 4060 X 266
to a P 100.
I got,
I went from a 3 86 25 to a Pentium 166.
That's like going from a skateboard to a,
to like a formula one, a rocket ship.
It was like a rocket ship. It was,
it was an unexplainable difference
in the computing experience. And it was lovely.
Well, and I guess that's kind of where we're getting here is, I mean, things like,
yeah, OK, your, your CPU registers are encrypted.
You're, and they have this huge list of just like I said, crazy stuff that I,
I didn't think you could actually do.
Like in the sense of you can do it but it
will kill performance so bad that you can't do it.
Well, I mean, look, so this is,
this is what's going to happen now with CP US is
we can't make them any faster because we just like physics,
right?
And
we can
work out
and, and, well, the thing is by increasing core count, then you have to have this
because, you know, once you have, well,
I'm not even speaking theoretically anymore.
Once you have ac pu with like 64 or 100 and 28 cores, well,
you can't just run a workload on it.
Right.
You're generally going to have more than one workload running on it and
those workloads probably aren't at the exact same security level or same tenant.
So now you have to start, you know, having strong borders and VM controls. Right.
Right.
And
the, I would argue that the bigger advantage even for their cloud providers
is
now they are very hands off with respect to what's happening in these V MS.
Or you think today,
if I go and I'm doing something illegal,
someone can make the argument to Amazon.
Well, you, you knew what they were doing, why didn't you stop it or rather they,
they could look, you know, like all those FBI subpoenas to Apple and Apple is like,
yeah.
Nope, we made the technology so we can't do that.
Yeah.
Right. Right.
Exactly.
And in this case, obviously
with,
with I mean, let's pick on,
on Google here because they're obviously the ones deploying this,
this gives them that deniability.
You know, if you're running in their environment,
they can't possibly look at what you're doing or do anything about it.
It's like everyone wins here. Right.
It's like the whole safe deposit box at the bank thing. They don't know what's in it.
They don't want to know what's in it.
You've got your key, you go in the room, you mess with it.
Like don't just don't ask, don't tell, I don't want to know, you don't want to tell me.
No, this is uh we're gonna maybe, I don't know, there's a PDF here and
they have a list of stuff that they don't
yet support anywhere but like some of this stuff is
like page level side channels, example, attack, track VM,
access patterns through page tables like they haven't fixed it yet,
but it's on essentially, this looks like their to do list.
And that's really cool. I mean, this is, and look, let's
it. So here's, here's one of the things to always think about, right?
You've got Intel and AMD are the dominant CPU makers today.
Arms coming up pretty fast. I'm getting it
right arm is coming up. And what is the advantage Intel and AMD have over arm today?
For example, I can use it to heat my house,
but you get the idea right?
Is,
is this is the kind of work that someone like a MD and
Intel need to start doing because just having AC pu isn't enough,
just having cores isn't enough.
Just having fast virtualization isn't enough.
And so this is actually really exciting.
And in a lot of ways,
I think this is going to be more exciting for the future of processors
than what we saw in the past where it was just about speed
this
to that true utility grid
mode of computing
where I can just throw workloads out to some,
I may not even ultimate like essentially the model that a lot of people want is I,
I have a workload
and I go to a market for, you know,
compute time and power and I don't even
actually maybe know where my thing is running.
It's just I, I have a broker who offers me the best rate
and I get my workload run through them
and knowing that they can't monkey with it
and the ultimate provider which could be like,
Lord knows where can't monkey with it.
That's the dream
because it just makes security so much simpler.
And well, I mean, that's what we've done with the electric grid, right?
Like I get my electrons don't care where they came from.
Like uh my understanding is, you know,
Alberta has what we have a lot of power generation,
but we also import power from other places sometimes and export it.
And
like, I don't care if my electrons are from BC or the US.
Right. Right. I, I have a friend who
worked for a company that was an electricity broker and he explained this to me
once and I'm sure I'm going to oversimplify and get some of this wrong.
But I mean,
functionally it was a matter of people would have power
and they would say I'm going to sell this power for
this price and everyone just kind of laid down their price.
And for example,
a nuclear power plant is generating electricity
no matter what it doesn't, you know.
So they're just going to say I'm generating electricity,
here's the price I'll take and their price is
always the lowest just because it's like they're,
they're making it and they can't stop.
Whereas there's other places where, for example,
like a wind farm could look and say, all right, so the price looks like it's,
I can't make money doing that, uh turn them off, you know,
and then you just don't do anything and that's OK sometimes.
But I mean, obviously in the case of most renewables, it's very much.
Uh well, this is basically free. So.
Well,
the difference being with compute is if I have all this compute infrastructure,
essentially my marginal costs,
I'm not going to say are zero,
but they're damn close to zero in the form of electricity and operations.
And I have to do operations like you can't just have
everybody take off for the day and not pay them,
uh, electricity.
You know,
I can't just actually turn everything off to a cold state and save a few bucks.
So, the problem is I have all this stuff that if it's sitting there not making money,
it's, I'm actively losing money because also, like, last I checked,
computers don't hold a lot of value past three years.
Three years, probably three months now. Well, yeah. Well, in data centers. Yeah.
I mean, that's my understanding of like a lot of S sds and stuff because they,
they ro I and what not, especially on energy expenditures measured in months.
But I mean, that's
exactly it. Right.
So your electricity thing,
there's also I learned the other day actually that there are
companies that agree to buy a certain amount of electricity,
whether or not they need it.
Thus they get a better price.
So it's like the inverse of the nuclear power plant generating it all the time.
They say we will guaranteed consume X.
And the challenge though is they actually have to physically
consume X ray because otherwise the grid would get unbalanced.
I bet for factories. That's probably not hard crypto coin mining.
Right? That's, that's part of how these guys get their cheap electricity
is. They, they basically say like, well, I got a bunch of, you know, mining rigs.
Yeah, they have to stay turned on or I'm literally like, literally losing money.
Right. Right.
And so they agreed to buy x amount of electricity, you know, for cheap and,
and do it no matter what,
which is one of the reasons apparently why they have such a hard time doing upgrades.
Right, because they can't shut down properly. Right. Interesting.
So, here's, I have one other bit to add before we end this. And
that is.
So obviously I'm sure that one thing everyone's thinking about right now is
talking about this kind of utility computing and sending jobs out is,
oh, but who owns the keys?
Because obviously,
if you don't control the key and you're sending a job out it,
it doesn't matter because if the bad guys
own, if they have access to all the keys,
they can do whatever they want. But the good news is the window of opportunity is very
much shortened. You don't need a window of opportunity.
Part of this technology is their management interface
gives you the ability to bring your own keys into the environment,
which is
really, really wild. I mean, I,
of course, there's tons of asterisks and there's lots of complicated
things you need to worry about here.
But you know,
more of the point I'm looking at this and the amount of
progress they've made in the last four years is mind boggling it.
It, I have no doubt.
And I'm saying I should,
I should have looked more of this up before we started the show.
Unfortunately, ran out of time. But yes, it is
amazing. Technology encrypted CPU registers without a performance hit. Well,
performance hit. It's acceptable though. Yeah.
Right. Right.
I love it. It is so cool
and I'm so excited to see someone actually using this now for real.
Well,
not just using it but providing it to the rest of
us in a way where we can actually use it realistically.
You know, this isn't some, like hypothetical, well, you know,
if you rewrite your software to use these special extensions, it's just a VM.
Yeah, it's,
it's extremely cool and I can't wait to see
where this goes next because I think there is
a lot of potential for a lot of really cool technology. I mean, this is the dream.
Like I want to be able to chuck my workloads
and approve and I don't want to pay the extra,
what is it like $10 an hour for a, like for a, you know,
a dedicated computer host because $10 an hour adds up?
Uh Right. Oh, yeah, yeah, definitely.
But even even with dedicated compute hosts,
if you can't trust your cloud provider,
you have a problem.
It's awesome. I'm excited. I can't wait to see where it goes. All right, man.
I'm calling it.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes,
use the Poland Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media,
Kurt and have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.