Hello and welcome to episode 46 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
Merry Christmas. Kurt.
Huh?
Yeah, that, that right.
So yesterday was
Christmas time for security people because of that crazy Google fish.
I was so excited. It was, it was amazing to see someone
mount an attack that while everyone kind of knew could happen,
-- we haven't seen like a good worm in a long time and this one
-- a
while
ago,
uh that was less exciting. I felt like, uh, and,
and this one was
very well done.
I was, I was incredibly impressed
and, and granted, it didn't really do any, any significant damage,
which makes it much nicer as well.
Like if it had taken out half the internet I'd be crying instead of being all excited.
Well, see, and that's,
that's actually the worst thing is it could have done something really nasty, like,
say, replaced a random value in every spreadsheet it found,
you know, and just modify it by like, say 2%.
And the funny thing is you, you would have been able to find it.
Had you been willing to go through your logs of what changed over the last 24 hours,
but who's going to do that?
Right.
Google.
Well, but, you know, see here's the thing.
So, like, uh I have, you know, well, like most people, I have Google apps, you know,
for my personal email, right,
or Google, whatever it's called now.
And I actually pay for the Google uh vault, right? The extra
uh and the nice thing is it gives you insane audit trails.
Like, for example, my calendars, every single thing, addition change removal,
everything is audited and like logged and you can go
through those logs and search them and export them.
So the reality is like a worm like this.
Yeah, it could have been like, let's say for the sake of argument,
it did do something terrible like delete stuff or modify stuff.
You actually could have like programmatically
cleaned up after it.
And my thinking is like, you know, it's like those crypto locker viruses where you,
you know, these people can't, they have no,
they have no like imagine a crypto locker virus
that instead of crypto locking just said was like,
I may or may not have randomly changed some values in your financial.
It would be
probably more powerful.
Yeah.
Um
So I'm I'm kind of curious it, it's interesting to me now because in theory, you know,
because all this,
we have these huge audit trails and we have all this data stored by Google
in a way where, you know, even if it's deleted, it's, it's not really gone anymore.
Yeah. And that's kind of something I suspect is
even if you're not paying for their vault,
I bet they could undo any changes and let's face it too. So true
story.
Yeah.
Uh, person I know,
um,
their email account at Google, um, got,
uh,
the organization deleted it.
This person because of who they are in
the industry was able to find somebody at Google
to have them reinstate the account and recover it.
Right.
So it's, it's technically possible for them to,
it's just normally they don't do that because, you know, it's such a hassle, right?
They don't want to get support calls being like
dip, I accidentally deleted my account. Can you please fix it?
But the reality is like that stuff.
I mean,
obviously Google has backups because you know what if one of their
data sensors catches fire or what if all of them catch fire?
-- I
-- don't know if they have backups in the traditional
sense as much as just massive replication of data.
-- They do have offline backups.
-- They do good for them.
But I mean, I think fundamentally this is one of the things with cloud,
people need to make sure they understand is if you hit delete
it, it's never gone.
It.
I guarantee
that data sticks around probably forever.
Well, but the, the, probably the closest we'll ever get to being gone is,
you know, all the backups are encrypted now, obviously, because, you know,
backup tapes do get lost
or forgotten or sent to the wrong address.
Um So the, the generally speaking, the closest we'll get to delete it is, you know,
crypto shredding of the keys that would
un encrypt the data.
I, I bet they don't even go that far.
Uh The, well, depending on which organization it is. Some do.
-- It's
-- probably for, for example, I know in, in like elastic search,
when you delete data, it doesn't really get deleted, it's just mark deleted,
it's all still there.
And the thing is too, is,
-- is properly deleting data is like horrendously difficult and
-- it takes a long
time and when you're really concerned about latency and things like that,
like who cares, do it later
and there's ways to force it to happen like
where you condense your indexes and things like that.
But fundamentally,
no,
because what if your elastic search is sitting on some sort of NFS file system
that's abstracted and actually running on a cluster
file system that's actually running on an SSD
ignoring that, right? Just in the context of
data store. So anyway, I am
not done
with the Google Fish
because I love this story and, and I want to tell you what happened to me
and I'm, I'm smiling, I'm so giddy. It's not even funny. So anyway,
I'm on a phone call. I have a meeting. Right.
And my wife barges into my office and says
I've just been hacked someone, sending everyone in my contact list emails.
And I thought, oh,
ok. Well, that's exciting.
Right.
And so I, I get up, well, the first thing I did was I said, bring me your computer
and, and of course, so she does. And the first thing I did is I logged.
I too use Google apps.
I log in as my account administrator and I just lock her account.
I sign out all sessions and I change her password, right?
And I thought, ok, now we'll go and uh
II I set her up with, with uh
last pass and UB key for, for U two F and all that stuff, right? And I'm getting her,
I'm walking her through it and whatnot.
And then I come back to my office and I sit down and I see the email from her
and I thought, oh, ok. Well, let's see what this is right.
And I look at it and think
this is good, right? Like
it. So, I don't know. Did, did you get one?
I sadly did not,
you're just not cool enough, Kurt.
So anyway, anyway, so here's what happened is
you get the email and it basically says like so and so shared a
Google document with you and it looked just like the Google Docs sharing email.
The, the email looks fairly legitimate
and
you open it up it appears to be a Google Docs sharing email.
And
so I click the open button
and the first thing it does is it says,
which account do you want to open this with for Google?
Because obviously everyone has more than one Google account.
And I thought this is new. Right.
So I, I click on my, uh, funny enough, my kids account
is the one I have.
Right. Right.
Well, they don't send email, they don't have contacts, things like that.
So anyway, uh I click their account
and then it asks if I want to allow Google Docs
and it has all the Google icons and everything,
Google Docs to have access to my email and basically everything, right?
Like full access.
And I thought that's not right.
And so basically I, I went back and I pulled apart the email
that I got to just see what's going on and
it turned out it was pointing at a another domain.
And
uh well, no, no, the mail was all your mail was CC demin.
That's how they were harvesting kind of the contact lens. That's
what that ends up being.
But then uh so basically what it was, it was in, in an o
off request for all access to some site. That was, it was very well done
in, in terms of what it was named.
And then,
right? So obviously this was not Google, it was just, this is how OO
works
in the context of allowing just
for a quick maybe run down for our viewers. What exactly is oo
it, it's kind of a, an authorization system that exists on the internet.
Like when you, when you try to log into something, it says log in with Google,
that's essentially o
off and part of that system says you can grant access to certain information.
So for example,
when for at a minimum, it needs to know who you are from Google
and then certain things like actually that,
that unroll me thing we talked about last time
was this where enroll me?
Told Google, hey, uh I want access to all this person's email and of course,
the person has to accept it.
Same thing here, right?
So anyway, my story is not done though.
So anyway, I, I figure out what's going on and I'm like, oh man,
this is an oath attack like this is super cool.
I get all excited and I'm like, oh, no, wait and I go running through the house.
I get to my wife like, give me your computer right now and she's like, what's going on?
I said just give it to, we don't have questions and I like taken from her
and I go into her Google settings and I,
and I remove that application from having access to her account right immediately.
And she's like, what's going on?
I'm like, stop talking, I'll tell you in a minute, you know,
it's like, I'm typing furiously to get to what needs to be done.
And anyway, then it gets done.
I tried to explain it to her and she mostly understood it.
But, but the fundamental thing and here's what it really has me. So excited is
what are the things we'd love to talk about in security? We love to talk about.
Uh, make sure you give your user awareness training, which doesn't work.
And then we say, well, why don't you two factor authentication?
But in this instance, two factor a
does not help you because you're already authenticated.
It's just someone's tricking you into giving a a
malicious site access to all of your Google data.
I'm like this is like the perfect attack, right? It's, it's brilliant.
Yeah. No, I'm just, I'm actually looking at. So if you go to my account, do,
for example, with Google,
you go to my account.google.com/permissions and that shows
you which apps are connected to your account.
So obviously, my Google Chrome has full access to my account.
At least I hope that's my Google Chrome.
Uh Same for my I Os and Os X.
And then I have a thing called Pixar Express
that I don't remember giving access to something.
What the
heck is that?
OK.
Remove that.
So yeah, I I myself have something I'm looking at and I do not recognize it.
I bet that's super common because people
give access to stuff all the time.
Everything else has access to just basic account info,
which basically means like feed le or discuss whatever it just, yeah,
it knows who I am so that I can authenticate to that service.
But so yeah, perfect example. I had that Pixl dot whatever the hell that was
and I don't, I don't recall at all what that was
interesting.
Um I think it was an image editing thing that I might have fired up for some.
But uh regardless, this is a great example because, yeah,
even as a security professional, I clearly at some point whiffed one of these.
But
here's the thing actually,
if my wife hadn't run in the room and said I'm being hacked,
if I would have just opened that mail from her,
I would have been like, well, this is a little weird but OK,
and
I, I'm not saying I would or wouldn't have,
but I don't think clicking the allow Google docs access to
my stuff would have been out of the question at all
because it looked,
it looked really legit. I'm not gonna lie to you. I mean,
it looked good. The, these people, they did a great job making it look good.
Yeah. No, this is what gets me is um
the majority of protocols,
especially security protocols and authentication protocols
don't really seem to have a graceful failure scenario for
when an attacker uses them to impersonate somebody else.
I mean,
uh TLS and SSL are a great example, right? Oh Look for the lock icon.
-- Well, except, you know, now you can get an SSL actually.
-- Could you bring that up?
Because obviously that's the first thing I did is I looked at the URL bar saying,
where am I? Right? I'm on google.com. I have the green EV cert.
So I'm thinking all right, this looks legit, right? Like,
and that's the thing everything we've ever taught people
failed in this instance because we were not prepared for this instance.
However, however, here's the one thing I will say
is
there, it would be very difficult to defend against this.
But what Google did is exactly the right thing is they acted quickly in like an hour.
This was shut down.
You think about that an hour, how many,
-- how many it departments can respond
-- in this specific attack was shut down quickly.
But the problem is the fundamental,
here's what I have with this attack is that
fundamentally you can't stop this attack because it's,
it's like a name space problem, right?
And even if for example, this um
like for example, Google could show the domain name that the
oath request is coming from as part of that request.
I think that would be reasonable.
And also it said Google docs,
Kurt like Google should not allow anything with Google's name in it.
But what about
uh
well, what about
like, you know gmail or what about, you know, the problem is there's so many
stuff.
I don't know
what I'm saying is from a name space perspective.
There's so many keywords and words that have special meaning like admin or
support or,
you know, help or like you get an email from like help or support or something,
you know, chances are it's gonna fool enough people.
-- Right. Well,
-- ok. Yes. And, and I think the right way to handle this is to lay down
some level of sane rules.
Like for example, I think saying nothing with Google in the name or,
or if it has Google in the name,
make a human click the OK button after they verify what's going on.
But I think the right answer is to
not over engineer this but wait for things to happen
like this and then just fix that particular instance.
But see the problem is perfect example,
I've actually had this happen to me is when we went to cloud flare,
uh the cloud security lines went to cloud flare.
You know,
supposedly cloud flare will be all automated provisioning will
happen in minutes and you'll be up and running.
So I click turn on SSL and guess what happens?
Nothing.
-- Uh
-- You told me this story because you were using something weird
-- because the
-- word we have the word security in our domain.
And so it required a human check and I did this on a Friday afternoon
and it didn't get handled, I think until Sunday or Monday.
And that was because of the, the, the higher level registrar,
I think it was like Komodo
or whoever
was handling it, you know, that was, it was their thing. Right.
It was kind of outside of
exactly the right way to do this.
Well,
but the problem is then you end up pissing
the number of false positives is going to be huge
because your restricted keyword list is going to have to be huge. What if I use IBM?
Or what if I use, uh Compu
Corp or what if I use? You know what I mean?
Walmart?
I,
I'm ok with that. I think if you're running it,
how does Walmart legitimately tie into it?
Maybe they don't.
Well,
but now you're not going to allow Walmart to run
any apps that allow people to authenticate via Google.
-- Well, no,
-- no, no, you certainly do.
But you, you add an extra layer of protection, I think.
Uh, see,
I disagree because fundamentally you're going to
get people just doing click through.
Ok.
Right. We tried that. Remember Windows vista?
This is different.
It's not different. You're gonna ask people, are you really sure you want to give ft
full access to your Google Drive?
Yes or no.
If they click, no, the service doesn't work and they're like, well,
what the heck just happened
if you click? Yes, it works and nothing bad.
-- No, no, I
-- don't.
No. Ok. I think we're talking about two different things. I'm saying
if I'm trying to register
something against Google to use o
of
because obviously you have to register
against their service.
And I'm saying if the name, if the word Google appears in the service,
you're trying to register
Google should say,
hold on their buddy
and then have either extra hoops to jump through to do some extra verification or
just have a human being at Google. Look at this and say,
yeah, this is fine because it's like,
you know, Googly
Eyes dot Commerce.
-- So
-- the problem is it would have to be automated because otherwise it's not going
to scale because the Attackers are going to send in billions of these requests,
right? Because you can just set the o
off name.
Well, yes, but if it doesn't scale like that and, and you have a problem with it,
then just deny them all
right. And, and if you want to get it, then pay Google,
you know what I mean? Like become a proper customer and give them money.
Like that's the thing, right?
You need to make sure there's a certain barrier of entry here that makes it too.
It's like you were talking about this uh some time ago about when
you register a domain name charging people like a quarter to prevent those.
That's what I'm talking about here is you need to have some sort of barrier to entry.
Sorry, I thought you meant the end users
were doing
actual Google
that makes
more
sense.
Users are the product, right? Like ignore those guys.
So that makes a bit of sense. Yeah, I mean,
in that case,
but the problem I see with this though is that
Google would have to have a huge list of keywords
and people would still fall for it. I mean,
the the great example is right now, you know,
the revenue Canada has sent out multiple bulletins saying like first of all,
we're not going to phone you,
right?
Second of all,
we're only going to email you if you have registered an account with us.
And third of all,
we definitely don't take payment of taxes and itunes gift cards over the phone.
-- Like really we don't,
-- that could be a huge business model,
you know, and and it's getting to the point now where, you know, it's, it's
like this one lady um uh had a newborn, she was super sleep deprived
and she's lost her life savings because she, you know, like
-- you take somebody who is insanely sleep deprived and yeah, you know,
-- ok, but so,
so here's the thing
what you describe
sounds like revenue Canada is taking what I
would call acceptable steps to mitigate this threat,
but they can't mitigate it, right?
They can educate the people, they can't actually stop it from happening,
they cannot stop it from happening.
But if you can make sure it's ok for let's say 80% of the population,
that's good enough and that's the best you're gonna get.
You're never gonna get it through 100%.
And let's face it, man.
We've been around long enough to know that,
that like 20% of the population can basically basically be tricked into anything.
-- And,
-- and well, see, my concern is for, from Google's perspective,
is it worth building this thing?
Like does it, you know, reduce their cost,
does it improve their brand enough to get more customers?
-- Does anybody
-- care?
Uh Right. I think there's two sides to this coin. On one side,
Google has to ensure whatever they're doing,
helps maintain their revenue stream and their trust.
Because a lot of what Google does is built on trust, people, trust Google. OK.
-- And I know I can we
-- go back to the Galaxy Seven argument. We
-- argue
-- that
we can
-- argue
-- that you can set stuff on fire and people don't seem to mind it.
-- But
-- here's the other side of it is I think at this
point and I think Google has recognized this to a degree.
Google is an organization now that I think there are
certain expectations of them to act in the public.
Good
because they run the freaking world.
Yeah, it's, well,
it's interesting to me because kind of at what point do they become
a utility essentially in the sense of like from a regulatory and public
use and good point of view, right? Because,
and I would argue that they're very definitely there.
I, I, I don't think you're wrong but they're,
-- they would disagree. I'm sure
-- of
course they would
disagree. But
the reality is like, you know, here's the thing.
Um, you have to give up Gmail forever or running water forever.
And the fact is you're going to think about
-- it.
-- No, I would give up Gmail before running water.
But only because I've read a lot of
stories about what life was like before plumbing existed
and
for the
sake of
cholera,
you can live off the grid and you have to
do your own electricity or you can give up Gmail.
Let's face it.
Building your own little mini grid would be a lot easier than having your own email,
docs and stuff at this point.
-- It
-- sounds like fun to build my own grid.
Yeah,
but I mean, that's the thing, right?
Is like the fact that you're not just, you know,
it'd be like the difference between giving up like candy and you know, whatever,
right?
Everybody would be like I give up candy fine. It's awesome, you know. But
I mean,
yeah, that what really worries me though is like at some point.
Yeah, I just
these,
you don't want to introduce the other concern I have is with these security measures
is you don't want to introduce security measures
that have a high rate of false positives
and a low rate of actually catching the bad guys
and maybe a low rate of actually being effective.
And that would be part of my concern with this is that
you filter out maybe certain keywords
and yeah, you'll get some of the low hanging fruit. But fundamentally,
I mean,
uh my take on it would be maybe more that, that, you know,
when I grant access to Google Docs to an app,
you know, it'd be really nice if I could just give it access to a single folder,
right?
So I could have like that one folder for, you know,
using with whatever that Pixar thing I had was instead of everything of it,
you know what I mean?
Or for example, that, you know, it created uh like
a
like, you know, it created sort of like a quasi
user called pixel or that I could then assign access to the, you know,
the documents and stuff I actually wanted to interact with,
you know, the downside of that being is that everything just doesn't work anymore,
right?
You have to go through a whole bunch of extra
steps to set up security and permissions and travel,
avise me if they've discussed things like this before.
But I think there's,
there's also one other really important point we have to make sure we discuss is
this exact attack was described in 2011 on a mailing
list which I'll put a link in the show notes
and, and anyone who understands oo
is well aware that this has always been a possibility.
But here's, here's my question though.
This was described in detail in 2011.
And it took essentially six years before anyone did it.
Well,
six years until we found out anyone did a
worm,
I'm sure there have been similar attacks. And that, that leads me to really wonder,
did the person who did this,
did they screw up where it wasn't supposed to worm itself?
It was just supposed to attack their target, you know,
X fill whatever I assume they're looking for, for contacts
to be X filled
and then they somehow goofed it up.
So it turned into a worm on accident or did someone legitimately create the worm?
I think you'd legitimately have to create the
worm because to accidentally worm something is,
you know, it's a bit of nontrivial work.
But
I would say even more fundamentally,
this problem boils down to something we've known for decades, which is when you let
anybody choose any name and present it as being like, hey, I'm Google.
Really? That, that's what this says,
you know.
Right. Like it's when my old ISP, let you choose your host name.
And I tried admin and that was a reserved keyword and I tried support and that
was a reserved keyword and I tried local hosting that was not a reserved keyword.
Sweet.
-- And then you have to actually call them on the phone,
-- right?
Because, yeah, because my internet like collapsed
because the way DNS works is you look, when you look up a name, first of all,
you look up name dot whatever your search domain is,
then if that doesn't work, you look up that name, you know. So in.
Yeah.
So I basically got hammered with everybody's local host traffic to some degree
for badly behaving apps, right? Because realistically anyways,
yeah,
but the point being is whenever you've allowed people to present a
name with absolutely no third party verification or very limited verification.
Like
for example, you know, SSL and TLS domain verification, it's like,
yeah, I registered this domain and I control it.
That proves that I am food.com, which is technically correct.
But that doesn't prove that like legally you should have the rights to food.com.
You know,
a great example being like in Australia,
apparently Burger King is not Burger King because
somebody already had Burger King in Australia.
So Burger King in Australia is hungry. Jack's
interesting.
I, you know, if I'd gone to Australia
and gone to a Burger King, I would have been like, what the heck is wrong with the menu,
you know, like
I would have been very confused.
And
-- so
-- here
essentially the bad guys can do this globally though, right?
They can grab any domain name.
Yeah, they can grab any domain
Google dot
Yeah, but if you look, if you, if you take like Google dot something,
they're gonna come get you and they're gonna get it back.
All right. That's the reality of it. No, they, they're going to
maybe if, if, like, if I go by
cried dot CX or something and put like, porn on it.
No, you probably can't do anything about it, but Google can.
True.
But I, I,
and that brings up one of my favorite things with all these new top level
domains is one of the main selling points for like dot sucks was like,
you probably wanna do uh defensive registries.
And that's kind of,
I was actually thinking about registering like a root top level domain.
The whole point of it being
it was, that's like 100 grand, isn't it to get
100 and $80,000 in the US?
But when you look like we registered dot Watch domain
and it was like 500 bucks for a year.
So, I mean, you only need a couple 1000 registrations to break even.
-- I'm just saying
-- only
except I'm man, I bet it's so much work to do that.
Um Well, there's a couple of 100 new top level domains. So, I mean, there's a
lot of
people,
you know, and if you look at,
I was actually looking through the people applying to be these top level domains,
some of them were Big corps that you would expect,
right? Like big DNS registers, whatever and some of them were like
as far as I could tell like a guy
uh yeah, there was uh Oh, I forget I was talking to some guys from,
I think it was Blue Coat one time and they were talking about there,
there was this one TLD
that was, it looked like it was owned by literally like a guy
and it was like 99% of the traffic that came from these domains was malicious.
Like it was clearly set up for, for tricking people and that's all it was done for.
No, I've thought about this
as you know, but it turns out I'm not a bad guy so
that we know of.
Yeah, true.
But uh no, I mean, that's, that's what gets me is, is um I mean,
that's one of the reasons I like the UB
key and the uh the that authentication protocol is,
it includes the domain name
in the authentication process
which really helps cut down on the fishing stuff on the UB key. And,
but the problem is if you're authenticating against
some random domain where it's
like the
Google doesn't show me really the domain that that request came from.
You know, it shows me the a
name like a great example here is I see.
Um
I
do
it.
OK. So here's the deal. I'm gonna stop you though
is
I suspect the right way to handle this is
using Google to authenticate authenticate against an unknown domain
is great because now you've got a very limited o
off trust relationship. The trick is
Google needs a nicer way
to make people requesting additional permissions outside of just who am I?
They need to add hoops there
because this comes back to that 25 cents to register a domain
because let any Tom Dick or Harry off people against
you because that's actually very useful and far more secure than
people picking crappy user names and passwords for every stupid
website they need to use like every forum on earth.
Right?
But there is no reason
for a like random site to read your email.
Well, I mean, unless it's something I want, like it's a spell checker
or I've been seeing
a
thing that checks your grammar and actually just one comment too.
I'm looking at the my
account.google.com/permissions thing,
for example, I click on Ed X, right? Uh That
online university thing doesn't show me the domain.
It just shows me Ed X and their logo and remove and it says when I
authorized it
and, and
this is
useless.
There's no information here for me to make a decision.
-- Yes,
-- it's a bad U I in that respect. I agree with that.
-- I suspect they're going to fix it after this particular event.
-- I would hope so.
I mean, because I would go,
I mean,
yeah, that would definitely go a long way to helping people
and, and this is part of it again, is
security is hard. It's easy to screw it up.
Google responded quickly, which was great.
And now as long as they do something about this and they,
they make some change to fix it.
I would say this was a
successful event
-- for the powers of
-- good.
And here's my biggest concern though is Google will
most likely make some changes and do some real,
I'm guessing that they'll do some public facing stuff we know about.
And I'm also guessing they're going to do some stuff in the background.
You know, I would assume that they're smart enough to be like, hey, you know,
we know a little bit about machine learning and domains.
Maybe we should sort of like,
yeah, like you said, add a hoop for people requesting full access and, you know,
compare that to,
you know,
people who close their accounts or complained about being hacked or whatever.
But my concern is that Google will do something about it.
But all these other places I'm apparently o off
against won't,
it doesn't matter with all
-- up though
-- because
for example, Twitter or Facebook
-- or
-- those guys,
I guess here's part of it too though. Those guys are pretty smart cookies.
I'm
the number of sites that use Twitter to authenticate and then
want full access to send and receive tweets on my behalf.
-- I'm like,
-- no, I have never, although I never use Twitter to authenticate,
I will, I will set up AAA different account
before I would use Twitter. I use Google
or I create crappy passwords
using the password manager but I, I refuse to use Facebook or Twitter
to do any sort of,
well, I guess part of it too though is every time I've tried, like you said, they,
they, they ask for too much and I think that's why,
where Google seems like they've got it figured out of, like, email only.
Yeah. And I'm ok with that.
What do you mean email address only? Not actual?
Right. Right. Exactly. Like who am I?
So, which they're gonna know anyway, if I register a regular account with them,
here's a thought for Google. If you're listening,
uh by default, give them access to whatever they want.
The Google Docs, the gmail, the whole contacts thing,
but make it like a fake sandboxed one
until the user explicitly gives them real access.
That could be interesting to actually,
that's kind of how Android permissions work.
Now is you install an app
and then the first time it wants to say, like, use your camera, it'll say, you know,
the blah, blah, blah app wants access to your camera, allow, deny
and, and the various permissions and.
Right. Right. Which, which does work well.
And it would be really interesting too if they would tell you
what particular linked things and what they're accessing and what they're doing,
that would be probably
the other advantage would be is it wouldn't automatically break all these apps,
you know, some of them are legitimately useful.
Yeah.
Yeah, we can.
Well,
I question if any of the ones that can read
and send email on my behalf are technically useful.
I did,
I did use one for a little while that allowed you to interact with PDF S in
-- a way that Google Docs itself did not support and
-- that needed access to your email.
No, it needed
access
to my
Google.
I get
that. That's fine. That's fine.
You
know,
and the other one I've seen,
like I said is a spelling and grammar checker thing that helps you.
Uh just write
better emails, better papers, better, whatever
I heard
this, you know, I see, I keep seeing ads for on youtube which makes me, you know,
wonder why I'm being targeted for this.
Do I not speak good English?
Um
No, you
don't write well.
So I actually got a targeted dad the other day that actually applies to me.
It was for goldfish crackers which my kids eat a ton of man.
Every kid eats a ton of goldfish crackers.
And I bet under, under your car seats, I bet you have,
I
have to
goldfish,
I vacuum it out every two months because they,
they eat goldfish crackers in the car and it's just,
they do vacuum up nicely.
They, they're until they get crushed and ground into the carpet.
Which, but anyway, anyway,
-- you know,
-- go back to this. I mean that this is the thing, right? Is
I, I guess really we have really two big problems here.
One is, you know, oh, it says it's Google or Apple or support or my it guy.
Sure. Right. That must be legit.
And there's no real easy way to tell actually who it is.
-- Right.
-- And so they're riding on the coattails of like Google's authenticity.
Right.
And I think that was kind of,
the intent always was we assumed Google was doing something there,
which they either aren't or there's some sort of loophole.
Yeah. And then that second, um, problem is just,
you know,
generally speaking,
if we make permissions fine grained people end up turning them
all on anyways because they just want stuff to work.
So a lot of places like this, you know, defaults to do,
you want to give it access to your email and it's like, boom all of your email,
like not just your inbox but like the whole thing or same thing with docs.
It's like all of your docs, not just
you remember back in the day where you had
a shell account and you had your public underscore html
directory and if you put stuff in there, it would now show up on the web server, right?
You know.
Uh and, and that actually worked pretty well for a while. Um
So, you know, something like that where for example, maybe, yeah, like I said,
it adds a fake user or it kind of adds like a
folder that you can like share the stuff into so that one app can access, you
-- know what it
-- means. Like you're talking about a lot of complexity.
Well, exactly.
And that's why it won't work for 99% of people and only work for you and me.
And then one day we'll get tired of it and just turn it off or enable it for everything.
See, that's the problem. Right. With that, those complex permissions.
Yes,
they become
painful to administer.
and,
and if I had to guess Google is going to solve this on their end with some Google magic
because we can't rely on people to do it. Right.
Well, even if people do it right.
99.9% of the time assuming Google has about a billion users. Which,
-- that's
-- true with the law of large numbers,
every insane thing possible does happen all of the time.
Yeah.
I mean, the reality is somebody's going to be sleep deprived enough to not realize
or just
not a computer person.
Oh, it's funny. So, yesterday I had some, uh, I got some new headshots taken,
you know, from my website and whatnot.
Like my linkedin profile because basically my, my current headshots are,
are old enough that I have hair in them.
Um,
and, and also I've had people go, who is that?
Um, but anyway, so the guy is, you know,
obviously we're chit chat and he's asking me what
I do and it's computers here and he's like,
oh, I got a question for you
and basically too long didn't read a friend
of a friend, had a spouse or whatever. Die
computer has a password. Computer also has photos on it. What can we do about that?
And so I explained about, you know, getting one of those, uh, bootle
C DS to reset the password and windows. And
I'm assuming that their hard drive is not encrypted because, you know,
they're not a super savvy person. So this should actually be relatively easy to do.
And if that doesn't work, you know, just pop the hard drive out, put it in a caddy,
plug it into your machine and, like,
go hunting for photos,
you know.
But, and it was like, it really does boil down to, you know, that like,
sort of normal people, like,
on the one hand, I, you know, I wish everybody would encrypt their hard drives,
but on the other hand, I really, it's gonna, you know, for your,
for the survivors of when that person dies and takes the password with them,
it's gonna suck,
you know, because how many people have, like, say their passwords
written down in a way that somebody else can get access to and keeps them up to date.
Most people don't.
Exactly. You know.
No, no, I, I'm very familiar with this problem.
Right.
-- So,
-- part of me wants people to have better security encrypted devices,
like encrypted phones and stuff.
But at the same time, you know, now we're getting to that
more common case of like, oh, you know, my son died,
I'd like to get access to the photos on his iphone,
which then also raises the question of, you know, maybe he doesn't want,
maybe he doesn't want people to have access to those photos. You know
what this reminds me of always is,
is the jokes you see on things like reddit where people joke about,
you know, delete my browsing history when I die.
But of course, as a security person, my first thought is, well,
why aren't you just using an incognito browser?
You idiot.
It's a funny joke. And I totally understand what you're saying.
Yeah. Well, see, that's one of the biggest problems is right is when something asks
for permission to do something,
we don't know necessarily what the intent is.
-- Uh
-- if you don't, then,
then you deny permission because if you don't know what the intent is,
why are you even doing that thing in the first place?
Well, because you know,
-- this unroll me thing says it would get rid of all my spam email,
-- right?
And, and in that case, I think
the you understood the intent.
It's then there was a misuse of trust on the part of enroll me
and, and things like that are also going to happen and,
and even I'm sure Google is guilty of this to a degree.
But in, in those cases, you just have to deal with them on a case by case basis.
Because, I mean, if,
if you pretend you're a paranoid nut all the time you end up like us.
-- Right. Yeah,
-- exactly.
Unemployable outside a very niche.
Right.
-- And, and you get your own podcast someday. So,
-- yeah.
Yeah. And you anyways.
Yeah. No, it's, I, yeah, well, see what fundamentally boils down to me is,
it's a user interface issue,
right? Like, really what it boils down to is is you're trying to
let me,
let me finish it.
It's the interface of the computer and the person.
And that's a tough problem.
Right?
I, I'm going to say that's an impossible problem.
I think we,
we have never been able to design a system that people can't be easily fooled.
And even if you design a better interface,
the bad guys are just going to design a better attack.
I think the only solution to this is to stop this kind of stuff on the back end.
And when I say stop this stuff, I mean, stop 80% of it because you can't get it all.
And that's, that's basically the best we can hope for is as long as we can kind of,
you know, it's kind of like your disease analogy.
You always use, you know, we, we can't stop everyone from dying,
but we can stop most people from dying.
-- Well, for a while.
-- Hopefully.
Yeah,
it's uh no, I just know what I mean, in the sense of a U I issue is that there's,
it's really hard to display security
related information to people in a way that's really understandable.
And I mean, a good counter example of it is roads,
right, road signs, you know, a lot of thought went into those things,
the colors, the shapes, you know, the all of that
to make it clear, like, you know, this is a yield sign, this is a stop sign.
One of these is a strong suggestion.
The other one is like,
you really better do this or else something bad is going to happen.
Sure.
You know, and I've never seen good.
I mean, windows vista being a great example of that, you know, the,
with the user access controls, like those constant pop up warnings.
Yeah, they were a great idea except then it, you know,
you immediately went to alarm fatigue.
Do you know, I talked to the guy who came up with that idea.
This was a long time ago and like he said, as security people,
we thought it was a great idea, right?
And then obviously it, it turned out to be a terrible mistake
and, and I, I guess this is part of our challenge as well,
is security people often think something is
a great idea and normal people disagree.
Well, even security people, the part of it is this idea
seems great on paper and it looks great if you do it. For one or two days.
But if you have to use it for like 10 years,
you know, you're going to want to murder somebody by the end of those 10 years.
That's also true.
Firewalls. Great idea. Except now we all just poke a hole for port
and maybe port 80.
Uh
Sure, I think firewalls are fairly successful.
But I think the reason for that is we made them usable.
The majority of places I've seen using firewalls don't actually have that
detailed or tight rule sets outside of where they're like using a subscription to.
Like, here's a list of a sites block them,
you know,
and so it's, they've, they've sort of outsourced that piece and, you know,
and this is something where like this is something I've never seen is like, you know,
some sort of registry or review site for like, you know, here's these o
off sites
which ones are trustworthy and which ones are not like, for example,
looking in my thing.
Well, some of these are apps. So right off the bat that gets a bit complicated.
But some of them, you know, like, for example,
disgust.com wants basic access to my account info clearly.
That's ok.
Right. It's, it's the online comments and it just wants to know who I am. Sure.
So like five out of five stars, a
green thumbs up or whatever, you know,
same for feed, le same for medium,
you know. But then there's like these other apps where it's like, you know,
uh, because I've often wondered, like,
are people trying to maybe use this to harvest
account names?
It
maybe, I, I doubt it.
-- I think
-- that, I don't think it's worth it,
but it's probably not, it's,
it's way easier to just write a worm
that handles everybody in your contact list.
Yeah. And even that seems like, seriously, like,
I mean, it's a good way to get valid emails and the relationship of the, you know,
what actually would be maybe even more better there.
Is, is it more better? Terrible? Sorry.
Um, what's more interesting to me there is that not only with the contact listing,
do you get
the names of these people
but kind of who you should send the email is being from,
to get a higher response rate?
Well, and not only that because they had full access to people's gmail,
they could legitimately send it as that person.
Like, not even, not even Joe Job send, like, for real, send
the email.
Oh, yeah. No, I, I, yeah, like I,
yeah, that, that's actually,
I don't know what would have happened if they've gotten away with that.
Well, they,
they wouldn't have and, and so this is what makes me think about.
There's really two scenarios I can see that are plausible is, first of all,
it was just some, like dumb kid, which is what the suggestion currently is that,
that made a mistake
and didn't realize what was going to happen. Right.
The alternative is somebody made a mistake and this was meant to be
a targeted attack to maybe go two or three levels deep on somebody
in terms of email contacts and it exploded and went too deep.
And I, I don't know,
basically,
sure
it had to check to see if the system was already infected,
but
it only checked like one in 10 times or whatever and clearly, that's
right. And that's fair.
Uh
This is a tough one to call because I can see
two,
well, those 22 options where it's either mistake or, or clearly malicious.
Here's the thing I don't get if it was clearly malicious in a targeted attack,
don't you think they would have set up like a couple
dozen Gmail accounts with various contacts and tried it out there
or is that just too much hassle for QE? And you just fired off?
Well, it can be a simple bug too
where
it was, that was not the intent. And I don't know how this was actually triggered
where obviously there was some sort of command and control system somewhere,
right? That was essentially making the magic happen.
And, and I don't understand what, what went on with that either.
And it could be a lot of things. I mean,
in addition, they use
Meiner, which is
relatively uncontrolled. So,
and, and obviously, as happened,
Meiner found out and they shut down that account. So now you've lost your data. It
honestly,
this smells like a mistake from someone who didn't really know what they were doing.
But
it, at the same time,
if I wanted to mount a really nice attack to harvest a bunch of contact information,
I'd make it look like a mistake.
You know what I mean?
Well, that's one thing I'm kind of wondering now is, are we like some of these, like,
really widespread attacks?
Are they actually a targeted attack?
You know, hiding inside of that thundering herd?
I,
I mean, look, you can put on the tinfoil hat and, and make any claim you want.
I think that's a plausible thing to think about, but it, it's not helpful either.
Yeah,
it's tricky man. Welcome to the, welcome to the future we deserve. Right.
I think really a lot of this,
what it boils down to is having those offline backups and
having those audit logs that can't be modified or new.
Yeah. But in this case, who cares that that wouldn't have helped either?
Well, no, no, no, but at least you can sort of clean up after the fact and
I
get
it
so that, you know, the attack doesn't stay in
assuming they had
modified data.
Well, they don't have to have modified data, right.
They just the fact that they still have access to your account six months from now.
Now I'm assuming Google is smart enough to have nuked everybody's, you know,
trust relationship with that entity.
That's, that's happened.
And my understanding is they cleaned it up for anyone who is linked to that provider.
I mean,
the thing that gets me really is I don't have to kind
of worry about what happened because I do have these off like,
well,
effectively offline backups in the sense of Google just has a
whole bunch of magic going on with this Google vault stuff.
And I can like,
you know,
if somebody were to ever come to me and say what exactly what happened on my domain,
at least I'd be like, well, let me check and I'll tell you, you know, and as a,
as a company
that level of sort of like what actually, how bad was this? What actually happened?
Oh, we just lost, you know, the contact list. Ok. Well, it's not great.
-- But
-- see,
and I think that's exactly the point we
should end this conversation on is the concept that
by leveraging someone like Google,
they have immense resources in terms of security people and
storage and operations and just everything across the board.
And so
even though there might be hiccups here and there,
if this had happened to basically any self hosted organization on the planet,
it would have taken
more than an hour. Well, it wasn't a Friday. It was.
Yeah. Yeah.
But I mean, that's the thing if it happened on Christmas or a Friday or whatever.
-- I mean, it would have been, especially any
-- day that occurred. I bet,
I bet any other organization who wasn't one of these big guys, someone like Google,
it would have taken a minimum of four hours to
figure out what was going on and to start,
I would have guessed at least two days.
-- It might even be days.
-- Four hours
is I'm going to be optimistic and generous.
Well, to me in my mind, just to even get your head around the problem. Right.
How many people truly understand o
off
for?
No, there's probably not a ton, there's enough.
But I think, uh, just recognizing the attack, first of all is tricky and,
and my guess is Google knew what was going on because in all seriousness
in the like 20 minutes, I was dealing with this by the end,
it was clear that things were under control already,
which is awesome. Right. That's fantastic.
And you figure I,
I was helping out one person and it took me 20 minutes to figure all this out.
You know,
I wonder if this has happened before and we just never noticed.
I guarantee it has,
but again, we can't fix everybody. We just have to fix most people. Right.
Yeah.
So anyway, any closing thoughts, Kurt,
yeah. Make sure you have audit logs
and some way of gripping them or whatever so that if something does happen,
because that's what gets me is a lot of organizations
just wouldn't have taken a long time to respond.
But, like they would have had to, you know,
figured out where the data was that they need to look at.
Yes, I'm also familiar with this problem.
It is,
logging is tricky and it is certainly not an
easy thing to do and it's becoming increasingly difficult
as the amount of information we have is growing exponentially.
-- But that's a topic for another day, I think. Yeah.
-- Yeah.
Yeah.
You know what really is interesting is, yeah,
I don't think there's a single piece of useful
advice we can give people to avoid this attack.
There is nothing we can tell people which is what makes it so exciting.
I mean, the only thing I can think of is go through your oo
providers like Twitter, Google linkedin, whatever
and, you know,
hunt down whatever that link is to see what's connected
to your account and maybe give it a quick once over
that. That is. But again, that's all I
got too late at that point.
Yeah. Yeah,
it is. Again, this is why I'm so excited. This is like Christmas time, man.
This is basically a, a new
attack. Not, I shouldn't say that
we've known about it.
We've known about it, but we haven't seen it, like, legitimately exercised
in a large scale manner.
So
I wonder if this is the new exercise for web.
It very well could be.
I don't know because, I mean,
people do put their banking details in their Google docs
and password resets if you have access to their email.
This is actually extra interesting because I've heard people talk about before
about putting a Google spreadsheet together with all your passwords in it.
That,
that's probably bad.
It's, well, it's, it's
probably less worse than having it
on your desktop. But
fundamentally, I mean,
you know that, well, yeah, it's,
it's probably better to use a password specific storage mechanism,
you know, than a spreadsheet.
Um, because you can't
encrypt or password protect specific spreadsheets in Google docs, I don't think.
No, no, you can't.
So, all right, man, it's time.
Thank you.
I'll put up,
uh, well,
I was just gonna say we'll put up a list of uh those links to where you can access your,
uh, what's accessing your account,
I guess on those major
providers. So you can double check them. So go to the website for that.
And, and what, what is the website, Kurt,
uh, open
-- source security podcast dot
-- com. That's right.
I, I don't think that's the first time you ever said that.
So,
on the show. So, anyway. All right. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, everybody for listening. It was fun as Kurt said, open
source Security podcast.com where you can find the show notes.
We have links to Twitter, we have a Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag you can use to get a hold of Kurt and myself.
We have a Facebook group that we monitor,
you can handle us there if you want to and otherwise, uh, Kurt,
you have a fabulous rest of your day.
-- Yeah, I hope everybody's enjoying spring.
-- That's right. Stay safe.
Everybody don't, don't be clicking on those emails.