Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 48 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
And today Kurt, we have a special guest. We've got a fellow I work with at Elastic.
His name is Mike MCC.
Say hi, Mike. Hey guys, pleasure to be here today.
And today we're going to talk about machine learning
because Mike is our resident machine learning guy.
And so I guess Mike,
why don't you explain kind of a little bit about yourself where you came from,
how you got here
and, and what you know, and then we can, I guess dive right in and,
and learn all about machine learning.
Sounds good guys.
Well, uh as you mentioned, Josh,
we work together at Elastic right now and uh I joined up uh
Elastic because I had come from a company called
Pret and uh pret
had been working for a number of years developing machine learning technology
and we at Pret
had developed
a product that was
marketing, we called the Behavioral Analytics for the Elastic Stack.
Uh It was a way to take the pre
machine learning engine and operate on data that was indexed in elastic search.
And uh the elastic team uh saw it and they liked
it so much that we ended up uh joining forces.
So I got to elastic uh through the pre
path.
And uh so, but my, my background before pre learnt um was uh you know,
developing uh security products, uh network intrusion prevention, DD OS defense,
uh lawfully authorized electronic surveillance and SIM products.
And so I actually came to pre learnt to help uh apply
the machine learning technology that the pre
team had developed
uh into security use cases. And so here at Elastic, I get to continue to do that.
-- So
-- you just said something that, that confuses and scares me.
You said they've been doing machine learning for a long time.
This is brand new, isn't it?
Yeah. Yeah.
So
uh
no,
it's funny.
Um machine learning, you know, a lot of the,
a lot of the basic concepts are based on uh classical statistics
and stuff that's been around even since the 19 forties and fifties.
Uh And, and uh what, what's really new is the way to
implement uh some of these techniques in, in ways that are robust to the, you know,
today's data, time series data that comes at extremely high rates and
large volumes. And uh so um
yeah, so it's, it's what's old is new,
you gotta love it.
So one question I have, what sort of is the cut off?
Like where does it become machine learning and say, stop being a,
an overgrown pearl script?
Uh It, it's, it's a great question because if, if you, you know,
if you double click into that, um a lot of times you say, well,
what are you using statistics or machine learning?
And uh you know, it, it isn't, it isn't a black or white, it's, it's an evolution.
So generally, um you know, machine learning uh is,
is when the uh it is software at the end of the day,
uh and what it's doing is it's able to adapt, uh it's, it's um
uh it's able to adapt to the, it's able to learn from data uh that,
that it is operating on
and then operate differently on subsequent data based
on what it learned from previous data.
Why don't we back that up for a second, Mike and just
give us like the, the,
the 32nd elevator pitch of what is machine learning for those who,
who maybe don't know and let's face it.
A lot of people don't because I know even,
I don't totally understand necessarily like statistics, machine learning,
artificial intelligence.
What is what? No idea. So, Phil,
sure.
Um II, I don't believe there's any single taxonomy that's accepted by everyone.
So I'll certainly give you the perspective that I have.
Uh
So, you know, artificial intelligence uh is an extremely broad,
technological and philosophical topic
uh that, that uh can get outside the scope of this podcast.
But within artificial
intelligence
is outside the scope of this,
we have no low point, feel free.
But uh within, within the scope,
you can think of 11 discipline of artificial
intelligence uh might be that of machine learning.
Uh And so uh machine learning itself has many, many categories.
Uh You may have heard of things like neural networks.
Uh You talk heard, heard of things like supervised machine learning,
uh semi
supervised machine learning, unsupervised machine learning.
Uh Those are all discipline within machine learning. So I'm a hierarchical guy.
I like the things I think of things as top down.
So uh I,
I uh exclude a lot of artificial intelligence to come up
with the bucket of things that fall into machine learning.
And then um we, we talk about those in some detail.
So when we are talking about machine learning in the context of
the software for doing things like threat detection,
uh We're,
we're talking about a couple of branches that
are probably coming closer to things like um
uh semi
supervised or unsupervised machine learning.
-- Um And so,
-- so can can you explain
what kind of what is unsupervised, supervised and semi
supervised machine learning?
Yes.
So the 11 of the concepts in machine learning is uh whether or
not the the data on which the algorithms operate has been marked up,
uh marked up with ground truth information
so that it represents uh a known state
uh
algorithms that operate on marked up data and then build from that
analysis a model that they can apply to subsequent unmarked up data.
Uh That is a technique called supervised machine learning.
So, supervised machine learning generally requires this pre
marked up
corpus of data from which the um
uh software can build models.
So that would be like say having your email trained
on a bunch of ham and a bunch of spam.
Yeah, that's, that's a very good example or,
or another one is uh in the use of malware detection
uh right, having a sample of a million examples of malware,
a million executables and then running your algorithms
across that entire corpus and learning from it.
What are the similarities between malware taking that model
that you've derived from that analysis of marked up data
and then applying that to new
executables to see if you can determine whether or not their malware.
That that's a good example of the supervised machine learning as well.
-- OK.
-- Nice. That makes sense to me. But that also occurs to me.
This is kind of that cat and mouse game, right?
Where the malware authors and the spammers are always
changing things so they can get around your rules,
right?
They Yeah, so that they get around your your algorithms.
Uh And in fact that exact thing happens.
So, so uh let's take the the case I brought up of malware analysis of,
of determining whether or not an algorithm.
Uh Excuse me,
an executable is um malware based on applying these learned models uh to it.
So I saw a presentation um probably six months ago
where um basically a malware developer um got a hold of that software,
uh built his malware and just kept running it through and making modifications to it
till he found a variation of the malware that was not triggered by that algorithm.
-- And then of course, he went ahead and did what he wanted to do with that
-- version.
Nice. That's awesome.
So, well, I've seen similar things with spam assassin.
I mean, I've seen a ton of email that scores 4.9
and the default for spam Assassin to mark something with spam is five. So
yeah,
that makes sense for supervised machine learning, right?
Yeah, that, that, that's a perfect explanation. Thank you. So what is semi
supervised? Now,
how about how about if we start with unsupervised
and then we'll
get the hybrid in the middle.
So unsupervised machine learning is generally defined as that,
that does not require
marked up ground truth data to start with.
So it it learns on the fly from the actual data
that's being analyzed and it builds its models uh you know,
based on the data as it's being analyzed and then simultaneously
or there very shortly thereafter is are able to make determinations of
whether or not the the data um uh meets certain criteria or is anomalous or you know,
has some characteristics uh that, that are learned from the data.
So the the benefit of unsupervised machine learning is that it
is operating on the actual data that is to be analyzed.
So it's learning from the actual data,
uh it doesn't have to learn from this artificial train set.
Uh And then um
it is able to, so with supervised machine learning switching back,
one of the challenges you have is that if the
training data isn't exactly the same as the actual data,
then you get drift between the model that was developed and the
actual signals that you want to be analyzing from time to time,
you have to go back and do some retraining.
Whereas the approach that unsupervised machine learning takes is that it sort of
sounds like uh college, but it's continuous online learning.
So as new data appears, it's constantly updating the model.
So the model has a a temporal characteristic of being representative
of the data now or at least very very recently.
But I I guess the challenge there though is you need
a corpus of past data to essentially feed the machine,
right?
Or, or you just wait.
So um you know, you can start to start it now and as the data comes in,
you build it up over time,
uh most good techniques will have the ability to do both.
So what you do is um you know,
the benefit of the analysis is that uh it certainly as it's applied
to security is the ability to operate on data in near real time.
Uh However,
uh when I start my machine learning job and I want to look for some uh unusual
behaviors then uh I don't want to have to wait for two weeks to get any results.
Right. Well, I could even see it. I mean, you think,
I know uh listening to conversations with, with some of our machine learning folks,
the Black Friday problem always comes up where
you kind of train
your, your algorithm for,
let's say normal use and then something like Black Friday
hits and all the rules get thrown out the window,
right?
So uh it's a great question.
That's, that's something that is in a oxymoron is called the uh you know,
the the expected anomaly uh and, and things happen.
So the answer is uh those expected anomalies are,
are really the exceptions to the rule.
So um it is, it really isn't possible to model those.
So what you want to make sure is that those events don't dis
your model so much that they're providing skewed results.
And so a few techniques are used um good techniques of unsupervised
machine learning modeling are able to
identify when something is highly anomalous,
in
essence, the more unusual it is the less likely it should be to affect the model.
Uh And so that um things may
be skewed for a short time period after Black Friday, but then they're,
the models would converge back and, and they would um you know, return to normal
the general technique on how you get around the Black Friday issue.
So one question I have is, is I understand how unsupervised learning could,
for example, you know, get you
sort of like this is the weird anomalous data that doesn't fit with the rest of it,
right?
Like 99% of the stuff is this and 1% of it is like
not this,
but
you know, how do you apply that to a like for the sake of argument, you,
you want to build something that recognizes cats.
Can you do that with unsupervised learning?
Because at some point, how would that thing
learn or you know, you'd have to tell it at some point what a cat is to some degree,
right?
Yeah.
So uh so generally not,
so the the unsupervised machine learning techniques that we'll be talking
about relative to security are operating on uh time series data.
So this would be either numeric or categorical data that has a time stamp.
Um It is not operating on uh images or uh other, other types of constructs uh that
to which the the the greater problem of machine learning can be applied,
but not the um uh the unsupervised things like neural networks, for example,
could be used as, as part of image recognition
uh based on certain um marked up data sets of
images and other techniques that try to hybridize that to
help you just uh uh basically specify characteristics
and then find images that contain those characteristics.
Well, and I think this is actually an important point to focus on Mike is that at, at,
at elastic, the work you're working on is
it's not magic.
It, we have a very defined scope where it's when you say time series data,
you're basically talking about logs.
And the idea is to look at the logs using machine learning for security anomalies.
Right.
Yep. That is correct.
We're talking about the application of machine learning in
the form of automated anomaly detection applied to time
series data which as you correctly point out are
mostly logs or at least also numerical metrics,
which you could argue are also logs.
-- Sure,
-- sure. Which, which I think is
that's where I feel like I get confused sometimes is when
we talk about something like artificial intelligence or machine learning,
I think people
naturally assume this is essentially magic math that can do anything.
But in like in our case
where
we're scoping it to a point that it's useful because I think this is like anything.
-- If you scope it too broadly, you end up with, with nothing. Right. Exactly.
-- Exactly.
So this is uh indeed,
you know, that's why we think of a huge funnel,
we had artificial intelligence at the top and then we have machine learning.
Uh you know,
next level down and then we have unsupervised
machine learning on the next level down.
And then what we got is the actual
outputs is automated anomaly detection and time series data
as a practical application of
-- unsupervised machine learning.
-- Right. Right. Right.
And, and I think that makes sense.
Now, the one thing you have not explained to us yet with the
supervised machine learning is which I'm still trying to figure out.
All right,
so let's say you're using unsupervised machine learning to detect anomalies,
anomalous activity, either in values, frequencies,
counts or things are statistically rare or things are different than one another.
And you identify
um this set of unusual
behaviors in the data.
But let's say you have lots of unusual things.
Um let's say we're applying this technology to
fraud detection.
And let's say you had uh payment card transactions and you
wanted to find a way to score those transactions to find,
to give a good indicator as to which ones might be fraudulent.
You would use unsupervised machine learning to find things like
unusual um amounts of the transaction, unusual locations for that card,
uh unusual times of day for the purchase.
Those are all unusual things that are anomalies.
But in order to put those together and to
find out which ones predict the fraudulent transactions,
what you really need is some confirmed fraudulent transactions.
And so the technique of applying multiple observed anomalies towards a score adds a
sort of a marked up data set, right?
You get some, here's, here's 1000 transactions and these 100 were fraudulent.
If that is verified truth,
then what you do is you build a construct called a classifier which tries to map the
observations of anomalies that you've seen
from your unsupervised machine learning onto
the marked up data set.
So that you come up with essentially a formula for taking
the level of unusualness of the things you've observed and finding out
a waiting factor that will produce a score that
will predict the fraudulent nature of a transaction.
So that would be an example of semi
supervised that's using
unsupervised elements,
but it does have some marked up data on the output
that a score or a weighting can be used to create.
-- So
-- essentially just you're creating a feedback loop.
Yeah,
that's right.
OK. Well, that makes sense.
So I guess the inevitable question now is
we,
we started out with why is machine learning not necessarily
A I which it sounds like it kind of is,
but the,
the question on everyone's mind,
I'm sure is is can the machine learning algorithms
become self aware and take over the world,
the philosophical parts of
our?
OK.
So
um
so, so I I tend to uh
have less, less opinions in that area.
Uh It's not, it's not a concern that I, that I worry about so
-- I can sleep at night.
-- Yeah.
Well, and just one example of this too is, I mean,
these things don't have to take over the world to cause a problem.
This actually came up
yesterday. Um,
so this, uh,
this Canadian couple bought airline tickets, uh, from Canada to Portugal and back
on their credit card. They got to Portugal. Ok. And then when they tried to go home,
uh,
they were told that the purchase was fraudulent
and that their airline tickets had been yanked.
-- That's terrible
-- halfway
through.
Yeah, they were in Portugal, they went to the airport, they tried to, you know,
check in and they were told that their airline tickets had been
essentially, you know, too bad. So sad, good luck with that.
Uh So they ended up having to buy one way tickets for like six grand.
Uh And then it wasn't until, you know,
the CBC news contacted Air Canada that Air Canada finally was like, oh yeah,
we should probably refund you.
So, yeah.
Anyway, so, I mean, that's, I mean, that's a great example of obviously, you know,
some sort of, they claim it was some fraud detection thing that like, oh, sorry,
false positive, you know.
Um, but that's a great example of, you know, where it has
or it can have a really significant real world impact,
you know, and doesn't have to kill anybody, but it's, you know,
really inconvenient.
Ok. So this story leads to a place I, I wanted to get us eventually is
so
when we look at machine learning, especially in the context of security,
it, it sounds like in this case, their fraud detection was very slow
and
often when you're under attack, very slow is very bad.
And so
the, the, the one thing I I always love to think about
and this is kind of for you to comment on here, Mike is
people used to actually read security logs
and
they totally can't anymore because everyone's generating so many of them,
it's not even funny.
And then I guess this kind of brings us to machine learning can give us
the power to essentially do analysis and
detection instantaneously or very close to it.
Correct.
That's right. That's right. It's uh that is the power of,
you know, the, the cliche and the buzzword of big data. You know, it's the ability to
uh index, you know,
massive amounts of data and then perform analysis on
it and then find ways to aggregate it,
visualize it and then uh uh perhaps uh notify people when certain things take place.
So that that is exactly what we're we're talking about.
And the ability to do that in near real time, meaning, you know,
meaning seconds to minutes after it actually happens is extremely valuable.
Uh as, as I'm sure you guys know, and you've probably discussed before, you know,
the, the lag period between when
data breaches uh uh are,
are taking place or when the compromise takes
place and when the organization that's affected,
learns about it is, you know, is massive.
Right. It's, it's months long.
And so if you can prove that down to, uh, you know, down to hours or minutes, uh,
even though it's not traditionally millisecond real time,
it still has massive value.
Well, and I think not only that this is, I, I, I'll let you kind of plug a demo.
I know you worked on at one point was
it's rare for an attacker to kind of only do one thing and get in, right.
There's often many, many signs of compromise. And I know for elastic
con
you guys put together a machine learning demo
that use some of the fancy bear data
showing off kind of kind of what happened.
Can you, can you explain what you guys did because it's, it's super cool.
So, um so a couple things um
the
machine learning. So, so there's um
you know, there's threat indicator lists that are,
it's good to know if uh entities within your infrastructure are
visiting um network locations that are known to be associated with,
with threat activity.
So that that's good to know.
Uh But what is also good to know is
when entities in your organization are behaving unusually.
And so the de the demo that we put together combined both of those
uh
and, and it was a storyline. So the the attack progression started
with a computer uh in our uh network that
indeed was visiting sites that were known to be associated with threat activity.
Uh And, and we had records of that captured in the logs because, um,
we were able to match the destination IP address
to which the network connection was targeting,
uh against the threat list.
Um, but by itself, that isn't necessarily something you'd alert on.
Um, but it's just something good to notice.
And in our demo, what we did is much later in the process,
we found that that system was performing
behaviors that appeared to be data exfiltration
uh by sneaking out data over the uh DNS protocol.
And so during the course of the demonstration, we had machine learning
uh automated anomaly detection, say, hey,
something really unusual is happening uh on the DNS
protocol and this workstation is responsible for it.
And upon investigation,
we went backwards and looked through the data that we had the security log data.
And sure enough, looking back,
we were able to establish that the bad behavior started with this initial visit,
visit to the IP address associated with the threat activity.
That's cool. Well, and then didn't you guys manage to kind of link
two machines together due to some sort of activity that,
that a human almost certainly would not have found?
Yeah, we used uh uh this, this technique as a form of graph analysis
uh which allows you to visualize all the activity that we had in the logs
uh between the
the, the workstation that was detected, performing this anomalous DNS behavior
we look to see,
was there any commonality between the sites that it visited and
uh sites that other systems in our network may have visited?
And sure enough, um you know, the system that was doing, the exfiltration
has visited sites that uh only one or two other
systems within the organization had also visited in common.
And uh they were,
um one of those sites was associated with the
same country to which the threat activity was seen.
And so visually, being able to identify this, he said, aha, I
may not have seen ext
activity
from workstation number two,
but I sure as heck am gonna go investigate
it first to make sure that doesn't happen next.
Right. Right.
Which kind of brings us into the new universe of something known as thread hunting.
Right. E
exactly.
You know, traditionally because of the very problem you brought up, Josh, you know,
it used to be practical to go ahead and look at security logs and,
and have humans parse them and read them.
Um, we, we're, we're to the point where that's, that's just not,
not possible anymore.
So the way that we progressed within security operations was to introduce
automation
and the basic forms of automation was in the rules.
I write rules that say, uh, you know, look at all my log data and if you see
anything that looks like this or the number of these that exceed a threshold.
Uh For example, the number of bytes outbound from any
client in my network. If it exceeds 10 megabytes, I want to know about it.
And these attempts at automation were absolutely necessary because
the volume of security log data had increased.
But
the rules themselves were not actually that great. They were noisy.
They generated a lot of false positive alerts
and I spent a lot of time investigating rules rather than looking at security logs.
I was ruling out, you know, false positives.
And, and so
what we're, we're talking about, you know,
that's how threatened monitoring uh came about.
And so this machine learning technology
that we are talking about today can really help
automate that further and, and make monitoring much, much more high fidelity
in terms of finding the unusual things that are uh
would have been very difficult to write rules for.
Right.
So I guess here's the,
the magic question is you mentioned false
positives and anyone who's ever looked in any
sort of logs or any sort of rules for their SIM or what not,
is
the false positive rate is abysmal.
So now have you guys done any research into kind of how the
machine learning false positive rate compared to the I I guess static rule,
false positive rate you'd normally see.
So we have we have a couple of examples.
In fact, it's,
it's really similar to the one I was just talking about
if you look at logs that come from uh web proxy,
uh let's take this as an enterprise, web proxy,
which means any user in the enterprise that wants to go to the internet,
uh makes the requests to the proxy first and then the proxy will
either uh not let your request go through or let it go through.
Logs from proxies are great sources of analysis for rules of all sorts.
So traditional security information and event management product,
a SIM product had a rule and dashboard set up that took those
logs and looked at the sum of the outbound bytes for a given entity
and triggered a rule if you see anybody over.
Um I can't remember if it was 100 megabytes uh in a daytime,
then uh run this analysis every day and let me know if,
if someone had this kind of volume of external bytes in the outbound direction.
So we,
we got the opportunity to see the results from this running on a 30,000 seat
enterprise and the number of alerts triggered by that rule as it was in,
in a given day
was around 8000.
So
how did you, you can't deal with that? Right. So it was, it was just uh unusable.
Now, that was with the static threshold.
Lots of SIMS have technology that use basic statistics, right?
Which say, hey, you know what,
why don't we run a running average or build a running average of what
the number of bytes is over uh this time period of the analysis,
which happen to be a day
and then only flag an alert when you have uh you know,
uh plus two standard deviations over the average,
this running average that you have.
And
that was done with a traditional SIM
and that reduced uh that reduced the number of alerts about eight fold.
Uh So it got down from about 8000 to about 1000 in a given day,
which is still completely insane though, right?
In
progress, but nobody wants to, to look at 1000.
So we, we, we took the, the same, essentially the same logic rule.
Uh But instead used machine learning to model what is the normal behavior
of the sum of the outbound bytes as reported by this web proxy log
at a given time and only flag us when things are significantly unusual.
And so the in that case, um we got down to tens of alerts on, on a daily basis,
including some that were highly unusual that would have snuck underneath both the
moving average and the static threshold things that were really of investigation.
So, so we're really talking about orders of magnitude, right?
So we're going down from thousands to tens of alerts in a, in a given day.
So at least a couple orders of magnitude and we've seen better results than that.
Well, I feel like 10 is a number
that a security team can handle.
-- 1000 is not, right.
-- That's right.
Wow, that, that's wild man.
That, that sounds like an impressive false positive rate.
Uh Although now, now let me say though,
is how difficult when you talk about kind of these rules to decide what the the uh
I guess thresholds are for your, your data use in this case is
is this supervised? How I guess how do you define this rule? Right?
Because you can't just kind of be say here
magic machine learning algorithm figure out what's going on,
right?
Like a human has to set this up, right?
Yeah. Yeah.
So, so um there's a portion of,
of machine learning that that is called uh feature selection.
Um And that's basically just deciding which fields in the data and,
and logs that you're gonna look at and you're gonna model.
Uh So the the feature selection part is done by the analyst. So when you configure,
um let us take the case of the
unsupervised machine learning that we're talking about.
You, you basically configure
this basic element of machine learning called a job.
And what you point out in that job is this is the index
that we'd like to operate on.
So this is the log source,
these are the fields within the log that we'd like to do operations on.
And you give general guidance as to which type of anomalies you'd like to look for.
And that's it.
And then you start the job and then the machine learning does all the rest.
You do not specify model types. You don't specify
uh averages, standard deviations, no statistics, no programming,
uh no model instantiation.
You basically just point it to the field and say, you know, go,
go determine what's normal.
And let me know if what actually happens
is different than what you've determined is normal.
That's really cool.
Yeah, I
love
it.
And you know, Josh, you bring up a great topic, which is the false positives.
So when we talk about machine learning, because it is mathematics and statistics,
there's usually um depending on who you're speaking to,
um that you'll find two different definitions of false positive.
The security guys are going to say
was that an actual cyber attack? And that's their definition for a false positive.
Whereas the mathematician will say,
did that produce something that was truly statistically anomalous
and a lot of times uh the answers are uh uh no and yes, respectively.
So
let me give an example of,
of another situation that we run into with this machine learning in the security
um realm. Uh We're looking for a different kind of ex filtration.
Uh not, not with web proxies, but by looking at DNS logs.
And so
the analysis ran over a billion uh records a 30 day supply of DNS query.
Uh questions coming from the client population,
going to the DNS server and they got the logs
back from the DNS server and performed analysis on them,
looking for,
looking for unusual behavior that might be associated
with exfiltration of data over the DNS protocol.
So the algorithms identified exactly four instances of high
scoring anomalies that were related to DNS tunneling,
which is, you know, the practice of sending data,
non DNS data out over the DNS protocol.
Sure.
And so the company investigated those and it, and it turns out that
there is an antivirus product. Uh Sophos
antivirus uses this product called uh uses this protocol called SSS XL,
uh which actually tunnels over the DNS protocol.
It's how they do some of the live updates for some of the stuff that they work.
So all four anomalies detected by the algorithms were verified to be actual
DNS tunneling that was um running over this antivirus uh Softwares protocol.
So, was that a false positive or not?
So, I don't think so,
but,
oh, that was just antivirus software that wasn't really an attack.
And so, you know, we, we took the position, look, look,
you know, did would you have wanted to know about that?
And so as it turns out, so we take the position that was not a false positive,
that was a good detection.
And in this case, here's why, so the company that had those results said,
wait a minute, we don't use
Sophos S XL and employees are not allowed to install
their own antivirus or have their computers on the network.
Give me the IP addresses of those four computers, please.
And then they took off and they went and looked at it.
So, you know, it was a,
it was a good event but it wasn't necessarily a cyber attack in progress.
-- Right.
-- Right. And
let's face it too. I think
in any enterprise,
a significant number of your problems isn't necessarily direct attacks.
It's people making a whole bunch of foolish mistakes that end badly. Right.
And this gives you kind of an opportunity to identify some of those foolish mistakes
prior to it starting on fire.
Exactly. Exactly. Right.
So why don't we change gears for a minute? And
let's talk about wanna cry,
which has been super exciting while using the word exciting in quotes, I guess.
And how can something like machine learning assist us
with, with something like this ransomware attack that's actually happening?
Right.
This is kind of let let's do some real world application
to what is kind of magic technology to many people.
Yeah. So, so um you know, the the the wanna cry is an example of ransomware.
Um as, as you guys know, ransomware is not new, been around for a long time.
Uh This was a particularly interesting one because it combined uh
uh ransomware with, with uh worm type uh propagation.
Uh Not unlike a lot of the worms we had 10 years ago um that were taking advantage of
vulnerabilities in the the windows uh SMB service.
So if you combined ransomware with worm, you get a rapidly spreading
uh
phenomenon like we we had with wanna crime.
So the the question gets back, how do you detect things with machine learning?
And let's take machine learning in the form of automated anomaly detection
that might indicate the spread of more ransomware like this.
Uh
and again, by, by and themselves, ransomware is not new. Uh worms are not new.
Uh How do you use these techniques to determine the presence of those two things?
So
what, what's unusual about it?
So one of the things that is unusual in the spread of a worm
ransomware or otherwise is whatever their scanning
activity is for finding the next victims
is, is probably unusual. In fact, it's almost always unusual.
So taking a look at network traffic by protocol, for example,
and building models on a protocol by protocol basis of what is the amount of
activity uh normal basis hour of day and day of week modeled over periods of time
and looking for anomalies.
And that uh can be a very good early indicator of worm based activity.
So you'd be finding uh you know, unusual amounts of uh requests for TCP 445.
Uh that would be an indicator that, hey, something's going on strange here,
better go investigate that.
So that's, that's a simple example.
I've seen some more elaborate ones uh that are looking
at information coming from the file system on a computer.
Um,
it turns out that when ransomware is running
the activity of encrypting the files on the disk
is highly unusual.
It is a uninterrupted sequence of file reads and writes that looks
different than many of the activities that normally operate on a computer.
So we, I have not seen these results but we,
I know of a customer that is using uh
unsupervised machine learning and anomaly detection on file system
activity as reported by an agent running on their clients
that is reportedly able to identify um the operation of
crypto uh you know, ransomware within um a
very small number of files.
So while it wouldn't prevent the entire system, sorry,
it would prevent the entire system.
It doesn't protect every file, but it does detect this activity as being unusual.
So that would be like another example that's a little
bit on the newer end of the ransomware side.
Right. Right.
That, that sounds like it would be super heavy resource wise to, I guess,
track and even process that volume of data.
So it is, right. So
in order to detect this, you'd want to have updates on, um, you know,
pretty frequent rate coming from all of your end points.
Let's say you even got, you know, every, um,
twice a minute uh coming from each end point and you've got a big enterprise
with tens of thousands of enterprises and the uh file activity is just one area.
These agents you have today from some endpoint detection and response um software.
They have all kinds of things.
They have information in a whole tree of process related information, file system,
physical device,
uh memory and all these metrics and logs are coming
in and it is just truly a massive problem.
So you are right, in order to detect
ransomware activity,
you need to be able to have events coming from the end points at a high rate.
They need to be able to be indexed very quickly into the
uh analysis system. And then the
analysis,
the machine learning job would have to run on a
very frequent basis to be able to detect that within,
-- you know, within minutes of, of it actually beginning
-- right now.
Now let me ask this though. OK.
So let's say we, we see something like that in this context to
would it be expected for an automation automated response or do
you just kind of blink a light and tell the person,
hey human, come, come check this out, something weird is going on?
Um So that's a really big topic, the automated
-- response.
-- And that also sounds like where things could really go sideways
once you automate it.
That, that generally is the reason why in my experience,
most organizations have very limited if any uh automated responses.
Um There's a couple of exceptions, but in this case,
it would be letting somebody know, is the most likely scenario.
Right.
Yeah, I can,
I can totally see that, that
it's like when you always hear these stories about where
there is, there's an antivirus program that, that detects itself,
it's a virus and then it
kind of
self destructs or something
because
that's, that's wild.
Interesting. So, I guess the, the next thing that, that's in my brain here is
you, you've spoken at length,
kind of about how all this stuff works and what's going on.
And
the thing that always comes back to me is the thought of
when
you look at spam will be my example here.
Um And, and even, I guess viruses to, to a degree is they,
they always find a way to get around this. But it sounds like with
proper unsupervised machine learning,
the ability to evade detection is going to be
incredibly difficult.
That is one advantage that the unsupervised machine learning may have over,
you know, trained or supervised approaches.
Uh is,
is that because the models that are being
used to determine whether or not things are unusual
are specific to the environment in which they're running.
Um It's very difficult for an adversary to do what we spoke about earlier,
which is to, you know,
run their malware against the the software model that everybody uses.
And so it does have that advantage that makes it
harder to evade it also has some characteristics that you
could think of as being less favorable uh in the
sense that let's say you start your unsupervised machine learning
jobs
in an environment that already has bad unusual behaviors uh that are going on.
Um We talked already about data exfiltration.
Let's say we started machine learning
uh analysis running on the logs from my network,
but my computer was infected and it was
ex filtrating data continuously or every day.
So,
one of the things you have to watch out for is that the
machine learning jobs could learn that that's normal and they would never raise,
they would never raise uh any, any indication that something is unusual.
I suppose that's, that's a really good point, isn't it?
Yeah. So, but there's a solution to this,
um, because the different types of
machine learning jobs that can be run,
uh include a couple of fundamental, um,
anomaly detection techniques.
So normally when we think of anomaly detection, we're, we're saying, hey,
is Mike's computer operating differently now than it
was predicted to be now at this time based on past behavior.
So, in other words, if every day, you know,
I do certain behaviors and I use DNS and I use HTP
and the system learns what my normal behaviors are.
If I start behaving differently, then it's gonna say, hey, anomaly,
my system is behaving differently.
So that's, we'll call that type of analysis, you know, individual entities,
uh looking for uh deviations of behavior based on its learned past.
So,
that would have the characteristic that we just talked about
that if I was behaving badly the whole time,
it wouldn't be unusual.
Another type of analysis that is commonly done is called the population analysis
where we look at in aggregate in, in one analysis, the behavior
of all the systems that are like
uh within an environment.
So in that case, we look at all the computers,
Mikes and Josh's and Kurtz and everybody else and
we'd have a population of those and you say,
is any one of those entities acting differently than the others.
So, unless all the other entities were infected in exfil trading,
uh at least Mike's computer would stand out from that analysis that says, you know,
Mike's computer is acting like it always does,
but it's acting differently than the, the group of pure computers.
-- Uh, that, that it's part of,
-- right? That sounds really useful.
That's like very her mentality, right?
Where we're looking for a, a across everything because,
right, I mean,
and so this is one of the things I always love is, for example,
if you look at the security guy's computer, obviously,
it's a train wreck all the time.
And so that's not a good example.
But you know, if, if you got like some random support guy
that doing something really crazy, you know, there,
there could be something weird going down there.
So, I, I like that. Ah, that's cool.
So we almost think of those as, you know, orthogonal analysis, right? So, uh, so, so
like when we, we,
we work with a customer to set up their collection of machine learning jobs,
you're looking for both, uh,
entities behaving unusually versus their past
and entities behaving differently than their peers
and
constantly for each
area of coverage that you'd like to get within the,
you know, overall problem space of threat detection,
uh, in each of those,
if you have some jobs that are looking at
individual behaviors and some jobs are looking at populations,
you generally get good coverage and you don't,
uh, you know, have the, the, the vulnerability of, of, uh,
stuff that's been there forever.
-- That's normal but
-- bad.
Right. Right. Well, I mean, let's face it too.
If you're in enterprise today, you have
threat actors inside
just period. There's no way around that. It's just, it's the way it is.
That's cool, man. I love it.
So, I guess, uh, we're, we're getting close to the end here.
So,
is there anything else you want to kind of fill
anyone in or is there anything we missed or,
or something we, we should have talked about that, that you can think of.
-- I think
-- some of the, the really cool stuff.
Um, so what we've been talking about so far is you using
automated
detection to detect things that are like, you know,
you'd call them elementary attack behaviors.
Right. They're data exfiltration. Yeah, that's a good one to know about,
you could talk about unusual logins, like, you know,
I saw a successful login but it was at an unusual time for that account.
Those are, those are interesting. These are all good
elementary tech behaviors that security people would like to know about. Right.
But really the, the hard part is how do you stitch those together
and identify attack progressions that may take place
over days or even weeks or even longer.
And um a lot of the capabilities that you know, that we,
we get excited about the application of machine learning for threat
detection is is to do just that um it's to take these
elementary attack behaviors that we detect through this anomaly detection
and then start to perform additional analysis on those.
And uh in in a particular case of the solution from elastic,
the way that we accomplish that is the anomaly detection results are
written back into an index that itself can be analyzed and searched.
So there's kind of this second level of analysis that
can take place on the things that have been detected
that um
can be very helpful in correlating unusual
activities across different entities within your organization.
And that's where I think the the the future is on, uh you know,
really doing some amazing detection that, you know,
none of the adversaries would be able to predict because it's, it's all gonna
be using machine learning and other types of analysis to find
things that you probably didn't even think of in the,
it sounds like you're literally looking for anomalies in the anomalies
or at least relationships.
That's awesome.
I love it. I love it. Uh, Kurt, any last questions, isn't that always the,
the truth where people in hindsight look at, you know, some
attack or something and they're like, in hindsight it's really obvious,
you know. But at the time it was like,
yeah, it's like one outgoing DNS packet amongst 3 billion.
Yeah.
And so, so I think, you know, going forth
in the future, we're gonna, we're gonna see more, uh,
I think more attention played on exactly what, what you just said is things that,
that may be hiding in plain sight are obvious and,
and how do you identify the patterns in those, uh to notice if they happen again,
notice earlier sooner when they happen again?
Awesome. I love it. I, I'm super excited about this.
I, I can't wait to see where this industry goes in,
in the next couple of years because, well,
then I imagine in two years it's gonna look nothing like it does today,
which is fantastic.
-- All
-- right
now.
-- So it, it sure is. I, I agree. Josh.
-- Awesome. All right, cool.
So we, we've come to the end and one of the,
the silly things we like to do is what we call the lightning round.
So we're gonna put you on the spot here, Mike I can ask you some, uh
we'll say ridiculous and somewhat unrelated questions because it's fun to do and,
and so we're gonna,
we're gonna, we're gonna make you dance for your dinner here.
So, Kurt,
why don't, why don't you lead this off, man?
All right. Uh Favorite star Trek, Captain Kirk Cooper cards.
Kirk.
Good answer.
That is the correct, correct.
It's always wrong and people get that one wrong and then
alright. uh
favorite uh uh benevolent A I
um,
let's see what really helps me,
sir,
sir.
It's actually for real. That that's a good answer.
This is something I was thinking about actually is
if you have, if you look at science fiction,
there are remarkably few benevolent A is, you know,
you got like the Terminator and you've got Gladys from portal, you've got
the, well,
I guess the ship's computer in Star Trek is
sometimes colossus from the Foran project is I would say
somewhere in between. Yeah. Well, that's the thing right?
In, in science fiction, the vast majority of a is, are uh evil, right?
There aren't a lot of good ones which,
which it's kind of scary that we've yet to come up with, with good examples of this.
But, but anyway, anyway,
we'll keep going. What, what is your favorite open source project?
This should be an easy one
elastic. There you go. That's the answer I was looking for.
Nice and easy.
And Kurt, I'll let you finish it up.
Sorry. My browser just locked up. Oh, that's all right.
We got, uh, so what's your favorite security standard, Mike?
I know this is one of the things you actually deal with on a regular basis
standards
or, or at least favorite you could say. I don't know. Is there a difference?
-- I like the, uh PC I data security standard.
-- There you go.
Yeah, that's a good one actually PC I is not too bad.
I think it was one of the first standards to
actually take and to have the guts to actually write
down some things that were prescriptive as lightweight as they
were before that a lot of the regulations were all,
you must have controls that, you know, blah, blah, blah, so abstract and
it wasn't perfect, but at least had some guts to say, OK, look,
you got to have controls in place, meaning
you got to monitor stuff coming from your network ideas and your host ideas,
you know?
No,
no, I totally get that. It's awesome.
All right, cool. Well, Mike, thank you so much.
This has been a blast and, and I guess maybe,
maybe in a couple of months or so once the industry changes drastically, you want
to come back and, and let us know what's going on.
I'd love to. It's a pleasure. And thanks for inviting me along. Fantastic.
All right, cool. So, so thank you, gentlemen.
I'm gonna bring it home now is for those of you listening.
If you want links to any of the things we spoke on today,
you can visit open source security podcast.com.
We've got links to Twitter and Facebook and, and any of the other random stories and,
and whatnot
that were covered.
I guess if nothing else, Mike and Kurt,
you guys have a fabulous rest of your days and until next time.
Thanks everybody.
Bye now.