Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in appreciating silence.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- Oh, my goodness. Did we, did we talk about silence
for two minutes?
No, no, no. I mean, in what was it? Two or three episodes ago?
Because we talked about the hiss,
the, not the hiss, the
-- Yeah. Yeah.
-- Yeah. Yeah. The high pitched wine from your
-- led,
-- the high pitched noise that we can't hear that I took out.
And now before
so I, I have a checklist for, for anyone who doesn't know,
like when we record the podcast, I have a checklist.
I go through to make sure I don't forget to do
something prior to recording because I used to always forget things
-- and I added an item that says record.
-- It's weird how checklists work. Right.
Exactly.
And I, I just added a thing recently that says record five seconds of silence.
And then I'm going to,
I can use that silence from Kurt and I then to remove
any possible background noise from fans or any other weird things happening so
well and get the right silence.
That's true. I've become obsessed with silence.
This sounds like, uh, I sound like a crazy person when I talk to people now, but like
there's a really good Reddit thread on this, you know.
Anyway, also with respect to checklist, go, if you haven't bought it in Reddit,
go get the checklist Manifesto from Atul
Gowanda.
I probably butchered that name.
But yeah, please go get that book and read it.
Do yourself a favor. It's, it's worth it.
So,
but sort of in line with this today is
sort of a hodgepodge of things that are all linked together ultimately.
And it sort of started out with open source, doesn't require providing bills.
So
you sent this to me and I read it and I was like,
and
well, it's,
but you, I come from a time when open sources didn't provide builds,
we had to build it ourselves.
And so a couple of things, number one, this is talking about providing builds,
not actually, for example, doing bills internally testing them and then
not releasing them, for example.
And for example,
this is one of the things that really like some of the B sds
like net BS D is infamous for running on everything from a toaster to
everything.
Um And so, you know,
they have a whole bunch of people with weird old strange whatever hardware
and sort of one advantage of actually building the stuff and testing it is
there are bugs that only bubble up on big Indian versus little Indian systems.
That is true.
Another thing is to put it bluntly if you write source
code that has to be compiled and maybe you don't like,
maybe like me or a Python person.
And so this whole argument is like, you can just,
you can just skip to the end and have a grilled cheese sandwich.
But if you are actually working with a language that needs to be compiled, you know,
to run it and to really test it and whatever or
to ship it.
I feel like I like certain types of software.
You absolutely have to do this to get anybody to download it and use it.
I mean, sure, sure.
And other pieces of software you don't because
like like said
knock right, R and C
and completely the disres will compile them and
ship them as part of their default tool chain
100%.
But when you start looking at sort of higher level software that
maybe how do I put this nicely that normal people use?
Yeah, normal people don't want to compile this and fight with it.
They just want to download a binary onto Windows or Mac or
the 1% of them onto Linux.
I have a great example. Great example.
If you're a Kubernetes user,
the like client is KCTL,
right?
And the install instructions for
CCTL are basically download this thing off the internet and put it in user local bin.
Yeah,
like,
yeah, those are the instructions.
I'm curious. Does it include an internal upgrader?
Because that's another thing I'm seeing more commonly now is
-- no,
-- you have to upgrade it, it, it on your own.
Oh, ok. Interesting.
-- It doesn't magically
-- upgrade. I've noticed a lot of programs internally
shipping with an update or,
you know, like
web browsers.
The are one of the original example of that where that really caught on.
Well, web browsers are special web browsers don't count.
They're, they're, you're their own beast,
but there's lots of stuff. But anyway,
I don't know what to say to this. Like
part of me thinks duh. But at the same time, another part of me says
there's a generation of computer users
that are used to projects, just publishing binaries. And I think there's
a bunch of reasons this happened.
One is
in many instances,
your users can't build your software and a distribution won't include it.
Like
Coop CTL is a great example.
So the last time I was working with Kubernetes, this is like a week or two ago.
Yeah. How is that? Not
by
distro,
you
think?
No, no, no. It is. It is
my Debian machine in the basement
is what I'm running Kuber
neti stuff on, right?
I install KCTL from Debian and it is like years out of date
and KCTL releases
quite often.
-- So I had no choice.
-- That's one thing that drives me nuts
and, and well, and that's a perfect example too.
Of like, I want my software up to date for free from a bunch of volunteers,
repackaging it,
work faster
and then, and then things get really ugly where, you know,
the, let's call it the vendor,
the original source provider project, whatever you wanna call it
is like, OK, we'll make a binary but we only want to like make a binary for Linux.
So we're gonna ship in a flat pack or some other
or a docker container or something.
And then of course, everybody gets angry at them for not giving them more choices.
And it's kind of like
whatever.
I've seen people complaining that like, oh you provide this in flat pack.
Flatpack is the devil's
Kale lettuce, whatever. I don't know. A lot of people really hate Flatpack.
-- It's simple for me. I hate all
-- of
it.
I hate software.
I don't like
it. I
just,
-- all of it.
-- It's like every time somebody starts complaining about R PM or
dack
or something, I'm like, yep.
And, and here's the problems with M SI and here's the problems with
-- this.
-- Everything is terrible. That's all it's
for sure.
So, so anyway,
I
wanna, I wanna bring up one more thing.
I think that makes it an interesting story about the build. Like providing builds.
I think historically speaking,
providing builds was tough because you have to get the software,
build it and then upload it somewhere.
Dude, you had to build a CD N
uh No, no, no, not that. Well, that's part of it.
Right. And now with things like github,
github
can build and publish your binary magically. And I suspect that's part of it as well.
Well, it's, it's like everything we've leveled up the world.
You know, we used to buy cars without air conditioning or seatbelts.
Good luck trying to sell a car in the North American
market or most of the world without seatbelts or air conditioning.
I don't think you can legally sell it without seatbelts and
yeah,
I wouldn't want a car without air
conditioning because the summers get pretty rough.
So part of it is everything has leveled up. Like, for example, people expect
the software to mostly work. I remember downloading like versions of Bind and DH CP
having to hand
patch them for known vulnerabilities that they hadn't
or known problems that they hadn't yet fixed.
Let's not dwell on the past because it's gonna get boring.
We got a lot more stories here.
The thing is, things have leveled up but not everybody has gone with it.
Right. Some people
who,
why everybody not providing binaries for their stuff, by definition,
to some degree.
I feel like it's pretty common now.
Well, and some of, well, yeah,
but there are still people who don't provide binaries and, you know,
people ask why not and they're like, well, too much work or, and I,
I can't help but wonder maybe it's,
they don't know that it's easier now
-- or they just don't want to, which is
-- fair. This is the whole open
source owes you nothing story. Right? Like if you're an open
source project and you don't want to provide Binaries
good job.
Well,
the flip side being though is that there's that
fine line of open source owes you nothing.
But
I feel like open source should try to play nice with others and allow people
to come in and maybe help out like if somebody does want to build binaries,
-- maybe let them
-- uh maybe, yeah, I'm fine with that.
I mean,
and I get every single here's what I'm just gonna say,
every single one of these is totally different and
it is going to involve some form of negotiation and
compromise and whatever.
It's complicated. In other words, what really gets me is that
as we kind of level up, what is possible?
Like everybody expects you to have a public get repo now,
that was not always the case.
Uh
access to source code
with a lot of stuff is still like we publish a tar ball once in a while.
-- That's it. Like
-- I, I don't think that's very common anymore.
Well, there's a few but it used to be the default mostly.
Yeah. Yeah, because we didn't, it didn't exist
because
if you published, if you had a public source code repo,
you know, three people would try and check it out and it would crash
right because
that's true because it was CV S and CV S was terrible.
I remember running that thing on a machine with eight megs of ra M and I was like,
-- all right,
-- I'm gonna, I'm gonna move this on.
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna move this on because you also put a link here in
the notes titled The Things nobody wants to pay for from WN.
Uh I,
I won't lie to you.
I do not read this because I didn't have time prior to, to recording this episode.
-- So fill us in. What
-- is this? So it's talking
in broad terms. It's just talking about
how
software, like a lot of industries is on the backs of people who will
do insane amounts of hard work for little or no pay.
Like, like the restaurant industry is a perfect example,
like when I, you know,
really found out what most restaurant chefs make compared
to how many hours a day they work.
You know, it's like, that's so stupid. Why would you do that? You
earn more money
than mcdonald's?
But I get it's passion, right?
Same thing with like, like teachers, nurses, these people.
Yeah, for what they get paid compared to what they do like, wow. Uh
No, it's not passion. It's, it's definitely
a
sense
of duty
by capitalism.
-- Well, yeah,
-- and, and these, these people have a sense of like duty and obligation to
help the world out and they do and thank God because,
but what's interesting to me is that there's
people have always had a need to
paint on cave walls or to make music or to
run in and cook for people and make food for people. Right?
Like how many people have a, a
relative whose thing is like feeding
20 or 30 people at Thanksgiving and Christmas,
you know,
and they actually enjoy it to some degree.
And what's fascinating to me is that software
because in some ways the barrier to entry is so low.
Like nowadays you just need a computer and an internet connection, which is,
well,
you could just go to the public library and use theirs
if you're in a place with public libraries that have that.
But in general, you know,
virtually anybody can get a hold of a one or $200 laptop and an internet connection
and join the open source world.
All right, I'm going to reframe this discussion because I,
I don't think you're barking up the right tree on this one.
I think
this story because I've skimmed a bunch of it since, since you started talking,
I think this story can fundamentally be summed up as what we're getting
today in open source is what the market is willing to pay for.
And there's quotes here, there, there's one here talking about when,
why rel deprecated KDE?
Well, yeah, because no one used it and they, I mean, R red, red hat is a great example.
They're literally a company. If they don't make money, they don't do a thing.
If someone doesn't use a feature they're going to get rid of.
Right. Because they're not making money off of it. KDE was one of those examples.
Like, they didn't have a lot of users so they got rid of it.
I mean, I remember when you were at Red Hat, the whole KDE, like
everything was one or two people. It was
embarrassing.
Yeah,
it was a miracle. They got it to work because it's like holy crap.
But here's the, that's kind of the default because
as a company, if I can keep it working on life support,
why would I do more?
Here's where it gets interesting, I think is there's so it says here in a recent Linux
journal discussion, Kent Overstreet who I don't know,
complained about the lack of testing infrastructure for
the colonel calling it a failure of leadership.
But then Greg Kh,
who you and I both know and is a very
opinionated gentleman will say he said the problem lies elsewhere.
No,
they fall into the, no company wants to pay someone to do the work category.
So it doesn't get done.
And I think that is exactly correct. I think
if no one wants to pay
for it,
don't do it, no one wants it good enough.
The reality is these volunteers are not making a lot of money off doing open source.
Like
in most cases at best, they have a job doing it and they're making an ok living,
but they're certainly not bringing in millions or tens of millions of
dollars a year on a product based on that open source.
Whereas a company like I'm gonna pick on Amazon because
they're infamous for taking a bunch of open source,
turning it into a service and then
selling it as a service and not giving anything back
typically or nothing of meaning.
Ok.
So, you know, if Amazon's going to do that,
are you going to support them for free and buy testing
infrastructure for them to make sure that it works better?
If Amazon wants to make a lot of money using this thing, then they should,
they should spend the money as needed to do a better
-- job
-- or they won't spend any money because it basically works just
-- the way it is.
-- Well, they got it working on their limited set of things.
So, yeah, exactly.
You know,
another great quote here from someone called fungi
from
Python community. I don't know, I don't know what this person is.
Companies are unlikely to fund open source communities that are critical
to their own business because someone else will do it.
So it ends up falling on a handful of volunteers and people donating their own
time after hours because they're already being paid
to work full time on other stuff.
Yeah.
-- I mean, there's a lot of that
-- like, I appreciate, for example, when those XML hash off
uh
things came out when I just started at Red Hat
and,
you know, the, the, the author was like, yeah,
I don't have time to work on this for like two months, but I will happily do it then.
And we're like, ok, we'll take on it and do it.
And I actually, in hindsight now totally respect his. Like, this sounds like a
-- problem. Not a me problem.
-- It, it totally is 100%
you know, and that's fine. I think that's the right thing to do though.
If you're an organization that cares about a thing
and you want it fixed,
like, fix it,
-- you know,
-- or if you want to feature
-- funded
-- or
I'm, I'm ok with that. I think that's kind of the nature of open source.
I keep saying to myself that like, there's a reckoning coming in open source,
but I don't think there will
no,
see, but the thing is as much as I kind of agree with all this,
the reality is the world is built on top of, I don't want to say exploitation,
but it's,
it's built on
using things and not paying for them directly. So, like
every company on the planet uses roads
and, you know, indirectly pays for them with fuel taxes or property taxes or
whatever, some form of taxation, usually
sometimes toll roads, but we'll ignore that
same thing for having air that's breathable, having contract enforcement,
having a civil law system that does contract enforcement, right?
Not the whole,
the whole world is not. But the point I'm getting at is
there is no reckoning coming in because it's typically
you can't really use, it's up open source like you can with,
you can't pollute it like a river.
Your example is flawed
because you mentioned things like laws and roads and public infrastructure
-- which you pay for indirectly through taxes,
-- right?
Which we actually discussed that we've discussed it many times on the show.
I'm not going to go down the the government taxes open source universe.
But this is, I think the
what you're discussing is public services versus what
open sources today is an exploited ecosystem.
But the thing is open source is actually
like a lot cheaper to run. Like
I think we can all agree.
We probably don't need as much money as we spend on all the road infrastructure
to properly fund open source. I imagine those two numbers would be very different.
Like open source.
I don't know. Actually, I, I can't answer that. I suspect it's cheaper but I'm not.
When you think about a city like your local city,
how many people in public works are out there fixing roads, building roads
were earning a decent wage. Let's see.
I mean, you, no, II,
I live in a small city but we're probably talking in the neighborhood of
tens of billions of dollars to properly fund open source.
-- That's my guess
-- that's a vastly smaller number
than what everybody spends on roads and trains.
-- I mean,
-- we're talking country level budget, right. This is
my point being that this isn't a problem like the state of New York could solve,
right?
Like we need
some sort of global effort
if we want to fund
stuff.
I mean, this is where, like the, so funny enough, remember we talked to the,
the Sovereign Tech Fund folks a while back.
I I should have say the article, I don't even know where I saw it,
but apparently France is starting something very
similar to the Sovereign Tech Fund now.
And I'm like, yes,
so the German Sovereign Tech Fund basically takes applications to fund open
source activity, not just necessarily security stuff but usability, whatever
as I understand it.
And I'm going to be doing some work for them,
evaluating open source projects and what I really appreciate
them is they don't just have me like,
evaluate a bunch of projects.
I actually have to like staggering them from like one to whatever.
And then ideally also get on a call with a couple of other people that are doing this.
And then I assume we just,
it's like, you know,
it's like baseball draft or something where we
just started like hashing it out and picking,
you know,
fantasy football for
-- things
-- and looking at things like, not just, you know,
for example,
it can be a software that's directly used by a lot of
people or it could be like a boring piece of software.
Like, remember we looked through the, the, um,
oh, that list that not the sovereign tech fund, but the other one had
with the bug bounties and there was like that fishing software in there.
And I'm like, yeah, I guess people need to,
you know,
and so it's, it's really interesting to see that.
Well,
basically they're trying to get as much bang for their Dollar or Deutschmark as,
or sorry.
Euro. Wow. I'm old.
Get as much bang for their Euro as they can
and not just necessarily for that software but for,
you know, kind of what, what impact could this have, could it, you know,
maybe inspire other people, things like that.
And I think this is part of the way forward because then
at least we'll kind of have that critical level of like,
ok, this is stuff that we absolutely really need.
Like,
we can all, like, we could live without audacity. It would
not be fun and you'd be annoyed because you'd have to find some new software.
I haven't used audacity in a long time.
They got evil
and a lot of people quit using
evil.
Yeah,
it's a long story. I'm not going to go into it,
but I'm actually using a closed source product now called Reefer,
which is just like,
it is like flying the space shuttle of audio.
I learned it and it is incredibly useful.
And it's one of those things like I'm happy to,
it's just like some guy is the author of it and I'm happy to
give him some cash and I get a product that it probably cuts.
So this is funny, actually,
it should have cut down my editing time
by a pretty wide margin because generally speaking,
the way I
say editing audio works is number of guest times length
of audio is how long it takes me to edit,
which is generally true.
But because Reaper has so many extra knobs to twiddle,
it definitely takes me longer to edit shows now than it
used to because I keep like messing with stuff constantly,
but
-- whatever it is what it is anyway,
-- sorry, I was just looking up audacity
fire
stuff.
So it's complicated. I don't remember even the whole story.
I just know like it went off the rails and I quit using it
and I'm very happy with Reaper.
-- So
-- it's like, well,
a perfect example locally we now have um so
we almost had rotating blackouts because of the cold.
Now today we have a water related emergency.
So Edmonton has two water treatment plants.
The Rossdale, which is the really old one,
right? And the New El Smith, which is the really big one
and apparently the entire water delivery system.
So like takes the water that they've treated
and pumps it into the Edmonton water system,
which also feeds a couple of other small towns in the nearby area.
It's broken.
Whoops.
Yeah. And they don't know when it'll be fixed. So, like, they're literally,
they were saying, like, major water users need to stop using water,
but they were even giving advice.
Like, if you're brushing your teeth, turn the tap off,
like, while you're brushing, like, I'm not sure how much that's gonna help,
but sure.
But it's, but it's, it's kind of like,
honestly, the water system is limping along because we've got the raw stale.
But it's,
you know, it's like, I think one, if I had to guess I'd say it's like 1/5 of what we need.
But the point is like, it's, it's limping along.
-- Things haven't gone off the rails yet.
-- No,
no,
no.
I think, I think you're on to something and this, this is the, the, I think the,
the discussion to end the show is.
So I think what you're describing is
in North America,
an enormous amount of public infrastructure has been neglected
for probably the last 20 to 40 years.
And an enormous amount of it is going to
start failing catastrophically because it's like the old saying,
if you don't schedule downtime, your equipment will, right?
I think we're, we're going to see that more and more often because, like,
you have to maintain this stuff, you can't just like,
use it and forget about it forever.
Right. And I think maybe that's part of the problem is we're seeing that sort of
starting to come home to roost in the open source world where, I mean,
it's not like they're building financial products out of this stuff, but they're,
they're, no,
they're, they're using it.
And the thing is I keep coming back to if they were just using it. Sure.
But they're using it and making demands of people and like,
stressing them out and making them miserable.
Like a great example is curl
like Daniel posts those
emails he gets from people who are like, you're hacking me because of the thing,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And like I got that too.
And you know, I,
I've literally been on the receiving end of that and
seen other people on the receiving end of that,
like where a company did something with a piece of software shipped it badly
and the person like kind of searches the error
message and comes to this open source project and like
screams at them and they're like,
what are you even talking about?
Like, my favorite was people would take copies of the links, administrator,
security guide, post it on their websites.
And I actually kind of preferred it when they removed my name
because they would post it on my web on their website,
leave my name
and then people would yell at me for not updating it, of course.
And I'd be like, yeah,
IA I didn't know that it existed on that website in wherever and b I can, it's
my website and they're like, what do you mean?
It's not your website, it's your content. And I'm like,
do you know how cut and paste works?
Like it just, there was no reasoning with these people. Right.
Because if they could be reasoned with, they wouldn't have
attacked me in the first place.
Well, it, it's complicated, I think.
But, but regardless the point is right,
I think some of our infrastructure is going to be a similar,
I will come. I I'm not sure what word to use here, but like
if we continue to neglect open source and we don't do anything about it,
there are people starting to do things.
So this may not come to fruition.
But like if we continue to neglect it for long enough, like it's going to collapse,
right?
That is the inevitable outcome of neglecting a system such as
yes.
And the question is, does it collapse collapse or does it sort of decline or,
you know, like that's a great example is the oil and gas industry.
Like if we turned off oil and gas tomorrow,
everything would crash because we don't have time
to transition and we don't have the,
the
things we need to transition. But
had we spent say from the 19 seventies,
uh you know, oil crisis
really transitioning
well, yeah, like 50 years later, we'd probably all be driving electric cars by now.
I mean, it's certainly a possibility.
It, it,
it,
I,
I don't know if that's technically a perfect analogy here, but I, I feel like
it might be now at the same time, it's also plausible
that open source is one of those industries where
the, the powers that be are more than happy to just let people show up, get burnt out,
leave and get replaced by someone else doing some other thing.
You know, two problems with that theory though is one
existing open source is vast and complex
and you can't just show up and start
contributing right away.
Like there's a, there's an on ramp and a learning curve for a lot of software,
right? Like, I mean,
you can't just write a Linux device driver,
you need to probably spend a couple hours reading
-- is
-- special. Don't bring
into this
even set an A
like they're so optimized like panda or numpy.
Those are, no, no, I don't think that's how it works. I think.
No, but what I'm trying to say is
to get fresh people into the software ecosystem and get them productive.
-- It's not like they just join and are immediately productive.
-- No, they do.
They do though. I think they do
because I think here's what happens. Let's pick on like go or Rust, right?
These are relatively new languages
and there's a ton of people that just showed up one day and
made a thing because they needed a thing to do a job.
And like these are ecosystems
that I'm,
I'm seeing it now where there's people clearly burning
out in some of these places and they're like,
I'm out
and
some of those things are widely used and we're going to find out what happened.
Well, what I was trying to get to is
if, for example, all the rust developers quit,
there wouldn't be a crop of new people that would show up and be immediately
-- helpful. Like it would take a while.
-- No, it wouldn't. Rust dies.
That's how that ends. Like
if you have an ecosystem like that where a bunch of people burn out and quit,
I think it's going to die and be replaced by something else.
I don't think people are going to show up and fix it. And I think
that is part of the other piece to this whole open source.
The things nobody wants to do is when you have a project that exists, like let's, I,
I will pick on the Linux kernel.
In this instance,
the Linux kernel is probably the most established and largest open source project
ever, maybe ever. That will be right
now. At the same time,
I don't think you're gonna see loads of new people just
like show up out of the blue to work on Linux,
they're gonna be paid to do it because first of all,
there's a lot of companies that need it.
But at the same time, if I'm a new person,
I'm not gonna even try to get involved in Linux
because the the barrier of entry is a freaking mile high
cliff or we'll say kilometer high cliff for you educated folks.
But like it's, it's gigantic, right?
Or I could just do my own little thing and create a repo and
github
and good enough. Yo.
Well, and my other thought is now, for example, what I wonder what the average
age of a Linux kernel developer is
and especially, I hate to say this, but if you look at the established names in it,
obviously, they're all getting a year older, one year at a time like Greg
Pearl
Hartman, Lin
Carl. But really
all those established names have been there for
-- years or more.
-- There's a lot of
communities in general that suffer this problem and there's,
we're not going to talk about it today
because it's, it's a big can of worms. But here's the thing I keep thinking of
is how many of these communities don't have fresh people because the
old people won't just get the freaking heck out of the way
because like I have been in working groups
that had, people will say that are well past the point,
they should have been involved in their
careers and just personal lives and everything
and they will not leave and anyone young and competent is like,
I'm out because I've talked to people that like be like, please come back and help me.
They're like, no, that guy's an idiot. I'm not coming back and I'm like,
I mean, you're not wrong. I'm not going to argue with you. But,
yeah, I've,
I've seen a lot of that and I'm actually beginning to suffer some of that myself.
I'm very aware of the fact that if anyone younger than me wants to help,
I'm out, I'm gone. Like, yep, I'm out, I'm not gonna stay and mess things up because I,
I know I'm out of touch in a lot of ways and that's ok.
Like that's part of how it goes, you know?
Yeah.
And so
I don't know, I just,
I think it's going to be one of those things where it's
fine until it isn't fine and then when it isn't fine,
there's, you know, not
the expertise to actually implement a solution is nontrivial here.
Right? This isn't a thing where you can simply throw more money on it. Right? Like
we're witnessing the whole thing where uh Cisa released that thing
saying that developers need to be part of the security conversation.
Yes. Yes, they do.
And as we've learned from 50 years of computer
security educating developers is not going to fix this
and assuming you can educate them,
then they have to work at a company where they're like, yeah, well,
we'll let you go like half the speed that we want you to go.
So you can write secure code and not just crank out features
like I'm sorry, but
outside of the space shuttle software, you know,
which is infamous for being very good.
And like they had a problem with the Canada arm and then they like, actually fixed it,
but fixed it in case they ever mounted it on the
left side as well as the right side or whatever,
vice versa.
Right.
-- I love that. It's just called the Canada arm.
-- That's
the one, it's our claim to fame. Damn, it,
there's one on the space station too. Like it's a good arm.
It's our thing, right? Like,
I like that Canada was smart enough to be like, yeah, we,
we can't really afford a shuttle but like we can build you an arm for it.
I love, it's awesome. You know, and it's a cool arm.
-- Like, anyway, anyway,
-- uh they had a mock up of it back in the day at tell us,
which I liked looking at the tell us world signs anyways.
So to be blunt,
this is one of the reasons I love curl
because he keeps celebrating new people joining curl.
-- And they're up to like, what is it? Over 1200 now? It's
-- a lot of people. Yeah.
You know,
and I,
I don't see a lot of projects doing that.
I don't know of any other projects that do stuff like that.
And I think it's a really big deal and I think it's very cool.
-- To, to make it a big deal. So
-- I just looked at the NTPK her brief
and it hasn't had a commit in nine years.
I, I don't, does, is NTP still used, aren't there?
There's something else isn't there now,
N
PC. And I
actually, you know what, you just reminded me of that.
I'm going to end the podcast on because I feel
like we've come with no solutions to anything other than
-- maybe things are terrible but probably
-- not buy canned food.
I, I guess, no, I'm not buying canned food. If my
all right, all you preppers. My, my plan for the fall of society is to die first.
So
it's foolproof as far as I'm concerned.
But anyway, anyway, uh,
there's one other thing I'll mention about all this kind of
old man stuff is there was a history of X Windows.
I found on youtube the other day and watched it and it was quite good.
Yeah, it starts like at the very beginning and basically explains like the madness.
And it's funny because I remember watching this.
I'm like, oh, I remember that, I remember that guy.
Like, I remember when that happened
and it was very nostalgic for me,
but for anyone who's ever wondered why X Windows seems as ridiculous as it is.
It's because it is ridiculous and there's ridiculous reasons. It is ridiculous.
-- So it's very good.
-- It also came from a time where literally,
-- I don't have enough horsepower to run application, whatever
-- they
-- talk
-- about
that.
And so I'm going to run
on the sun pizza box and display it to my crappy little PC.
-- They talk about that. That's part of the part of the story.
-- This is what I
love is watching people in the A I space rediscover resource limitations
and just struggle with it like they are just hurting.
No, we're not doing this right now. I want to end this on a semi
posit note.
And I guess here is what I will say
is while I read stories like these about the
builds and the things open source doesn't want to
do and talking about all these working groups full
of people who push out the youth or whatever.
I think fundamentally
the fact that we're at least acknowledging this
I think is an acceptable
first step. There's a long way to go.
But I think five or 10 years ago,
no one was even talking about this stuff and people
on the inside of open source knew this was brewing,
but no one else did. But today, I feel like it's definitely becoming a bigger issue.
So I'm hopeful
there are people
in positions to make a difference that we also notice this
and we'll see more things like the sovereign tech fund,
for example, trying to make open source more sustainable
and make it survive into the future.
Well, I think more to the point, it's probably a lot like NASA,
where every dollar you spend fixing some open
source component that like your country relies upon,
probably indirectly returns
easily 10 to 100 times that
just the friction alone of like people having to switch to something else or a
single log for Jay incident. Like
good Lord,
the amount of time we all wasted on log for Jay doing silly things like
the number of security questionnaires.
I had to fill out to tell people my,
like our response as an organization to log for Jay and it's like none like we don't,
don't use it.
Sorry,
I'm
calling it. I'm calling it.
I guess the good news is, yeah, people are aware of this.
We're seeing articles about it and we're actually seeing
governments start to spend some money on it.
-- I hope so,
-- man. Which makes you real.
All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go up at our Security podcast.com head at the show, not UZ Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag to find us some.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.