Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
All right. So take two again.
But
so the I I want to cover this quickly and I do not want us to dwell on it.
And actually the last thing we recorded, we spent too much time on it.
So that's great.
So I've had a number of people contact me about the Twitter
hacking incident where about 100 and 30 accounts were compromised and this,
this attacker basically used it to try to get Bitcoin out of
people and they made about 100 and 30 K is my understanding,
give or take.
And
uh people are saying, why did the attacker only do this?
And why didn't they do something
more interesting and potentially more profitable?
And my response has been,
most criminals are idiots and this person was clearly no exception.
So that's pretty much it.
Well, and I love that they, they, it's not that they hacked 100 and 30 accounts.
They hacked a management interface that had
apparently access to like all the verified accounts
with. And apparently Twitter has like multiple levels of this.
So it's like dumb schmucks like us,
there's verified accounts with the little blue check or whatever.
There's like the ultra secure verified can't be abused accounts.
Like, you know,
apparently the president of the United States thinks
Twitter is a place to send out policy.
So,
I mean, uh yeah, anyways
anyway. So, yeah. No. And, and you're right, like smart criminals either.
Well, smart, really smart criminals do one of two things.
They either do white collar crime because that stuff almost never gets
punished and when it does get punished it's like google the term,
you know, the sec, uh, fined by the sec but admitted no wrongdoing.
You know, like that's
the kind of white collar crime you want to be doing. If you're smart or number two
you do stuff that isn't crime yet and, and that can be like,
really hyper aggressive sales.
Like, I'm sure we've all met some sales people that are like, pretty scary or,
you know, they just, they invent new financial instruments that.
Right. Right.
Well, it's not a crime because the, you know,
we never had outer space alien fungible tokens before.
And the beauty of being legitimate is you don't
have to launder your money or fence your stuff.
So
it's, yeah. Anyway, anyway, I don't want to dwell on it.
No, the whole thing is just, it's,
you know what it really reminds me of is the whole, remember when DD and esco
denial of service down in the Mar I bought net.
We thought, oh my God, it's this massive state level actress thing.
And you know what?
It turned out to be three college
students that were doing Minecraft server extortion.
It boils down.
You have a Minecraft server.
It'd be an awful shame if it fell over,
you should pay us some money and some guy didn't.
So they dosed his D
DNS provider and
like,
literally everybody thought it was like China or
Russia testing out some new cyber weapon.
-- It's like, no, just a bunch of college students.
-- That's
right.
Honestly, if somebody wrote this and made this movie, I'd be like,
that's some truly crap script writing.
Like they are not trying.
I agree. I agree completely.
-- Yeah. Good
-- times.
It's
uh well, and, and this is what this is directly, what feeds today's show.
Today's show is sort of about that whole attention economy thing.
What's,
what's fascinating to me is you have all these super high tech companies
that are doing like tons of machine learning and A I and like,
Facebook has their own data centers and not just like a few little ones but
massive data centers, you know, their own open.
What is it, the open hardware thing with like those, you know,
it's this like rack design where there's no power supply,
there's just like these three scary copper bars at
the back that like if you touch them,
you will die because it's something like it's like
12 volts at like 400 amps or something ridiculous.
And like
the,
the way they monetize all this is by taking your attention and trying to show you ads.
And so
there's a fascinating thing that has just come out recently.
It's the new GP T three A I that generates text.
You should explain this because I wouldn't even say it just generates text.
-- Like I can generate text.
-- So
true. Like we've had ways for computers to generate text.
But what's special of this one is you feed it a bunch
of text like that you wrote or somebody else wrote or,
you know,
of scientific papers and it basically spits out new content
that is similar to the old content but is well,
it's new
and it, it really does appear to have been written by a human.
It does tend to have uh where it starts out,
it says something interesting and then it just sort of trails off
and goes off on tangents and never reaches a conclusion because,
you know, it's not sentient in the sense of thinking and analyzing these ideas.
It's just literally constructing grammatically
correct sentences that also kind of
-- have all the right words.
-- I would, I would argue that
sports writing
-- is this.
-- Well, sports writing has already been automated this way.
Baseball games and a couple other sports are in the process.
There's a company that does this now
-- that doesn't surprise me
-- and has been doing this
for one or two years and even adds backstory.
So, like, when they see these two teams playing each other,
they'll talk about their historical rivalry or whatever,
you know, because, yeah, I mean, no offense. There's no
so many ways to report on a sports ball game.
-- Right.
-- Exactly.
That's what I always feel like any time I happen upon a story about sports,
it's just a lot of, you could have written it in four sentences instead,
I'm reading three paragraphs.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, the winning team obviously gave 100 and 10%
and the losing team.
Well, they didn't.
Yeah, they suck more. It definitely wasn't. Mostly luck. And, yeah.
Anyway, anyway,
no, that's, that's cool.
What's, what's fascinating like, so there's a GP T two which generated text,
you know, but, and it was kind of noticeably you could
iff it out after a while,
but GP T three, they basically trained it on like 100 times more data or whatever,
you know.
It's, it's a lot more sophisticated and it does a much better job and it's,
it's not open sourced unfortunately, although it might be at some point,
even though the organization is called the Open A
I
-- kind of the biggest naming scam ever. In my opinion.
-- It's like wikileaks, not a wiki.
Yeah.
Like they, they open A, I started with the premise of we will be opening, you know,
advanced A, I, and people won't have to re invent the wheel secretly.
And,
yeah, I know. That's not how that turned out.
But, yeah, it's fascinating because this guy wrote a
blog entry and it sort of starts out, like, ok,
and then it just sort of gets a little weird and
-- honestly I've, I've read words, things from actual humans. I've
-- read much worse.
So there's,
there's an article we will put in the show notes
that Kurt sent to me and you read the article
and
I won't say it's, it's bad. It's not good.
It's, it's an article,
it's what I would expect on the internet for your typical news story.
And then basically at the end, the guy says
I didn't write this, the A I wrote it.
Here's what I gave the A I and this article is what it popped out. And
it was fascinating to me that
an A I could be, I would say this
acceptable.
You know what I mean?
Yeah. And what's really fascinating was like the hacker news thread on it.
You know,
because as one point person pointed out it's really clear who just read the title,
who read one or two paragraphs and who read the whole thing.
Ah, interesting. But, I mean, that's the thing, right? We are literally in
the Clickbait era of
the internet,
right? You know, things go viral, whatever
and getting those attention tokens points,
whatever and trying to convert them into money by shoving ads down your face.
Sadly, I mean,
you know,
that's what blows my mind if you had told me back when I started using the internet,
that,
you know,
the way companies are going to monetize this all
is by trying to shove ads down your face.
I would have been, like,
at first I would have been horrified and then I would have been, well, you know,
that's every broadcast media thing ever.
So, yeah, that makes sense. Like, think about it. Right.
Have, how else have, you know, newspapers, TV,
movies,
product placement.
Like that's just, that's the best thing people have figured out.
Yes.
So, and what I really love to on a side note is, you know,
all those major advertisers leaving Facebook and I don't
think they're going to be coming back anytime soon.
I mean, so my argument here and this is sort of a tangent.
So I, I think I've talked about this before on the podcast, but
I run a handful of sites and obviously one of them is this podcast.
And so I have various statistics about how people are getting to us,
how people are exiting us.
And obviously there's always show notes.
We'll put things like on Twitter. Well, you know, whatever.
And I can tell you now that the click through of all of that stuff is garbage.
It is, it is effectively zero.
And I would be shocked if Facebook ads have any
actual return on investment because I have a strong suspicion.
The vast majority of people on Facebook are already so, like,
blind to what's going on around them.
Just because that's kind of the nature of social media.
Let's get your attention and then just like,
let's spoon feed you garbage and you don't even realize it.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, the classic thing with advertising, right is, you know, that I,
half my advertising is wasted.
I just don't know which half I
think it's actually a lot more than that.
Then the argument turns to all the whole, well, brand recognition.
You know, you're in the supermarket, you have to choose Coke or Pepsi.
You're like, I've never heard of Pepsi, but, hey,
Coke is a familiar brand because I saw it on TV, once.
Like my favorite thing is always advertising for gas stations because I literally,
I'm just driving and I'm like, oh, that one's a penny cheaper than that one.
-- I'm going to that
-- one.
I don't even do that. I just think, oh, I need gas. There's a gas station.
Well,
here we tend to like here the closest gas station to me is literally
always 5 to 10 cents higher than the one that's like three blocks further.
Super bizarre, but like, consistently.
-- Yeah, I filled up there once or twice and then I'm driving,
-- it's probably less busy.
I don't know, man.
But, um, but to me, as far as I know gas is, is fungible.
And, like, I put gas in my car and as long as I don't put diesel in my car,
I think we're ok.
The problem though with advertising is if you did zero advertising and, uh,
you know, you're up against a company like Coca Cola that does
tens or whatever, billions of dollars of advertising. A,
yeah,
you're going to get stomped in the mass market, sort of.
But on the flip side, you know, for smaller companies,
-- I can't imagine advertising working all that
-- well,
I mean, it's going to depend,
there's a million things to talk about here and
none of them are related to security really.
Well, it's what's fascinating to me is we have this attention based economy
and now we have ways to programmatically
generate stuff to grab people's attention.
We've already seen that with videos on youtube where people generate really cheap,
low end kids content.
Like to the point of that kid called
Evan in California who's apparently a multimillionaire,
even though he's not even like 10 years old and he literally opens
up boxes of toys and plays with them and talks about it.
Well, that's, that's real content though.
I mean, you can argue it's, it's crap and it might be but
like this is nothing like the machine generated
-- content that is out there
-- but where there
is machine generated content on youtube in the
form of cartoons and remixes and stuff.
Yeah, I know there's tons of it.
So one of the things my daughter loves to do, my daughter is 11
and she will, she'll tell me, oh, I'm going to go watch some meme
which at first I'm like, what? That doesn't make sense.
But so what people do is they basically go on to Reddit,
they download the meme images,
they play background music
and then they display memes like 10 seconds of meme for, you know, make,
make like a 10 minute video out of it.
You think about that's literally zero human interaction. Zero effort.
-- Yeah,
-- I just, I just googled, watch some memes. And
exactly what you're describing is what showed up.
I mean, because I've seen the thing on, on youtube where like they have Reddit
reading out like the top stuff from like relationship advice or
all the train wreck stories and like some of the responses
and they just have like a computer, read it out, like
text to speech
and it's got like some
random background, but this is a whole new level of, wow.
But now here's so here's the question
she enjoys doing this.
-- Is there anything wrong with providing people what they want?
-- No.
Well, do people actually want this
-- because
-- she does,
well, people eat too much fast food and junk food, right?
People want a lot of bad things, people want to smoke, people want to drink too much.
People want meth, you know,
some of these things we've decided are illegal like meth, but, you know,
some like smoking,
we still allow that and it's pretty clear it's not good for you.
So, I, I don't know if that's a, a reasonable comparison here
because
I, for example, love going to Reddit
and paging through the crap memes. Nothing pleases me more than doing that.
I mean,
is it any worse than spending four hours watching a
football game on Sunday that has six minutes of action?
I would argue. No.
So I, I get it, people want to sit down and kind of just waste their time mentally and,
and I do that too.
Like I also read Reddit and
you know, various other time wasting.
Like I watched, well, I don't watch TV, TV, I watch Netflix.
You know, which by definition,
if you're not watching some enlightening documentary,
you're basically just kind of wasting time.
But I mean,
going to the theater is that
also wasting time? Well,
to some degree? Yeah, and that's fine.
But the problem is, you know,
we're getting to this point where once
we get this programmatically generated content,
my fear is that it takes the money away from
the things that are a bit more interesting and useful because
one thing I'm seeing with all this programmatically generated content
is that they actually don't generate the content by and large, right?
They take like this meme thing, it just downloads stuff from Reddit, which is people
or you know, the remixes or the,
well, the articles about a baseball game, like it didn't create the baseball game,
it's
reported it.
That's
right.
And
we will.
So humanity has generated an enormous corpus of content
that these like a is can draw on.
You start getting into some weird questions when like the A I is using other A
I generated content and that's probably going to
start getting weird and crazy and stuff.
But
I, I feel like
I want to bring this up one more level from where we're at because I
think we could whinge all day on wasting time on Reddit or youtube or whatever.
And
I feel like from the perspective of
-- capturing attention is a better discussion, I think and,
-- and, you know,
this is something that Facebook has been accused of algorithmically, you know,
and, and kids games are doing this now where they're, you know,
working really hard to use psychological tricks
to take people's attention and monetize it
and, you know, do some really psychologically unhealthy things, you know, like,
well, the current thing, the doom scrolling.
Yeah. Oh, doom scrolling is a lovely term
for what's going on. Yeah.
Where you're just on this, like infinite news feed, web page that, you know,
you keep scrolling down and just reading.
Well, I mean,
so far has there been any good news in 2020?
I can't think of any
if there's any,
I mean, Australia stopped being on fire but
-- no
-- one,
-- no one remembers
-- only because all of it burned down.
Right.
So, picking on kids games isn't even fair.
I would pick on all mobile games, mobile games are not games,
mobile games are attention traps
that want to try to convert your attention into ad revenue.
Well, or,
or you buy coins to make the game go faster
because they intentionally make the game grinding and painful.
My suspicion is most people don't do that.
Most people probably end up watching stupid ads because you can usually like,
watch an ad for free coins or whatever the garbage is that they're doing.
I mean, this is, this is one of the terrifying things about
kind of how modern society has constructed itself and from like, from,
from my perspective of security,
I often wonder,
where does this end?
Well, it doesn't like, it's the, the logical end is blip
Verts with people exploding.
-- That's the logical end point to all this.
-- That's from Max Hedger
-- for you young people.
-- Yeah, we'll include a clip
but like straight up,
like until we get to people exploding in their living rooms because of Blip Forts,
it's just going to keep escalating.
I mean,
it, it might be,
it might.
Yeah, I know.
But, but at the same time, right. So, so let's, let's focus on the ants.
Advertising ad networks are well known for being
taken over by adversaries and distributing malware.
Yeah,
that's why I block them. It's,
you know between the the noise on the web page, the speed of loading it
and just the general. Well, this is how modern web browsers get hacked.
I mean, what's also fascinating to me is is back to my fear of
we need people to create content.
Now,
I have no fear that there will be people
creating content because we like stone age cave paintings,
people people make stuff.
But my concern is we also need people to
kind of make boring stuff like investigative reporting,
you know, the Panama papers, things like that. Like
there are certain things that are let's face it.
Not like like painting a picture of your favorite sunset.
Yeah,
like there will be no shortage of that.
Like people who want to be Bob Ross, no problem.
But people who want to, you know, go expose government corruption and write,
you know,
20 to 100 page
things about it that are, you know, well written in depth and
analyzed and
you know, fully sourced. Yeah, that
-- you can have to pay people to do that.
-- It's very difficult.
I mean, look, I'm going to pick on us here, right?
We have a podcast, we make $0 on our podcast.
So obviously we're not doing it for the money.
We are not insanely popular. So we're obviously not doing it for the fame.
It's something we basically enjoy doing. And so we do it
and
it's, I mean, I'm not gonna lie to you.
It's a convenient excuse to talk to you for at least an hour a week, which I,
which I love.
But like,
you know what I mean? It, it's,
if, if we were a monetized podcast,
it would change everything,
the dynamic would be different. Actually. It's funny.
I got, I got an email the other day from someone saying, oh, do you need an editor?
I'm like, well, I have no budget. So no.
What were they offering for free?
I did not ask, I would never do that to a person because I feel that's insulting.
-- But it would be funny to say
-- like somebody might want to edit our podcast to get it on,
you know, to get the exposure so they can get a better job.
-- But I'm pretty sure you can't buy food with exposure.
-- No, actually.
So I'm, I'm extremely anti exposure. I think I would agree.
Anyone who says, oh, do it for exposure.
-- No, that's just a way to try to trick people
-- unless you're a performance artist.
And there's like
seven of them who make a living doing this on the plane,
-- man. I, I'm anti exposure. I, I I'm not just, I
-- mean, I know.
No, I'm basically what I'm saying is I'm, I'm agreeing but there's like
the counter
argument of people can do this for a living.
See, you do this all the time. This drives you crazy.
You're like, oh, here's this obscure corner case. I'm going to bring up.
But no, that doesn't legitimize the moment.
But
my
point is,
that's exactly my point.
Like, there's only one bank seat.
-- There, there is. Well, he makes a fortune man. That guy, like, he's got it
-- made
and the rest of us are going to starve exposure is not going to buy us any ramen.
-- Right. That's right. That's right.
-- Well, I mean, that's the thing.
Like, how, how do we monetize, you know, the, the listeners we have, well,
advertising the answer or,
you know, the more nebulous forms of advertising, like, oh, a show sponsor or,
you know, brought to you by Dr
-- mcginty's, you know, firewall rub
-- advertising. That's still.
Exactly. Exactly.
-- So,
-- there's Patreon,
I was about to say, like,
the thought of getting somebody to pay for this.
Yeah,
jokes on you sucker.
Uh,
but,
and honestly, that's not an environment I even want
anyway. It's like if you have money to give to someone,
please give it to a charity, don't give it to me.
Like I'm going to spend it on probably booze where
a charity might actually do something useful with it.
Right. Right.
Exactly. Exactly. But it, it is,
again,
we bring ourselves back to this whole attention that this problem of attention.
Right. And, and that's kind of how you want to frame it and,
and obviously I always try to put my security hat on when I'm,
when I'm framing all of these discussions and thinking about
what does this mean and what doesn't it mean?
And everything? And I feel like
in any security situation, what you end up there, there's kind of two aspects.
Right? There's the, we'll say wholesome troublemakers
which,
which those exist, I think less than they used to.
And then there's like the legitimate criminals. Right.
And I feel like the attention economy today
is
you've got the legitimate businesses and you have some wholesome troublemakers
and I don't think like legitimate crime has figured this out yet,
but attention is becoming
a valuable resource
in the modern world.
What is going to happen when criminals decide it's time for us to get in on this.
Well, I mean, there was already some of this,
if you want to see some really deeply disturbing weird stuff, go
search for Elsa gate,
Els a gate
and that like, I'm not even going to describe it.
It's just so messed up.
And I, like my fear is we see stuff like that.
Like, I've already caught my kids watching videos where, like,
I'm paying attention to what's being said and I'm like, whoa,
like I thought this was just a video of somebody playing with a toy,
but like some of the stuff they're talking about is
that's not really appropriate for kids. And I'm like, is this
like, what is, I just don't understand what's going on?
Like,
I don't think it's criminal but it's definitely not what I want my kids watching.
Right. Yeah. No, I do. I, I think this is one of the biggest arguments for
having augmented reality to block out advertising because, I mean,
one reason I would love to visit Hawaii is apparently Hawaii doesn't allow those,
like, large signs by roads or anywhere.
Yeah,
-- because they're hideous and nobody wants to look at them like
-- they just
installed a couple new ones on a major road near my house and
they're just so big and ugly.
Yep.
Yeah. Right. Right. But they make someone money so they're going to do it.
But, um, I, yeah, I, I feel like
the way that criminals are going to weaponize and
subvert attention is going to be messy because I just,
I can't imagine them finding some clean and clear way to monetize
it because the legitimate people haven't and they've been trying for,
you know, a good 100 years.
-- I mean,
-- so, actually, do you know of an instance where bad people have used
advertising to their advantage?
Well, sort of the whole, well, ignoring, like, drive by downloads,
the whole sort of getting whipping up public outrage to, you know,
target a person or a group of people
has happened.
And so a great example, there would be, you know, the Russian
and Chinese online,
you know, trolling stuff, getting various other groups of people to do dumb things.
Like, well, I'm not even sure I want to say it because then we'll get, like,
beaten up on Twitter.
I think we can all agree that, you know,
there's a bunch of stuff that's happened online where people have
been whipped up into a frenzy to do really dumb things.
-- I
-- mean, that's not new by any means. I think online makes it easier.
But there have been state level disinformation campaign
as long as there have been states
propaganda, I mean.
Right. Right. Exactly. It works.
And, and I mean, let's, let's ignore that particular instance, even like, what are,
I can think, you know,
there have been some scams throughout history
where like the pyramid scams are obviously
an easy one where someone convinced someone else to invest in their opportunity.
I mean, that's why we call them Ponzi schemes. There was a guy literally named Ponzi
who came up with them
and, and so there's some of that,
but I feel like
there is never been a wide scale criminal aspect to advertising
through history. I think there have been one offs but it's never been
-- substantial.
-- I know bre
X that was a big gold scandal back in the day here in Canada.
And so basically it was a gold mine, I want to say in Indonesia
where the geologist salted the samples and because he was a geologist,
he salted them properly so that, you know, the,
the results came back very promising, but not like, oh my God, it's just full of gold,
right?
$6 billion blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, massive fraud.
Brix collapsed, blah, blah, blah.
Yeah, there was like no gold there.
-- Well,
-- so this is interesting actually is if you conduct fraud on that level,
you're almost definitely going to get caught
-- and you're probably going to face repercussions.
-- Yes.
And no,
if you get enough money and go to a country that's not very
nice and doesn't extradite to other countries and you're willing to live there
a pile of money. I mean, but that's pretty rare.
-- Again, criminals don't do this, they get caught.
-- It, it depends who you rip off.
I mean,
you're going to accidentally fall out of a window.
Right. If you, if you ripped off the wrong person is how those tend to work.
But when you, when you think about online, I mean,
let's consider it in the context of the Twitter story
where
it was, I mean, basically it was weaponized. Advertising
is the way I would think of it
and,
well, more weaponized attention.
-- Yeah.
-- I mean, same idea. Really? Right.
Well, you know, it reminds me of the classic thing,
like all these business plans that consist of we will,
you get 100% of everybody on the planet to spend 10
cents with us and that's why you need to invest,
you know, $6 million in our seed round.
Right.
Yeah, that is technically true, but
it's not going to happen.
Right.
Yes. Exactly. Exactly.
So,
anyway, anyway, So here's
my prediction
of what this is going to look like with things like A I
and
things like our attention economy. And so there is any time there's an incentive
you're going to have,
I would, I would say there's a spectrum from people with good intent,
people with ill intent.
And then there's a lot of things in the middle.
And I would argue, like, for example, social media is probably in the middle,
leaning toward ill intent where I think a number of these companies know
that they're, they're, they're selling us drugs
and they know it, but they don't care because they're,
they're rolling in piles of money
and that obviously changes people's perspective, but
there is money in this and I think it is a matter of time before criminals invest in it.
And I have no doubt anyone listening,
there are probably examples of this you might know about.
I don't
let us know.
I would love to explore this further because I feel like in this space, we often
assume,
I assume, I, I think if we, if we view it as like a number line, right,
where good guys are on the left, bad guys are on the right.
I think we assume it's farther to the left than it really is in terms of the content.
You know what I mean?
-- Well, I mean,
-- we know about ad fraud where they, you know, they click ads to get money,
right.
And that, that's pretty self explanatory. You know, you run a site that
generates clicks, you get money. So we run a site that generates clicks.
But as far as actually
kind of going that next step to, you know, how do I basically get,
assuming I have Kurt's attention for 30 seconds. How do I turn that into some money?
Yeah, that's, that's a tricky one because I'm not into microtransaction.
So, good luck getting any money out of me. I actually, you know what? That's not true.
I did get ripped off online.
There was this thing that was supposed to be like this fun drawing board thing.
So I ordered it and it was a complete piece of garbage that was like, worth, you know,
$2 as it turns out and didn't work.
But of course, it was, you know, cheap enough that I'm not going to, like, you know,
send it back to China and try and get my
money back and it was bought through some rather,
you know, dodgy site.
Like, no, it wasn't ebay or, you know, Amazon. It was like some,
not even like Alibaba thing.
And so, you know, my lesson learned there is now II,
I tend to stick to ebay and Amazon and some other major sites where
I know that I can actually get my money back if you know,
somebody sends me a brick in the mail.
Yeah. Yeah,
I mean,
I,
II, I can totally relate to that.
-- Yeah.
-- So, but,
but, I mean, beyond like,
sort of those, those, all those things, like what the new forms of crime will be.
Yeah. I don't know.
And, and if you do know of them and are willing to share, please let us know it.
I'd be fascinated to find out about this because I have no doubt.
Or, you know,
maybe there's already things happening that you and
I participated in and we don't even realize,
oh, I have no doubt. I, I absolutely have no doubt. And
I, I don't know, I think it'll be interesting to see where this all goes because
attention is becoming valuable, more valuable,
especially now we're all stuck at home.
Right. I mean, I
think
it is becoming more apparent
that there is value in getting people to pay attention to you and what you're doing
and how you get them. There
is
-- going to be an interesting ride for
-- sure.
Well, I mean, unless it's literally flouted legal or causing people to explode,
companies will probably do it let alone criminals.
Well, in part of what you said as well at the beginning is good criminals,
smart criminals.
They do things that aren't illegal yet.
And so there's going to be activity that is
happening now with social media and grabbing your attention
that is going to become illegal someday.
Right. Exactly.
Assuming they don't make enough money doing it to just make it legal.
Well, not really? Right. Like, I mean,
that's what always blows me about tobacco. Is that again? Classic?
You know, they paid a fine but admitted no wrongdoing.
You know, the tobacco industry paid a fine of hundreds of billions of dollars.
And last I checked,
you can still buy a pack of cigarettes here in Canada and the US and, well,
most of the world for that matter.
I mean, well, this is, I mean,
this is an argument you can make about countless controlled substances, right?
I mean, alcohol is problematic. Tobacco is problematic.
There's,
I, I'm, I don't want to dwell on this, but actually I,
I like to point at Portugal where Portugal was having a substantial drug problem
and they just made everything legal and the problem kind of went away
-- and did they legalize
-- it or decriminalize
it? I don't know which day.
-- I think that's a good question.
-- They decriminalized it. They did not legalize it.
So there's a subtle difference that I, I'm, I'm not qualified to explain.
But I know in Canada, for example, we legalized marijuana,
like when you buy marijuana now it has a federal tax stamp on it.
Like it comes in a package with, well, like a cigarette with a tax stamp on it and,
you know,
you go to the Alberta Gaming Liquor Commission website
if you want to buy the stuff online.
And, and so, I mean,
using this argument as well and we'll try to tie it all together is so,
I mean, you could argue that
looking at crap memes on Reddit all day is bad for people.
-- And it probably is,
-- I think the challenge is, it's like junk food,
junk food once in a while.
Fine. But if all you eat is junk food, you end up.
Well,
there was a report yesterday about the US where something like 25% of
young people can't qualify for the military because they're so out of shape.
And that in general, this, this terrible diet in the US, for them, like a lot,
a vast majority of people is becoming such a problem.
It's, it's feeding the health care issues. It's like it's causing real problems
and, you know, if you eat a Big Mac once a week, sure. But if you eat a Big Mac every day
for every meal,
well, you remember, yeah, the, the super size me guy where his doctors,
like your liver is turning into pate,
you know?
And I mean,
this is, this is difficult, right? Is, how do you, how do you draw the lines?
How do you say what's good or bad?
And
you're, you're right. If all I do is read Reddit all day, every day.
If all I do is read Facebook all day, every day, that is clearly bad for me.
If I read it sometimes,
-- maybe you could argue. It's not bad for me either.
-- Either adults have
agency and are allowed to kind of do what they want within, you know, some limits,
like you're not allowed to run red lights, we frown upon that.
But
generally speaking,
either adults have agency and get to make choices and
live with the consequences of those choices or they don't.
And there are some corner cases where we've outlawed some
things and behaviors because they just are so terrible.
We are, we are out of time.
But I want to,
I want to end on this thought and we could maybe pick this up at a future date is
I agree with you that saying adults have the ability to make choices
is
a valid argument.
But I would, I would counter that with in the world of, of social media and attention
things are being done to us to subvert our ability to choose.
And that is difficult.
Well, just like engineered foodstuffs that trick our tongue.
Very similar. Yes.
And there are,
there are always going to be people who have the
ability to step back and say this is not ok.
I don't like what's happening here and there's
all there's going to be another group of people
that it is, it is like a sickness to them that they cannot escape.
And this is true of drug addiction. It's true of food addiction.
It's, it's pick a thing
and there's always going to be a subset of people like that.
But in the case of attention economies,
they are weaponizing these behaviors in people for their own benefit,
which is horrifying.
Well,
and what's amusing is there are browser extensions or DNS services
that literally have profiles to like block you from accessing social
-- media while you're trying to get your work done.
-- Oh, cool.
Nice. All right.
Anyway, I'm going to call this because this is a weird meta episode band.
I love it.
I guess the moral of the story is stop
wasting your time and go do something productive.
Instead of listening to this podcast.
-- Wait,
-- no, they should listen to more podcasts. Well,
that we can win the internet, help us win the internet everyone. That's what we need,
right? Like what is it like and subscribe?
Oh, yeah.
Hit that like and subscribe button,
right? Anyway. All right, cool. I'm going to call this. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you.
Everyone who made it this far. You have a, a
fortitude. I do not. I think
so.
-- I know it's
-- good.
You go to over
to security podcast.com. Hit up our show notes to
the
pound
podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media. K
-- Have a fantastic rest of your
-- day.
You too, everybody. Thanks.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye,
the