Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 47 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
You chuckle because this is like, take two here.
I've, I've given up on trying to work with garage band for recording,
but that's another story and, and the world is on fire while, while I'm screwing
around
on.
-- That's true. Actually, everything is kind of better now, isn't it?
-- Yeah. Yeah.
A guy accidentally fixed it.
Yeah. That's always nice when people accidentally fix things. I appreciate that.
So, anyway, for the sake of posterity,
why don't you explain what on earth we're talking about?
So, for those of you who I guess, don't read any tech news.
Well, no.
And there's those of the listeners from the future, like, hello, 27th century,
you found this buried somewhere and
you've given up on any hope for this race of humans
as
they
-- exist today. But
-- anyway,
still vulnerable.
Yeah. So there was a, there was a nasty worm that went around the internet,
especially showing that it was a crypto locker
worm that then demanded $300 worth of Bitcoin.
But the thing is it was exploiting a vulnerability in Windows.
That is uh well, it's essentially, it's a well known vulnerability,
Microsoft fixed it back in March of 2017 with MS 17-010.
And it's basically one of those flaws.
It's like it's as bad as it gets for Windows, right? It's a
remote code execution flaw in the windows, server message block.
So the file sharing bits uh version one
now that's on by default, right? With
that's installed and on by default on
all the things because
that, I mean windows file sharing, that's something everybody uses basically.
Yes.
Anyway, so the real problem though is that there was that NSA
uh dump of exploit tools
and there was a weaponized version of the exploit for this flaw.
Now we should also clarify that the issue was fixed before the dump was released.
Yes.
And so this weaponized exploit um is especially dangerous in that there's,
there's a lot of exploits for vulnerabilities that are, you know,
more proof of concept, right?
Like it actually will
trigger the exploit but then just cause the, you know,
the program or the system to crash, right?
It doesn't actually cause code execution because
there's actually quite a few protections.
Now on a modern system, you know, with like um a dress stack lay
randomization. And you know,
all these different tricks that we use to essentially make it hard
even if you get code execution to actually properly exploit it,
you know, and get what you want.
Um But in this case, there was a fully weaponized exploit in the NSA dump,
which basically means that the attacker
just kind of had to take their existing worm kit and, you know,
plug the exploit into that framework and away they go.
Right. Which is kind of crazy if you think about it.
Well, I mean, there's been these worm kits selling now for,
oh jeez, it's, it's over 20 years now.
Um, and I know back in the day, like some of them had 24 7 email support out of Russia,
you
know, they still do.
Oh, yeah.
And they would have announcements like, you know,
now with like ebay fake email support and like now with, you know,
um anyways,
so this, this exploit was really bad because it basically affected
every single version of Windows that is currently in support and
basically all the versions that are not supported like Windows XP.
And so like, as it turns out,
like we all knew there's a lot of Windows XP out there still.
And,
you know, by definition, Windows XP is, has not been getting security patches for,
what is it?
Two or three years now?
And, and
I heard
that they released a patch for
-- this.
-- They actually,
well, I mean, from a public good point of view, they, they,
I don't even think it's a public, good point of view.
I think it's a
apr point of view
because
let's face it. If you're running XP, you have tons of other problems affecting you.
Well, yeah, I mean, the thing is if you're running windows XP, this is going to happen
again and again and again, it's just a matter of time,
right? Because there will be more flaws.
Uh, some of which, you know, will be exploitable and some of which will have
weaponized, exploit code. And, you know,
the problem now is that by exploiting this fly, you know,
this guy made some real money.
You know,
people have been monitoring the Bitcoin wallets that the money was sent to.
Yeah, they, a lot of people paid the 300 bucks because let's face it right.
For most places,
you know, if you don't have good backups of your system,
once you got backups, it's gonna cost you more than $300 to restore those backups.
Totally.
So,
yeah, so the good news is this guy who was on his week off, um, accidentally fixed it
accidentally,
you know, it's not every day you fix a worm, like just in general and, and
I don't know if anyone's ever accidentally fixed a worm before
which makes it hilarious.
Well, and especially a worm that was doing this well, like this thing was, I mean,
apparently, you know, all of the NHS, uh, fedex, uh, Telefonica
-- Banks,
-- you
wanna
know something really funny. So, when
I, I was, I was in Europe,
and I was on an airplane and I land and you sent me a message saying, holy crap, what,
what's going on with this worm?
And I thought, what, what are you talking about?
Like, I don't know it because I kind of had a media black out there for a while
and you, you just said check Twitter and that's when I knew it was gonna be bad
and I opened up the Twitter client and it's bad.
And then I remember thinking I was sitting in the airport and I thought
I have one more flight to get home.
I hope this thing doesn't hit the airlines because I don't want to be stuck here.
And that was,
-- that was my first thought and, and thank goodness
-- you
-- air systems
-- and whatnot. I'm certain it did.
But luckily for me, it did not prevent me from getting home.
So if it did get at the airlines, it obviously didn't shut down anything critical.
And actually, I mean, that's a great instance. Right.
Where if it costs the airline $300 to make it go away or they can literally probably
spend tens of millions of dollars missing flights
and things like that to restore from backups.
That's a no
brainer. Right.
Well, I mean, the good news is they're hopefully not using windows XP on the back end,
you
know, and if they have windows on the back end, they're hopefully patching it.
No, they're, they're probably using windows 95 on their back end.
-- Yeah. But uh
-- it's true.
But uh no.
So, I mean, this, this, this worm was, you know, it, it was very successful.
Um, but apparently it had a built in kill switch
where basically if you uh registered a certain domain,
it would check for that domain and if the domain exists, it,
it would stop functioning.
Now.
It's interesting to me is this guy found the domain name when he was like doing a,
you know, binary analysis of the worm, right?
He
got the worm code and he's taking it apart and looking at
it.
What's interesting to me is there's, you know,
these thousands of organizations that got clobbered by this worm
and like none of them, for example,
found this or noticed this, that, you know,
these things were all making the same DNS request to this, you know,
uh for this uh one DNS host name,
right?
You know, um which I mean, and, and realistically too,
even if you are recording all your DNS queries and everything,
you, you then have to actually do something with that data and correlate it.
And you know, and if here's part of the problem with incident response,
the your world is literally on fire, everything's falling down,
everything's caught fire.
You don't have time to take the measured,
you know, proper approach.
You're just, you know, you're sticking your finger in the holes as,
as fast as you can.
Right.
You know, I, I would actually compare this to, this is, this is something I actually,
I was talking about this last week with some people but
I, I would compare it to. It's like you're
a bodyguard
in a crowded marketplace
and
your goal is to protect the person. But let's face it. The reality is nobody cares.
And there's really no threat
but there,
there could be one but it is impossible to tell the difference between the
guy with a gun and just the guy trying to sell you a chicken.
Right?
That's the kind of the issue there is how do you figure out which is,
which until of course,
once they pull the gun out and shoot the person you're trying to attack,
it's super obvious who the bad guy was.
But um prior to that, it's very difficult or maybe even impossible.
Well, and this is part of where I think, you know,
what's gonna happen is um places that share and
gather intelligence will start to notice these things.
You know, these things can be noticed. You know,
if you have a cyberattack hitting 1000 sites
and these 1000 sites all have
one dns look up in common,
you know, it's going to be pretty obvious.
Yes. And
you know, I had this conversation also actually
was that
there, there is the,
the current sharing that happens isn't super useful because
it lacks kind of that next level of correlation.
That you need to do this
because, right, like one random DNS request,
not impressive
million.
Right. Exactly.
And, and let's face it.
If you visit any website,
it's gonna load like 25 bazillion ads from crazy looking domains.
So why would this one be different?
Well, and it's funny, I mean, so not to, you know,
completely plug a commercial product, but this is something that, you know,
we've been working with at the, the Cloud Security Alliance,
this platform called True Star.
And one of the main things that this platform does that a
lot of others don't is it allows you to anonymously share,
right? And that's one of the biggest things, right?
Is, is a lot of people kind of want to share
but they don't want to share
their data explicitly and, you know, and be embarrassed. Right.
That's, that's the other big problem, right? Like,
you know, these, I mean,
I'm sure there's lots more banks that got hit than just the ones that were
listed and lots more phone companies that got hit than the one that was listed,
you know, but they're never gonna like, publicly be like, oh, yeah, by the way,
last weekend, uh, we had a rough time.
Right.
No,
no, I know
exactly what you mean. No, nobody's gonna admit it.
I mean, it, it's embarrassing. Let's face it. Right.
Well, and especially if I wonder now here's a question.
I wonder how many infosec teams or even just operation teams got popped,
paid the Bitcoin
and pretended everything was cool.
-- Probably more
-- than
too
much.
Yeah.
I mean, the,
yeah. No, it's, it's, yeah, it's one of those things.
Well, by definition, if this worm popped you, you,
you're already doing a lot of things.
Not very well,
you know,
you've got either out of date systems or systems that are not being patched,
you know, with patches that came out months ago.
Um
Alternatively,
you know, and this is what's interesting to me is that
this
vulnerability could be easily avoided by just disabling SMBV version one,
which you can very easily do on windows and get away with.
Now,
you cannot disable version two and version
three like that will break everything horribly,
right?
But you can disable version one and that's fine, you know.
-- Well,
-- is that
a
practice? I honestly don't know,
it's,
I was just gonna say if you need backwards compatibility,
don't do it
right? Because there is stuff, well, it's like TLS or SSL, right?
There's still stuff that only speaks the old stuff.
But again, by definition, if you have that old stuff that only speaks the old stuff,
you really want to start thinking about transitioning that thing.
And I get that it's not easy, right?
Like everybody's making fun of the NHS for still using Windows XP.
But, you know, every time I've seen one of these, like,
let's replace all of our Windows systems with something, you know,
it always goes horribly wrong and costs
some ridiculous amount of money.
Right.
I mean, that's just, you know, replacing, you know, everything
-- while it's in motion is not easy.
-- It could be the year of the Linux desktop.
Finally, Kurt.
Right. This is the, this is the time everybody
anyway.
Well, assuming those are like those phones that you plug into a TV, then maybe.
Oh, I
know. I
-- know.
-- But uh
and see that's, that's you were mentioning earlier about the um
Well,
there's been some rumors that maybe
the dump with this vulnerability was intentional
and not like an actual attack that got a bunch of good stuff.
Uh What not. OK. No, no, I don't.
That, that doesn't make sense to my brain right now and it's possible it's just me.
But so here's
what, what I was making
it
was
leaked.
Well, well, so the NSA had an issue.
Shadow Brooker got a hold of some stuff and this was in one of the leaks,
but the
Microsoft fixed this
not a long time before the shadow brokers leak.
And obviously the NSA was aware
that certain,
well, certain tools they had had been leaked.
And so there are some conspiracy theories,
I've read that say basically the NSA knew it got stolen and told Microsoft, hey,
uh we know about this bug, you better fix it
and then Microsoft fixed it. And then shortly after the shadow brokers leaked
and it's not outside the realm of possibility.
It could just be a coincidence, it's hard to say, right?
Because I mean, and part of the challenge as well is when you have a tool like this,
as soon as you use it,
you risk run the risk of burning it because there are
organizations that literally log every single piece of traffic they receive.
Well, yeah, I mean, storage is cheap now and you know,
even one or 10 gigabits per second is
actually not that much data if you only have to keep, say 30 days of it.
Yeah.
You know,
um
Yeah, so II I,
yeah, I don't know about that obviously, but
in my mind, it's pretty obvious that, you know, uh the NSA is not stupid
and, uh, you know, generally speaking, I guess they would probably have,
I'm guessing they have a spreadsheet somewhere that,
you know, has some numbers and some formulas for like essentially,
you know, if we find this flaw, do we, do we use it? Do we tell somebody, do we ignore it?
-- You know,
-- that is,
we could probably discuss that topic for days and never come to a resolution.
So, so actually I do have a thought on that, that, that I was mulling over
earlier today.
In fact,
is these days I think regardless of what you do
and this includes three letter organizations around the world.
It is clear everyone is compromised.
And so I think if you're sitting on top of something like this,
I'm not gonna say it's wrong for these organizations to use it or not.
And that's up to the, the listener to decide for themselves.
But I think it's safe to say that
if you sit on it for too long,
the, the little graph of, of odds, someone else knows about this,
it approaches 100%. I suspect in less than one year.
I would disagree.
Only because we've seen flaws that have taken a long time to come out.
Well, that, yeah.
Does
anyone know about it?
Well, there, there have been, um,
Linux flaws that were like, you know,
brutally obvious in hindsight that have been there for years, you know.
Yeah.
No, I, I mean, I know, I, I think there have been some, but again,
does the NSA have a bunch of guys reading the Linux kernel mailing list?
-- I would assume so
-- if they don't, they're fools. But,
-- yeah,
-- because that's, that's like free gold. Granted.
You got to go through a lot of chaff but it is.
And just because you have people reading that mailing list.
So it doesn't necessarily mean there aren't. I mean, let's face it.
Every piece of software has egregious
bugs waiting to be found.
You don't. It's kind of like I always love when people joke about,
oh, you know, that they need to pay someone to put a back door in the software and
no you know what? It's a lot easier to just read the code and find the bugs.
Let, let's face it
because everything is, is basically broken. But
no, I don't know.
This is,
this is an interesting one to think about and I'm certainly
not gonna take any sort of public opinion because II,
I think there's too much nuance for me to really have a, a
proper judgment here.
Well, and not just nuance but there's all sorts of weird legalities involved.
Well, I mean, that's fair too. It's, I, I do enjoy living in my civilized country
where, where I like to think these people are, are fighting the good fight.
So
anyway, we, we will not dwell there.
I think here's, here's the thing I really keep thinking about
in terms of this, this war
is
you're gonna have people who talk about. Well, why didn't you patch your systems?
Ok. And
I, I don't disagree with that necessarily, but this is an ongoing
problem
that has come up again and again and again
for as long as I can remember now,
and I feel like if people actually were going to take it seriously,
they would have been patching their systems properly 10 years ago.
But it keeps happening over and over and over again.
And I remember like when this all started, people were saying on Twitter, oh,
finally everything is going to change and you know what?
I don't think anything's going to change
well, or ignore patching for a minute.
People still running Windows XP, which is now out of support for two or three years.
And the reality is there was some really good comments on Reddit where this one
I was like, yeah, we still have a bunch of Windows XP systems
to do wire transfers, millions of dollars a day worth of wire transfers.
That's horrifying.
And this software we, well,
I guess they don't have the budget to replace it because I mean,
obviously there's got to be wire transfer software that runs on Windows eight or 10.
But fundamentally, you know,
one of the banks I use, for example,
doesn't have the pin pads at the tellers.
They only have only one of the tellers has a pin pad and it's a cost cutting measure.
So what they do do is they ask for ID when you do a transaction, right?
One of my other big banks I deal with, it's a bigger bank.
Every teller has a pin pad, right?
And you put your debit card or your credit card in you type in your pin, right?
And it talks to their computer and it says like this is curtsey fried and blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, right?
And they don't ask for ID.
But this other bank basically to save money because, you know,
they would need several 1000 pin terminals
for every single one of their workstations.
You know, they just ask for ID,
which I also kind of appreciate because the reality is, you know,
somebody walks into a random branch with my debit card and pin
number that they beat out of me with a lead pipe.
-- No problem.
-- Why would they even go to a branch? They could just go to an ATM.
Right.
ATM has withdrawal limits.
Oh, but the, the teller doesn't.
But I would, I would hope if someone's asking for, you know,
thousands of dollars they ask for some ID.
Uh, I don't know. But anyways point being,
you know,
test that and find out because if they let you withdraw,
-- send
-- me some
thousands of dollars so I can
play this out because that's, I, I feel like there's step one, there's a little flaw,
-- let,
-- let, let's kick, start it.
Right.
Yeah. No fun.
Um, see what happens when Kurt asks for a big pile. Right.
But, uh, no, or somebody else was pointing out Hipaa compliance. Right.
There's all these things that,
on the one hand you're out of HIPAA compliance by running Windows XP.
But on the other hand,
you know, you've got this like
machine that does something and only talks to Windows XP.
What, what do you do? Right.
-- Replace the million dollar machine. You get
-- a waiver
and then everything's fine
and ideally stick a little firewall in front of it.
But apparently a lot of people didn't,
well, even, even if you have a firewall, I mean,
once this thing gets inside your network.
Well,
it actually
-- for the actual device. Right.
-- I see.
-- I understand what you're saying now,
-- but some of them again,
you can't do that because you have to share out for the
-- work.
-- Right.
It's,
it's tough, man.
And I, well, ok, so here's, I guess my, my real thoughts on this is first of all,
the concept of zero trust networking is real
and if you're not thinking about it,
you're making foolish architectural mistakes.
I think the reality is, it's not that it's,
it's not so much that it's real. It's, it's
provably where we are today.
Yes. Right. And that's actually true. It's not coming. It's here.
Right. Here's the reality. Right. You send,
uh,
you have a company with 1000 people
on a network.
It only takes one of them to open up that email and click that attachment.
Right.
Yep. Yep.
Absolutely.
You know, and, and again,
there was that Reddit thread that I tweeted out where this guy was like, lamb.
He's like, oh, a small medium business, this idiot user, like,
opened up their email and opened up an attachment
and, like, infected the network with this thing. And I'm like,
yeah, I mean,
because we've spent like the last 20 years teaching users like you get emails.
Oh, but don't open emails from an untrusted source. So they don't.
But, you know,
this email came from Bob who I email with
daily and he sends me attachments because like,
their invoices or whatever the heck they are.
And this invoice looked a little weird but no biggie and I opened it and oops.
Yeah, then
-- you know,
-- whatever face it too. I mean, any good fish
is often attacking someone else's address book.
And so you obviously already have that connection if you're
on their address book.
Well,
and more to the point my take on this
would be no wonder everybody hates it because like,
shouldn't it be safe to open an attachment on
my computer and not have something truly horrible happen?
Like, shouldn't that either be blocked because it's a virus or sandboxed or,
you know, it should be.
I mean, the reality is I am a security guy and I open attachments from my email.
Now,
granted I take some rather ridiculous measures sometimes when it's from somebody,
I don't know, but
generally speaking, I mean, I can't
not open attachments in email.
Well, you don't have to anymore. You just open this cramp in Google Docs now.
-- Exactly.
-- It's Google's,
you know, and, and, and I do do a lot of that, like I, I'll say like,
I'll save it to Google Docs and then open it there because, you know,
the hope being is if this like hostile PDF somehow manages to break
out of Google Docs into my web browser and compromise my system through that
nobody's willing to burn that many zero days to take over my system.
At
that point, it'd be cheaper to just, like, drive to your house and kidnap you and fly
-- country.
-- Give me a suitcase full of money.
Seriously. How
many, again, how many of you users wouldn't take $10,000 to do, like, plug a USB,
drive into the network?
And that, I mean, that's part of it as well. Right.
Is, you can't, we can't protect this stuff. We just can't.
I mean, that's the reality of it. Right. It,
well, it's like physical protection.
If somebody really wants to throw a brick at your window,
they, they will.
Yeah. Right.
And,
and I guess funny enough though is we always
complain about how people are the weakest link and,
and people had nothing to do with this, this worm.
We, we, any way you look at it, it's, it's doom everywhere.
I love it.
Yeah.
Well, and the other thing that really worries me is again, this guy on his week off,
found the domain registered.
It stopped the worm and we have all these
cert teams and all these law enforcement teams and,
like, you know, I'm really beginning to look
at certain teams and law enforcement teams and I'm beginning to kind of wonder
they do some good coordinating work and they do some really good work, you know,
tracking bad guys down
on certain networks and stuff.
But for something like where it's happening fast and happening, you know,
rapidly like this,
I don't think
-- they're capable of handling it well, or very few people are
-- ok.
So, I think there's a couple levels to what you just said and, and first of all
this guy got lucky.
Right. It's not like he tried
to necessarily shut the worm down. It's just he happened to find this
and thought I'm gonna register this domain. Honestly. He probably registered
it in hopes there'd be some sort of like,
awesome thing that happened later on because of it.
Right.
And, and,
or
some sort of command and control thing, at least then you can black hole it or
Microsoft, look at it. Ok.
So, so there's that aspect of it, right? But then if we think about these
kind of cert teams in law enforcement and all that stuff is,
first of all the amount of noise these people are going to have is
out of control.
Yeah. But you don't think every single major vendor security team
wasn't looking at this worm in the last 48 hours.
Ok. We're going to get to that.
I mean,
they, they were, but here's the thing, the reality is
it's really hard to do this kind of work.
And if I had to guess,
I bet there's
at most a couple 100 people on the planet who are
capable of actually doing it right and doing it well.
And so it's
there, there isn't,
most organizations might think they have the ability to do that sort of thing.
And they don't
and they might have staff who even think they can do it,
but they don't
because
-- it's, it's so complicated and so detailed
-- often.
What's interesting to me is is if you look at some of these cyber challenges,
people have put up like uh the cert cyber challenges or uh the def
con ones or whatever,
some of them are easily as complicated as this thing.
And quite a few people manage to pull those challenges off.
But again, they're not,
they're not running that time. Constraint or like, oh my God, the world's on fire.
This is, this is like
when, when someone is shooting like, like for example, military, right?
You, you can train all day long,
but as soon as someone starts firing a gun at you while you're doing the thing,
you need to do,
all the rules are gone and you don't know what to do.
And, and in fact, I just had this conversation with my kids today.
So I was driving down the street
and
I get to a, a roundabout,
right?
Or
traffic circle for, for some of you,
whatever. I still love the word roundabout.
You have those uh where you live. I thought America hated them.
-- Uh
-- Many do and I hate those people,
but that's another story.
Uh
So anyway, anyway, get, gets to the roundabout
and there's a guy in a truck in front of me
and he's not going
and there's nothing in in, in the circle and I'm thinking,
what's wrong with this idiot?
Right.
And all of a sudden I hear a siren behind me and I look in the mirror
and there's an ambulance behind us
and the ambulance, like,
you can't get through because that's just how these things work.
And I'm like,
and I'm thinking, yeah, well, you're right. This one was the one that,
and, you know, you know how they are, they like, set it up.
So you like, the cars can only go in one direction and stuff
and there's only, that's
generally held traffic circles.
I
know,
but I've,
I've seen in like the UK where they just have like,
nice painted things because people are civilized
enough to actually do the right thing.
-- Not like a giant,
-- like, like, not like concrete barrier things to
sure you cannot screw it up even though I've seen people screw that up that whatever.
And, and so anyway, this guy, obviously he froze when he saw the siren and of course,
the ambulance pulls up and finally just starts talking.
It's horn like crazy. And this
pull over to the side of the road, get out of the way. But
-- there was
-- no, there was nothing to pull over on, right? Like in a traffic circuit.
You, you just get out of the circle. That's the answer, right?
You don't stop in the middle and be like, now what? Right.
So anyway,
the point is though this is totally like fight or flight kind of where there,
there are certain people and, and, well, I, I'm sure it could happen to anybody but
something like that happens and you just freeze and you don't know what to do.
And so you do nothing.
And I would imagine in a lot of instances where you, you know,
you're an infosec team or something and you might be very talented.
But if you,
if you lack the experience and the training to
understand how to do this work under pressure,
you're useless.
I mean, that's true.
I mean, II I see this, you know, come across, well,
having done over 5000 CV si meet people who
are like seriously panicking about something and I'm like,
no big,
right? Well, you know, I mean,
man, I remember this dealing with like zero day flaws or, or when
something crazy happens or there's like some super crazy critic
issue that comes out is
the new guys are always like running around in circles on fire
and, and it's like I've done this enough times before that.
It's cool guys just chill out and we'll let the grown ups work, ok?
We'll take care of this.
Well, it's, it's part of it is having that perspective and you know, like, yeah,
we've done this in the past.
We know what happens
and what's always interesting to me is, you know,
we think these things that are like fresh and hot are going
to like blow up in our face and be just a massive mess
and they do sometimes,
you know, once in a while they really do blow up.
Um,
but quite often, you know, it's, it's well after the fact that the poop hits the fan,
you know, like, and this is a
good example of it, like two months, three months later,
Kabui, you know, like
from my understanding is there's,
there's entire countries that got like bushwhacked by this.
And somebody mentioned, you know, Chinese manufacturing,
which I I find really fascinating because let's let's face it, right?
Chinese manufacturing, you know, these guys cut corners and do it cheap,
right? That they're good at that, right? They do a lot with very little
and chances are they have
more than a little bit of windows XP floating around
or just windows servers in general like hooked up to
ska
systems or manufacturing systems or,
or just the front or back office systems or whatever, right?
And you know, my my real thought was like, is this,
you know, are we going to see like a 1% hit to Chinese manufacturing this month?
You know, I bet not because you know what, they're going to pay the 300 bucks
well, or they're just, you know,
they're so used to stuff pooping out that they'll just be like, sure whatever
it was like reading an article they were pointing out that in India,
you know,
people live with daily power interruptions. That's normal. That's the default.
So it's just not a big deal because they all have generators and UPSS and everything.
Whereas, like, you look at a place like North America. Right.
And you cut the power to say a downtown core for half an hour, an hour.
Oh, what a mess.
Like
it's the end of the world.
Yeah.
You know, but that, that kind of stuff is normal in certain parts of the world,
like very industrial parts of the world,
you know.
And so,
yeah, I mean,
I, I don't know the answer here because the reality is, you know,
anybody that should have moved off of windows XP would have by now by definition,
like they've had years.
And so if they haven't moved off of it, then clearly
they have some good reason not to,
you know,
budget or availability or whatever
and, and clearly there, you know, we can't, basically, we can't tell people, oh,
you should patch quickly because again,
if they were going to patch in a timely manner they would have,
they would have done it 10 years ago.
I mean, this has been an ongoing problem and it's quite frankly,
as long as we have people running their own systems, they aren't going to patch them.
That's the reality of it.
It's,
yeah, it just is what it is.
This is.
And, and then on the flip side, which is kind of painful, like so I look at things like,
you know, um what is it, the, like the zero trust networking and stuff.
And I,
that's how I've kind of built my network and
how I live my life now because quite frankly,
most of my devices are mobile and they float around,
you know, sometimes they're at home, sometimes they're at the coffee shop,
you know, once in a while I might go to defcon or something
and, um, or go through customs,
you know,
there's
no,
seriously, I'm way more scared of them than I am
totally.
Well, or, you know, with the theoretical laptop ban on all flights from
life. I mean,
it's gonna be so much worse than
people can imagine because,
well, but the,
well, and here's, but here's the really ugly thing.
It's not just that you won't have your tablet or your laptop on the plane.
I won't have it in the terminal.
-- So, not only do you not have it while you're flying but on the two hours before,
-- well,
and screw that even, that doesn't concern me the fact that I've got, like, some,
some,
it's out of my possession and
goodness knows what's happening. I mean, honestly, if they do this, I'm just gonna,
truckers alone are a problem, let alone an actual attacker.
Right. Yeah. Right. That's the thing.
And so I figured, like, if this happens, honestly,
I might just go to where I'm going and buy like, a $200 chromebook and then, like,
like, pawn it before I leave and be, like, whatever.
-- I
-- suspect that's going to become a bit of a thing because
there's a lot of people who legally aren't allowed to have their,
like, laptop out of their sight for, like, 12 hours.
-- That's true.
-- You know,
in certain industries, just
anybody in fintech, anybody. Well,
like, I, I,
I mean, seriously there's,
you know, and,
and the thing is you can encrypt your hard drive and you can do all that stuff.
But
there's, you know, if I have physical access to your machine for five minutes,
there's all sorts of shenanigans.
Like,
totally, man. Absolutely.
-- You
-- know.
Um,
but, and, and ignoring all that,
just the productivity hit of not having a laptop for like, 8 to 12 hours
when you
travel.
That,
that's ridiculous.
I can
read
-- nothing.
-- Well, I'm guessing maybe this will be really good for airport bars.
Uh, they seem to do fine as it is.
Yeah.
But, uh,
no, so, going back to this, I mean, the, the reality is
by definition, the world we live in is this way for some very good reasons. You know?
And then we,
and it's not gonna be easy or quick to fix unless
somebody comes up with some super clever solution that everybody's like,
-- wow, that's clearly better. Let's do that.
-- Yeah. It's called software as a service.
Although I guess here's,
here's one of the things I was actually thinking about though, on this note is
so obviously,
software as a service is becoming really hip and a lot
of people are using it and like you look at something,
we'll say Google
and there's the G suite and all that stuff
and, and they do a very nice job and I don't have to worry about updates.
It's just kind of magic.
But now,
but now here's the thing that I think about is
as software as a service becomes more important and more used,
there are going to be way more software as a service providers,
which means there's going to be some
that don't patch
and we're gonna end up in this situation again,
except now we have even less control than we do today.
Yeah. So the good news there and again, not to plug the CS A too, too much.
But the CS A has a program for that called Stars,
you know, where essentially it's like, oh,
what 200 question give or take or maybe more now, I don't know.
Um, but this like massive questionnaire that people fill out.
Uh, you can also, so you can have self attestation, you know,
where we basically trust the provider to what I said.
What they said is correct.
They can also be audited for it.
You know, they can undergo an audit to prove that what they said is correct.
And essentially they, they attest to things like this.
Like we have physical security. Right.
Like how many services and software providers have really good physical security.
You know, how many of them
actually properly destroy media when they, when the hard drive dies,
most of them probably run in Aws.
Yeah,
or whatever, you know,
um, how many of them encrypt at rest, how many of them encrypt in transit?
You know, where are they actually physically located?
Which jurisdiction, you know,
after the whole safe harbor debacle.
Um,
and again, you know, this basically boils down to is
us.
Hopefully these companies mature, the mature ones will take on security as,
you know, being a serious thing.
Like
Microsoft is a great example, right?
Microsoft used to be absolutely terrible at security 20 years ago.
Like they were the joke of the industry
and now it's like, oh, you know what, this is really bad.
Let's drop an, you know, let's drop a patch for XP even though it's out of support
and here's a patch and not only that, but the patch was pretty quick.
Uh, sure.
But here's, well, honestly if I guess, I bet it's very similar code base if it's S MD V.
Well,
I'm guessing they already had the patch because I
think there are some customers that are still paying
lots of money to get XP like updates.
I know the NHS was for like two more years.
Um,
but yeah, like you said, they might have had it waiting in the wings and just like, ok,
now we actually should release it publicly.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And,
and I'm hopeful the things you've described about stars
can make a difference for software as a service because
my, my biggest fear
and, and today I believe it's kind of the answer to many of these problems.
But my biggest fear is that it eventually
ends up with very similar problems to this. Just because
once you, once you become a certain scale,
things start to get weird.
And like today where it's very like the,
there's a handful of really big Softwares of service companies
and, and they seem to get it right.
And,
and I don't know that that's what really just scares me today.
I mean, that's, you know, I look at Google and one of the reasons I use Google is they,
they seem to be really on the ball for security.
And then, you know, you, well, there was that incident a week ago,
apparently one of my users had one of their uh, passwords exposed.
So I get this email from the Google
security team saying basically we found one of your
cre.org users
in a password dump,
go deal with it.
And they gave me specifics go change their password. And
very importantly to remember which a lot of people won't including myself,
probably
check their email forwarding rules,
right? Because maybe somebody went into their account
and changed, you know, set up their email to forward to them so that,
you know, their, their two fa, or their password resets or whatever, you know. Boom.
Some dude in Russia can fiddle with it,
you know, and so forth this user, you know,
I forced them on to two factor authentication and everything and, you know, and,
and so did, uh, you know,
it doesn't look like anything truly malicious happened
and it doesn't look like it was a,
you know, a, a significant password that got dropped.
Um, but yeah, I mean, basically
-- Google seems to be taking a lot of proactive security.
-- Oh,
they totally are.
And they're,
they're amazing. I mean, you look at things like project Zero
and it's, it's chrome.
Yeah. Right. Chrome
is fan. Even chromebooks, man. Chrome
is like they, they did a lot of that. Right. And it's amazing.
It's
so,
I, I think there is hope for the future and,
but the problem is gonna be is that even if only
1/10 of a percent of the world runs out of date g
garbage stuff,
that's millions of devices.
Well, we haven't even gotten to IOT yet.
Oh, that's gonna be such a horror show.
And honestly, I think the only solution for IOT is brick worms.
That's,
that's the only thing that's going to force people to
update is when they get their light bulbs bricked.
I know. I know. I, I think it's terrible.
I don't want to advocate for it, but at the same time I don't see another solution
and I know that's the least horrible thing that, that could result in it.
It's, well, until you're like, you know, um, in Anchorage,
Alaska and it's January and all your light bulbs stop working.
Yes.
Or your furnace.
I bet the furnace would be swelled.
Honestly, this is why I'll never buy an IOT furnace controller.
I just can't not have heat in January.
I live in Canada.
You know, this, like $30 thermos, uh, thermostat furnace control. I have, you know,
doesn't talk to anything. It's super simple.
No, I know exactly what you mean.
I, I have a similar thing where I know some people who are saying, oh,
you should get a nest thermostat.
I just kept thinking this,
this thing I have uses like literally a little piece of mercury, I think to,
to turn things on.
I mean, it's not gonna break,
it's not gonna wear out. Um,
is,
-- does my name, I don't think, I don't know
-- what my name,
the old style ones have. Mercury.
The new, anything made in the last, like 1020 years.
-- It definitely does not. No,
-- I think I, I think I've replaced it.
No, I did, I did replace it and it had a mercury one in it
-- that
-- spring. I got rid of
a B
meal
metal strip with the mercury bubble thing.
-- It worked
-- really well. What's
totally, I mean,
other than having deadly mercury inside.
-- But,
-- well, more to the point, you know, not being super accurate.
So, like 72 here is not anyways
though.
I grew up with that and the whole house being cool anyways it was. And now I'm the dad.
So it's like I'm a total fascist about it.
-- I,
-- I used to be, I've, I've given up, I'm like, you know what? I just don't even care.
I mean,
here's the thing I realized is one day I kind of sat down and figured some of this out is
when I'm a thermostat fascist, I'm,
you know, turning it down and whatnot.
I'm literally saving like $20 for quite frankly, misery.
It's not about saving the money. It's about just control.
I cared about the money. I'm,
I, I meticulously track my finances and then I finally, I'm like, 20 bucks, like,
-- for real, I'll just like,
-- well, the same thing I had with email attachment sizes,
right.
Like the defaults were usually around 10 megs
and I bumped it up on all the list servers to like 25 or 50.
And worst case scenario I was like, this is going to cost us like three bucks a month.
I just don't care anymore.
And, yeah, people should use dropbox or Google Drive or whatever. But you know what?
I can't be bothered to care.
I can't be bothered to care. That's exactly what got us into this in the first place.
Yeah,
pretty much.
Well,
and, you know, here's the thing as bad as this was.
Even if it hadn't been kill switch, the world keeps moving along.
Granted the NHS, you know, hopefully nobody died because of this because, I mean,
a lot of people missed their surgeries and, like, emergency treatment was down.
That's gonna cost, like, I mean, that is a huge productivity hit.
That's,
it's probably in the tens of millions of dollars for Britain alone for the NHS.
You know, the thing else, I, I, the thing I really keep thinking about here is
if it hadn't been kill switched, it might have gotten bad enough to make people care.
But I guarantee at this point
nobody's gonna care. This is,
this is an asterisk on the bottom of a crazy 2017
by Monday, we'll have moved on to whatever, uh,
something new and crazy
by
Monday.
It's a crazy world.
It's, it's the world we built Kurt.
It is literally that. Yes.
Oh my goodness.
So I guess, you know, here's the other thing I keep thinking of here is if,
if you were going to give people advice,
offline backups, I was thinking about this
and the only security advice I think I
can reasonably give anybody again at this point
is to have
some form of offline backup.
And when I say offline backup,
I don't actually necessarily mean like a
USB drive that you keep physically offline.
It could be, for example, like something like say Google drive or, you know,
icloud where, even if you delete stuff, you can still recover it.
Essentially, you need some form of backup solution
that even if an attacker gets your credentials and goes in
there and like nukes everything or encrypts it or whatever,
you can still get it, your data and like, recover it from a previous time and point.
-- And that's all I got.
-- That's it. No, I, I agree completely.
And that's actually where the, the cloud backups are vastly superior because
I used to do a bunch of shenanigans with local hard drives and,
and keeping some off site and various things like that.
And now Google Drive or not Google Drive, I'm sorry. Uh Now S3
has the ability to upload data
and
when you upload or no,
no, no, I mean, when you upload or delete
a file
it, you can snapshot it and store it for some period of time.
And so, for example, I might set up now that if, if a file changes or is deleted,
it keeps the older revision around for 100 days.
So obviously, even if like somebody came in, deleted all my stuff,
I still have that revision.
I basically have 100 days to restore my backup at that point.
So it's,
that's fantastic.
Like with the things I was doing with hard drives,
I didn't have anything close to that.
I mean,
at best I'd have a month old backup and that I had off site.
And that's
silly.
Yeah.
The only reason I do local backups is just to restore
the system in case I brick it on an update or
my laptop gets run over and I need to, you know,
restore it because downloading that would take forever.
Exactly. Well, that's the thing too. Right, is I've got,
you know, hundreds of gigabytes of data backed up now.
And, well, that 2 S3 is so cheap that that's quite reasonable.
And by having,
uh I do keep some local data just because I could restore at some
point in time and then update and I maybe only have to download,
you know, tens of gigs instead of hundreds, which would be a huge difference.
I think honestly from, because I was really thinking about that,
what is the like one piece of security
advice we can give people that's actually useful
and I really think it is that whatever it is some sort of,
some sort of backup that is resistant to an attack, even like by you and by that,
I mean, like I've also accidentally deleted the wrong folder.
I mean, I think everybody's done that at some,
of
course,
you know,
and, and so it's not just Attackers but it's like me fat fingering or
whatever, you know, RM hyphen RF space star,
you know, putting a
star between whatever I meant to put in whatever
we've
got. N
and, and so quite frankly, I think that's really the only,
that's like the one useful piece of advice I can give anymore
because everything else is so contextual, uh, so specific and, you know, well,
it depends, you know, that classic,
you know, should I use two fa, or should I use this or whatever? It's like,
you know?
Yeah.
There,
there isn't a great answer to any of this and I don't
think anyone's going to learn any serious lessons from it either.
I mean,
-- and all the
-- lessons, I mean,
we, we already know most lessons around this, but again,
due to whatever economic reasons,
we can't just chuck it all the Windows XP and we can't just patch
five minutes after Microsoft releases
-- in here or we will
-- is
let's think about this.
So you've got
a worm going around infecting these systems for $300. You can make it go away.
If you have an upgraded XP, you're not swimming in cash.
-- So that 300 bucks probably looks pretty good.
-- Right.
I don't want to blame the victim because clearly they
have whatever rational reasons they believe for not doing this.
The problem is society, right?
Society it's your fault.
Well, and also software vendors that, you know,
write software that just doesn't work on newer versions of Windows
or whatever, you know. Like,
yeah,
because I've seen stuff that, like, I've seen D OS programs running on Windows 10,
-- like at the dry cleaners, but
-- at the same time there,
there's newer things your dry cleaner could get,
they just choose not to because they probably don't care.
Well, you got to remember too for a lot of people. Like,
-- what does it cost to train somebody on a new piece of software?
-- Oh, my goodness.
I know. I know exactly what you mean. This is,
this is what I feel like when I, when I give, like, my parents something new
and
it's
like,
-- this is why I
-- made my parents go to an apple ecosystem.
So, like, at least, for example, one thing I love
the buttons on the tablets and the phones are basically in the same location.
That's really nice.
You know, stuff like that matters when you're, like,
trying to teach somebody who's,
you know, I don't want to go through another major technology cycle.
I, I'm done personally and I turn 40 next month and I'm, I'm done. Like, that's it.
No, I, I'm literally at the old crotchety man stage of it. Now.
You
can,
-- well,
-- I, I'm seriously thinking like I
do, I avoid VR or embrace it or just ignore it as long as I can until I have to,
-- ah, it's,
-- it's not super popular yet.
I think you got a few more years before you have to choose.
Yeah.
But I mean,
fundamentally, I mean, it's, yeah, I, I'm already there and I'm, I'm an it guy,
you know, so I can't imagine normal people. It must be hell for them.
I know.
I know. It's,
it's madness
anyway. Anyway,
so I guess in summary,
this was interesting.
It was,
the worm was accidentally shut down.
There is literally no actionable advice we can give out about
it. It just kind of is what it is.
And, and the really, the really terrifying thing though is probably going to be that
I would imagine there's somebody working on a
new version of this ransomware without a kill switch
that we
launched.
And heck, it wouldn't even surprise me if the original author
is gonna re release it at some point.
No,
-- everything old is new again.
-- Everything.
Yeah, everything new is new and everything old is old.
It's
it.
That's the thing I've loved, man is what do you even do about this?
I mean, there's people giving all this advice and making all these claims,
but the reality is just
what do you do?
Honestly myself, I've moved as much of my stuff into major cloud providers as I can.
And that's probably the only, actually that is some action of ability. And
that's the
reason I moved to the Apple ecosystem, right? I buy an Apple laptop, I log in
and it's my laptop. I get all my apps, I get
all my data.
It's it, right? Like
same with my phone. Same with my tablet.
It just magically all that data is there in the icloud.
Yeah,
totally, man.
All right. So anyway, our advice is we have no advice.
So
maybe try a really nice scotch.
There you go.
That, now that I like I can get behind that one, our advice is to buy Scotch or,
or there you go,
get, get $300 worth of Bitcoin.
And in one month, if you haven't spent it on ransomware, purchase a
fine bottle of scotch for yourself. Is your
picture that would actually maybe be a really good way to incentivize teams.
-- That sounds fantastic
-- to
me.
Whatever you don't spend on the ransomware budget you
can buy with you spend on booze and cigarettes.
I love it. That, that's perfect that I there's no better way to end this episode.
Kurt. It's well done.
All right.
Uh
Thank you.
Thank you for listening if you want.
Well, we have a handful of show notes but nothing too exciting.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
We got links to Twitter and Facebook and all those fun
things you want to get a hold of us and,
and make any comments about any of the crazy things
and I guess for nothing else. Thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt.
It was fun as always. And until next time,
-- thank
-- you folks.
And I'm actually looking forward to seeing what changes between this recording and
the release of it with respect to what we know about this form.
-- That is true. That is true.
-- I can't wait. I'm looking forward to that
all Right. Have a good one.
Bye bye.