Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 53 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh
-- Presser. Thought Crime. That's very clever. Well done, sir.
Well, just technically we've been admitting to felonies for the last 52 episodes.
My partner in crime
partner in crime, I understand
your crime. It doesn't necessarily have to be a felony.
Well,
I just over the weekend I learned a
lot about various indictable offenses and what not.
So it's, uh, I like to avoid admitting to anything I should or haven't,
definitely haven't done.
I see, I see that that's
fair. I can totally understand that.
And, and I'm a huge fan of
not telling people anything they don't need to know.
In fact, it's always funny because
whenever my wife and I have like a business dealing
or something or like buying a car or whatever,
she's very willing to give up information
without being prompted for it. And I was like,
stop, stop telling them those
things, you know, they don't need to know that.
And she thinks I'm some sort of paranoid nut,
which
probably because I'm some sort of paranoid nut Yeah.
Yeah, I actually got that comment from one of the other parents at school today.
That's when, you know, you're doing good.
Yeah. So, anyway, so some, there's a,
there's been an interesting development in, I guess, flight software.
Yes. And you promised to explain all of this to me and I have no idea what's going on.
So I will let you take it from here.
Ok. So I'm a classic, like, armchair aviation is,
I guess, is the word aviation
enthusiast. Yeah, there we go.
Um,
so I'm probably basically wrong about everything I'm going to talk about right now.
But having said that so traditionally, uh there's a concept
in software and security in general called security through obscurity,
which basically is to say
that by keeping something secret, it'll help make it more secure.
And
a lot of people hate this principle
-- and a lot of people like
-- this principle, it doesn't work.
Let's just say that.
Ok.
-- Well, at least in software security, it doesn't work security
-- through obscurity,
really doesn't work if you can't change the secret.
So for example, you have a password, the password must be
secret, right? If somebody knows the password, they can log in as you.
But with a password typically, you can change it very quickly and easily.
Obviously, software is like at the opposite end of the easy to change spectrum,
you know,
if, if you're trying to keep your software uh
secure and un viewed
uh while the second it becomes exposed, uh you know, it's going to take you days,
weeks, months, years, decades to rewrite the whole thing.
So, it's just basically, it's not possible really, in most cases,
you know,
I don't even,
I don't even think it's that as much as I think there's, I, I, I've seen two
kind of attitudes here is you've got encryption
where people would say if you don't know the algorithm,
how could you possibly crack it?
And actually if, if you do any sort of research and encrypt analysis, uh yeah, that,
that doesn't matter because they have ways to do this.
And then,
-- and
-- that's the public stuff we know about.
Right.
It's anyway.
And then, then there's
the kind of I'm going to keep my source code a secret.
So the bad guys can't find bugs in it. And I think
the history of windows is kind of the,
the body ridden path that proves that does not work.
-- Right.
-- Well, the reality is there's a lot of security flaws that are trivial to find.
I mean, cross site scripting is a great example, right?
You just plug in random wonky values and uh Boop comes a javascript alert.
That's true. And you generally don't have access to that source code.
Well, look at what Tavis has done, you know,
he was fuzzing Windows defender software and
he apparently got tired. It was very slow on windows.
So he actually ported it over to Linux.
Uh, we'll,
we'll include show notes to that because I don't even want to try and explain that.
Uh, it makes my head hurt when I think about it.
And, um, so, yeah, he's fuzzing Windows Defender on Linux machines and, you know,
he's found,
uh,
I think there was just a new article on the
register with him mentioned from yesterday or the day before.
Yeah.
Yeah, he just released, I think two days ago from when we're recording this, his,
-- his latest Windows defender security problem.
-- Exactly.
So, like, yeah,
clearly you don't need access to the source code to find really nasty flaws.
Um,
and on the flip side, however, I wouldn't say that, like,
just because you're open source means everybody's going to like, look at your code,
find the flaws and fix them.
And that was uh Eric Raymond coined the term Linus's law,
which was what with enough eyeballs, all bugs are shallow and that, uh,
that law is false,
right? That, that is not a law.
The trick
is
nonsense.
Well,
the problem is people have to know that they're looking for bugs and quite honestly,
most of us don't have time to go looking for bugs.
-- We, we're so busy like fixing stuff or
-- even the
man, I mean,
this actually came up just the other day at work where someone basically said, oh,
look what I found.
And I said that's a security issue because of this, this you know,
and then I laid out what,
what would happen and it was a very complicated process and they're like, oh, crap.
I said, you know, security guy ruins it again, you know.
Never fails.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
I, so, yeah, the reality is, um,
I think if you're heavily relying on security through obscurity,
you're probably gonna have a bad time
because quite frankly, the bad guys generally don't need to see it.
-- Even the good guys
-- don't. Yeah, exactly.
Um And the flip side too is, is at some point, you know, everything leaks eventually.
That's true. And that's another story
we can get to after you tell me all about
this airplane because I actually really want to know.
Yeah.
So, ok, so basically, uh apparently
in a pro
this is off of Bru's
blog.
Uh So in a proposed rule by the FAA, it argues that the software in an ors a model E RJ,
that's a uh what does it stand for something?
Regional jet
enterprise, regional jet, whatever
uh model 1 90-300 airplane is secure because it is proprietary. So to quote,
in addition,
the operating systems for current airplane
systems are usually and historically proprietary.
Um And I suspect that's more true for like legal reasons than, and actual like,
you know,
security reasons realistically, um you know,
you don't want your competitors to see your special sauce, right?
Airbus versus Boeing.
Uh Anyways,
therefore, they are not as susceptible to corruption from worms,
viruses and other militias actions
as are.
Well, and of course, I hope to, goodness sake,
none of these are running on Windows XP.
No, they're, they're not actually.
So this part I do know something about because
I've had dealings with the FAA in the past is
when you write software to run on airplanes.
Now,
there's a huge difference between software that runs on
the ground and software that runs in the air,
the stuff on the ground,
there's a bit more leeway and you can
start getting into general purpose operating systems.
But the stuff that's in the air, basically, it has to be,
it, it has to be custom written
because you have to be able to show why every line of code exists in that. And then
basically anytime there's a change,
you have to show exactly why the code is changing
for what reason and it has to be fully documented.
So they,
they literally can take this operating system that's running on an airplane
and they can trace it back to the dude who wrote the first line of code or JT,
I guess, you know, we won't be those guys, but you know what I mean?
It's, they can literally, they can show the history,
they can show the provenance of all of this stuff.
It's crazy how strict it is.
Well, the reality is, planes are really expensive.
Uh Well,
they're expensive but there's also like that whole like people die if it crashes,
right? It's, if your car crashes or stops working,
it could be bad. You may or may not die.
But if the plane stops working, like you're going to die, you know.
Uh but anyways going back to this.
So uh because access to the design details of these proprietary operating
systems is limited to limited to the system developer and airplane integrator.
Some systems installed in the umbrere model E RJ 91 90-3 300 airplane will use
operating systems that are widely used and
commercially available from third party software suppliers.
So I'm assuming that's stuff like the entertainment system or whatever.
Let's hope so.
Um The security vulnerabilities of these operating systems may be
more widely known than the vulnerabilities of proprietor operating systems
that the avionics manufacturer currently use. So
um
I'm gonna say they're not entirely 100% wrong but
they're basically mostly wrong and I think they're wrong.
Probably not for the reasons that
people and you
think they are.
Um
my first comment would be again, you know, back to this whole source code versus like
binary thing is I'm pretty sure if we lease a one of
these jets and like do a uh a memory dump of,
you know, the operating system and everything.
I'm pretty sure somebody like Tavis given
a week could probably find something nasty.
He probably doesn't need a dump of it. You would just need some level of access.
And I'm going to hope now,
although there's that guy who claims he hacked an airplane and made it, like,
turn or something through the entertainment center.
Right.
I think that was debunked.
But the reality is, I know on some models of plane, apparently now they are using
a single physical data bus with essentially V
lands to separate entertainment. And,
-- well,
-- I agree.
Yes and no, because here's the thing,
this is a difficult trade off because on the one hand V
lands and that type of tech technology
is quite well understood and reasonably secure.
And the reality is adding
secondary wiring to a plane. You know, it's going to be at least
several dozen, if not hundreds of pounds of wiring equipment.
And that has a real long term cost on the plane.
Um Air Canada's uh subsidiary Jazz is a great example of this.
So Air Canada has this like cheap flights, thing called jazz.
Uh And they took all the life jackets off all the planes
-- to save weight.
-- Does it never fly over water?
Uh It has to fly within like 20 or 30 minutes of the coast or something.
So, in theory, you can like glide to the beach if like it's,
yeah, basically so that the flight is uh somewhat restricted,
but they're mostly flying over Canada, right?
They're not doing like, uh cross ocean flights.
Um,
but the reality is this like even a cost savings of like 100
pounds over the co over the like life of one of these aircraft
is a lot of fuel
saved,
you know.
Um, so, yeah, it's, I mean, on the one hand I, I am like, oh yeah,
you should just physically separate this all out, but on the other hand, you know,
that's like an extra 100 pounds or 200 pounds of equipment and wiring and everything
and that really does add up especially across a fleet of planes.
Um
But what's really fascinating to me is that
uh reading uh so there's an FAA bulletin
um
essentially special conditions, Ombre
S A model E RJ 190 slash
dash 300 airplane, flight envelope protection, general limiting requirements.
I don't understand anything you just said,
ok,
so basically, um
when we started out with uh like planes,
we literally had wires connected to stuff that you would like when you pulled the,
the the stick, like say when you pulled it backwards,
it would actually like pull on a cable that would physically move
Arons and
like move stuff around, right?
And like, so, you know,
flying was a physically demanding and exhausting profession.
Um
And you know, then you got things like power assist like in your car and
eventually you got fly by wire where you
essentially have like a joystick telling a computer,
you know,
like turn the plane to the right and then the plane decides what to actually you know,
it turns the a
or, you know, moves
Arons or
the flaps or whatever needs to happen to turn the plane in that direction.
Even outside of computer, there's a certain
hesitation for a lot of people to think that like when you move the stick,
you're just flipping a switch that then goes through a wire as electricity and you
have
something to do.
What does, it doesn't even have to be a computer necessarily, right?
It can basically be a switch
that does something sort of stuff, regardless.
It's all computerized now.
So, and what's interesting is so, you know, as, as time goes on,
we've gotten a better understanding of aerodynamics and crashes of planes.
And so, for example, we have things like stall warnings, you know,
like you're going too slow,
so you get a stall warning or you're going too close to the ground.
So you get a proximity alert, you know, saying pull up.
Um, but as of yet,
there are very few, like there are some specific
things in flight systems for certain well understood corner cases where the,
like the plane,
some models can essentially take control and get you out of the problem before.
Like the humans realize it's a problem,
right? Because part of the problem too is with a lot of these aviation things.
Like if you have a problem and you don't react to it in five or 10 seconds, you're dead,
you know, you're literally you're gonna hit the ground.
So what it sounds like is uh blah, blah, blah,
this airplane will have a novel or unusual design feature when compared to
the state of technology envisioned in the
airworthiness standards for transport category airplanes.
Uh So basically what they're saying is this airplane has a
new thing compared to all the other transport planes and,
and when they say transport planes,
they don't mean just like transporting stuff but they mean people as well
to be clear these planes
for
people.
Yeah, exactly.
Just really bothersome cargo.
Uh This design feature is a new control
architecture and full digital flight control system,
both of which provide flight envelope protection.
So what is a flight envelope? Well, a flight envelope is a fancy way of saying
if you go outside the flight envelope, like you go outside these parameters,
you die.
That's it, right.
Um The,
the air France disaster uh over the
South Atlantic is a great example because essentially
to fly
in a very fuel efficient manner, you have to fly very close to what is safe
and if you go a little bit slower or a little bit faster or a little bit too,
you know, a slightly different angle of attack,
uh the plane will stall or,
you know, bad things will happen and you will die.
Um
So essentially these planes are, you know,
flying in a manner where even a slight change in circumstances mean you,
you're now up up the creek without a paddle.
But if you can fly that way, reliably, you can save a ton of fuel,
you can get there quicker, all these good things.
And so what it sounds like is that this flight software is now
sort of understanding the flight envelope of the plane
and ensuring that it stays within that flight envelope.
So
I think, um,
like there's been cases for example of where people had the autopilot going,
they were flying a certain speed,
uh, you know, and then they hit some weather or they hit like, um, you know,
hotter air or colder air which has a different density
and that changes the, the characteristics of the flight
and the flight envelope and
you can have a problem
and the auto
doesn't like that.
Well, what if they're like having a nap or eating their dinner? And
I don't
know, I
don't know how,
well again, autopilot.
So, I mean, depending on how sophisticated they are,
some autopilots literally are just like, keep you on a bearing
to
the wheel
pretty
much. Yeah.
And again, that's, that was a, there was a,
there was a flight that crashed up in northern Canada because
they engaged the autopilot to fly a certain course
and that course flew them into a hill.
Whoops.
Yeah.
Uh, the worst part is the second officer raised this concern and was overruled.
-- Yeah.
-- Well,
what, like we're flying right at that hill.
What
basically
what happened
had
day we're flying right at that hill,
you know.
-- But anyway, sorry, autopilot. So, what does autopilot do
-- today?
So, there's, there's a variety of sophistication but like a variety of autopilots.
Uh, well, obviously the more sophisticated ones now will do, you know, they,
they'll do things like, keep you,
um, at a stable altitude, you know, regardless of, you know,
kind of a little bit of variation,
you know, they'll keep you on the same heading.
Like, so even if you hit, like say a wind coming across,
you know, it'll turn you into the wind a little bit to keep you on course, you know,
-- things like that,
-- right?
I got you
right.
Because what you could hit a jet stream hitting you sideways at 100 miles an hour,
right? If you're flying,
well, no, it's, it's people fly through the jet stream all the time, right? And
uh a lot of airline routes take this into account so that they can, you know,
use it as a tail wind to get there faster.
But anyway, so the thing is with these autopilots,
like the majority of them will essentially keep you on course.
Um But they won't necessarily like keep you
within a safe flight envelope, right? Like if,
and it sounds like this one is essentially, it's that next level of smart
uh
so that it will, you know, for example,
if you hit a thunderstorm or something like that,
it'll take appropriate action to maybe speed up or slow down or,
you know, just otherwise reconfigure the flaps of the plane.
Um,
because here's a dirty secret. Right.
You want the plane to have as little drag as possible so that it flies efficiently.
-- Dirty secret. I think that's like the fundamentals of avionics.
-- Right. Right.
But the thing is they've pushed it very far
now to the point where it's almost dangerous.
But if you fly correctly it's, it's ok.
I got you.
You know,
so when it works, it's great when it doesn't work. You know,
because like, lift is one of the side effects of drag.
So
-- if you have no drag by definition, you have no lift.
-- Exactly.
And that's what happened to air France over the South Atlantic. Apparently
I got you.
So
they
fell
out of the sky.
This sounds to me like self driving airplane.
Um, it's,
well, here's the reality, right?
You could have a self driving car and just give a GPS coordinates and like,
just hope to goodness that nothing gets in your way.
Right.
-- Sure.
-- You know. But, but obviously that would be insane and not
very
smart
-- to not hit things though.
-- Right.
Well, and so that's obviously we have to take that into account. Right.
Because the situations change, deer come out of the road, other cars, whatever.
Right.
Well, have you seen that video of the Teslas detecting crashes?
And it's like as a human,
I have no idea what's going on and the Tesla already knows what's coming.
And it's, it's amazing.
Yeah.
And so that's, that's a good example of this, you know, in theory,
this flight envelope thing, you know, can detect, oh, you know,
we're losing lift because we're approaching our, you know, the, the, the
arons are trimmed to, you know, make us very fuel efficient,
but we're losing lift for whatever reason.
Maybe I need to sacrifice a bit of fuel efficiency. So we don't all die.
I, I, I'm comfortable with that decision.
Um, you know, but to make that decision and say 1/10 of a second versus a human being,
which may take, you know, 1030 seconds or a minute or two.
Yes,
that's right.
-- Yeah. No, I
-- get that and that's a big difference.
Well, and not only that, you know what the thing that's going to be really cool.
And I don't know if this system can do this and, and it may not,
but once these planes can start recording all of the data about all of their flights,
then they
start using things like machine learning and artificial
intelligence to basically make the autopilot significantly smarter.
-- Right?
-- Oh, they already do that. Uh And for example, the engines, uh
see here's the thing, for example, like when you buy a plane engine,
you typically don't like a lot of times you don't buy them, you're just leasing them.
Um And I know the, the nicer, like the Rolls Royce engines, the higher end ones that,
you know, are like on 740 sevens and whatnot.
They essentially send back telemetry.
I, I remember that because the
plane that vanished with the Malaysian Airlines plane
and
the engine, people had
some, some information about where the plane was, which
basically
where it was based on like Doppler shift and what not going back to the Inmarsat,
-- which
-- is wild.
Yeah. So, I mean,
the, the real,
the thing is like a plane isn't like a car,
these things are really expensive and so quite often,
um,
the plane you're on, you know, the company operating, it probably doesn't own it.
They may be leasing it dry leasing or wet leasing.
So a dry lease is where you just lease the plane,
a wet lease is where you lease the plane and a crew.
Um, and you know, for all, you know,
that
that plane may not own those engines, they, those engines may be leased.
Uh, because the thing is like, there's a lot of aviation companies that, you know,
they don't have the expertise to fix one of these engines.
I doubt any of them do.
I mean, if you didn't build it,
I'm skeptical you can touch it because have you ever seen what
looks like?
Do you think a big airline can though?
Oh, they
do? Yeah, like Air Canada, for example.
Um,
actually the Air Canada and several North
American Airlines have now moved all their,
um,
major sort of repairs and refit down to South America
because it's actually cheaper to fly the plane down there and take
it out of service for an extra 12 or 20 hours.
But fly it down to a country where the wages are so much cheaper
to do all the maintenance refit,
you know, and, like, take the plane out of service for three days and, like,
tear it apart and put it back together, basically.
Right. I've, I've read about such things actually and it's a,
because I,
I didn't realize this but most airplanes are in service for 20 or more years.
Which is just crazy to me.
What is the, hang
on
a second
-- and
-- they, like, just keep taking them apart and fixing them and then, like,
they'll put in new seats or they'll put,
-- starts to crack.
-- Right.
Right.
Or, you know, the wings, you can essentially,
yeah, you can just keep, like replacing the engines and all the other bits.
Um,
what is the B 52 service lifetime at this point? I think it's going to be 75 years.
Uh,
do, do, do,
do
it.
They're planning until 2040.
So that's another 20 some years. And it's been around for about 50 years so far.
It's a good plan,
I guess so.
And here's the reality after what the F-35 and
F-22 cost to design and build and produce,
I don't know.
That we can actually have a large bomber program that wouldn't turn into a,
like trillion dollar
train wreck.
Well,
you don't even need bombers anyway. Just drones, man, everything,
drones. And
that's
the other problem.
Well, the other problem too is I,
I don't think the US has ever sold the B 52 to another nation.
Right.
So they can't, you know, kind of defray the cost, like, you know,
with Canada and Australia and variety of other nations buying F-35s for example.
So,
but no, this is interesting because, um, like on the one hand, see,
here's the other thing, right is if the plain avionic system doesn't have like
a,
an interface you can talk to, like, it doesn't have a Wi Fi or a network port, you know,
it's not on the internet, I hope.
Oh, boy, I hope,
um,
you know, it's really hard to attack this thing.
You know, you have to go like the Stuxnet route of like a USB stick or something.
Yes. And that's, that's fair.
This is a good reason to not tie the
entertainment center in with the now self-driving airplane.
But you, you're probably the
self
driving.
Let's be clear on this. They, they autopilot.
-- Most airplanes spend something like 98% of their flying time on autopilot.
-- Right.
Right.
Well, you know, it's going to be really wild.
I wonder how long until we see the first flight
that basically takes off and lands completely under computer control.
Uh,
so that's already happened.
Has
really
ok
with people on it.
I'm not 100% certain. I know the, I think it was DARPA
with,
no, no, I'm saying like a passenger jet, not like some DARPA
crazy airplane that's fueled by like, you know, rodents or something. I mean,
like an actual airplane
with, with not me sitting in the city,
it's a tough sell. I mean, I, I suspect it will happen
after self driving cars because we'll get used
to self driving cars and giving up that control
and that perception of control.
I don't know if it, it's gonna be that hard to sell though, man. I mean,
I feel like self driving cars are being nearly everybody accepts them and,
and basically anyone I run into that says I don't trust a computer to drive a car.
And I say
you honestly think anything can be worse than a person. They go.
Yeah, you're, you're probably right, like, literally,
I have yet to find anyone that you have to stand their ground on this one.
And I suspect airplane now, granted pilots are highly trained
and so it's slightly different there because it's not just like any Yahoo who,
you know,
paid 20 bucks to the DMV and passed their crappy test
pilots are, are a different breed. However,
I would still trust a computer over a person
any day because a computer doesn't show up drunk.
The computer doesn't fall asleep and I know the computer is going to do it
is you can literally hit
realistic scenarios in flight that like nobody's
ever accounted for like um captain.
So with the, I've lost both engines
-- on
-- take
off, there are always going to be
those kind of extra strenuous circumstances and, and I expect that to be the case
and
I this is where it gets tricky is, I can envision two scenarios.
Number one is where you have
kind of some sort of remote command and control room
with qualified personnel in it that are able to,
you know, kind of take over.
You
have
to be able to redirect the flights because of weather
and,
well, the computer can redirect flights.
Well,
but at some point you have to be able to tell
the airplane like you cannot land here because for example,
there's a national ground stop.
Well, yeah, but why couldn't you? I mean,
well, I'm saying you can
just ask the plane nicely. You want to be able to, like you said, control it.
I would assume there'd be some sort of centralized
air traffic control system that's fundamentally making sure these planes
and part of it too is
you're going to have to make sure the planes aren't too near each other.
I would imagine when it's computer controlled you'd
want to keep them even farther apart,
maybe
closer,
-- safer.
-- You think? So, I don't know.
Anyway,
you can
a
-- heck of a lot faster than people.
-- Here's the second part though.
The alternative is you just say
there are going to be rare events
and the computer is going to do its best,
but
sometimes it's gonna crash
and that's even true of people, honestly. Right. I mean,
Sully was an anomaly because you had a very experienced seasoned pilot
that, that knew what to do,
you know. II I, if it was anyone else, that plane might have crashed,
the problem is the perception of control. Right.
Like my understanding is a lot of people,
their fear of flying is not a fear of flying per se.
It's a fear of not being in control while they are flying.
The problem isn't flying, the problem is crashing. Right.
Well, yeah. And, but the problem is they, they're not the one driving.
Like they have to trust somebody else to, you know,
not crash the plane and some people just can't handle that.
You know,
I, I, and I see the same argument with self driving cars. Right.
-- I want to be in control of it. I don't trust a computer. I don't
-- trust me.
I
trust, I
trust taxi drivers.
Yeah. Right. No, I, I agree. I agree completely.
Uh, so anyway, I used to be afraid to fly and I, I didn't fly very much.
I, I was, um, I, I did not like it and I don't know
it, I don't feel like it was a control thing. I just didn't,
airplanes are very bumpy things
and, and like I took my first airplane flight, I'll be honest with you.
I was 22 years old when I got in an airplane for the first time. I was very old. Right.
Right. I never flew.
And so I remember just like all the bumps and the
weird noises and things happening and I was always like,
the
plane is
what's
going
on,
lack of control
it,
you know, it might have been because now that I understand what's going on.
II I don't get bothered at all.
And in fact,
I've been on flights where people were like screaming because we were
like crazy things were happening and I was just sitting there like,
man, it's fine and I remember turning to the person next to me, I'm like
this happens, it's gonna be ok.
You know.
No, I think I've been flying since I was like four, maybe three.
Nice.
Well, one of my kids are the same way they've been, I mean, they,
they won't remember not flying because I've been an airplane so much.
And yeah, I mean, it's just,
it's a non event because I trust in the system because by and large, yeah,
these are professionals with well maintained machines.
Much more so than say a taxi.
Oh man, I know, I know. Actually the most terrifying taxi I ever had was in Canada.
Did you know that
it was in, it was in Ottawa. In fact,
I was, uh,
it was technically an Uber ride
but I was, uh,
I was watching the map and I was worried I was being driven somewhere to be murdered.
Luckily I was not.
-- Yeah. Anyway, anyway, all right,
-- back to the flight control software.
So, I mean, the thing is
the biggest, I think, honestly, one of the biggest things nowadays is,
is it attached to a network and, or the network being the internet, of course,
and if it's not attached to the, the internet,
bam, it's a lot harder to attack because, you know,
some schmuck from Russia can't just like,
connect to it.
Well, so here's the thing, I,
I think of the immediately is if you have the equivalent of a self driving airplane,
you're going to have quite a lot of
communication happening between the airplane and the ground
and
you're going to have some sort of routed protocol.
I suspect even though it's going to be happening obviously over satellite or, or,
you know, ground to air or whatever.
And
the issue I could see being that if they have, say a central
kind of control, uh uh flight tower or whatever you wanna call it, right.
Keeping track of all the airplanes and, and telling them all what to do,
kind of like autos,
air traffic control. I don't know what you even call it.
But anyway,
that is probably going to be connected to the internet because
you're gonna have many of them scattered around the country and
even if it's a VPN, like they're on the internet,
which means people can get to the airplanes.
So here's the good news, there's already an industry that has,
uh, encountered and addressed and solved that problem largely.
-- Which,
-- which problem I mentioned 10 things. What about satellites?
Satellite control?
Right.
There's ground stations that control the satellites, military, civilian,
whatever.
And, you know, and let's face it, satellites,
they're even more expensive and container
than airplanes.
Right. How
-- many breaks? You can't go fix
-- it. How many of these ground stations are there?
Uh, I
don't know.
Uh, the US government military operates a bunch. Right.
I mean,
-- the GPS thing alone is like quite
-- the military is different because they have,
they have their, it's called super
net and it, they're kind of, you know,
classified network that, that's very well controlled. Right.
I could and granted, don't get me wrong.
I don't think this is going to be a problem because for two reasons, first of all,
I don't know if anyone's a big enough dirt bag
to actually crash an airplane on purpose like this.
I mean,
uh it's already been hypothesized. Remember what was it?
I want to say the Polish Defense Minister or Prime Minister or
something like that and his entire cabinet or something was aboard.
Oh, here we go. Yeah, Poland claims proof Russia caused presidential
plane crash.
So, yeah, it was the Polish
President and his cabinet.
I, I don't think that's comparable to an airplane I'm going to be on.
Ok.
No, but, you know, maybe somebody else important is on that airplane.
-- Let's
-- hope not.
I, I'll make a point of avoiding planes with important people.
But anyway,
let's face it too.
Uh,
even if they connect these things to the internet
and they're using VPN S or whatever to,
to communicate between them and whatnot.
Uh,
for the most part, this stuff works pretty well and,
and even if they get broken into which, which will inevitably happen,
if, if they've done it right, they're gonna figure it out and deal with it quickly.
I mean,
that's just kind of becoming the reality of the world now is
people are getting hacked a lot and if you have a very,
very high profile resource,
you have to be extra vigilant.
Yeah.
Well,
I think that in this case we actually have economics working for us in the sense of
you have airplanes, especially the commercial,
you know, wide body, uh, carriers
are a massive capital cost.
Yes,
there's that not only that the FAA has a ton
of power here and if they tell you to do something
you're gonna do it because you don't have a choice. Right.
It's not like an IOT light bulb where nobody cares.
So, I think that's, and, and to be honest, that's, you know,
one of the reasons I would generally trust the system.
Will there be problems? Yeah. Will people die?
Um, yeah, I mean, that's the nature of almost any technological, you know,
system, especially when you're moving people around at hundreds of miles an hour.
Um, but is it going to be safer than driving a car from point A to point B
-- almost certainly
-- until self driving cars are here.
And then actually, you know, that's one of the things I think about is,
is self driving,
cars are going to change the travel industry in ways we can't even imagine because,
like, here's a great example is
if I need to go to the east coast, the east coast is like a 13 hour drive for me. Right.
I'm not driving that
I get on an airplane. I fly there. Right. However,
if I could get in a car, like at six in the afternoon
and fall asleep and wake up, you know, in Boston.
That's sweet. You know, I would seriously consider doing that.
There's, I mean, I was reading an article talking about this that it really,
in theory, yeah, self driving cars, especially if you go overnight
would just decimate the airline industry for anything less than 500 mile flights.
Yeah. Right.
And, and it would be way more convenient to do that in, in, in all seriousness.
The vast majority of my flights
I go there a day before because I can't, you know,
I have got a morning meeting so I cannot show up the day of,
and then I end up leaving at, like,
noon because it's the only time the stupid airplane leaves.
You know what I mean?
Unless I want to get in at 2 a.m. which I don't.
So,
yeah.
No, this would be ii, I actually hope that this, you know,
in theory this could result in like,
essentially all the regional air traffic being pretty much gutted.
I'm ok with that.
And, um, you know,
just essentially maintaining the big hubs to fly
people to Europe or Canada or whatever.
-- Yeah,
-- I could see it, man.
It's, it's certainly possible. Not only that, the other thing I think of a lot is
so I live in, in an area where the,
the o'hare airport is basically like the, the
Giganto airport for the region
and it's three hours away by car.
So II, I never drive to o'hare because it's too far to drive.
And also I don't want to waste six hours of my life.
Well, between that and security and everything you're looking at like, five hours.
Yeah, at least. Exactly.
But like, if I could get in a car that was gonna drive me there and I could, like,
work or read or play video games or whatever, like,
I would seriously consider that because that would not be a waste of my time.
You know what I mean?
Well, I, I think that's going to be a big thing. Is. I, I know a lot of people who commute
and that's an extra 2030 minutes each way that,
yeah, they can't work. They can't really do much of anything useful
other than listen to, like, books on tape.
-- No,
-- I get it, man. It's gonna be, it's gonna be crazy
anyway. All right, we're, we're in the weeds. Uh,
let's
speaking on the topic of security through obscurity.
There was also the Microsoft leak
that happened.
What was that? When, whenever, whenever it happened,
that's when it happened
last week, a couple of days, whatever, it doesn't matter, it doesn't matter.
So what, what basically happened was
some guy found on an FTP site, a dump of a,
what is it like 32 terabytes of windows source code or something?
Apparently
something like
official and nonpublic.
I don't know, it was installation images
and they say so
for blueprints, what is it?
What is the software blueprint?
It doesn't matter because we're going to talk
about source code and hiding source code.
And, and so, and then of course, Twitter lights up
as, as it does and this is what makes Twitter so much fun
because everyone's like, oh,
someone at Microsoft is freaking out that's ruined their weekend, whatever.
And I was thinking about this and
yeah, I'm sure there's people at Microsoft that weren't happy,
but like at the end of the day
doesn't really matter. I don't think it does.
Like, like,
I think Microsoft is so far past the point of
believing their source code is some sort of security asset.
Now,
granted there's there's trade secrets and we won't talk about that necessarily.
But
as a security asset, I don't buy it.
Well,
it says that the uh the leak code is Microsoft's Microsoft's shared source kit.
So this is
assuming that is source code that they share with
-- partners and what
-- the shared source thing was.
Oh man, I've got a great story about this.
So shared source was the thing they started where
like if you were a university student or,
or part of faculty or something, you could get access to Windows source code to,
to do stuff,
right? You could look at it and I think you could build some of it. I don't,
I'm sure you could send them changes whether they took them or not. Who knows?
And you of course, had to sign a phone book contract and,
and all this. And
I remember I was out for dinner one night with a Microsoft sales rep.
This was, this was right when shared source first started. And I was,
I don't even know if I worked at Red Hat back then. It was a long time ago.
And anyway, I remember this guy looks at me and he says, why do,
why do you do this stuff?
I don't, I don't get this open source.
I'm like, it's fun, you know, I can, I've got all this source code.
I've got all these tools. None of it costs money. I can work on it.
I can contribute back, you know, whatever.
And he looks at me and like he was completely honest and he said,
but we do that. We shared source and
he took everything in me to not laugh out loud at this guy.
And it's like I,
I would love to educate you but you don't get it and I don't think you ever will.
-- It's just, they are not the same thing.
-- No, no.
My understanding is that well, I mean, according to the article it's things. Uh,
yeah, it's not even close to what you would need to build windows.
Uh, well, no, probably not. And, and, but wasn't there a windows dump once?
And somebody did find some security
issues
for
it was a long time
ago.
And,
but whatever the point is though,
that Microsoft has a very mature and when I use a mature, I mean,
like the granddaddy of security development life cycle programs
and these guys have been through it all. They've seen it all
and, and let's face it. Worst case scenario, bad guy gets a source code.
They deal with it. Right. I mean,
yeah,
-- well,
-- just like with the stuff Tavis is finding
because he's found at this point. Probably.
I haven't been keeping track of everything he's found, but it's,
it feels like a couple dozen really bad windows related security
flaws and windows and defender and a bunch of other stuff.
-- He was looking
-- at
everything
-- Tavis has
-- broken.
I'm thinking of all the antivirus that he beat up and then
just kind of gave up on because it was so terrible.
I don't know if he gave up on it, but
here's, here's, well, actually, so this is another part of this story is uh open VPN.
Right.
There were what two professional audits done of Open VPN where,
like people looked at code and they scanned the code and they did their thing, right.
And they found a bunch of minor stuff
and like some dude fuzzed
it. He found a whole bunch of
bugs.
Yeah.
Well, and there were, actually, there was about,
I think there were three other flaws that we didn't give CV S because they just,
they weren't exploitable in any way, shape or form.
Um,
but, but here's, here's the point too. It doesn't matter
how hard you look at it, it doesn't matter how good your SDLC is.
All it takes is some guy to show up and run a tool and now you've got a new bug and I mean,
that's the thing.
Like you move with Tavis. Tavis can work on this stuff forever
and you know what the next day he could come in
and find a bug worse than anything he's found yet.
It's just, it's the nature of this stuff.
Well, and it keeps changing and moving. Right.
It's not like we're, you know, assessing a bridge for flaws. It's,
we're assessing all the bridges
that are constantly being rebuilt and refurbished.
You know, I like.
And if you look at the, if you look at the turn rate in some open source code projects,
the Linux kernel is a great example, like how many
lines of code are added, removed, changed every, you know, major release.
-- And the answer is like, well, it's a lot,
-- you know, that would be really fun.
I might do that. I should, I should take the GIT repo of the kernel
and look at how many lines because obviously you can only
go back to when it was imported into GIT because,
you know, line is used in FTP site.
It starts code management a long time ago.
But it'd be really interesting to look at how many lines of code were
in that initial commit that are still actually part of the kernel today.
Probably, oh, even the license might
ignoring text files in license files and things like that. Right.
I'm talking about like c source code and we can even ignore comments
but like actual compiled code. I'd be interested to see
that'd be fun to you too.
I bet I could get GCC to tell me which lines were c,
like which lines it compiles and which lines it doesn't.
This would be a fun project. Maybe I'll do that this weekend.
Yeah.
No, I mean, and, and not only that but the underlying technology, you know,
part of it too is, and this is what I love is,
this technology is so complex that we have emergent behavior.
Like a great example being the Kuala stack
card stuff,
it's like literally whoops,
you know,
that didn't do what we thought it would.
Yep. Yep. Yeah,
you gotta love it, man.
What do you do?
Well, I mean, train people to react quickly when the law is found and get it,
get it fixed and get the fix out to customers and to users.
I
tend to agree
with that. I, I think that's the only answer because even if you have the best
security training and security reviews and, and whatever
in place,
it, it doesn't matter because you still have software for the critical issues.
I'm, I can't, I'm sure it's out there,
but I'm trying to think of a major vendor of software related stuff
that actually builds
reliably 100% of their own stuff.
Like even the sombre thing is saying that
we use third party code and operating systems.
The only,
the only thing I could possibly think of would be the space shuttle and only
because it's running like a code base
-- from 1970 the
-- space shuttle doesn't fly anymore
and I'm sure it used.
Well, I'm sure some of the airplanes,
I bet this operating system that we read about is probably 100% proprietary
but the whole, but no, no, no,
I'm saying the plane as a whole includes other components.
And that's what I mean is,
I don't think there's a single thing anymore that ships with software
that is 100% like in
house. You
-- know
-- what this is though?
You're
shipping somebody else's stuff as well.
Did you?
No, no, no, you're uh
you're on Reddit.
So I know you saw this.
Did you see the story about the guy who made the $1500 chicken sandwich?
Uh
-- No.
-- Ok.
Uh So it rings a bell.
This is, this is old, I think,
but it showed up on one of the subreddits over the weekend and
I've not heard this story before now,
but apparently this guy decided he was going to like, make a chicken sandwich as in,
he's going to raise the chicken and grow the wheat and he like,
grew all the vegetables and everything to make this sandwich.
And it ended up costing him $1500 and took six months, right?
That's why
build a toaster from scratch.
-- The guy who tried to watch the
-- TED talk, a TED talk. This guy tried to build
a simple electronic toaster
that TED talk was stupid. Like this guy actually made a sandwich, right?
That the TED Talk guy, he, he made a wire, right? Like it was
my life were not bad.
What was your favorite part of the process?
I really enjoyed milking the cow,
they were friendly and like to be rubbed on the base of their tail.
But it was also scary because the farmer was telling me
that if spooked they kick with what's called the death kick.
Uh,
yeah, that, that burnt down in Chicago.
But, but anyway, so here's the deal, right?
This is why nobody writes all their own software
because otherwise you end up spending $1500 on,
-- on a chicken sandwich and it takes
-- you a
web server
or even a basic network communications protocol. Like,
have you not noticed all those places that, you know,
use UDP and then try to make it into
reliable delivery and end up badly recreating TCP.
They create a broken TCP every time.
Yeah, I mean, and I think this goes back to a lot of,
you know what I've said about security is I think we'd
be better off if we had people focus on using,
you know,
some of the better frameworks and just like, please, for the love of whatever,
don't like, don't write your own encryption or web server or whatever.
-- Like
-- the news, one of these professional stats is off.
Don't roll your own.
I
know.
Oh yeah, I saw,
I just like two weeks ago saw a new one mentioned on Reddit and it was like,
just all the y
because they can
because we, we finally convinced them not to roll their own crypto. So
now they're rolling their own off
which,
well, and, and
o has to involve crypto now.
Yeah, it usually does, doesn't it?
Well,
how are you going to transport in store and verify secrets without crypto?
It's true. It's true.
Oh,
my goodness.
I guess the moral of the story is buy your groceries at the store.
Yes. Well, not only that, could you imagine the, just
absurdity if everyone trying to kind of grow and,
and do their own thing for food instead of relying on, you know,
essentially factory farms.
Well, we, we did that.
It was called the agrarian, you know, the agricultural revolution.
And like
8% of people spent all their time trying to grow food and not starve to death.
That's a good point
and
kind of sucked.
And then we did the industrial revolution and it was not super awesome for a while,
but
it got better.
It did. And we cured polio, which is a big deal.
And now obesity is one of the leading causes of death globally,
not just in North America.
So
we win.
Yeah, 2 billion people are overweight now.
Yay,
whatever. All right. So the moral of this story is
you, you, you have to work with other groups, you have to use third party software.
And so I guess our trick now
is how do we vet third party software?
And, and I don't think we're going to answer that today
because that could be probably a, a 10 part episode if we wanted to cover it.
But II, I think that's becoming the new issue and,
and I see a lot of people are being like, oh, open source bad.
But in reality it's like,
it's, it's just a tool. You know, it, it, it's your hammerer. Now. Go find some nails.
Well, more to the point. You're,
what choice do you have?
-- You don't, you don't have, like,
-- do you remember?
I mean,
I remember when there were several very successful closed source web servers,
-- they're mostly dead
-- now.
-- I the Microsoft one is still around, isn't it
-- true?
But that's only because, you know, Microsoft,
-- but nobody else can afford to
-- do
that.
Yeah, the other big one was what the, the Netscape
-- Netscape
-- had one,
had one
and so
had one and there was that one from that
company in Italy that was actually really quite,
quite efficient and nice.
Um
I can't remember the names anymore. They're just
gone to the winds of time
and, you know, the more successful one now is while Engen
X, which is, of course, open source and Apache, the granddaddy, open source,
you know, so
although the Google web server serves a lot of traffic,
not that anyone can run it but them, but I don't even know what that is.
If it's just some bastardized Apache or if,
or if they've, they've written their own.
My suspicion is it's probably a whole bunch of open source put together.
Uh I think they're smart enough to
not completely suffer from not invented
here syndrome unless it's absolutely necessary,
like, say the chrome web browser.
But even that uses it
a
bunch
of
-- other
-- stuff. It wasn't not invented here.
It's just when Web KT became difficult to work with, they had to fork
and I don't, I don't blame them for that.
I, I remember when that happened, it was, it was kind of messed up.
I think I was on the security team when that happened.
I was on the web KT security team at one point.
I was, I assigned other CV S
man. That was a long time ago. I forgot that was even a thing.
Anyway. Anyway,
it's, it's time to call it. I think any funny thoughts, Kurt.
Uh
Yeah, I don't know, hobby farming. It sounds fun but
terrible.
Like
I love that I can go buy fruits and vegetables at the grocery store.
Yeah, I think fundamentally, I mean, specialization of economic labor. It's,
it works.
Yes, it does.
All right, man.
Thank you, everybody for listening.
Thank you, Kurt for a, a enlightening conversation.
As always, we'll have the show notes at open source Security podcast.com.
We have all kinds of crazy stuff this week to talk about.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag to get a hold of us.
We have links to Twitter and Facebook there you can use and if nothing else,
thank you.
Everyone for listening. Kurt. You have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too.