Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 175 with myself, Kurt
-- Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh
-- Pressers.
How you doing, man?
I,
I think I'm actually finally over whatever that head
cold thing was that I had for two weeks.
You know, I feel the same way.
I was remarkably ill for the last couple of
podcast episodes we recorded which I do my best
to make sure it doesn't come through when I
take out all the horrible noises we're making.
But yeah, I actually like,
I've slept through the night for the last couple
of nights and I'm not coughing and making terrible noises
all day.
-- I mean, there's still
-- some, my one son is so congested, like, and this is him,
like standing up being awake and it just sounds like ouch.
It's just the poor guy.
You gotta love it, man.
So anyway, I'm glad we're better by as better as we're going to get
at
this
age.
The ravages of old age
anyway. So it's new man.
Well, so it looks like criminals have finally caught up with technology,
-- but when it comes to car thieving,
-- I would disagree with that.
I think
we are noticing criminals have beaten us yet again,
which they always do because by definition, that's how defending works.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, there was a, there was a kind of a, ok, so,
basically stealing cars used to be pretty easy because you
just smashed a window, jammed a screwdriver into the ignition
and twisted.
Right. We've all seen the movies. Yeah.
And, and that's actually, I mean,
basically that's what the key in your car does
is it turns and completes an electrical circuit.
Right.
So you've got your first position, which is what, like your accessories,
like you control on your radio and lights
and then you turn it all the way and it'll crank the,
the engine and try and start the engine. Right.
If you live in Canada and you forget to plug your car in,
you know, that, that can be a bit of a crash
sometimes.
Right. Right. It doesn't always happen.
I was quite shocked to find out that they sell cars without block heaters in the US.
But then, you know, I guess in Florida that makes sense.
I've never owned a block heater and I live in
one of the colder regions of the United States.
I've never seen a car that doesn't have a plug on it
because you live in like the freaking Arctic Circle, man.
Well, anyways, so the thing is you just,
you know, it's not like you need to pick that walk,
you could just jam a little screwdriver in there and twist it right.
So, ok,
car manufacturers came up with actually what I think is a pretty
solid effective system, uh the ignition interlock.
And so basically your key has a little computer chip in it that is
interrogated by radio
and it sends back a code and, and that's it.
So basically now you can still twist the lock and like,
or pry it or pick it or whatever.
But the ignition interlock is going to kick in and, and refuse to start the car. So
like you can't start the car, which generally means you can't steal it.
That's the idea. Yes. And, and that has worked really well for a while.
And of course, people, you know, well, and here's a great example in Canada,
you know, a lot of people for some reason,
want a remote car starter so they can start the car,
let it warm up for five or 10 minutes, you know, blow
hot air
defrost a bit and then get into the nice toasty car and drive to work.
I remember the one time, uh, the last time I got home from a flight,
I had to sit in my car for five or 10 minutes
in the parking lot waiting for my car to warm up because
breathing in my car was enough to fog up the windows. Awesome
remote car starters obviously need a way to sort
of bypass this ignition interlock to start the car,
right.
By definition, you can't start the car.
So they basically do the same thing.
You know, they have a little radio fob, uh, it tells the car, go start the car goes.
Do you really want me to start?
Like, I need you to kind of answer this little secret radio query and the key fob goes.
Yeah. Yeah. No, I really meant it. Start the damn car and the car goes. Oh OK.
And
the,
the thing is there's a really
conceptually simple attack here which is
typically
the key fob,
the attacker can't interact with it because the key fob is in
your pocket or in your purse or in your dress or whatever.
Right.
And by definition, if they can interact with it, they'll just steal it and run.
And,
and it should also be noted that this is extremely common in newer higher end cars.
Obviously the target market for car thieves
where you don't even have keys anymore.
It's all the fobs where you just like my father's car, he walks up to it, it unlocks,
he gets in, he pushes a button, it starts and he leaves.
No, there's, there's literally now that we have the microchip,
there's literally no physical reason to have the key
other than that's how we used to do it.
Right. Right.
It's just that simple. So, yeah, so, but, but through the magic of radio,
you can
extend a radio signal who knew by, uh, well,
I think every electrical engineer on the planet knew that.
Right.
But, you know, you know, but nobody ever listens to them. So it's fine.
So basically the Attackers have discovered you just, basically,
it's not even a replay attack. It's a relay attack. So you basically have a,
so a device that listens to the radio signal and
boost it and, and relays it on which I mean,
-- we've been doing that in radio for well since ever
-- forever.
Right? And it should also be noted that it sounds like in most of these attacks,
the keys are near the front door
of a
wall or somewhere close to where the thieves can go.
It's not like they're just standing next to your car and picking up the keys
bob from 100 yards away, then it starts
well, and, and in theory though, to put, uh, to be clear, they,
in theory could do that if they had a
strong enough amplifier and a high quality enough receiver,
in theory, they could
inverse square law would make it really difficult just easier to stand next to it.
The, the background noise probably would drown that signal out
after a couple of feet. Is my suspicion or meters for you. Civilized folks.
Well, yeah, inverse square law. It's a heck of a thing.
Um, essentially it says that, you know, your radio
anyways
so long and the short of it is, is that Attackers have figured this out. And
the thing is this is something where I can build this device
and I can teach you how to use it in about,
I don't know, a minute, maybe 30 seconds,
-- maybe two minutes if you're not listening. Right.
-- Right.
So here's,
here's my take on this is you sent me these links and said we should talk about this.
And the first thing that popped into my head
was this is just the nature of the,
the cat and mouse game of adversary versus defender
where a new technology or a new something exists.
And there's always going to be a certain group of people that find ways to abuse it.
This has been true of telephones and radio and television.
-- I wouldn't
-- say
abuse it so much as exploit it because they're
not abusing it in the sense of doing something wrong with it.
They're, they're literally doing what it's meant to do.
I would call it abusing it because
you're operating outside intent of that technology.
Right? I mean,
email with phishing. You've got
text messages now with people sending, goodness knows what,
telling you to send them itunes gift cards.
I've gotten so many refunds from my cell phone companies.
That's amazing. Like I am just rolling in money now. It's awesome.
That's right. I have all those gift cards pretty soon. I'll be
when that,
when that Nigerian money comes back to me.
But
that's right.
I mean, this is the nature of,
I guess, opportunistic criminals.
They,
they find something they can exploit and they exploit it
and then the industry has to catch up behind them
because while you could argue, oh,
they should have known someone could replay this radio signal.
The reality is when they came up with this, this technology, probably what,
1015 years ago,
the ability to do something like this was well
outside the skill set of your common thief.
I remember when I first heard about software defined radio and I was like, wow,
that's, that's black magic.
It still is.
Yeah.
But I mean, and, you know, now I bought one a
couple of years ago for, I think it was like, $15 or something.
So you bought like the SDR thing, the little dongle that can also pick up digital TV,
like the nice ones.
There's something called the hack RF.
That's probably one of the better ones on the market.
It's like 500 bucks, which is, if you're looking to get into SDR,
you can do it for the really cheap ones.
They're really fun.
If you want to do anything actual legitimate, you need to spend like, 500
bucks, which is not cheap. But if you're stealing an expensive car that's free.
Yeah. Well, more to the point is successful. Right.
Yeah. Right. Right.
You know,
and what's funny is always anytime we talk about
this RF ID or chip signal or anything radio.
I'm always reminded of,
I got my nexus pass for travel and it comes in a copper foil lined sleeve
and it explicitly says to store it in there and to only take it
out when you're using it and then put it back in the copper slate.
And this is, this is something from the US government, right?
This isn't a bunch of crazy. This isn't, you know, me buying an RF ID blocking wall.
This is,
you know, I went to the airport answered a bunch of questions, waited,
what was it like four weeks and got this card in the mail.
-- So
-- actually, you remind me I have AAA kind of tangential topic.
So my ts a precheck had come to
and I think it's every five years you have to re up this
and last time, the first time I got it, which was the last time
I had to fill out a bunch of paperwork and go sit in a little room
and get asked a bunch of ridiculous questions and scan my fingerprints and you know,
all the hoopla
and this time
they sent me to a website,
I filled in some stuff. I answered all these silly questions
and hit submit and they were like, congratulations. Your ts a precheck is updated,
but they've already
got all your biometric.
They do and everything.
But I'm like, wow, that's still like, that's surprisingly efficient
for
the government.
Honey,
I just got an email a few weeks ago for my nexus.
I need to actually bring my passport the next time I go to the airport because
they're basically going to want to
take the biometric data off of my passport and tie it into my Nexus account.
And so it's the, the,
you know, for those of you who don't know if you have an RF ID enabled passport,
which if you have a passport,
that's I'm guessing less than five or 10 years old you do.
There's
copies of your like a digital copy of your face is stored on that chip in most cases.
Exciting. Think about it, right?
Because that's like, you know, every time you see this passport shenanigans,
what is it they're doing in movies, they're always cut, you know,
with an exacto knife,
cutting off the photograph and gluing a new one in and you know what I mean?
I would, I would think
that
the better way to do this is to just have a number on the passport
and then like have a database somewhere.
That means network connectivity. That means you have downtime.
That means also you got to remember this. Who do you have access to that database?
I don't think anyone's port of entries work without network access
anymore.
Uh They still do.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, you're going to be there a while maybe, but the reality is I,
I personally would have done the same way I would
build this so that even with the lights are out,
you can still do it with a flashlight.
-- But you can't, if you have a flashlight that r, that RF ID chip has
-- no,
I mean,
you can still look at the documents, you can examine them,
you can look at the guy's face with the,
yeah, whatever,
-- whatever. I'm not going to argue with you.
-- But, um,
so anyways, it's, but it's interesting to see this March forward where,
what they officially sent an email essentially is this is,
it's not a security reason they're doing this.
It's a convenience issue because I know one
thing is I hate touching those fingerprints,
scans, right?
Because you got to put your hand down on the little glass plate
and kind of wobble it around so it can like get a good
copy of your fingerprint.
And I'm just thinking like,
-- where's the hand
-- sanitizer?
Oh,
I'm sure people have washed their hands thoroughly
and there's no fecal matter on those scanners.
I'm sure they're clean as,
I mean,
it would be nice if they just had like a little cover,
you could put over it with the UV light to sanitize it.
But whatever the, the, the, the facial recognition thing is is faster. And so
because even with the automated
kiosk, uh you know, once going through Toronto, man, there was a line
like even for the automated stuff because it was just so crazy busy.
Yeah, I, I believe that. I do love the Canadian passport scanners though.
They have, like,
the whole machine lifts up to your height and then takes your picture.
It's like
this seems unnecessarily ridiculous.
Oh,
not out here. I had to, like, kind of half squat to get
to see
when I was in Toronto. Like a month ago.
Toronto gets the nice stuff. Edmonton is, you know, we're a backwater.
I understand.
I, I'm in a similar situation where I live does not get fancy things anyway.
Anyway, we're off in the weeds.
The act of criminals being opportunistic.
-- Well, criminals do attacks that are easy. I
-- would say high return on
investment.
You know, it has to be safe and it has to be easy.
Like those two guys that robbed that cultural museum in Germany and
took off with something north of maybe a billion dollars in artifacts.
You don't rob Fort Knox. Fort Knox is surrounded by grumpy people with guns,
right? And contrary to what we learned in James Bond
there, you know,
you can't knock them all out with sleeping gas and then rob the place.
I'm shocked to learn. That's not true.
But I mean, no, you're absolutely right. You don't, you don't rob
somewhere that's well protected because that's hard.
You can easily if all you're doing is opportunistic crime.
Like
the flip side though.
There are the, the high there is that magical movie level of high end criminal So,
one of my favorite car theft is the head of Mercedes in Germany.
Had a custom Mercedes obviously with like all the features, you know, bulletproof,
all the anti-theft stuff and it got stolen
and they're pretty sure some Russian wanted it and ordered.
Right. And that happens also.
-- But,
-- but that's,
you know, the 0.00001% of crime.
Well,
and I think it's also important to realize that when
you are the explicit target of a well funded adversary,
there is nothing you can do.
Not even well funded if they're motivated to be mean to you.
I like, I'll be,
how much money would it take for me to fly
down there with a monkey wrench to where you live?
A couple of 100 bucks probably.
Yeah.
You know,
you don't need to be well funded if you're willing to go fly somewhere and get,
potentially get caught.
However.
No, no.
But it's, it's more complicated than that,
I think because let's say you come to try to beat
me up with the monkey wrench and I'm not here.
-- Now, what do you do?
-- I just wait at your house till you come back.
And what if I'm not coming home for a week? Are you going to sit here for a week?
No, you're gonna get bored, you're gonna leave and then you'll be like,
do I want to spend another couple of 100 bucks to
fly to Wisconsin and beat Josh up with this wrench.
-- Like, how bad do you want? I wasn't
-- gonna beat you up with it.
I was gonna threaten you with it.
Well, that's even dumber. I mean, at least get your money's worth while you're here.
But I mean, for real, right?
Where if you say, like,
I will literally give you as many resources as you
-- need to accomplish this task versus
-- most of these things.
Don't take that, you know, a week of your time, five grand
and you could basically visit anybody on the
planet and probably get up in their face.
Yeah, except if they're gone, then you've just wasted five grand.
And do you, how many times can you waste five grand before you?
Like, I don't really feel like flying to Wisconsin this week to try to beat up Josh.
I bet you do it twice
and then you'd be like, all right, I give up Josh runs. Right. Right. Exactly.
Whereas if you're funded by the Russian mob and they're gonna be like,
you have as much money as you want to fly to
Wisconsin as many times as you want to beat him up.
You're gonna be like, oh sweet, like I'm in
right.
Anyway.
Well, it was also interesting with all this car theft, at least in Canada.
So let's say you actually steal a car in Canada.
Right.
Let's say you steal like a real nice, you know, Ford F 150 truck worth about 60 grand.
Ok.
-- What do you do with it?
-- I assume you have to get it out of the country because
the
-- repair shops won't take stolen parts.
-- Yeah, that's the easiest way, basically.
Uh, I also saw this really cool documentary where, what they do is
they go to an auto records yard and they get basically a record
frame but with valid VIN numbers
and essentially take it apart and put everything on the new frame.
-- Don't, all
-- the parts have ID numbers also though.
Yeah, but the person you're selling it to isn't checking those
database.
That's probably fair.
You know, when they take it in for servicing,
they'll find out that like everything in there is stolen.
But that's, you know, that's tomorrow's problem for somebody else.
But, yeah, they're finding that these things go out of the country, you know, in,
well, ship containers obviously
because you can't mail a car, I don't think.
And even if you do, you still have to wrap it.
It occurs to me that, you know, you think at ports of entry,
you see them scanning outgoing cargo and making sure it's legit.
So you have to imagine
that it would be relatively easy to catch because either
I, well, it's not like you're going to hide your car shipments in
a shipment of outgoing toilet paper or something. Right.
You might, I mean, this is how smuggling works they have.
I mean, again,
these are criminals are opportunistic where they have found ways to game the system
to get them what they need.
And actually, it's, it's funny you bring this up because I,
I recently watched the movie Lord of War
and it's about Nicholas Cage as an arms dealer.
And it's actually a fascinating movie.
I didn't know this because I never actually watched to the end. But it says,
uh,
like these events are based on true stories
and there's a surprising number of parallels,
I guess to real world arms dealers from various
uh decades
that, that this has been a thing and well, it still is a thing.
But anyway,
one of the things that, that I,
I chuckled at was all the bribing he did of all the
people when he was smuggling his weapons into the various countries.
And like
that's the thing, man,
when, when you work with someone like that,
what you're actually paying them for is they know who to bribe and how to bribe them,
right?
Some people you might bribe with candy, some people you might bribe with money.
And again,
this is that opportunistic criminal attitude of they,
they figure out how to get it done and they get it done
and then the, the authorities,
the defenders have to play catch up and you have to figure out, all right,
how did they do it this time?
How do we stop this from happening? And look, I'm not gonna lie
in most of the cases,
if you go to someone working at a port that's probably not making
tons of money and you give them a bag full of cash,
they're probably gonna be like,
I'll let this one go.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, it's, um, it's hard to defend against that.
Especially in countries that are less wealthy,
it's impossible to defend against that because, like,
in that instance they're attacking human nature
and you can argue.
Well,
we need to start putting RF ID tags and everything
and computerizing everything and tracking everything and to a degree,
you can do some of that.
-- I
-- mean, this is one of the major pushes for electronic currency in a lot of uh,
jurisdictions,
right?
But
uh, it will make corruption and bribery
much harder in that. It can be tracked centrally.
I mean,
I always love that. People talk about this, but look, the reality of it is
the United States $100 bill is never going to go out of circulation.
In fact, you can,
you can take $100 bills from 50 years ago and bring them to a bank and cash them in.
And most most nations will like,
expire their currency after a certain period of time because they say, ok,
if you haven't traded in old money by this day, like
too bad.
So sad you lose.
Whereas the United States have never done that.
And that's why it's obviously the, the choice
-- of criminal organizations.
-- Well, it's also a heck of a stable currency compared to
-- that.
-- Exactly.
That's,
that's important.
-- I'm sure part
-- you can't use Bitcoin for this.
That's
right. I mean, seriously.
But like, that's the thing, man, I don't think you can talk about, oh,
we need to move to all electronic currency and all this stuff.
But the reality. Yes.
-- Oh, to be clear,
-- I'm not a proponent of that. I'm not for that.
I'm just saying that that's where some of those countries are headed because
tax purposes, corruption purposes, just general whatever.
-- But
-- like at the end of the day,
if the United States is still letting people carry around bags of $100 bills, like
-- it doesn't matter.
-- This is this. I knew it was high but this is amazing.
Well, number one of all the currency, us, currency in circulation.
What
percentage of that do you think is $100 bills?
Oh, I bet it's like 30 or 40%?
-- 77. 0, no kidding?
-- Wow.
Now what percentage of those bills are overseas?
$100 bills? I bet 40%
80%. Holy crap. Let me ask you a question.
You live in work in America when the last time you saw $100 bill or used one?
-- Uh,
-- I run into a couple a year actually.
Right. Like Canada, we run on twenties. The whole economy runs on $20.
Usually what we have here when you have a 50 or 100 they're a pain in the butt and, like,
every now and then someone will give me one for some,
whatever reason they owe me money or something.
It's like, oh, crap. What am I going to do with this?
Yeah, I go to the bank and I, I,
yeah, I get a couple, you know,
I'll get hundreds when I travel because I just
don't want to carry a big wad of twenties.
But, um,
but fundamentally that's the only, like,
the number of times I see and touch 100 or a $50 bill here in Canada is literally, yeah,
it's like once or twice a year.
-- So
-- my funny story there is the first time I ever went to the UK,
I go to the bank and I'm like, oh, I need some pounds.
They said, you know, how much do you want?
I'm like, I don't know, a couple of 100 pounds and they gave me all fifties
and I didn't think anything of that
except I get there and everyone's like,
we're not taking that.
Like, nobody would take my money and I'm thinking this is a pain in the butt.
Well, it's kind of comical that the only people that really want to use the big bill,
the big currency bills are, are criminals because, you know,
they can't be carrying around a stack of $5 bills.
-- That's right.
And conversely they're probably also the only people that regularly
check and know how to check these things for authenticity,
I believe.
You know, that's always one of the terrors I have too is, like,
someone gave me $100 bill and then you bring it into the bank and they spent, like,
inspecting it and it's like, oh, if this thing is counterfeit, like,
what do I even do, you know?
Yeah, I'm out 100 bucks. Exactly.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's whatever.
I mean,
the thing that I think it boils down to
is most criminals are not creating new attacks.
Like,
I'm always amazed when I watch those Defcon talks
where these people are talking about elevator security or
car RF ID security or, you know, all the research they've done.
It's just, it's amazing and it's, it's literally one person, you know, spare time,
maybe a couple 100 hours spread out over a year. Right.
And they, they get some amazing work done, some results done
and,
yeah,
there's no way criminals are going to do that because if they could do
that they would just get a white collar job making a lot more money
in many cases. Yes. That is exactly correct.
There is probably very little money to be made in opportunistic crime.
I'm sure there's a lot of money that can be made in organized crime,
but that's obviously a whole another
can of worms.
I, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And then now at the same time I don't want to
blame the people doing the research as somehow making things worse
because
I think if they didn't do it, someone else would,
well, we'd stay there.
We'd still be having cars with no microchips in
the keys and you just jam a screwdriver.
You know, uh, what is it? The yellow wire in most cars?
The ignition wire is yellow and the other one is that I want to say blue. I have no idea.
I was just watching some videos on this.
The guys monkeying around with their vehicle immobilizers and whatnot because
it's not like there's some encrypted circuit between your battery,
your ignition switch and other stuff.
Like it's just a bunch of dumb wires and dumb relays.
Uh Probably I know, I know like nothing about cars.
You know, this isn't an Apple iphone where memory is encrypted and everything's,
you know, there's a security enclave.
Don't laugh.
I would not be shocked if Tesla or one
of those things have some sort of security enclave.
Tesla is a corner case. I think you'll agree that
respect to technology in cars. Right. Right.
And I mean, actually they're probably a good example though.
So if you stole a Tesla, what do you think would happen? Let's say you could steal it.
II, I imagine they've been stolen in the,
but my understanding is they basically have like GPS tracking and all of them.
-- Yeah,
-- they have, they have remote blah, blah,
blah, as
soon as you called up and said, someone stole my Tesla.
They'd be like, oh, there it is. Shut it down and then drive it home like, you know.
Yes. Ok. Well, the numbers are going up so in 2011, guess how many Teslas were stolen?
2011.
one
one.
-- Yeah.
-- And then six in 2013,
9, 15 in 2014, 9 in 2015,
28 in 2016, 57 in 2017 and 23 from January to May of 2018.
0, and
yet almost every stolen Tesla over these years has been recovered.
All except for three and I'm assuming those three stolen Teslas ended up in a lake or a
river or something.
They're in the lake
because one interesting thing with Tesla is I was watching some
uh some right to repair videos and they were talking about Teslas and
there's no secondary market for Tesla parts.
Like if you want to repair your Tesla yourself, not go to the dealership,
you basically have to go buy junk Teslas
-- and strip the parts out.
-- I believe
that and even that is
-- almost impossible to get a hold of.
-- I mean, so there, there's two sides to this.
First of all,
I think the people buying Teslas are going to be
the kind of people who bring them to the dealership because
that's just it, it's less work.
Well, I also feel like the problems that a Tesla is gonna have,
are not simple mechanical problems.
It's
subtle pain in the butt.
I mean, look, think about a, a gas car.
It has what, probably several 1000 moving parts.
At least. I think it's more than that.
It's, it's going, it's an enormous number and Teslas have
a dozen. Probably, like, they've got the four
motors on the wheels and you've got the
doors and the windshield wipers and then like,
what trunks?
I don't know. It's, it's a very small number though.
And so you're right when something goes wrong,
it's probably not a motor that's actually broken.
It's the computer under the driver's side door behind
the other computer taped to the top of the,
the floor or something.
Right. It's not something
you're going to see
normal mechanics operating
and religious. This one interesting
note is in 2016, at least the recovery rate for stolen vehicles was 58.4%.
-- That is, that is shockingly low to me.
-- Well, no, I think that's correct.
-- 40% of stolen cars just,
-- well, my guess is that
the ones they recovered were probably primarily kind of that.
I'm a kid, I'm stealing a car and I'm taking it on a joyride situation. Right.
Like, for example, I'm sure given the cold weather is here now
where you live,
the news people and police are saying stop leaving your car running
with the keys in it because someone's going to steal it.
Right. Which of course, we, we all still do.
So, one of the most popular stolen vehicles in Canada is the Ford F 150 pickup truck.
And I know anecdotally from uh two people that have had their stolen,
they stole the pickup truck, not to steal the pickup truck,
but to go steal a trailer of equipment.
Right? So they basically stole the pickup truck
and then use that to actually go steal a trailer of, you know, whatever was on it
and then, you know, the car ends up abandoned and trashed somewhere else
and that's recovered then.
Yeah.
Yes. That's funny.
And in fact, I,
I have several relatives who had their cars stolen
some because they left them running in the winter
where someone took the car on a joy ride and then they found it, you know,
later that day, parked in some parking lot, somewhere out of gas
and
it,
I, I get that right.
And my guess is the 40% that aren't recovered are
probably primarily like legitimate car thieves that are looking to
steal a car for parts or whatever it is. They do because let's face it.
No one's gonna steal a car and they keep it,
that's just not how this works. Not really. No.
Yeah, that would be dumb.
So, anyway,
uh, right. We, I know we focused on cars more than I'd hoped to in this, this instance.
But I, I feel like just kind of to to sum everything up all in all is just,
this is how adversaries work.
Adversaries by definition are always going to be a
step ahead of the defenders because by definition,
you're defending against an adversary.
If there's no adversary, you're not defending,
right? That's just that is the nature of it.
And so I think there's always going to be opportunistic criminals.
There's nothing we can do about that. And
as long as there are people which again, like rooting for the machines to take over.
But as long as there's people,
this is the way it's going to be because most of these opportunistic criminals
are taking advantage of weaknesses in people
more so than weaknesses in technology.
Well, I mean, if you have
somebody leaves their car running with the keys and short of having
like face ID to unlock the car and let them drive it,
you know, having some insane level of biometric security.
Uh, you, you can't,
you just can't fix that problem.
Yeah, that is correct. Yep. Yep.
Actually, if you want to know what really ticks me off. So, the,
our, our newer car, we have a Toyota minivan
and I can't start it and then exit it
and lock the doors with like the clicker.
They won't do it. You can only lock the doors from the inside with the button.
As soon as you open the doors,
it won't re lock them because obviously they don't
want you to lock your keys in the car.
But it's like it's freaking freezing. And I want to start my car in this parking lot.
Well, even my car does that. I have to, I, like, get in my car, start it,
lock the doors, like, click the locker to lock all the doors,
then open the door which unlocks it, push the button down and slam it
or I can use the key to lock the door.
But yeah, it's,
and I think that's a reasonable trade off for making
sure you don't lock your keys in the car.
I don't think I can do that even, I feel like I tried that. I'll have to try that again.
But yeah, and in fact, for what it's worth, like my, my pickup truck,
which has numerous mechanical problems because it's very, very old.
I've locked the keys in that thing running more times than I can count.
And I just, I, I have like a key hanging, it's in my desk
just, I know, not everyone knows.
I
feel like if somebody's rooting around your desk in your house,
the fact that they're looking for your car key is the least of your words.
-- Exactly.
But I mean, yeah, for real, like,
it's such a problem I have because for whatever reason,
like every now and then I'll start it and shut the door and like,
the auto lock enables.
Now, granted my auto lock is, it only works about 2% of the time.
But
I
don't, I don't think it's supposed to lock when I shut the doors either, but, like,
it doesn't happen enough.
I really care.
But like the one time it does it's like, oh, crap,
I did it again then I gotta go for the key.
But anyway, anyway, this is,
we're, we're in a rattle. All right, man, I'll give you the last word here.
What are your final thoughts on all this?
-- Uh
-- Keep your keys inside your house away from the door or window?
Uh
Sure, that seems like fair advice.
I mean, it, it again, eventually,
I expect auto manufacturers will solve this with technology.
But yeah, in the meantime,
just don't put your keys by the front door.
And I think honestly, that's probably good advice in general
because
if somebody is entering your house unwelcome,
is that a word?
Uh But if someone's entering your house,
they're probably gonna come in the front door and it's like, oh, look,
the keys are right there.
I'll just take these and go.
So even if it's not a wireless key f
All right. Anyway, wonderful. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up
on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks, everyone. Bye bye.