Hello, and welcome to the open source Security podcast.
Today is December the second and it's myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
See how I,
I was a little quicker this week than last week
and you gave the date which you've never done before.
So now people know when we're recording
as opposed to just guessing.
So
I
think,
I think it might be a useful thing to have.
It's possible and I think we're gonna stay a bit more topical this, this week.
So, having a date would certainly be useful,
as I'm sure in several 100 years when we have
researchers looking into what went wrong with society in 2016,
they can probably identify us as one of the major problems
doing
that.
So, I guess, I guess, do we want to start off with the bad news or the good news?
There's no good news. Current,
I think it's good news.
Good news.
Well, the fact that, uh, according to Krebs online or sorry, Krebs on security,
uh, apparently the, uh, the avalanche global fraud ring got dismantled a bit,
uh, yesterday.
That's good news,
you know.
And, uh,
so for those of you who don't know him
because I certainly don't really track this stuff.
Uh, there are, well,
there's a whole bunch of groups doing online fraud and
some of them are quite well organized and some of them
are quite prolific.
Like, uh, I don't know if people remember back in the two thousands, but, I mean,
there was like that one spammer.
What was his name? The spam house got sued by and sued him and uh
Bins
Blanky
called him the spam king,
the spam king guy.
I
need to remember.
Yeah.
And it was like,
wasn't he something like 80% of the global spam
at some point or just some absurd number?
It was insane. And I remember looking at graphs of when they shut him down, the only
spam it plummeted, it looked like, oh man, it was, it was a phenomenal graph.
But of course,
as history always shows you can shut down one bad guy and there's
a whole bunch of new ones just like waiting for their turn.
Well, you know, if there's a market for a service, somebody's gonna go provide it,
you know, like look at the,
look at
all this.
Yeah. So anyways, this avalanche global fro
ring,
um What, what I, what I'm kind of really impressed with is it,
it was something like three
major law enforcement groups plus a bunch of regional ones.
Uh So we had Europol, which is basically a European Interpol, right. It's, it's a,
it's
a,
a European wide
uh coordinating body and then we had something called Euro justs,
which I've actually never heard of before today.
Uh And they're basically another, um,
they're a judicial co-operation unit, which makes sense. Right?
Because, I mean, it's not just enough to catch these guys,
you have to prosecute them.
Right? And I assume that's where Euro just comes in,
you know, as coordinating prosecutions,
like who gets to take a crack at them and stuff.
Uh Of course, the FBI was there and then authorities from the UK,
Germany and uh I'm guessing, you know, other countries were involved as well.
Um
And like what I mean, just the scale of this, right is, you know,
830,000 web domains used in the scheme and, and it's actually worse than,
or not as bad as it sounds because these guys
use a technique called fast flux. And uh do you want to explain it
or shall
I have no idea what that even is?
So, basically, when you host a nasty malicious website,
eventually, either one of two things happens, um
typically,
like you're serving malware or something and that gets
flagged and then your domain gets flagged and blocked,
right?
Or, you know, somebody hits the uh like in Google Chrome, they hit like the whoa,
this site is really terrible.
Like it's fake, it's nasty, it's spam, it's malicious.
And again, the domain gets flagged and blocked.
So how do you avoid that? Well, you, you go through domains very, very quickly.
Like some of these guys are using domains for like tens of seconds,
right?
So there's, there's,
you can ban all these domains and it doesn't matter because they've already,
by the time you ban the domain and push that updated, you know,
ban list out these guys have moved on to another domain,
right? That
makes sense. I get that.
Yeah. And you know, because domains are basically, you know, cheap to free.
Uh But anyway, so they generate these domains and they use them very,
for very short amounts of time.
So banning them doesn't do anything, right?
Um They host, they also host them off of many, many, many different IP addresses.
So you also can't really, you know, ban the IP S reliably, right?
Because,
you know, if you have say
1000 infected servers, well, you know, that's,
that's a lot of IP S to ban and deal with and confirm.
So anyways, they basically dismantled this botnet uh slash crime group.
Um And what's really sort of terrifying to me is, uh
it's, they've only arrested five individuals,
five people
did all of this.
Yeah. Well, five people got caught doing this.
See, and something to remember is now, I mean,
again, a market is need, you know, there's a market for this so it's fulfilled,
you know, crime has outsourced stuff, right?
Like if you for example, want malware, you don't write it yourself. You, you,
you go to a board like a website,
you know, that's somewhere in the internet that none of us really know about.
You go there and um and you say I wanna, you know, I want malware that does this
right? And let's say you want something to target a new browser.
You go and buy a zero day, you hand it over to the guys making the malware and they,
they spin up a malware with a new zero day to attack stuff and
give you the finished product.
You know,
it's capitalism and its finest.
Exactly. So, I mean, the good news is they, uh, they did dismantle this one and it's,
I suspect a lot of it is from what I've seen of online crime,
there's a lot of people doing online crime
but the good news is, there's not that many people
in that.
Right.
Well, no, no, I mean, globally, like there's, there's, you know, tens of thou,
like the whole Nigerian 419 scam stuff.
Right. There's thousands of people in Nigeria doing this.
I
don't
know. Yeah.
Oh, yeah. No, I was, I was watching a documentary on it.
There's just cyber cafes full of these guys,
right. Just pounding out emails, you know, manually.
So, like I said,
the good news is most of these scammers and hackers and whatnot are not that good
and, you know, part of it.
Is, they don't have to be that good to make a living, you know,
and especially in some of these countries, you know, a couple of $1000 a month,
you can live like a king.
So
anyways, the good news is, um, they, they, they took apart this, uh, this ring and,
I mean, there's a, we'll link to the show notes will link to the, uh,
the Krebs on security
article.
Um, but what's really interesting to me is, you know, these Attackers are, you know,
they're building like three
tier
application crime models, basically,
you know, like they have their front end,
they have like a middle layer to do proxy and to
hide themselves and then they have like an actual back end
where like they live, you know, and, and that's what these, uh,
the investigators had to get through, you know, these,
the front end through the proxy layer to actually find out where these guys are,
you know, who are they, you know, to hunt them down and arrest them.
That's
crazy.
So, I mean,
I guess the good news is this shows it can be done.
Um, you know, it kind of reminds me of so this week, uh,
somebody parked in front of my driveway and, you know, there's a simple process.
I phoned the non-emergency police line, uh,
navigate the menu, treat a parking enforcement
and, uh, give them the make and model of the car and the license plate and then,
you know, about 2030 minutes later,
a parking enforcement car shows up and then usually the person
comes and moves their car rather than get a ticket.
Now, if, if
so they'll write a ticket, will they tow the car?
If nobody moves it
in certain situations,
they will just take it and in some situations they will tow the car.
So for example, if the car is blocking a driveway,
which depends on how much it's blocking, they'll tow it.
-- Or for example, if it's in like a handicap spot
-- and was your,
was your particular perpetrator blocking enough of your driveway
to justify a tow or just a ticket?
Uh, I think they would have towed it, but like I said, nine times out of 10,
somebody pops out of their,
-- somebody pops out of their house and like, you know, moves the car,
-- did they,
-- did they move it before they got a ticket or do they still
-- got a ticket?
Yeah. As soon as the parking enforcement car pulled up, the guy came out
and to move the car,
-- would
-- you
a ticket?
He should still got a ticket.
No, but basically, I mean, a lot of parking enforcement boils down to, it's,
it's less about, you know,
handing out tickets and more about getting people not just to not park like maniacs.
No,
-- no,
-- no. The point is
the government sent out this person
to enforce the law
-- and the purpose of fines is to pay for the enforcement
-- right, to enforce the bylaw.
It's not a law, it's a bylaw.
This isn't a cop, right. This is just a person who can write tickets. Right.
So,
I don't know, it's how the system works and, and more to the point fundamentally,
from a quality of life perspective.
I, I got what I wanted, which is to use my driveway.
It's upsetting to me that you lacked retribution against this person
who's
part
of
you,
that they should get a fine,
they should get a fine because maybe they'll think about not doing it in future.
Right?
And,
and clearly this is a person who has no regard for the rules of
society that are necessary to keep it
functioning in a civilized and reasonable manner.
Yeah, I would agree.
But on the flip side, I mean, it, you know,
it's like people who constantly complain about speeding tickets, right?
There's like a large segment of society that sees speeding
tickets as like a cash grab by the police.
Well, to a degree,
you can argue that like there's a small city in Wisconsin where I live
called. Uh, is it Rosendale? I think it is. And
they are well known for having speed traps throughout the
city because there's basically the this relatively high speed highway
that runs literally through the city and you have to
slow down to about half the speed to go,
to go through town and then you should be back up
and they have way more police per capita
than it's necessary by, like, any stretch of reasonable policing.
And clearly they have that because they're handing out tickets, like they're candy
and I guess
in, in one, in one way good for them, you're, uh, essentially you found a loophole to
do something. Right. But, but at the same time it's, it's also, this is,
this is how society has to work. If you have a road that goes through your town,
you can't have people driving 70 miles an hour through the middle of your small town,
somebody is going to get hit and die.
Right.
The, the correct solution. Mind you is to just have the highway go around the city.
But of course, no one wants to pay for that.
It's, this is, this is not unlike running a corporation right where you can.
There's the right way.
There's a way we do it now and there's something we
have to decide that is good enough to get us by
without ruining anything for anyone
or spending any money.
Right. Or making money in some cases
handing out tickets.
Yeah,
I don't know.
I mean, yeah,
part of me definitely wouldn't mind these
people getting a ticket because quite frankly,
it's easy to not park in front of somebody's driveway.
Like, especially this is what drives me nuts.
It's not like my street is parked up, there's probably
30 to 50%
Ok. So
-- this was not the only parking space. No,
-- no, no.
That, that person
is a monster curt.
That person is a monster and they should be punished for their terrible behavior.
Yeah.
Well,
part of me is always thought about letting my
kids play in the driveway with a bowling ball.
That would be acceptable also. Yeah. Give that, give them BB guns or something.
Right.
Shoot that car.
Yeah. So, like I said, I guess the good news is that there is the occasional hope that,
you know, a botnet or a crime syndicate can be broken up online, but
it's not the occasional hope. Look. I mean, this is how it goes. Right.
There's always an ebb and flow to crime where the bad guys will get ahead for
a period of time and then the good guys will do something to disrupt their business.
And of course,
now there will be some slowdown of illicit activity of this nature and then in
probably a couple of weeks, I doubt it'll take longer than that.
Someone else will show up and replace it and the cycle begins again.
It's just, it's how it's been throughout history in all seriousness.
Well, I'm actually more concerned will this actually have any impact?
I'm sure it will
be
a short period of time,
but long term. Absolutely not, this will just be replaced by something else.
And, you know, there is somebody who has been waiting for this to happen,
that's just ready and they're gonna go to town as soon as it is.
Yeah.
No, I, I, yeah, I don't know because, I mean, moving away from the good news,
there's more bad news this week.
There is
the,
and how are we pronouncing it?
I've heard Mira,
I
don't,
the
botnet
formerly known,
I
don't know
the Mira botnet which everyone I'm sure can reckon M Ira. I,
yeah.
Um, so, yeah,
apparently it was going and attacking about
a million German broadband routers on port.
What was it? 7547. So I'm guessing that thing has some default credentials.
It, I don't know if it's default credentials or, or what is,
it's some sort of management port
that is used by the I SPS to do stuff to the equipment.
And obviously they're doing it on a public interface because it's being attacked
from the internet
and then just kind of ruining
the routers for these people.
It sounds like they're just kind of knocked off line
and there's nothing they can do until they replace it.
What is not very well known server on port 7547
is also a tr 064 server uh landside CB configuration.
Uh And it's got a bunch of commands kind of like um so you can, you know, device info,
get info Wlan configuration,
uh proof of concept exploit basically consists of,
oh the, the proof of concept basically consists of go talk to it
and tell it to do stuff.
Yeah.
Uh, precautions they could have taken. Um,
yeah, like,
yeah, this thing is just,
uh, wide open, basically. Great. Awesome. See, that's what frustrates me. Right.
Is I have, you know, I have internet at home obviously
and, um, you know, I for sure do not trust the routers modems,
whatever I've been given by my ISP because, you know,
I have no idea what they're doing.
No, I, I agree with you completely. And in fact, I
am a customer of an ISP that lets me purchase my own equipment.
And so I gladly did that and, and granted
renting it from them is significantly more expensive than just buying.
But it pleases me that I, I know it's not.
Well, I shouldn't say that right,
because I'm sure they're pushing firmware and
doing goodness knows what to my router,
but at least the router is just a router and it doesn't
have any ports on it or anything like that for being,
being the, the access point and all that fun.
So then I obviously acquired my own access point slash gateway
that does all of the magic there
for, for the exact reason you mentioned is I I these service providers are,
if you're a security person,
they are historically will say uh less than ideal for our needs and wants.
Yeah,
I gotta admit my solution for my second backup
link is everything over it goes through a VPN provider
because I can't control the, uh,
you know, I can, I can purchase the modem from them but I can't purchase my own modem.
Right.
They have to, uh,
they don't allow that for whatever reason.
And so, yeah, I just have everything go through a VPN and I have a firewall that blocks
everything outgoing except to the VPN provider.
I love it.
Although, did you, uh, there was, there was a news story about how terrible
the VPN providers all were because they were using like horrible
static passwords for encrypting the data as it travels over there.
I,
I assume that for,
you know,
I mean,
actually the one I'm using, they support certificates as well,
they use open VPN obviously and they support
certificates.
Um, I mean, yeah, they do use static passwords but I mean, you know, I,
I generated some ridiculously long password for my account.
Well, no, no, no. The, the problem being that the way some of this VPN traffic works
is you have a pre shared key between the server and client
and the pre shared keys were comically bad
between.
So it was basically you could, you could break a,
a significant amount of the traffic that was kind of traveling over the wire
between
the, the clients and servers.
Yeah, I've always wondered because the majority,
when I looked into VPN providers is that really helpful?
Actually,
we should probably link to that in the show notes that VPN comparison spreadsheet.
Uh I don't know if you, if you Google like VPN comparison spreadsheet, uh
it'll be in the, uh,
you get this really nice huge list listing like, uh oh yeah,
the official name for it is that one privacy guy's VPN comparison charts?
Uh And so anyways, you know, and it's got lovely thing, um, like, uh you know,
how much they cost and like what, you know, do they, well,
what they claim to say about logging data, not logging data and all that.
Um,
but yeah, I mean, none of these things I've ever seen listed, sort of like, how,
how competent are they?
I, I would
always, I would
-- assume it's one
-- guy,
they're not competent
because that'll just get you in trouble.
Yeah. So,
well, there's a good question.
How do you properly validate the security of a VPN provider?
You don't?
And even if
they tell you things, there's a significant amount of trust,
you have to just put in their word
because
how do you prove
they're not logging data? How do you prove that they're storing passwords safely?
How do you prove that their certificate key wasn't generated, you know,
on some guy's laptop with SSH ports open to the end,
like you can't prove any of this stuff.
And so this, this is a huge challenge and in fact, this exists
in
a number of places where your,
your hosting provider you use on the internet your operating system provider,
your computer manufacturer,
you have to draw a line at some point and just say,
I'm putting my trust in the organization up to here
and anything past that you have no control over and
you just have to admit that it is what it is
-- and it, it's sort of terrifying in a lot of ways.
-- Right.
Well, it's getting better because, for example, um, I mean,
one of my favorite things I did you ever watch the DNS E key signing ceremony?
-- Because they broadcast it online for everybody?
-- Completely absurd.
-- Oh, yeah.
-- No, it's security theater. But, you know, they're
like,
they're at least giving a degree of transparency
and attempting to be open and honest.
Right.
You know, it's like the certificate, uh, logging reports. Right.
Like all these providers that are issuing certificates and in past
they would issue certificates and not tell anybody that they
issued a certificate other than obviously to the customer,
they issued it to,
you know, and then Google finds, like, because they do certificate pinning,
they find like, oh,
here's a bunch of Google certificates that we did not buy.
You know, and they write from, uh, I forget who it was.
Well, it's been a couple of providers
and so,
you know, I think a lot of
the future security. I mean, here's the reality. Right.
Writing secure code that, that has not worked out for us.
It is impossible to write security for humans,
let's clarify that for humans to write secure code
when the A is take over,
I will, I won't say they can do it,
but they might be able to do it whereas humans are in absolute cannot do that.
So I think a lot of what the future model of
security is gonna have to be around is around transparency.
You know, like
what, how did we do this?
You know, here's like, here's the steps we took to generate the key,
you know, and at least, you know, because I've, I, I,
I've also encountered situations where I've asked somebody,
how did you configure this or why did you configure this it this way?
And they don't have an answer and that immediately is a huge red flag.
You know what I mean?
Like if you can't tell me why or what you did or why you did something,
then chances are you did it wrong?
That's a reasonable argument. I think.
However, I'll still say that
let's pick on DNS sec.
In this case is apart from, we can argue the merits of DNS ec none of people will say,
but just focusing on the key signing like
they can,
they can do this theater
and it's recorded and whatever, and you can,
you can verify that the key signing the route is the same thing,
but then it still can kind of fall apart after that
because now you, you, you still have various layers of trust that have to exist.
And it's,
yeah,
I don't know. I mean, ii, I,
at
-- some
-- point we have to trust people. Right.
We can't very like, like food safety is a great example. Right?
This is one of the reasons I love living in
uh a boring country like Canada.
We have a very solid food safety system.
You know,
we have agricultural inspection agencies.
We have uh, you know, I, I know a person who is a food inspector,
it's a four year college.
Here's the deal. And actually you just brought up a great example because
food inspection
is not done by the organization
creating the,
typically
you have some sort of independent inspector and verify,
you have regulations that dictate it.
Exactly. And so I think that's really the important part.
Everyone always talks about this, you know, self regulating and what that's crap.
Right.
When you self regulate,
that means we like regulation until it gets in the way and then it's dumb.
And
I
think you always need external auditors otherwise you do encounter definitely
the, the conflict of interest is unavoidable.
Yes, absolutely.
Even with auditors, the conflict of interest is a problem because, um,
you know, their, their client is paying them to audit them and they wanna, you know,
obviously get repeat business.
So
I don't know if you remember that certificate Authority in Holland a few years ago
that was found to be completely virus ridden and like their key lived on,
like, basically a workstation attached directly to the internet.
Like, it was just comically terrible,
but they passed an audit, you know,
from one of the major accounting firms that does these things.
Right.
So,
anyway,
I think I,
so to me it kind of falls down to two things
and this is one thing where transparency helps is number one,
ideally we have, you know, some form of base level auditing best practices.
I mean, you know, as, as much as people hate PC I and PC I DS S,
it's better than nothing,
you know.
And then the second thing is is when the failures happen, catching them quickly
as quickly as possible. You know, like,
uh a great example being the, the, the, the Tylenol poisoning
way back in the eighties, right?
Um It took them a while to figure out what was going on because, well,
part of it is something like this had never happened before, right?
It was just, it was unthinkable.
It would literally,
they're investigating these crimes and they're like
treating it as like murders and,
you know, trying to put it into the existing framework of reality.
Whereas no, it's just some
crazy
person.
We should clarify for the people who aren't old
about the story you're telling about the Tylenol poisonings from the eighties.
So
let, let's start here. I'll, I'll start, I'll, I'll set the stage
and then I'll let you, uh, take it home is. So a long time ago
they would sell
well, well, Ty Tylenol, I guess in this case, drugs,
drugs in general at the drug store
would be on the shelf and there was no like safety seal on it.
So you could literally just open up the, the case
and take out some drugs if you wanted.
Like, like for example, if you had Aspirin or, or Tylenol, in this case,
you could just open them and, and take them out or put them in for that matter. Right.
There was no such concept as a safety seal which now we're all very familiar with.
Well, it's, and just to clarify it's there, there were seals and things,
but they didn't show if they'd been opened or not.
Right. You could open a package and rec close it and it wouldn't
really show us, you know, it wouldn't be obvious that it had been opened and closed.
Right. Right.
And so now we bring ourselves to
the Tylenol poisoning incident.
-- Yeah.
-- So someone, uh, and they've never been caught.
Basically, somebody put cyanide in these, uh, Tylenol,
you know, bottles
and what's really, uh,
well, I mean,
unfortunately some people died but the good news is
the company that owns Tylenol Johnson and Johnson,
you know, they handled it properly,
right. They did a nationwide recall of all the Tylenol.
Uh, and the other cool thing is,
uh, well, not cool really,
but cyanide shows up on x rays for some reason it's dense or whatever.
So they took all the Tylenol,
they were pulling off the shelves and running it through airport X ray scanners.
That's crazy.
You know,
and then they invented
tamper proof and tamper evident packaging.
Right. Right. Ok. So I pulled up the Wikipedia page for those of you interested.
There were seven deaths and it was in, uh started September 29th, 1982.
So that's,
that's quite some time ago,
you know, but the beauty is now as a result of that, we have
packaging laws that, you know, make, have made things much, much safer,
you know, as a lot like that. But,
and, you know, unfortunately, though we needed, I mean,
things have to get bad typically before people, you know,
realize they're bad enough to need fixing.
Um, and I'm, I'm kind of wondering if we're getting to that point on the internet now.
I
-- don't
-- know,
we're even close,
we're not even close and, and I know you're aware that I've,
I started doing research actually into industrial safety
compared to
iot security
and looking for parallels.
And I have gone down a rat hole like I did not expect to happen, but
I'm now researching various industries and how bad it got before they got better.
And I'm gonna put together a nice talk to, to kind of give on this.
But, but fundamentally speaking, like
we aren't even close to bad enough when you look at things like environmental
protections or food safety or worker safety or auto safety or airline safety or
like literally things were exploding and people were dying before anyone cared.
And even then it took a while before people really cared.
I mean,
literally on the internet until things are physically exploding and people are
dying and a lot of them are going to have to,
nobody is going to care.
And the thing that scares the crap out of me though about this is
you look at cybercrime
and it is going to be in their best interest
to make sure nothing lights on fire and kills people.
They wanna make it bad enough, they're gonna make their money but not so bad.
Anyone fixes it.
And I think that's where we're stuck at today is,
it's bad enough that Cybercrime can make money,
but it's not so bad. Anyone's willing to fix it.
Yeah. Well, and, and part of my real concern is with self driving cars, right?
Because traditionally computers have been in things or controlled things,
uh, that are not very mobile.
You know, like with the exception of, uh, well, I say planes and trains and ships,
right.
Uh, and now cars, but, you know, we've never give them sort of that
autonomy and connected them to the internet directly.
Ok. There's, there's that, but let's also think about planes and ships
specifically because those are very computer controlled,
but they're also not the sort of thing that the general public owns.
Right.
These are things that are controlled by organizations that have
a specific interest in ensuring a certain amount of safety.
Right.
And that's gonna be the trick with cars is if we let anybody buy a self driving car,
anybody can do anything, they want to a self driving car.
But if you have an organization that has certain
requirements around safety and security,
then it changes the game and I know this is gonna open a crazy discussion.
It's something to think about.
Well, one thing I think about is you can already build a self driving car, right.
Google has, um, various inventors have done it.
You know, you could also definitely build a remote control car, right?
And use it to cause all sorts of mayhem and chaos.
The reality is to get it working, you know,
you need a certain level of sophistication that most,
you know, bad guys probably don't have or care about because
here's one thing to keep in mind, right? Is with a self driving car using it for crime.
It's still sort of tricky to monetize that. Right. I mean, yeah, I would certainly,
you know, uh, you could certainly do some things like, uh,
blackmail people or cause, you know, denial of service style attacks,
but to actually turn a self driving car into a money making thing
criminally,
you know,
-- it's, I, I, well, people will find a way
-- I'm sure ransomware, dude.
Right. Ransomware could certainly be one.
But, but here's, here's the thing I always am concerned with,
with self driving cars.
It's, let's say
we have self driving cars taking over the world.
There's no more people and all the self driving cars,
talk to each other and they all know what's going on.
And so for example,
we don't need traffic lights anymore because
the cars magically deal with intersections.
What happens when I decide I'm special,
my car isn't going to stop at the intersections anymore.
And now I have the only car that never has to stop
when it's traveling because all the other cars are willing to stop.
I would assume those cars would report that activity to the police, right?
Because see one thing and I hate like one thing I'm I'm wondering about, for example,
if you have a few percent of self driving cars on the roads,
uh let's say on the highway, what happens when they start
providing telemetry data on other cars to the police saying, you know,
here's this car that went zooming by me.
I was going this fast, this other car was going
100 miles an hour.
Here is video of it happening. Here is a high resolution video of the driver
as they went by good side profile.
Here's their license plate and all that
or
maybe not the police.
But what happens when they start providing that data to the insurance companies?
-- I think the eff is crying in the corner right now.
-- Kurt.
Oh,
yeah. No, I, I sort of am too but
I, one thing that gets me is our fundamental view of what is privacy,
you know, and what is
public is, is going to change so drastically because
there's going to be all these
machines with computers and, you know, liar, light sensors, cameras,
sonar like God only knows what kind of stuff,
you know.
Um I've heard talk of having biometric recognition so that you can
have automated billing when you get in and out of the car,
you know, so you don't even need to put your smartphone out
things like that. Right?
And so I'm I at some point, for example,
like I assume a self driving car service provider, you know,
is going to start monetizing that data
because they would be insane not to
right
from a business perspective.
I hate to say it, but if you have data that you can sell to an insurance company
for a million bucks a year or 10 million bucks a year, well,
they're probably going to do it.
Well, and I feel like this is one of those places where
laws aren't keeping up with reality.
I think in this case, it's worse than that.
Laws aren't even aware of these realities.
That's true. Right? Like like a great example being Bruce Schneier
talking in front of, what was that? The US Senate or the US Congress testifying.
Right.
And he's pointing out to these people that you have to stop
thinking about these things as a self driving car with a computer,
you need to start thinking about these things as a
computer living in a car with four wheels that controls.
Right. Right.
Like your fridge, your fridge is no longer a fridge with a computer. You,
it's a computer that happens to have a fridge wrapped around it that it can control.
Not my fridge, man,
I'm
the last person with a non
-- IOT
-- fridge. A great example is all these smart TV S that are apparently just garbage.
Right?
Every time I read about smart TV S online,
all I hear and all I've experienced is like they're so slow, right?
You turn them on and it takes a minute or two for these things to get, you know,
to youtube or Netflix.
Mine takes 12 seconds
because I had to configure my harmony remote
to work with uh turning on the TV. And then jumping to my myth TV machine,
uh switching inputs and it's 12 seconds from the time
I turn it on until I can switch inputs.
But now I recognize the risk to this and I have a special network,
wireless network set up that it connects to
that literally, this TV sees the internet and nothing else.
But granted most people don't do that.
But uh I mean,
that's the thing right is like we've already crossed that, you know, uh,
river with TV, S, all TV.
S now have a computer
to some degree. Right. And, but the good news is TV. S can't, like,
fall off the wall and kill you or, you know,
-- generally they can't set themselves on fire
-- or, you know, I would bet you,
you could get a TV to light on fire.
I bet it wouldn't be
for sure. Probably don't have hardware safeties and fuses and cut offs.
I bet you could. Yeah.
Yeah,
I bet you could do things with the display and like maximum brightness and just,
like, go to town on that sucker.
I bet. I bet you could light it on fire.
Well, see, and here's one example of a really something that would be not super fun,
you know, imagine a botnet gets into a whole bunch of smart TV.
S and they just start wi fi jamming.
Yeah,
-- I
-- suppose
that that would be really quite
so, here's the deal though is
there's no money to be made
in that activity.
-- Ransomware, denial of service. Right. Except
-- you can't un
ransomware that because it's, it's denial,
the service in itself,
you
know, like for an hour and then you put a message on the TV saying,
would you like your Wi Fi back
or, I guess you could even say, do you want your TV back? Right?
I mean, you know, send, send $10 to this Bitcoin address and you get your TV.
Back and let's face it. It's like, yeah,
it's easier than buying a new TV.
So, no, it's, and that's, that's the thing.
Like, so I've actually decided I'm, I'm purposely avoiding
things with computers in them unless, like,
they really need to have a computer in them.
You know? I probably can't even buy a toaster without a computer in it now.
Well, let me rephrase a computer that connects to the internet.
That's fair.
-- That's fair.
-- You know, because
I'll make a few exceptions.
Like, I,
I really do love my bathroom scale that I have all the data charted automatically.
Um,
you know,
but fundamentally, yeah, I'm avoid,
I like every time I go to Home Depot now
I avoid the home automation aisle because I'm just,
I'm, I know it's tempting,
you know, that thing's a train wreck and most of it phones home besides.
So, you know, it's like doubly bad.
Yeah. Well, like those, uh, Android phones that had that, uh,
malware that was phoning home to China and giving apparently all the data like S
MS emails.
-- So
-- here's the deal with that. And this, I've been thinking about this a lot because
is phoning home to China
any worse than phoning home to Google or Apple,
which is what these phones currently do today.
I guess it sort of depends on.
Well, for example, myself, I live in North America so I would prefer that they
phone home to a jurisdiction that I'm in because if there is some legal problem,
I have a, a
faint hope or possibility of legal redress.
Whereas with China, I mean, it's just, there's no way it would be worth my time.
Whatever, man. If, if you wanted to go after say the, the producer of your phone,
we, we won't identify the company.
They, what would you honestly do? Even if you hired a lawyer, they probably
and do nothing. A class action lawsuit. Whatever, man.
I, I,
no, actually so funny enough you mentioned that is, there's, uh,
I, this is something that I,
I wonder about a lot and I've spoken with a handful of lawyers about is
it's not that easy to sue people because it turns out at least in,
in the United States, I can't speak for Canada,
which I think it's even harder to sue people in Canada than it is here. But
without the ability to show physical harm of some way,
like monetary harm alone is not acceptable for a lawsuit.
And so, and how many people, I mean, other than Samsung phone owners,
can anyone show physical harm from their phone?
Well, actually in Canada there is a class action lawsuit taking place, um,
around the Apple iphone six and six plus, uh, so-called Touch disease.
Uh, where apparently the screen starts to
-- not work.
-- Yes, but that's physical harm, right?
Because you have a physical good that you paid money for that no longer works.
It's different when something is just shipping data across the country or world.
Right. There's no
physical
-- would be,
-- the data privacy laws would be in violation that
Europe
does have data privacy laws. And so they might have some advantage there.
But again,
do you think this company is probably selling in Europe?
And if they are, what would they do,
they probably just stop selling in Europe because they're already,
I'm sure making a fortune selling, you know,
crap phones to people in the United States.
No, I hate to say it, but I suspect,
II, I really can't see any option other than regulation to force the market
to be incentivized,
to make, you know, these things more secure
and, and
I don't disagree with you,
but the challenge with regulation is regulation
always is like years behind what's happening
and we're at a point now where you think about two years ago,
what technology looked like and
it is
unidentifiable by today's standards. And you think in two more years
there's gonna be stuff we can't even imagine
that's gonna be commonplace.
Well, you could see the thing to remember too is you can always regulate
uh how to explain it. You can sort of re
regulate the behaviors more than say the technology.
So for example, I think it was in Britain
rather than coming up with regulations for every single, you know, illegal drug.
Uh they either were talking about or have I I should check, but basically
any psychoactive substance,
which, I mean, uh, you know, that's like, also,
I guess technically includes toilet bowl cleaner,
um, which you should never drink, by the way, let's be clear on that.
Um,
but so, rather than, you know,
come up with these new laws for every single drug because these
drugs keep getting tweaked and produced in China and then mailed,
you know, to the UK,
they just all psychoactive substances.
And I suppose, for example,
you could look at blanket regulations like anything that
uh well, and to be fair, they already did this with the uh the computer abuse act.
Remember it was like any system that stores transmits or processes data,
right? Yeah, that's, that's true.
You know, so and I mean, let's face it, right?
By defining it as a system that stores processes or transmits data. I mean,
that's everything,
you know, there's, I can't imagine
it is now.
So this, I mean, so that's it. It's a good example actually is
I would bet you most of us commit
felonies every day by the C FAA standards, right?
And
it's terrifying
to think about some of that and, and now granted there's certain like sanity
that exists in the courts to a degree. But
I mean, this is one of the hard things is how do we solve some of this?
And some people talk about regulation. Some people talk about liability.
Some people talk about insurance some people talk about guarantees.
And I think here's what I always come back to is that
these problems are too new for us to understand how we're going to fix them.
And I'm not saying we shouldn't try and I'm not saying people
shouldn't be talking about regulation and
people shouldn't be talking about liability.
But
the problem I see is by the time we think we understand what's going on,
everything is changed and now we have to rethink our way through this
stuff and by the time you make it through that everything's changing again.
And so this is like the ultimate game of Kelvin Ball.
The world is playing with itself and we're currently losing
badly.
So for those of you who don't know,
Calvin Ball is from the uh comic strip Calvin and Hobbs.
And, uh, if I remember correctly,
the idea was that Calvin Ball had no rules except for all the rules it had,
which constantly changed.
And so you get scores of like 17 to purple losing.
Right. Right.
And, and so what, what it really is is, it's about whoever can think of the best rules,
the fastest wins.
Right. And Kelvin always lost
because
-- everyone else came up with
-- the
point too is even if you come up with good rules, you still have to enforce them.
-- Right?
-- And the bad guys just make up new rules. Right.
-- Yeah.
-- Or they move somewhere where they can't be enforced.
Yep. Yep. Yeah. Well, heck, we have that already. I mean,
look at, look at the countries, these,
these criminal organizations are typically running out of now.
Right. They're in countries that
are willing to
overlook or just don't care about, you know, kind of computer abuse law.
Yeah. Or they,
well, I remember, oh, there was a, I remember back in the day this, uh,
they finally caught this Taiwanese guy that wrote some really massive virus.
Uh but there were no laws against it in Taiwan.
And so he ended up going and doing his military service and getting a job in it,
I believe,
you know.
Um,
and, you know, and, and quite rightly, I mean, unless you can, I guess,
extradite him to a country where it is against the law.
But, you know, most countries won't extradite unless you've broken
something that is comparable to their laws. Right.
Most of them will say,
like it also has to be an offense in our country to a comparable degree because,
you know, um, there's a lot of countries with a lot of crazy laws.
Like you can't, you know,
in many countries, you can't say things about the leader of the country,
-- you know,
-- very democratic countries. Right.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
yeah. No, it's, I, I hope that we get
regulation. I'm not sure that it would even work, even if we had good legislation.
I'm not sure it would work because there's the enforcement angle.
Right. Well, and,
and not only that, let's think about open source.
Now,
how does open source fit into this story where
you don't necessarily have a company behind something?
You've got like a dude in his basement who wrote the image library that,
that has a remote execution issue in it.
Now, like, what do you do?
Well, the thing that always gets me fundamentally open source
will need to be able to disclaim liability in some way, which it already does. Right.
-- You know, you agree to use the software and basically not sue us
-- if it be a
single piece of software
liability waiver.
And that's the second point, right?
Is if open source can do it,
why can't the close source guys and the commercial guys do it?
So, no, the point being though that the closed source guys,
I think we're doing this first.
Well, they ha, well, the thing is you can't
for open source and in general for the, the software,
the current software industry to survive,
it can't be liable
for every little thing because I, I've seen cases where, you know,
somebody does something stupid that, yeah,
maybe their computer shouldn't have let them do.
But fundamentally, you know,
they kind of brought it upon themselves and for example, didn't have backups
and then, you know, they want to sue for business losses,
which as we found out are very difficult to do,
-- however,
-- it has been done physical damage.
A lady sued Microsoft for forced windows update and got away with it, like,
managed to get it through.
But again,
it goes back to that sort of damage thing where they forced a windows 10 update,
that kind of bricked or laptop or whatever.
Um
So part of me, as much as I say, I would want regulate, like,
and obviously I want like magical fairy unicorn
regulations that are actually correct and good,
which is probably not what we're going to get.
Um, but even assuming, you know, we get that. How, yeah, how do you have that, um,
that disclaimer or that opt out for open source?
So that open source doesn't get killed,
you know.
Well, it's not even about open source getting killed.
Everyone is using open source today.
There's
like my TV,
it comes with a special screen that shows all of the,
the, the licenses in libraries inside
my car. Does that. Now, I got a car with the touch screen a couple of weeks ago.
And how do you show
the
open source?
Like, shouldn't you be able to write them a letter to get a CD or something?
-- I would be very curious if anybody on the planet has done this.
-- I should do that.
I should look actually if I, I got a Toyota
and
I should, I should see if they, if they make that available.
They legally have to, don't they?
Well, legally have to and just ignoring me is
two very different things,
right?
And this is, I mean, this is part of the regulation challenge, right? Is
you can make laws telling people to do things,
but you need a way to enforce the things that
need to be done because if nobody's enforcing them,
you effectively have no regulation.
-- Yeah,
-- I don't know. I mean, what, what do our show listeners think?
You know?
So let's, let's assume for a moment,
let's pause it and this is not entirely unlikely, I think,
but let's assume for a moment
that we will never have regulations at
all to apply to this because they either just don't get done or they,
by the time they get done it's like 20 years from now.
Oh, sweet. I can finally buy that monkey.
Yeah. Um,
well, I mean, more specifically with, uh, with it, security type problems.
But, um, you know, what does the world look like?
How do we keep it from catching on fire?
You know,
and I'll be honest part of what I'm trying to do with the,
the common vulnerabilities and exposures.
The, the CV stuff
is honestly one of my goals in life is to flip it right now. Generally speaking CV.
S are seen as bad. You messed up. You have a security flaw, bad, bad, bad.
Right. Whereas, you know, it, it, in my opinion should be the opposite. Good.
You found a security flaw and fixed it. I mean, and obviously
it only works if people fix these things, right?
But my, you know, because I look at these vendors like, um
you know, Google Chrome Firefox, right?
They're great examples uh Internet Explorer safari, right?
These browsers all have tons of CV S
that they fix, right?
Uh The most recent one being Firefox fix that zero day, that's, you know,
being exploited.
Uh I think by law enforcement actually,
um which suspected,
suspected, sorry.
Um
And so, in my opinion, you know, you know,
those are the web browsers I wanna use because
they have security flaws that they fix quickly versus
I figured it out.
You just need to pre assign
300 CV I DS to every software project on the planet.
And, you know, the ones that fill them all out,
look for all the issues and the ones that didn't,
didn't care enough to look for all the security problems that occur in their code.
You know,
you, you say that, I think in Jest, but I
-- told the worst idea I've heard all week.
-- It's half crazy.
I'm writing this
down
as
well.
And this
is to
me, we, we already do this to a degree with the CN A si mean, a great example being Mier
actually sent out an email, me
or the company that, you know, manages the CV database ultimately
sent out an email saying, you know,
reminding us all to get our 2017 CV S because come January 1st,
we're gonna start naming them
and
I, you know, requested the block
and uh it was up in the 27 hundreds.
That's awesome, man.
It's
amazing.
So like, yeah, these vendors, these CNAs do care and
you know, and if you look at who are CNAs, you know,
it's major companies that do care about security, like
Microsoft Red Hat, IBM Apple, you know, they, they have security process,
they have security updates.
And what sort of worries me is when I look at these vendors, especially big ones that
I don't know if they have a security process,
they certainly don't have CV S that they've requested, you know,
they might have had them assigned to them by somebody else.
Um,
and so to me, it becomes actually a very good metric is more CV S fixed obviously
because the reality is the software is gonna have flaws. That's just a given,
right.
The question is,
how quickly do they fix them? How, you know, robust, do they make the software? How
do they do stuff to avoid CV S in future? Right.
But the reality is we all have so much technical debt. Like,
um, you know, even the open BS D people still have CV S even SSH, you know,
this year had a couple of CV S and, you know, two of them were pretty bad,
you know, but they fix them really fast and they pushed out updates really
work.
And
I think that's where the,
the good
industry, players have figured out that it's not about prevention.
It's about speed more than anything.
Right.
I mean, you, yes, prevention is certainly something you should focus on as well. But
it's really about just being able to move fast.
Well,
I think the truth is you can do all the prevention in the
world you want but you will still have house fires to deal with.
You will still have somebody
either doing a bug bounty or a bad guy,
right? Because if your software is popular, the bad guys are gonna poke at it.
That's, it's just how it is, right? Because there's value there.
And so whether or not
you like it, I mean, open SSH is a great example.
Like they've done prevention for over a decade, maybe two decades now.
You know, they, they pioneered concepts like privilege separation, right?
They, they had a small core part of Open SSH that ran as a privileged user
and it's like
only a couple 1000 lines of code and then it immediately
gets out of that privileged thing as fast as it can,
you know.
Um
And yet they still have, you know, CVS that they have to react to.
So I think the thing is, yeah, no matter how much prevention you do,
you're still gonna have those reactive security moments.
And you know,
the reality is if you can get those things out in 24 48 hours,
then you can really minimize harm
if it takes a year or two years or it never gets fixed. Right?
Like, like, I mean, the reality is there are major vendors out there with, you know,
popular software,
internet facing software with flaws that have never been fixed.
It's true,
you know.
Um, but yeah, the reactive side, you, you have to have some capability there. Just
you have to.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I agree. I agree.
Oh,
make my head hurt. Curt.
All right, man,
let's call it.
So I guess the good news is law enforcement works sometimes and the bad news is
the bad guys also go to work.
Indeed. It's cat mouse, man. It never ends.
So until next time
you have a fantastic day, Kurt. And thanks for listening. Everybody again.
If you want the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com
and see the links to all the
interesting and
we'll say mostly tangential and off topic things that we discussed today.
-- Happy Friday, everybody. Happy
-- Friday. Take care.
Bye
bye bye.