Welcome to the special Halloween episode of
the Open source Security podcast this week,
Kurt couldn't join us.
So I have a special guest star, a fellow named Dave Serene. Say hello, Dave.
-- Hey, guys, how are we
-- doing?
-- Why don't you tell us a little bit about yourself, Dave? Yeah,
-- sure.
Uh So, uh I'm a fellow Red Hatter here.
Uh Working with Josh, I'm a, actually a technical account manager.
Uh I work on the public sector team
and uh managed to uh luckily enough or unluckily enough.
Uh put all my eggs in the basket of uh security, product, security platform,
security,
you know, specialize in identity, uh crypto.
And I also like to bake and play rugby and uh do various other uh extracurriculars.
You bake. That's fascinating. What do you bake
uh everything. Um and uh ask around.
Apparently I am well known uh for my chocolate chip cookies.
-- Um
-- I, I am hurt then. I have never had your chocolate chip cookies, Dave.
Uh Well, I'll be doing some,
I'll be doing some holiday baking coming up after Thanksgiving.
Uh So give me, give me, give me, give me your address and I'll send you,
I'll send you a box.
I
hereby declare this the holiday baking episode
of the
Security podcast.
It's no longer the Halloween episode. It's the,
speaking of that, it is Halloween today, which for us is today for other people.
It might be tomorrow or another day. Well, yesterday, whatever time is hard.
So,
so I thought, why, why don't we talk about that? Right. Halloween is a
crazy time.
This is one of the few times that it's ok to dress up in a costume, roam the streets
and demand people give you things when you knock on their door.
Actually, you know, we should, we. Ok.
So it,
it is quite conceivable that we have listeners who have no idea what we just said.
So let's have, why don't you
explain the concept of Halloween in the United States for those who
are going to think it's the most ridiculous thing they've ever heard.
So,
the concept of Halloween in the United States is
probably the most ridiculous thing you've ever heard.
I could delve into the history of it.
Uh But suffice it to say it's when kids and those who are kids at heart
will uh dress up in outlandish costumes and
go from door to door in their neighborhoods or to their friends and
you know, request or demand, uh uh treats, uh they go a trick or treating.
Um, and uh you are obliged often to be standing at your door with a bowl full of candy,
uh, to,
-- to, uh, dole that out,
-- which I will be doing this evening. How about you?
Do you, do you walk around or do you, do you hand out the candy?
So, I, I will,
I would love to hand out the candy because I don't like being that
guy who puts the bowl of candy on the front porch saying take one.
and
the
-- first kid who shows up takes the whole bowl.
-- That's exactly right. Right. Right.
So, uh, I, I should put a camera there saying you are being monitored, right.
This is to keep people honest.
Um, no, but, uh, I, I love handy candy.
-- I always buy way too much and the kids
-- call me,
you're gonna put a camera that says you're being monitored,
but they're all wearing costumes. So you don't know who they are.
What's the point?
Yeah. But, you know, it's, it's, it's the, it's, it's that fear, right?
You know, I mean, how many kids do you think will say?
Oh, well, he can't see my face or he doesn't know who I am. How is he gonna know? Right.
They're gonna be, oh, I'm on camera. It's, it's, uh,
it's that, uh, it's that magic button. Philosophy, right?
You know, we're in the elevator, you push the closed door button,
it actually doesn't do anything.
-- It just gives you the feeling that it's doing something.
-- Right?
Which this leads beautifully into,
I think the most important Halloween topic we could discuss,
which is real versus perceived risk.
Now, when I don't know how, if this is true, where, where, where you grew up.
But when I was a kid, there were all these stories all the time about, oh,
you gotta check your candy.
There's razor blades in it and there's poison in it and there's, you know,
rusty nails and whatever.
And in reality, if you look at history
that has never happened.
And I don't hear of this as often today, but it's still,
it's one of those things that people are afraid
that they're gonna get bad candy from somebody. When in reality,
you have a far greater chance of either choking to death on one
of the pieces of candy or dying of obesity from eating it all.
That's exactly right. Right.
Uh, you know, so where I grew up,
I grew up in very rural Northeastern Connecticut and, uh,
uh, the
people to whom I went trick or treating were family. Right.
And, and it was usually a 15 minute ride to get there.
So I didn't have to worry about the, you know, razor blades and candy,
but you definitely heard a lot about it.
Right. You know, and it,
it's one of those things that, on the news every year that the story is,
check the candy, check the candy, but there's no substantive, as you said,
no substantive,
uh, uh, research on and no substantive evidence on
-- it being an actual problem. And
-- it's even crazier than that. I remember
this was, I was, I was old enough.
I wasn't going around the houses because obviously once you reach a certain age,
it's just uncool to go get free candy.
But then you, then you reach another age, we're like free candy.
Like, that's awesome. Right.
Fortunately it's frowned upon now when you're an adult and,
and you show up at the door.
But anyway,
I remember when I was older, like,
there were, there were a doctor's office and dentists who would advertise,
they would x ray your candy for free
after Halloween. And in hindsight, I'm like, that's the most ridiculous, I wonder
just irradiating the candy
that probably makes it more dangerous.
That's, that's good marketing. That's what that,
that's good marketing for the dentist in the doctor's office. Right.
We're gonna get you in and then we're gonna try and sell you.
Right.
Hey, kid, it'd be a shame if something happened to those nice teeth.
Exactly. Exactly.
So, so I guess
insecurity,
yeah, we'll,
we'll keep on this topic is there's always this real versus perceived risk.
Like my favorite thing is,
is passwords
where you got to have this ridiculous password that
you can't remember and then use it in everywhere.
Right. And that, that's kind of like
there's always that perception gap, I think between real security
and
I
guess schneer
calls it security theater, you know, whatever you want to call it. But it's,
it drives me crazy and it makes me wonder if we can't fix this with candy
on Halloween.
Is there any hope
that, that we're ever going to get, get, get in front of this, in,
in the technical world?
Likely? No.
-- Um, but you know, me, I dave,
-- you're up
to,
I gave this one to you, like I handed it to you on a plate,
making me feel good about myself.
-- Yeah.
-- So let me, let me go ahead and let me be my, my perpetual hopeless optimist.
Right.
And I'd say I'd say yes,
because one would imagine that in the security world we're all adults here, right.
You know,
and we should all be, have critical thought. Right?
Um, when you're talking about candy and kids and parents, there's the,
there's the natural instinct to be overprotective and
over cautious and this plays into that,
over cautious and over protectiveness, right?
Um,
but
as, as freethinking, free willed adults, I'd say
there should be, there should be a possibility here to
get around some of that security theater.
You know, it's funny you mentioned passwords, right.
You know, I just, uh, I just had to, uh, uh,
reset a password this weekend on one of my accounts and
the, the password requirements where, you know, your,
your password needs to be 6 to 10 characters long and it needs to be,
you know, characters uppercase, lowercase in numbers. It's like
-- you are drastically limiting
-- by,
that's gonna take in upwards of 25 seconds to crack, I imagine,
I say. Right. Right.
I, I like, I like you're, you're killing me smalls, you're killing me.
Uh, you know, so, um,
uh, I think, I, I think that
it, it, it, there, there's an interesting middle ground here to be had, right?
Because, you know,
6 to 10 characters you're making it easier for people to remember,
but you're also limiting that uh, footprint of the password, right?
Uh You know, XK CD did a great comic, you know, and I've seen,
I've seen debates about it, you know, one way or the other where, you know,
it lays out how long it would take to crack, you know,
certain types of passwords and password complexity.
But,
you know, you string together five words that mean nothing together, right?
Um But put spaces,
it's infinitely more, uh uh memorable, but infinitely more difficult to crack.
So this would be the time. Do you know, have you heard of Dice Wire?
Are you familiar with it?
Uh Dice?
No, I'm not.
So, the XK CD, correct?
Horse Battery Staple comic, which I still wonder how many people use that password.
I bet, I bet the number is horrifying.
-- But anyway, I'll bet
-- you it's any Rainbow Table you find out there,
right?
Without
a doubt.
So I'll, I'll put this in the show notes, but
there is this, this thing called dice wear. And the idea is,
you know, human is gonna remember
crazy passwords, right?
Like a good properly secured password is, is unmemorable by a human being.
But as you said, a string of words is easy to remember.
And so what dice where essentially is is you're supposed to like, you use real dice,
you roll them
and you write down your rules and there's,
they've got like the rules to find how you should roll them, what you should do in,
in all this
and then they have like a catalog of words and you look up
the words that correspond to what you rolled
and then you write them down.
And so you aren't because here's the deal as a human being,
your string of five nonsensical words is probably not very nonsensical.
And I suspect even a bad a, I could predict
what your password is if you know the first one or two words.
Whereas with dice where you're obviously you have a certain
amount of guaranteed randomness and the guys who did this,
like, they go into
the bits of randomness and,
and what this all means and how hard it would be to crack and all this stuff.
But I mean, fundamentally speaking, they've done a wonderful job and if you have,
I think like a six character password,
they figure at this point would take thousands of years to crack.
It's a really cool system that they put together.
Interesting.
Definitely check it out, man. It's super cool.
I, I, I'm gonna let my nerd, I'm gonna let my nerd show here a little bit.
That, that reminds me back in the days of playing Dungeons and Dragons where, uh,
uh, the,
the player's handbook had a name generator where you would
roll dice and you would find the number in this table
-- and, and you've got your name. Yeah. exactly.
-- Exactly.
I mean, I still have all my dice. My kids think it's awesome.
I have this enormous bag of dice because, because I,
I used to do dungeon masters stuff in, in college
and
I like a bunch of the guys I played with
that either didn't have dice or they'd always forget them.
And so I just one day went and I bought like 30 sets of dragon dice at the,
at the comic shop.
And, yeah,
the bag is enormous now and my kids think it is the coolest thing they've ever seen.
-- I'm like, you guys have no idea how dorky this makes your dad just,
-- just don't,
just don't let them get their hands on the D four.
Right?
-- If you think stepping out of Lego is bad, stepping out of D four
-- is, uh,
I've never done that.
I've, I've always taken very,
I've been very careful about not losing my dice and in fact,
I do love the D four somehow.
I don't know how this happened. I have ad four that glows in the dark.
That's,
it's awesome. I'm not gonna lie. I love that thing.
It is my, it is one of my most prized possessions.
Excellent.
Oh, man. Ok. So, so speaking of prize possessions, let's talk about our
uh golden calf for the last
two weeks.
Yes.
What, what, what has been eating up a lot of our time?
And that would be Dave,
that would be dirty cow,
dirty cow.
So, in fact, Kurt and I talked about this in the last episode,
uh kind of gave a rundown of the technical bits and, and what not, but
I guess it's, it's a gift that keeps on giving. Let's what's going on now.
-- Yeah.
-- So, um you know, we've put out a, a uh
uh publicly facing article uh uh outlining the,
the vulnerability talking about how to
fix the, fix the issue.
You know, patches have been uh shipped for rail seven,
rail six and I believe rail five at this point.
Um
um but, you know,
as with all things patching kernels and nobody
has time for uh rebooting thousands of systems,
right?
Um So it's probably a slow roll out.
So, um we have uh put together a, a system tap script that
uh
is, is meant to mitigate the issue by intercepting the uh the suspect system calls.
Yes. And there is also uh K patch which lets you do line patching. But
I think you have a really interesting point is reboots
are painful and a lot of people can't even do them.
I know, I, I've heard stories about,
you know, regardless of the whole Dev
ops. So let's just keep moving things around rebooting quickly.
I've heard stories about people with systems that are
built in such a way and they're so large
that it literally takes more than a day to reboot
because you obviously have to take things down sanely and
then do your work and then bring them back up and they have to load stuff off disk and,
-- and
-- put, and
load into memory.
It's crazy.
S
a
is, is a huge uh uh part of that, that, that issue, right?
Because those systems tend to be so huge and so
important to the business workflow, right? Where,
you know,
they may have maybe two hours of downtime and it
takes them an hour and 50 minutes to boot,
right? So it's crazy.
So, you
know, it's,
I remember when I was my first job out of college, I was an A IX system administrator,
which
was, this was back when I, I wouldn't even say A X was popular then.
It, it has it ever been popular anyway.
I, I remember that we had this machine
that literally took half an hour to shut down and it took half an hour to start.
And so if you had to take this thing down, like it was a huge deal and I'll never forget,
like, one day it crashed
and we literally had
30 people just staring at you like, what's going on and,
and they could not do their jobs until the, and I'm like, it's booting this.
Like, I can't do anything else but watch the screen
as it, like, ticks through the numbers.
That's right. It's, it's going through its memory check now.
No, I was, I was a, uh, uh, I was a net wearer
uh in a previous life and the same,
same issues applied, right.
You know, these giant behemoth machines that were running a
relatively slow os. Right?
And it's got to go through all the system checks on boot up and it just took forever.
We ran on X 86. Right.
-- Uh
-- Yes. Yep.
Yep. Right. Right. Oh, man, I do. I remember network too.
I have one of my claims to fame
was when I was in high school, I helped
the local
uh land administrator guy take care of the network
and of course we ran netware. Right.
And I, I found,
I
don't remember the details or what I did,
but I remember finding a way to create a drive share.
That was where we put all our games
and I somehow made it so even the,
the network admin could not view what was in the drive,
only me and my friends could get to it.
So we would log into the school's computers and we
had drive G for games and everyone was like,
oh, we want Drive G and I'm like, no, you can't have it.
And to my knowledge it was still there after I
graduated and they could not make it go away.
So, like, the people, the younger kids, I knew
who were part of the group still had access to the games and they
could not get rid of them because they could not figure it out.
-- It became myth and lore.
-- Yeah. Yeah. Right. Right.
I don't remember how I did this because it's, it's long enough ago. It's in the sense
of that, that,
that speaks to security too, right? Because
you
trust
personnel and uh
I,
I was clearly not a trusted personnel
in the, in the public sector. We would call that a bad actor.
We would call that a bad actor
and nothing's changed.
But,
oh my goodness. All right. So,
yes, bad actor. I love it.
So the other really crazy thing that came out this
week is there have been a bunch of hardware timing attacks
and,
and these always get my, get my ire because I remember when the first one came out,
man, I bet it's been at least five years, maybe more.
And it was about stealing RS A keys on virtualized machines where you had one VM
could do things to essentially
acquire information about another VM. But like,
man, it's been,
these guys have taken it to the next level and, and in ways that scare me to death.
Oh,
yeah. Absolutely.
Because you, you think about the hard, you can't patch hardware, right? I mean,
you can't address it.
-- I mean, that's
-- not technically true
because,
well, so, so I,
there are, there are different things that exist and not ignoring the F PGA world,
which is a field programmable Gatorade.
And that's literally, you have a chip, you can program it to do anything you want.
And in fact, back in the day when they would,
I don't know if they still do it anymore just because the chips are so big.
But back when they were doing,
the pentiums Intel would build a Pentium out
of F PGA arrays to essentially test the logic
to make sure it was correct before they would send it off to the fab factories.
Because obviously, if you make a mistake in your logic, you're talking about, well,
like look at the floating point error they had that cost them a fortune to fix, right?
But anyway, there's something called micro
code in in CP US today
that lets you essentially do a, you can't do tons of fixes.
Obviously, there is a certain level of hardware fixing.
You can do,
you cannot fix the particular issue that was found with the Haswell chips though,
which is a, a cash timing attack on the branch predictor,
which probably doesn't make a lot of sense to most people. But
so, so here's the issue.
I'll kind of, I'll give you the, the nickel tour just because I can.
And
you have what's called the pipeline. See this, this gets crazy.
It's so complicated.
You have what's called the pipeline.
And now processors don't like,
you don't take one instruction and run it through the chip and then you're done
and then you take the next instruction, run through the chip and then you're done,
right?
They what's called the pipeline and
you basically put it in, you,
you keep loading this pipeline where you put instructions
in and they like this is this instruction starts,
you know,
doing what it needs to do and there there's multiple stages
and I don't even know how many they have these days.
I just remember back when I was in college,
we were talking about like, I think it was maybe eight stage pipelines or something,
which seemed insane at the time.
I'm sure it's ridiculous now. But anyway, if you, if you miss the branch
because the branch predictor decides.
All right,
I think it's gonna take this branch and
it starts loading those instructions into the pipeline.
And if you have a branch miss,
then it has to throw away all those instructions,
all that work it's doing and it has to load the new branch path
right?
And then start doing the work on that and granted these chips run super fast.
But in a high performance environment, you're talking about potentially losing,
you know, nanoseconds of work.
But you know, I mean, again, depending upon many factors,
it can make a big difference.
So anyway, you have the branch predictor.
And from what I read in this paper is they essentially have it set up. So you can
put together a fake program
that
mimics
the kernel space branches
and kind of run them side by side.
And based upon the performance,
you can determine if the kernel is missing certain branch calls
or if it's making those certain branch calls because of the cache
because obviously it,
it caches certain information
inside the chip.
And so what happens then is
by by paying attention to the cash hits and the cache misses on your
not the kernel program that's just mimicking the the flow of the kernel,
you can figure out what the kernel A SLR
uh random I I guess random offset is
which is like crazy to think about.
And the thing is that's important because when you write a kernel exploit,
there's something called kernel address space lay
randomization.
And the purpose of that is so when you write a kernel exploit,
you need to know memory addresses, important things are stored
and they use the
A SLR to essentially randomize those locations, but they're,
they're the offsets are known.
So if you can figure out the base
of the randomization,
you can use it to figure out where other stuff is.
And so the goal of this attack is to figure out that base.
So then you could write an exploit in the kernel knowing
where important memory structures are you want to overwrite or control.
And this is like this is such a Rube Goldberg machine.
But it,
but it, so there's, there's two, there's two sides to this, right is on one side,
it's awesome that we've reached this point of insanity
in how we attack systems, right?
Which is super cool because that means a
lot of this other technology we're doing works.
But on the other side, it's like
it's so complicated. How do you possibly plan for or even defend against this?
Uh Yeah. Yeah. Right. So,
I don't know. Uh
I'm
not being super familiar with the way
the system calls and those things are, are cashed up and, and, and pushed out and,
and flush through the system.
Uh I'd imagine that the busier a system is the more likely it is to
quickly get that offset, right? Is, is,
-- is that kind of a correct assumption?
-- I I'd imagine.
So, historically speaking,
these attacks only worked in labs because you had
to have a relatively idle system to build,
to exercise this stuff.
But as,
as roll hammer, for example, shows us
that's not always true. And in fact, there was last week too, Ro
Hammer,
someone released an android exploit.
You can root like any android phone with the Ro Hammer attack,
which is just like what, what is going on, like,
what has happened to the world we live in.
Right. This makes sense.
Yeah. And, um,
you know, I'd imagine, uh, I'd, I'd imagine, I think, uh,
I read something yesterday, uh, about this,
there was a conversation going on about using, you know, uh, CRC checks or, you know,
um, adding some, uh, adding some functionality in there, right,
to be able to mitigate some of this.
But,
um it will inevitably slow the system down. Uh you know, sometimes imp perceivable.
But
um you know, you talk about
uh you know, f si folks, right, who are doing high frequency trading, right?
You know, every last bit of performance is
crucial,
right? Um
But now, in their case,
I would imagine they don't have random people who are able to execute a
-- hammer attack on their systems,
-- right?
-- At
-- least I hope not.
I'd, I'd, I'd hope not. But you know, those, those are,
that's that soft
Nity Sinner, right? That, you know,
that's, that's the holy grail. So people are going to try, right?
People are going to try very hard.
-- But, but
-- so, so here's the irony of this as well is CRC
is
easy to discredit in this instance because it's going to
be very slow and with memory speed is king.
Now, let's even think about the context of ECC which is error,
correcting memory and it's not perfect and raw hammer can easily get around ECC.
You just have to flip two bits instead of one
and then your check some works out whatever it doesn't matter.
The point is. ECC ra M has been around for a long time.
It does what it's supposed to do. It even corrects errors
where you can have a certain amount of problems in your memory and it will fix them.
And there's, uh, people have done studies on how often RA M
has bit errors due to hardware or solar rays or like frogs, whatever,
it doesn't matter.
And it's, it's not zero but it's not very high.
But ECC is expensive
and it is slightly slower
because of this fact.
Now
it is never caught on in the industry. And generally speaking,
it is a very niche market.
And in fact, like, I know some people who swear by UCC and I'm like, II,
I refuse to pay the extra $20 AAA sim or whatever,
whatever, the
whatever I
don't even, I've got a pile of one on my
shelf over there. They're so cheap.
But,
and, and here's the thing
is the people who most need this technology, be it like
a, a cell phone or an end user or even even a cloud provider,
they don't want to pay for it because they're already operating.
Either they're cheap skates like me where I just like, I'm like, no,
I won't pay an extra two cents for more security.
Right?
Or, or you have the margins are so small that like a nickel, a device or a nickel,
a machine makes a huge, huge
and we're actually not talking nickels, we're probably talking dollars,
right?
And, and you're not, and you're not just talking about,
you know, currency cost either.
You know, you mentioned speed and speed is king when it comes to memory. I mean,
you know, it,
I just, I just overheard a conversation this morning, um, you know, at,
at the store because, you know, I had to get my caffeine fixed this morning.
Um People complaining about the chips and uh credit card now, right?
Uh People hate it. People hate it because it's slower.
Um But, you know, albeit, you know, chip and sign,
that's a whole another conversation, right?
Chip and sign is really not much more secure than swipe and sign, right?
You know, until we get the chip and pin. But
um
you know, it's there for added security. It's that first step.
But people hate it
and people would love to go back to the swipe even though it is markedly less secure.
You know, this is,
there's various other people I pay attention to and there's a fellow out there.
Uh
I think it's Michael Santa
Angelo. His name is and he talks about this a lot and the fact that
we've yet to see a significant benefit from moving to chip
chip and sign
because apparently the levels of fraud are not decreasing,
which is
that fascinates me a little bit because on one
side I would have kind of expected the chips
to, you can't clone a chip. Well,
as easily.
I
won't say it's impossible because I know there's
been some research done around this but,
but that makes it right.
So there's still, and that,
that clearly means a significant amount of this fraud
is either online where you don't need the card present
or they're just stealing the cards and going and buying stuff with them.
And
I, I don't know exactly how it is. I don't pay that close of attention to this.
I, in, in the case of a stolen card, a pin will obviously
deter that attack,
but in the case of online, no card present.
It doesn't matter if you have a pin, right?
You're, you're still gonna be able to do that stuff.
Mhm. Yeah. All, all you need is that what the C, the CV V on the back of the card?
The CV V? I don't let me
-- right.
-- That
terrible noises as I dig my wallet out here. Uh,
and it doesn't say
so, what about my other card?
I have no CV V. Sure. We'll, we'll call it that
if we can.
Now,
I do have one awesome story here is I,
so, so my work credit card has been stolen so many times I've lost count.
I get it replaced probably every two or three months
and the last time I got it replaced was shortly before I was going to Europe
and
I call him up and I'm like, look guys, like, let me set a pin.
This thing keeps getting stolen and I'm going to Europe and I, I give me a pin, right?
And they did, they gave me a pin and I was like, oh, this is so cool.
And now even in the US
when I use that card, I have to type in the pin instead of signing a sheet and I love it.
-- It is so nice.
-- Absolutely.
I just, I actually just got my uh my new card uh couple weeks ago
and it,
it had the chip and
pin, it had a pin.
-- I didn't have to ask for one. They just gave me one.
-- Oh man, that's so nice.
In fact, I called my bank with my my other card,
my personal card. I'm like, hey, give me a pin like no, we won't do that.
Come on guys like help me out here,
you
know, they
have nothing to do with it. Although I guess in, in
so I, I kind of under here. Here's the question right.
Here's the ultimate question if we want to kind of tie it all back is,
is the cost of supporting pins. Good look, face, people forget them.
They type in the wrong pin, the key pads are broken, whatever,
there's a million things that can go wrong
is the cost of supporting a pin infrastructure cheaper than the amount of fraud
that happens
without
it. And, and, and I, I don't know. Right.
I can't answer it, but fundamentally that is the question that has to be asked.
Uh, as long as insurance rates are low
uh for, to, to cover fraud. Right.
I mean, I would imagine that the economies of scale. Right. You know,
if, if they can pay a couple of $1000 a year to be insured against fraud and get it,
just get it paid,
then
why bother?
And,
right,
because,
yeah, because,
you know, once you go to pin, you know,
not only do you have to support the changing of those
pins and assigning those pins and people forgetting the pins,
but,
you know, you have the,
the added hassle of making sure that those pins are stored in a secure way.
Right. Like, like one would hope, you know, passwords are stored hashed and salted.
Right.
You know. Um,
so it, it
seriousness though, I,
well, I, I shouldn't say that. So
with chip and pin,
I don't know who stores the pin.
I think it's, the card issuer
has control over that or it might even be
Visa or mastercard.
The, the.
Hm. That's a good question.
I, I should actually look this up but I know like in the context of PC I,
they have very good rules around password storage and
things like that and even even card number storage.
Where there's some, I mean, granted
we can complain about PC I all day long but that particular part they,
I think they did an ok job of is,
is having very clearly defined rules for storing
these passwords and what's going on there.
Yeah. Uh, the PI I protection,
um, you know, in general. Right.
You know, social security numbers, card numbers pins everything.
-- Yeah. No, absolutely.
-- In, in theory. Right. I mean,
there, there been some incidents
we will say,
depending on the auditor who read the, uh, compliance standards at that moment.
Right.
And that's actually, that,
that's something else that comes up every now and then is,
I will have to deal with an issue where an auditor has decided
this is the way the rule reads
and the old auditor didn't.
And now we have to reconcile that
and it's,
and it can be such a pain in the neck. I mean,
so that's one of the problems with compliance, right?
Is you at the end of the day, you're at the mercy of your auditor.
So, so buy him very nice dinners when he,
uh,
we, we, yeah, that, that, that, that sounds perfectly acceptable. Right. So
questionable.
That's exactly right.
So, we, we run into that a lot in, in the public sector, right. Um,
where, uh, each program, each project has what's called ad A a and,
and I don't ask me what that stands for.
I don't know, off the top of my head.
Um, but when dealing with things like AAA.
Right.
Uh And for those who might not know,
you know, and IE
A is, um,
it's, it's a, it's a vulnerability audit, right.
That's put out by disa be between dis
A and U cyber com. Compare
to a CV E ID, which people
will be very familiar with.
It's more complex than that in nuance,
but we could conveniently say it's basically a magic CV E ID.
Exactly. And it contains a bundle of CV ES
and,
and not even just that it can also contain
uh like physical requirements and,
and warnings about non computer security events.
It's, it's crazy what they are. But anyway, we won't,
I'm not, I'm not going there, man. Like my brain can't handle it this morning.
But uh, so, so basically to, to shorten this up a little bit. It,
you know, we run into that a lot as well where, you know, I, if, if you, if,
if somebody says, hey, you know,
we're not gonna fix this vulnerability because it's super
low and here's what you gotta do to,
to,
to uh exploit it and you know, the way we ship the product, it,
it doesn't really affect it in, in the way that the CBE out outlines.
Some DAAs are like fine, great. Just give me that right up and we'll move along.
Some are absolutely, you know, no, we need a patch for this and we need it tomorrow.
Right.
So, uh, you know, it's,
we've run into that a lot, um, in,
in the security world where depending on who you talk
to will depend on what answer you get and how
important they feel a certain issue is.
You kind of love it. There's nothing like reproducibility
that.
Right.
Yeah, exactly.
-- That's right. Predictability and reproducibility. Right.
-- Oh, man.
Yes.
Oh,
my brain. I can't take it.
It's,
it's early in the morning. Let's
talk about
it.
A more pleasant topic
which is, uh, Schneer
had a thing about listening to voice over IP keyboard
noise to figure out what a person is typing.
That's not horrifying in every way.
No.
And,
and I'm staring at my mechanical keyboard right now saying I have made some very,
very poor life choices.
Uh,
you know, I think computers were where we went wrong, Dave, if,
if we had just paper and pens, everything would be fine.
Let's go back to abacus and punch cards.
And, uh, I think, I think the world would be a better place.
I think punch cards are, are too modern,
too modern
actually.
I mean, so this actually this ties back into some of the hardware timing attacks and
there's the issue of lab environment versus real world.
And in fact, I remember reading uh,
an attack some years back where people were analyzing the noise on a power line
to determine what a person was typing on the keyboard. Because obviously
with the way electricity works is any time anything happens on the computer,
it generates a certain amount of noise and the
noise ends up feeding back through the power line,
like, like literally the outlet your, your computer is plugged into.
And these researchers figured out a way to
ascertain what is being typed by the noise
on the, on the power system.
Well,
that's, there's also the, one of
uh it was, uh, the iphone guys figured out you can use the, uh, uh, uh, what is it, the,
the gyroscope in the, in the iphone
to figure out what someone is typing if it is on the same desk.
Oh, interesting.
Yeah, it's,
we're just doomed like that. That's
the lesson from all of this. We're doomed. There's nothing you can do.
Go eat your poison candy.
-- And that's the end.
-- Right.
I, I, I'll, I'll gladly eat my poison candy because then I'll,
-- I'll at least I'll at least go out fat and happy right
-- at the end.
The hurting finally stops.
But,
so here's the thing
that I always come back to is I look at all this and if you read
the research,
everything is on fire
yet
the world is mostly still functioning.
Right. Yeah.
And
what that's going on.
-- So, I think, uh, if I were to hazard a guess and
-- please do,
we often guess and speculate and nobody is fact checking us.
So it's just fine and, and by the way,
if you have any problems with the content of the show,
uh I will put Dave's Twitter handle in the show notes.
Tell Dave because I don't care.
And, and, and I will, I will
speculate your guess. Let's hear that. Why, why is everything
not
on fire?
Uh Everything is not on fire because, and, and I,
I'm gonna tie it back to how we started the show with the poison candy, right?
Because
it gets these stories come out and they get so publicized that people think that,
you know, I can do this on my Commodore 64 and you know, be able to exploit these,
the these vulnerabilities
where as you mentioned, Josh,
a lot of them are very pristine in the lab.
You know,
Mars and Mercury need to be in retrograde to be able to uh
-- but
-- they're
-- not,
-- actually, here's the deal. They're actually not anymore.
Like Row Hammer is a great example of Row
Hammer is like legitimately being exploited in the wild,
not in the lamp,
right? And, and
y yes, uh we're gonna, we're going to have, we're gonna have those. But
a
again,
I think the the bar to entry for a lot of these vulnerabilities is just really high.
And
um the the cost benefit analysis there,
there's a whole economy around these types of things, right?
Where I think a lot of these, a lot of these vulnerabilities like Ro Hammer,
it's not going to be worth somebody's time and effort to
leverage this, this exploit this vulnerability against
you. You know,
uh
you know, grandma Smith down the road, who's just, you know, sending, you know,
facebooking pictures of her kids, right?
Um The there's this whole economy of scale and
this whole economy around this cost benefit analysis,
right.
So where uh you, you mentioned these v these vulnerabilities,
these exploits are getting more and more complex and more and more
uh uh technically advanced and
-- the time energy and
-- effort,
-- Goldberg machines.
-- Right. Right.
So the time energy and effort that it requires to um
put, put the resources in place and put the
uh facilities in place to be able to leverage these exploits.
And these vulnerabilities is so high
that they, they need to be very targeted as to how they are used.
But then we get Iot botnets, right? You know, so
there's things on both sides of that coin.
Yy, you know, we
-- Yeah,
-- II I think
you must apologize actually since he brought it up because I
spent the entire episode mispronouncing the name of the botnet,
which I, I'm slightly embarrassed by uh luckily not too embarrassed,
which is why I'm still doing a podcast now, but
it's,
I love it.
It's, I mean, keeping track of all this can be such a hassle sometimes, but all right.
So
I'm not gonna disagree with you.
I, I think you're,
I'm not gonna say you're wrong because I can't say one way or the other.
But I,
I think what you've just described is probably more plausible than
anything else because if you listen to the security people,
there's no reason civilized society is still functioning, but it clearly is.
Or at least I think it is.
And so
it's,
yeah, I don't know, whatever. Like,
I don't
go human race.
That's,
that, that's, that, that's, that perpetual optimist in me. Right?
Is, is II, I like to believe that there's,
yeah, IIII, I just like to believe the best. Right?
-- You know, that's,
-- and although there's, there's an election next week,
so maybe you can change your mind.
I, I'm,
-- I'm still, I'm still digging my bunker in my crawl space.
-- So
you better get on that, man. It's, uh,
no matter who's elected, the world ends next week.
I, I'm, I'm optimistic but I'm also a realist.
So, and then half the country moves to Canada as well. So which half we don't know?
All right,
I've got one more topic here that I want us to talk about and then
we're gonna call it a wrap because I think we've wasted enough time with our,
our wonderful listeners.
So
Mozilla I heard is going to support TLS 13 in Firefox 52.
There are two crazy things about that I think is, first of all,
they're, they're turning it on by default, which generally speaking in history,
we've been
a little bit more conservative with things like
this where TLS 13 might have been there,
but we wouldn't have used it automatically.
But the craziest part
is this protocol is still under review at the I ETF like,
it is not a formalized done deal,
which is,
that's crazy. Like, like
they're supporting a I,
I won't call it a beta protocol but like this
is still something in review that's still in draft.
Unbelievable. Absolutely. Right. And
I like the gumption.
-- It's fantastic.
-- I
agree completely. I think,
I think this is the way everyone should work is move fast, make mistakes,
let's face it.
There's gonna be mistakes.
There are,
I bet you they released a fix for this less than two days
after it goes out because it's probably going to break something nobody foresaw.
But I think that's ok because the,
the answer here isn't to do it perfectly the first time,
which let's face it is the reason this thing is still
in draft review,
not to get it right the first time,
but to be able to move quickly.
So when you make a mistake and when you have a problem, you can fix it immediately
-- instead of obsessing over corrupt, which never happens.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
I mean, look, look how long it took people to move from SSL V two to SSL V three. Right?
-- Um Being able to move quickly,
-- there was, there was no SSL V three.
It was called TLS one point. Oh, Dave.
Totally different. Totally different.
Was there a
L three?
I don't think there was
all right. We gotta look,
thank goodness we have the internet. Right?
Uh Let's see here. Now there is an SSL V three.
Yep.
Uh Is it 3.1? Is TLS 1.0
I,
you may be right. I, I, I'm not super familiar with the details on that.
It's, it was a pedantic
problem and I think it was a, a trademark issue or something like that.
Got you. Got
you.
Ok. So yeah, TLS 1.0 would be about like TL S3 0.1 because it has minor differences.
Ok. So I was wrong.
There is an SSL V three. I'm, it pleases me that this was long enough ago. I forgot it.
Fair
point.
I, I'm very happy for that and the fact it was, oh, man,
1999 it was in TLS 1.0 was drafted.
Oh my goodness.
And, and we're just, we're just at TLS 1.3 today.
Uh
Well, ok, so let's look at the timeline here. TLS 10, all right.
Let's start at the beginning.
SSL 1.0 1995.
Yes.
Uh It
is uh oh,
wait 2.0 is 95 1.0 was never publicly released because of serious security flaws
so good for them.
Uh
3.0 was 96
and we just got rid of 2.0 what, like a year ago. Not even
so good for us.
Uh, 3.0 which I,
3.0 I don't think I really caught on all that. Well,
uh, TLS, 1.0 is 99
TLS. 11 was 2006, took seven years.
Uh, 1.2 was 2008. Only two years.
And now 13, which we're expecting this year would be eight years, eight years later.
So that's,
that's too long.
It is.
We are in a universe now where
I think if we're not updating these drafts on at least a yearly basis, if not faster,
we are going to have significant problems.
I, I, I'll add it to my to do list. Josh,
good. You get on that, that would be helpful.
Uh Yeah, and, and I mean, if you look at the rapid fire, you know,
issuances at the beginning, you know, you had 9596 then 99 for, what was that?
99 for TLS one point? Oh,
and then just these huge gaps of time, right?
And things change so fast, you know, why aren't these changing fast? And
it's that fear, failure, right. And
why fail, fast, fail loud, learn from it. Move
forward.
Although I guess so, I part of me understands this from the,
the,
the the perspective of being the standards bodies is you look at something like IP
you know, I PV four
that's been around for, like, 20 years.
Like, they clearly did a pretty good job there. And I think
that's the prevailing attitude is if we do it right, once we never have to do it again.
But for something like TLS, like, even if you did it 100% right in two years, like,
it's, it's a piece of crap
in 10 years.
Cry, cry,
cryptography research has gotten to a point and computing power has gotten so
great
that it,
it's al it's null and void. Right.
-- Yep.
-- Yep. Yeah. Right. Exactly. It's,
the world is changing, the times they are changing.
But II, I, I'm, I'm with you on that.
II, I love the fact that they're, they're making it on by default,
they're pushing it and,
you know, see what breaks, fix it.
-- Right. Fix it
-- quick.
Yeah. Yeah.
Now, of course, the,
this also depends on the server side also being able and willing to move quickly.
Sure.
So we will see this is, I mean, that's one of the challenges is the modern internet
isn't like one thing.
It's like 7000 pieces that are held together
with duct tape and some good intentions,
right?
-- Prayer. Lots of prayer.
-- Right. Yes.
That's
right.
Unicorn
tears,
quantities of it.
-- But
-- that's like I remember I was,
I was at black hat and I was walking around and I saw
there was a sign that said prayer room and I'm like the,
the best chance of fixing your infrastructure is like right there, you know,
all this other stuff they're selling, whatever
praying
-- will probably get you farther
-- because, because, you know, you know,
there's a not insignificant quantity of
infrastructure out there that's still running on
NT four in the version of IIS that was shipped in NT four.
-- Right.
-- It's without a
doubt
without,
well,
how many things still rely on IE six every now and
then I'll run it into something that talks about IE six.
And I'm thinking like, where do you even find that today?
You must have like a windows 95 CD on the shelf, you know, just for that,
the box of the box of 3.5 floppies,
the box of three and a half
seriously.
So, you know, speaking of that, and,
and we can end on a happy note is remember booting up
the old machines with floppy drives and they would make that crazy like
noise.
I found out what that is.
So the reason they did that is
the floppy drive generally had,
what is it like 50 sectors or 60 sectors or whatever it was?
I forget. And obviously
the red head, the computer had to know where the red head was
and most of these drives were inexpensive
and did not have sensors that could tell the computer where the redhead was.
So it would basically just tell the floppy drive back the reed head up like 50 times.
And obviously, when it hit the end, it had a mechanism in place did not ruin anything.
So it just make a funny noise when the re head was parked,
but it was still getting back up the redhead commands.
And that's what that noise was,
was essentially backing the reed head up to zero by
just issuing like 60 back up the reed head,
you know, commands in a row to get it there.
And then you knew the reed head was at
sector zero and you could start going from there.
Problem
solving. Josh,
you think that's like an elegant solution to what could have been.
And, and again, this kind of comes back to that whole ECC ra M thing is
you could add a sensor to the drive for probably a dollar or
just back the thing up 60 times which costs nothing
-- and maybe wear and tear and you got to buy a new drive sooner.
-- Right.
But with this, then
the sensor costs a dollar, but it's gonna cost you as the consumer five. Right.
Yeah. Right. Right. Well, that, that's a good point as well.
It certainly won't be free and
yeah, it's
maybe that's, we need more elegant, simple
solutions.
-- I, I like that idea. Josh. I like that idea a lot.
-- Get right on that.
We'll have it next week, right. We'll cover that.
Oh, my goodness. All right. All right. So
it has been a fantastic time, Dave. Thank you so much for helping.
I really appreciate it
and,
and to fill in for, for those of you listening.
If you want any of the links to any of the crazy things we discussed,
it'll be on the website, open source security podcast.com
and
uh Dave's Twitter handle will be there.
So by all means, let him know whatever mistakes we made
because then he can tell me and I don't have to pay attention
and, and yeah, thanks for listening folks. I really appreciate it.
Have a great week. Happy Halloween.
Thank you.
Have a Happy Halloween.
Assuming you're listening to this on Halloween, which you probably won't. So
we I I'm assuming you had a Happy Halloween. All right, there
you go. Alright. Take care, Dave,
-- take
-- care.