Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in using an American IP address, Josh Pressers.
I always, I don't always have an American IP address.
Sometimes I have an IP address somewhere else.
I pretty much always have an American IP address now because I need
to use A I tools that are pretty much all laws to America.
And what I love is is I will like log in to one of them and it'll be like you can't do this,
you're not American.
And so I like turn on Nord VPN because I forgot to turn it on.
I don't have it set to start with the system, right?
And then I'll like hit,
I literally hit like control R and the web page is like, oh,
-- happy to see you, Mr Siefried. What can I do for you
-- today? Very nice.
Thank goodness, I have an American billing address for my corporate credit card.
Everything. Fine.
Oh, actually, no, wait because,
yeah, no, that's anyways,
it's just I get why they're geo locking it because like legally they,
I have to otherwise the European Union or something might spank them. But.
Right. Yeah, it's so annoying because I get these weird latency spikes.
Like, I can't use it during, uh, the podcast
or on calls. I'll just get weird latency spikes where I digital banjo for a minute.
I had a funny thing happen to someone the other
day actually is someone I work with was on,
uh, they were using Google Hangouts or Meet whatever they call it now.
-- Google
-- Meets, I think hangouts is dead. Ok.
I don't know.
I don't keep track that closely.
Well, and there's two versions of me.
-- So, whichever
-- one, of course there is, why wouldn't there be?
But they were using Google Meet
and all of a sudden it like boo
them off and was like, we've detected,
you know,
dangerous information or not dangerous malicious activity from this IP address.
Of course, they send me a message. Right. Right.
They're like, oh, is there what's going on?
It's like, you know, kind of start doing some investigating and I'm like,
-- there's
-- nothing
VPN this doesn't make, yeah, it was VPN
and I was like, ah, that makes sense.
Yeah, people log in through VPN and,
oh,
it's so annoying because I get all these angry
emails from the club floor automated system saying,
you know, like you're coming from an NYP address.
I'm like, I know, I know it's ok.
Calm down like we have pass keys and a security token enabled. It should be ok.
Well, and actually this feeds into the,
the today's show topic is being right all the time is hard
-- and, and our take on this is, but not needed and
-- impossible as well.
Don't forget that.
Yeah. Minor detail.
Minor detail.
I hit a pothole the other day because we had a big dump of snow and
there's this one
pothole I keep swerving around
and I forgot it was there and because it was covered with snow dunk
and that's a perfect example. Like roads don't have to be perfect.
Like there's giant potholes that destroy people's cars.
-- That's enough pothole talk.
-- But I got it in there.
I know you snuck it in.
I'm gonna, we'll see. I could, I can't edit that out either. It's
excellent.
Well, there's a couple of topics that all basically boil down to the same thing.
So on the, and I'm just going to list them out real quick. Number one.
Why do data breaches matter anymore?
Like we just, the latest data,
data breach apparently was apparently half of France.
Yeah, I saw that. That's
so, I mean, it matters. But
-- does
-- it,
no, does it actually matter
anyways? But let me just list all three.
Number two, Canada is moving to ban the flipper zero because you know,
it's a car hacking.
It's not a car hacking tool. And even if you did ban it, it's not going to really help,
can
break into cars.
But here's the, here's the even better thing.
One of the articles,
they actually have a quote from like
the Insurance Institute of Canada basically saying,
yeah, we don't support the ban on flippers.
What we actually want is for manufacturers to make more secure cars.
Right.
Because they, they have the data and they're going to look at this. And so,
well, yeah, if you ban the Flipper zero,
it might stop like two cars from being stolen out of a garage.
Maybe, maybe
it's gonna have a totally negligible effect. The third thing is
there was a really silly New York Times Make online make newspaper magazine.
I don't know which one it was
talking about how you should be really
careful about handing out your email address.
-- Oh my goodness.
-- And
you know why you don't need to be concerned
about handing out your email address as much anymore
because everyone already has it.
No
gmail and Yahoo's 2024 inbox protections changes are coming
and that's gonna affect everybody.
Ok.
Anyway, so where do we want to start with this?
All right,
I want to start with two data breaches
-- matter because I feel like they
-- do counterpoint,
they don't see to me the data breach is
not
the problem.
The problem is my bank giving a mortgage to somebody because
they faxed them a letter saying I am Kurt siefried.
Please give me $300,000.
Here is a photocopy of a driver's license with the same name on it.
-- I
-- mean,
I understand
the idea you're getting at there where this is, like
you're saying,
our systems should be set up in a way that
even if someone has a bunch of information on you,
they shouldn't be able to abuse that system.
-- But I don't know if that's realistic
-- because there's legitimate people.
I have to give this data to
my employer. If I'm renting, they kind of need to know some stuff about me.
You know, like there's a lot of situations where people have to hand out this data
and it can't we treat this data as if it's secret.
But we also like if you want to get a cell phone,
they're gonna ask you for your social insurance number here
so they can do a credit check on you.
I mean, yeah, and if you refuse to hand it over, they're like, well,
you don't have to hand it over, but we also don't have to sell you a phone.
Yes, I've seen that before too.
-- And
-- this feeds, this is like this is the exact same thing as the flipper.
Zero in the cars,
the insurance people and most Canadian consumers are like,
yeah, I would like our cars to not,
you know, luckily we don't have the Kia problem that the US has where they put the,
they didn't put an immobilizer on the steering wheel, right?
So like I have a Kia
and my version of the Kia here in Canada has a microchip in
the key fob which you know when I turn the car on it,
asked the chip for a code and the chip responds with the code and then it turns
in America, it doesn't have that.
So you just have this thing where you literally stick a USB drive into this
little slot and crank it physically turn it and it turns the car off.
That's what happened.
Somebody made a tiktok video of here's how you still steal a Kia car.
You, you just physically get entry into it.
Which, yeah, if you have a hammer or a rock or
whatever, not a difficult thing to do.
Like every time I've seen the A MA come by to like,
get up uh to unlock a car because there's keys locked in it.
You know, they're there for like
three or four minutes.
Oh, it's very fast. Yeah, it's not hard to get into a car.
My favorite thing is like the, the tools they have are like, you know,
it's like a cat toy with a stick with a string or it's like
a piece of crazy carpet with a string tied to it or whatever.
Right.
Yeah. But basically
no amount of, oh, you should keep your keys secure.
Oh, you should keep your data secure. I can't keep my data secure.
I have to hand it out to a whole bunch of people.
I had a credit card popped and I am 99% certain I know which website lost it because I,
I normally only use that credit card to buy things like from Amazon or from whatever,
from a bunch of large retailers.
The point is we're not going to get these more
secure systems because a car manufacturers gonna be like,
yeah, your car being stolen.
Sounds like a, you problem. Not a me problem.
I mean,
-- it kind of is your problem
-- until the cities
in the US have started suing the carmakers.
Now.
-- That's a thing now. And
-- that, that's good.
Well, and that's an American solution that wouldn't happen in Canada, for example.
All right. So anyway, so I guess here's how I would frame this.
You are correct
in that a data breach
technically shouldn't matter.
I mean, you, there's more to that, but let's set aside some of the, the asterisks,
obviously, like mental health
-- related data breaches
-- are. Right. Exactly. There's lots of personal details.
You don't want to get out.
Yeah, medical stuff and all that.
-- Let's
-- say your, your tax ID number,
home address, phone number, name,
date of birth.
If, if our systems worked in a perfect manner, you could say yes, you
like, you could print it on it,
t-shirt and walk around with it and it wouldn't matter.
I, I don't think it's necessarily realistic because
like, there's no such thing as perfect security. Right?
We exist in a universe where competent security teams
have gone away from this idea of perfect.
-- And they've gone to, like focusing on risk and reducing risk. Right.
-- It's simple.
Perfect. Security is too expensive.
There's, there's, the return on investment is negative.
It, it doesn't exist, it's not even too expensive. It just doesn't
f
managed risk. You,
it, well,
it manages your risk and you make money and you spend money appropriately and,
you know, I,
I don't have a whole house generator to power my house
because we have so few power outages here in Alberta.
Knock on wood except for that one time where
we almost had to turn off power to the province
when it got cold out.
Right.
But fundamentally, you know,
I'm not going to spend $15,000 on a whole home generator.
What I did do actually is I changed my furnace so it's now a plug
into a socket so I can unplug it from that and plug it into a Jacky
to run my furnace. Right. Right. And that was like a $50 change.
I mean,
so here's a good way to think of this and this is something I've I've done in the past is
like insurance. Does this as well. Ok.
Where you can put together ideas that say like
if we have a breach of this particular data,
we expect the cost of the breach to be this,
to prevent that breach.
It would cost us this much. If the amount of the breach is less,
then the cost of preventing the breach,
that's accepting the risk, right?
Because you're, you're saying we're going to pay this cost instead of that cost.
But the problem there is now that leads to a lot of Externalizing of security costs
much like, oh, if we put le if we don't quality control the,
the ingredients in our toothpaste,
we might kill a few people. The cost of that lawsuit is x
it's less than making good toothpaste, right?
And that's the problem is a lot of that.
Uh
insurance and risk kind of thinking
depends explicitly or implicitly on Externalizing cost.
Oh, these people will have to spend 10 or 20 hours dealing with their identity theft,
right?
Like every time I read about identity theft,
it sounds like such a nightmare where these people are going
to their bank and they're saying look my identity got stolen.
I need account locks put on, I need this, I need that and the banks like
just totally ridiculous,
you know, or people, well,
my favorite thing is like these people who post reddit and they're like
I turned 18 and now I'm getting calls from creditors about a credit card
that was taken out in my name when I was four. What do I do? And they're like,
here's what you do.
But the fact that these credit like these debt collection
agencies just are gonna harass and hound these poor people
knowing full well, there's no way that this is
like legally their card
and, and OK, so look,
I think there's two conversations here, you're combining together,
there's the aspect of trying to protect some of this data
and making it will say less useful to the universe.
But then there's also the angle of,
I don't think anyone would argue that a lot of
our existing systems that rely on like credit systems,
whatever
are kind of broken
because they can't accommodate the world we live in today.
And the costs are externalized.
And this is where like having a large fines for losing, you know,
tax ID numbers and things like that, you know,
social security numbers here in the US.
That's where having large fines,
I think can take it from an externalized cost
to an actual cost the organization has to pay
and you can say like we should have a system that, that doesn't matter if this
stolen. But I think
that does need to change as well because the current systems we have are
basically built for a world where everything is done on pieces of paper,
fines are just the cost of doing business.
-- I mean,
-- to a degree
have GDPR fines really truly meaningful
stop data breaches or made behavior that much different. Probably. Yes. And
that's a terrifying thing
terrifies me is things could be far,
far worse than they are and they probably would be without GDPR.
I think they would be.
-- Yeah, for sure.
-- But I do think we maybe need to start moving
the cost and the liability.
See if in my mind,
if a bank takes an action of creating a
mortgage and giving that money to somebody else,
if something goes wrong with the identity validation process, and it's not me,
the bank should be entirely liable.
Why should I be affected in any way? I'm, I'm the victim.
-- I mean, sure, that's a legal matter now,
-- but we don't have laws that really set
that.
No, we don't. Not at all.
Absolutely.
And, and I'm going to turn this into a conversation, let's say about
like in the US, there's this thing coming out called the, well, it's out,
it's called the SSDF
the secure development framework,
software, secure software development framework, SS two SS
and,
and CIA
is putting together like they're calling it an out
of station worksheet where in order the idea being,
if you're going to sell to the federal government,
you have to fill out this worksheet.
And it, it says things like I'm, I'm, you know, checking my,
my software for vulnerabilities. I'm, I'm vetting my
dependencies, you know, a bunch of stuff, right?
And like this is an example where if you don't do that,
there's a real cost, right?
Whereas when we think about a lot of,
especially like human personal security things,
there's often
no negative aspect for the organizations involved, right?
This is password breaches, data breaches, this is whatever.
Well, I mean, they outsource to some, you know, um,
I forget where was it that I got that email and I finally tracked it down.
It was legit, like some company got popped.
They hired a third party essentially call center to deal with it, you know,
and you get like a year of free credit monitoring, blah, blah, blah.
Again, the problem is if the profits outweigh the cost,
then the business is going to do that.
And that's why, for example,
for example, with environmental regulations, there is now in many jurisdictions,
not just fines but criminal
uh because you can't
pollute so much.
Like we don't want people like I don't want
people polluting the North Saskatchewan because you know,
the there's over a million of us that rely on that river to drink water from.
And if we can't drink water from it, as we found out a few weeks ago
when uh the electrical system died at the
station and took out all the pumps for like five days.
That's a little scary because like I don't wanna move.
But if my city has no water,
well,
that would like end a city for sure.
The there,
there's a famous thing about 20 years ago written by a member of parliament
talking explicitly about how the quickest way to kill
a community is to not have clean drinking water.
And this is the context of small northern communities,
essentially indigenous communities where we still have uh tens and hun, like,
I think it's maybe even hundreds of thousands,
but definitely tens of thousands of people
living in these communities without clean water.
And somebody pointed out, like,
if this happened in the Greater Toronto area it'd be fixed in a week.
Oh, yeah, for sure.
For sure.
Ok, let's, let's,
let's bring Flipper zero into this now because
I think it's a similar sort of problem where
Flipper zero for anyone who doesn't know Flipper zero is a little device
-- that does what
-- it's a software defined radio with a computer chip.
And a really, it's just, it's got a convenient form factor. That's it.
It's got a built in battery, it's got a couple of buttons, a little screen.
Yeah, it also does infrared and you can use it to like copy NFC.
Well, basically all the flipper zero does is it can accept radio transmissions,
it can do computation and it can produce radio transmissions.
So for example, you can record and play back a signal or um with a rolling code
uh
like a garage door, open or rolling code system.
If you uh record a couple of rolling codes,
you could write software to
reverse engineer the seed and
you can basically clone it. You can use it to clone it as a rolling door.
But you can also do that by just going to your garage door,
turning on the rolling code app, pressing the little button on your garage door.
Well, no No, no. Um, and teaching it and,
-- yeah,
-- like when you buy a $20
remote, I want to move on. It's being used to steal cars.
-- That's the important part.
-- It's not,
it's not being used to steal cars.
You don't think it's not being used is something else being used.
There have been zero confirmed cases. What has been
sort of,
yeah.
Well, I've, I ha there has been video evidence, for example,
from Britain where somebody was wearing a backpack
and holding up a big aerial and they were
using it to essentially proxy the signal from the
keys inside the house next to the the door
to the parked vehicle because as somebody pointed out, like when you start the car,
it, you know, talks to the microchip in the key and says, hey, are you the key?
Do you do the right key? I can start good
but you don't like
just because it loses contact with that microchip,
you don't stop the car because as somebody pointed out like,
what if your kid throws the key out of the car at highway speed?
You don't just have the car come to a
-- that way
-- on the brakes.
So what you do is you essentially have a stronger,
like a better finer tuned receiver and a stronger transmitter
so that you can essentially get the car to think that the key is in the car when it's,
in fact, it's, you know, 50 ft away or whatever.
And so you just proxy the signal. Could you use a flipper zero for that? Absolutely.
Yes.
But you'd have to like, take it apart and add the aerial and a bunch of other stuff.
-- And at that point.
-- Well, no, no, no, my understanding.
And this is
for, I think Hyundai and Kia,
you have such a weak system used in their keys
that it's becoming trivial to just
use any sort of
NFC device
to just
trick the car.
So there's like attacks where you, for example, with a rolling code, I block you,
I jam it and I record your rolling code
and then so you play rolling code A and I jam it and record it
and then you put the, you push the button again because you want your garage door open
that says rolling code B I block and jam that and I play rolling code A and you go, oh,
good.
My garage door worked it just glitched. Sure, whatever.
And I now have rolling code B that I can use at a later date
to open your garage door.
Right. Sure. Sure. And so flipper zero can do things like that sort of.
But fundamentally
I think what happened is
the Canadian Justice Minister's car got stolen three times in three years.
You know, versus the rest of us who people are having their car stolen,
they're tracking them to a shipping container and then to the
Middle East or Ukraine because they put air tags in them
and they're like phoning the police saying, hey, my car is at this, like,
I know where it is to within 10 ft.
It's at the docks. Can you please go get it?
And of course the cops are like, yeah, we might get on that real soon now and of course,
by the time they get there, the car's gone,
you know. And what, what I love is that somebody pointed out if you can smuggle cars
out of Canada this easily, what is being smuggled in anyways?
-- Ignoring that little chestnut.
-- Oh, who knows?
I mean, yeah, that's another conversation.
So, but the problem is we keep blaming the messenger
-- and not fixing the problem.
-- Well, I
don't know if I'd say we're blaming the messenger.
The, the problem I see this is a very human thing I think
is
we see inactivity happening
and will often say like, like stealing tax I DS is similar.
We blame the company that lost the tax ID.
We blame the company that built the flipper zero
when the reality is the place that thing is being used is the actual problem, right?
Where these cars have terrible authentication.
These credit agencies have no authentication.
We've already outlawed the behaviors. It's illegal to steal.
That mostly works but not really and real realistically,
you can't
make a theft proof car. You can't make a theft proof business.
Like perfect example is banks.
I love that banks
can still be robbed.
But the last number I saw was the average cash
getaway of a bank in Alberta was just over $2000.
-- So
-- they've, yeah, I, I believe it's terrible.
They've essentially minimized that to the point where it's like, oh, yeah, we,
yeah, it sucks.
But, you know,
we'll eat the $2000 loss rather than somebody get hurt with medical cost,
like $2000 of medical cost.
This is like three aspirin and a five minute
consult with your
doctor for sure.
And that's the thing, like, like we have potholes in pavement,
but as long as we minimize them,
so there's not like a giant one in the middle of a busy road.
-- Cool. Fine. Great. Let's do that.
-- We are not talking about potholes.
-- You're done, you're cut off and if you say it again,
-- no, no.
But so we, we plow,
we plow the main roads and the side roads are slick and covered
in snow and you better drive a little bit slower than usual.
But that's ok because you're only driving half a kilometer on these
small side roads when you get to the big roads that were,
you know, to get where you're going,
they're plowed and we just have to do a good enough
job.
But I think part of the problem is we keep Externalizing and we
keep allowing and almost encouraging companies to
externalize costs and make people miserable.
-- So that they can save a penny.
-- That's the, the story of humans.
What you're talking about is making unwanted behavior expensive, right.
So we want to make unwanted behavior expensive essentially. But
like in the case of the flipper zero or the data breach,
the problem isn't actually the unwanted behavior.
The problem is
the car has poor security or the credit agency has poor security.
But we are almost always focusing on
the other side of that. Right.
The place where the information or the device or the whatever came from
versus focusing on the actual problem itself.
Like a perfect example is, is focus
focusing on password breaches when the answer is
we really need to just move past passwords.
Sure. Right. Right. Right.
Like they're just, they're not capable, like they're just not capable of true.
Like, it's like cars, we, we had ignitions with a key,
we moved past that to ignition interlocks with a microchip because
just, it's, you can jam a screwdriver and then if you can physically turn it,
you can start the car
right. And putting a microchip in the key just 100% stops that.
And especially Britain, the numbers, uh, there was a report which I'll, uh,
anyways, the point is when they started
having microchips in the keys,
car thefts fell off a cliff. Right.
Right. For a while. And that's the thing. Right. It's, it's like this is a much more
if all I have to do is break your car window,
jam a screwdriver in the ignition lock and physically turn it with all my force.
Yeah, I can steal cars. But if I need to
buy a flipper zero and start cloning stuff, that's a much higher bar.
I mean, this is the nature of security. It's very cat and mouse, right? Where
the bad guys do a thing
and then the defenders can defend against the thing
and then the bad guys do another thing.
We see this in computer security all the time.
Maybe the thing is that it seems like we've plateaued,
especially with
banks and credit agencies and all this doing these
things that allow people to do bad things.
I mean,
I know that on the back end they are absolutely
doing more fraud detection using A I tracking stuff,
blah, blah, blah.
And again, it might be truly worse
if they were doing nothing.
But I feel like the car theft thing in Canada is getting bad
enough that it's making the national news cycle now on a repeated basis.
Let me maybe flip this on its head
and let's think about the data breach perspective because I
think that one is more interesting than stealing cars.
Everyone
is holding your data now.
It used to be 10 or 20 years ago. A
lot of places didn't have it,
but like your freaking grocery store has information on you now, right?
That's just the way it is literally everyone
there was that thing with the,
they found a bunch of vending machines secretly taking pictures of people.
M and M machines. Yeah.
Right. Like, when I read that I was like, what, like,
I wasn't even surprised. I'm not gonna lie. I was like,
I'm not surprised.
Well, they, they had the same thing with the, um, what was it clear case where the mall
-- kiosk with the mall maps had cameras taking pictures of people's faces,
-- right? Ok.
But anyway, so here's the thing,
I if the number of data breaches has gone up, but it's probably gone up less
quickly, less fast as the number of organizations holding your data,
which is everyone now.
So I do think things are probably getting better in some ways, in some ways,
they're not like we have other problems as well.
And I think this kind of comes back to,
we focus on the data breaches when obviously the answer is like,
why do you have my data
is the real question?
Well, and the problem is they need to have my data because if they sell well,
not so much now because you can't bond phones to plans, they have to be unlocked.
But back in the days, for example,
uh Well, actually, no, especially now when they sell you a phone in Canada,
they want to very much know who you are
because they're giving you this $900 device that you can turn around and sell on
Khai
or Craigslist for Americans and
you know, stop paying the monthly contract and run away from it.
And so they really need to know who you are.
And so they want to
like from their perspective,
we want to get all this data about you so that somebody can't impersonate you.
But then conversely, are they good stewards of that data?
Well, I think there are,
there are organizations we interact with that Absolutely
should have access to some of our information.
I acknowledge that. Right. Like if my, my cell phone provider needs to know who I am.
Yes. Banks. There's like there's
requirements for banks to verify your ID.
Right? Like when I opened a bank account I had to bring in a ton of freaking paperwork.
I get it. That's ok.
But like why does my freaking grocery store need to know my phone number and address?
Right. I mean, you can, you can tell them no, but we all know most people don't,
you know, they, I do love it.
They think I'm a freak because I never, I never give them that stuff.
-- I'm like, no, don't you want a reward? No, I
-- don't.
I've noticed more and more a
lot of them. Just very,
what's your postal, like they ask for your postal code in a way where they expect it.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, they, they, they don't even know what to do when you say.
-- No, sometimes.
-- Well, actually, no.
What I've noticed now is more and more they have
a button to just go on to the next screen.
Whereas in past they would type like hohoho or t one, t one, t one, t one or whatever.
But now most of them have a button that they just hit and it moves to the next screen.
Same thing at IKEA. Right.
If you're not an IKEA family rewards, whatever the heck it's called,
there's a button on the screen now that lets you go past it.
Whereas,
you know, a shopper's drug mart makes it like you have to,
you have to basically not be a member and click through
it like three or four times to get to the payment.
I, I don't think we can regulate those behaviors.
I don't think we can really significantly
prevent that because businesses want that data.
It's valuable because they can sell it.
And I think something to remember too is I don't care who
leaks my data. The fact is now my data is leaked.
It's in a public data set potentially. And
whoops. See. And that's part of the problem is
I don't care that my data is held by 10 or 20 or 1000 people.
I care that my data got leaked once and now is public to some degree
and once it's out, it's kind of out.
I mean, this is like, ironically back in the early days, you know,
there was the old hacker saying information wants to be free
and what the purpose of that saying really is, is like,
-- once information leaks it's out forever
-- you can't fix confidentiality.
Right.
And
this is one of those things that
there are a lot of people who don't care
that they might not have confidentiality, but there's
a lot of people do.
And it's also, it should be like a decision. Right.
-- Like,
-- if you legally change your name from Max to Maxine,
-- there's a lot of the world where you do not want that to be public.
-- Yeah.
Unfortunately. Yes, that's absolutely correct. It's, it's kind of nuts like that.
-- Well,
-- also we don't get to decide what matters 10 or 20 years from now.
-- Yeah,
-- that's true too.
That's another thing.
Like, there are behaviors 20 years ago.
You're not wrong
about things changing in the future, you're not wrong about
making this decision.
I mean, at the same time though, like,
I feel like we've just talked in circles
and there's no outcome to this conversation.
Well, and maybe there isn't and maybe this is just part of the human condition
and maybe part of it is
maybe accepting that
and part of it is maybe there are clever ways to make this better through.
-- Well, we've seen it with GDPR. Right. GDPR has tried.
-- We can't accept it.
No, we can't accept it. Look,
I think
when pollution was terrible 100 years ago,
there were lots of people that said Oh, we can't possibly do it anything about this.
And you know what we did,
we did something about it and it was really expensive and
it was really hard and it took a really long time.
Yeah.
And I think this is exactly the same thing.
This is like the story of computer security is,
there are tons of people that stand around and say there's nothing we can do.
It's too hard to fix. Like this is just the way it's going to be.
And the reality is
it isn't like we can literally do whatever we want. We just have to go do it.
Well,
maybe a better example is house fires because there used to be a lot of house fires.
And for example, the electrical code has changed so much in North America,
like disconnects arc fault circuit interrupts,
all sorts of things that are expensive.
-- Like an arc, fault circuit interrupt is like 200 bucks
-- for,
-- I mean,
-- automobile accidents.
How much does an airbag cost?
Yeah, exactly.
And maybe that's the problem is we're so used to houses burning down.
We just can't imagine a house that doesn't burn down.
All right.
I,
I want to end this one on kind of a happy note and we've run ourselves out of time
and I feel like we're not going to add
anything of value to this conversation at this point.
What a, what a strange topic.
It's always funny we go into some of these things like, oh,
that sounds really interesting.
-- And at the end I'm like, oh, I feel depressed.
-- That was depressing. I need
a drink.
But, but look, I think at the end of the day,
this is one of those situations where as professionals in this industry,
as humans in society, like
we it's OK to make demands, right?
It's easy to say, oh, there's nothing we can do.
There's always something we can do, it might not be super effective,
but
there's something you can do, right? And this is where
you know,
talking to politicians making sure you're like doing what you can at your job.
There's things we can't do.
I think educating people to the reality of this is very important because for
example,
this is like what Thomas was talking about where a
lot of these officials think open sources is this big
happy, healthy ecosystem
and some of it is like the Linux kernel. Absolutely A K
jillion people curl.
I think he's I know it's over 1200 developers was
the last time I saw him too on Mastodon.
God, I hate saying too,
I'm just gonna go anyway.
So he announced it on Mastodon and there are definitely there is that.
But then like your data with,
here's the long tail of like 100,000 N PM projects, you know, with 50 developers,
owning half of them.
All right, I'm gonna call this one. I
feel like
this is a conversation, I'm sure we will have again and it will never end.
So I have a parting thought that I think might help, which is
let's hope.
Let's all try to be better.
Yeah,
that's fair.
And if nothing else, at least be nice to each other.
Yeah,
that's the least we could do.
All right, thank you, Kurt. Thank you ever for listening.
Go to up at social security podcast.com.
Head up the show notes, U Pound do says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media or I ma
on not social media.
Was it x.com?
I don't know.
Yeah, that's right.
Zitter or something.
No, this show is over.
Kurt. Have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.