Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 143 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- I'm excited for this one.
Kurt has something special and he won't tell me what it is, which is as, as
two huge advantages, I must say first is number one,
I had nothing to prepare. So I've done nothing.
And number two is just the,
the ultimate excitement of not knowing what's going to happen.
I'll give you a hint.
What was that was that? Did you hit something?
Well, something hit.
That was me dropping a phone book.
You dropped a phone book. You have a phone book.
Yeah, they delivered a
yellow pages to my house the other day and I was pretty sure.
So the way it works locally,
if the I don't even know if the white pages exist anymore.
But the last I knew was that you had to sign
up for the white pages like you had to ask for one
and the yellow pages you opted out of right.
You got it by default and you could opt out
and II I thought I opted out but they delivered one
and it's really interesting
because have you actually ever read a phone book?
I
did when I was young.
I mean, I, I guess I used it, I wouldn't call it reading material necessarily.
I actually read it because
-- this is the, basically, this is the weirdest
-- thing you have so little to do
it.
I didn't read the whole thing. Well, ok.
Number one, this yellow pages is only four, it's not even 400 pages of content.
Ok. And I live in a metro area with a million people.
Right.
What's, but what's really interesting for a couple of things?
Normally this phone book is trying to be a website
on the front of it is 200 plus smart tips, high energy eating your dental health,
hiring a contractor and cut home utility costs.
Plus out and about Edmonton's diverse food scene.
It's missing like you'll never,
you'll never believe number seven.
Exactly.
And then,
and, and then like inside of it, it's great because you'll, you'll look up a topic
and it will be like, uh, go see whatever the topic is like here.
Hot water heater and tanks, see water heaters,
which is like at the opposite end of the phone book.
Ok.
So number one, like this is clearly a dying industry because of the 400 pages,
30 of the pages are plumbers
-- that doesn't shock me.
-- 10 pages of restaurants and eight pages of
dentures.
Uh,
I'm surprised there's only eight of dentures since their
target demographic probably also needs dentures or sorry.
-- Denture, its denture is, I've never seen that word before.
-- Denture.
Iss, is that like the people who make dentures? I, I don't know.
And they, I mean, they're splurging on half page ads.
The funny thing is the dentists
are not buying ads.
Oh, no, there's a couple of dentists with ads. But the dentures,
man, they're, they're buying ads like you would not believe.
And
about the demographic here. I mean, let's face it.
So I get a phone book every year and you know what I do?
I pick it up off my porch and I dump it in the recycling bin.
I don't, I couldn't tell you what's in it. I don't look at it.
I don't care because why would I want that?
Well, so here's what's most interesting is there's the, the 400 pages of content
and
at the back there's like this helpful stuff of
like how to dial a long distance number,
which is funny because we have just default 10 digit dialing now.
But there's actually some really interesting stuff at the back. So,
uh, my favorite part is number one
obscene or harassing calls.
The best way to deal with these calls is to hang up.
So even the phone company knows, don't feed the trolls
and number two. Have you actually ever,
did you know if you have a landline? You
there is actually a call trace function.
Uh What do you mean call trace like? Is that the what star 69 where you dial back or?
No? That's the, um,
well, that's the, the, the callback thing.
Um,
so number one, if you have a landline, well, when I say landline it's a voice,
like everything's a voice line here locally.
But if you have a voice line through the phone company, uh, first of all,
they have a call screen list and you dial star 60,
there's voice prompts and then you, um, and this is the worst to activate,
call screen, dial one or three to deactivate call screen, dial zero or three.
Like who designed that?
Ok.
And so you can basically call screen, you can,
you can set your phone like the phone company at their end to, to screen your calls.
You're maybe thinking of the uh the,
the callback thing where you dial star or whatever.
But no, they actually have a call trace thing where
hang up for several seconds, then pick up and listen for a dial tone, dial star 57,
a recording will guide you through the steps,
write down the date and time of the calls plus anything that was heard.
A recording will instruct you where to report successful traces.
So they basically made it so tracing the call because you know,
caller id is worthless now, right?
Like I get,
I get Chinese uh the Chinese kidnapping phone calls constantly from, from my phone,
you know, area code, which is obviously spooked.
I've sadly never gotten one. I want to troll them so bad
-- and it just, it never happens to me.
-- It's a, it's a recorded message.
Oh,
that's less exciting then.
-- Yeah.
They also have the rules about the
unwanted telephone or fax telemarketing calls and,
and what made me laugh there was, there's that article last week about the FCC,
right?
They've issued, what was it? $208 million of fines
to telemarketers. And guess how much they've collected
-- like $7 I assume
-- actually. Yeah. No, $7000.
You going
on?
-- And it's pretty close.
-- Yeah,
you had the first number, right? So,
and then there's a, there's, where was it? They, they actually have this like online
safety program
and they talk about it in the phone book for about half a page of very fine print
and then they don't give the URL.
That's great. Good job everybody.
So I googled it.
And again, it's pretty fascinating because also in the phone book,
keep your personal email account.
Personal. Don't use your personal email account.
The one you use to connect with family,
friends and manage your business matters for social media, the activities,
eg Facebook online contest.
See now to me, I think for a lot of people, Facebook is
how they connect with their friends and family
seriously and, and just use the same password for them both. And you'll be fine.
Ok. Anyways, instead create a separate email account. Like Google Mail.
I like that. They, that's it.
Everybody's given up. Like, even in print it's like there's,
you know. Yeah, you go to Google for that.
Right. It's, it's on the internet.
If this email account is compromised,
your personal email account will still be intact.
So, not the worst piece of advice ever. But,
no, that's terrible advice.
-- I'm, I'm just gonna say it's terrible advice because the reality
-- is, well, no,
there's worse advice in here.
You're already using a service like gmail.
You're,
you're getting reasonable protections for the most part and
they're going to block most of the garbage.
So it doesn't matter. Except now you have two email addresses.
You have to probably remember two terrible passwords and
they're 99% of the time going to be the same
if you're the kind of person reading the phone book.
Yeah, a good, hey, a good password is
eight characters long and includes numbers, letters and symbols, eg star
and don't forget to change your passwords frequently.
Oh, yes. That's great advice.
Like, every couple of days I recommend, like,
if a password is more than three hours old, too old, you should totally change that.
Well, see, and they,
they get that don't use the same password
for your computer smartphone email and other accounts,
this is a jackpot for hackers
if you can't remember your passwords.
No, if you can't remember your passwords,
write them down and put them into a folder with an unrelated name.
Like vacations in your filing cabinet.
Never leave them out in the open or by your computer where everyone can see them.
Now, wait a second. Who,
like, my computer at home is like,
my kids and my partner can see it and I guess
the cleaner, if she was here and I left the room, which that would,
yeah,
I've never understood that whole concept of, don't put a, like a post it on your,
on your computer or whatever at home
because everyone will see it.
Well, no, your family can see and your family can hack you because they'll just,
you know,
they have physical access to all your stuff on an ongoing basis.
Now I get it an office, like,
in an open plan office probably don't write your user name and password down.
Put it on a post it note on your computer. Right.
But II, I just love that whole, you know,
like now we know to look in people's vacation folders
when we break into their house to get it,
-- their written down passwords
-- and, and that's why I keep mine in a file called,
not passwords.
-- So it's obvious what it is
-- but what's in the passwords file? Like a mouse trap.
That's a good idea.
It works in the movies.
I, I think you're right
where if you can't trust the people in your house. You have huge problems.
But my suspicion is this is one of those old, well, it's like they also said,
change your password often, right?
This is one of those old attitudes that
may never die because humans think it makes sense even though it doesn't.
-- Well, it's because
-- we wrote it down
and we'd have to change it if we wanted to change it. But, but it's written
down.
No, no, like Nist changed their guidance
and
I give them a ton of credit because it's hard to do.
Well, but Nist actually is in the, is in the, is in the business of, of, well,
science of,
oh, you know, this thing that we thought was right, was wrong. So
we, we actually do need to change what we're saying about this because, you know,
standards and technology, like, it's in the name,
what I really love is that it actually gets even kind of
worse and weirder on, on their online thing.
So I don't know what the acronym stands for. It's wise,
it's like the wise digital pledge and there, there are, uh,
the logos like a little owl.
Yeah, there's just some strange things.
Like they talk about setting up a Google alert for your name,
which is fantastic if you have a somewhat unique name,
right? But like, what if you're John Smith?
Good luck. And then they also talk about where was it,
uh, the whole cyberbullying thing.
And I'm not really clear because, I mean, ok, they have one good message which is,
-- like, don't, don't
-- cyberbully people or
kind of like, don't, don't,
don't be a bully.
Which? Ok. Yeah. No, I agree. Yeah. Yeah.
Like, is that, how, wait, so that's what we,
we just have to tell people to stop being a hoes on the internet and they will.
That seems
easy.
Well, yeah.
Yeah. So,
there we go. Problem solved also while you're at it. Stop being insecure. How about?
And then security solved also?
Yeah. Oh, I thought you meant insecure, like, in my emotional state.
Well, no, I mean, that's your own problem. That, that's another issue. But. Right.
Right. And, and maybe stop driving like a jerk.
I mean, while we're at it, why not?
Well, and they do, they do say intervene if you see it happening, intervene,
which I agree with.
Right. Like, I 100% agree with that.
Sure. But beyond that, I mean,
I, I, here's my, here's, I guess what really kind of annoys me
is I suspect is that actually the best we can do because I think that might be it.
I think given the current state of affairs the answer is yes. And I will.
So actually this is very topical given you bring this up.
So there's a guy I follow on Twitter named Chad Loder
and I forget off the top of my head, what his role is. He's the CEO of, of some company
and basically he's put together like a Twitter moment
of people who are giving death threats to a Muslim Senator in the United States
-- and comments on
-- whatever. Right.
And, and I looked at this and it is
horrifying what these people are saying and Twitter
doesn't do anything unless you report them.
And he's basically saying people please pick some out,
report them to Twitter because obviously I assume the more
people who report something as violating the terms of service,
the more weight it would have.
But at the same time, you look at these comments and like, holy crap.
If Twitter can't like automatically pick these out
-- what the heck guys were.
-- They don't want to.
-- Well, and yes, I think that's, and, and
-- again, and I, and I,
and I don't mean they don't want like, and
I know I shouldn't talk to the mental state of a corporation and say like, oh, well,
here's how they feel but clearly based on the fact they haven't done it,
they don't want to because for example,
remember that whole thing last week with tweeting out, what is it?
IC U 0.996
and,
and the Twitter client returns an error
because it's been, it's been blacklisted
like you can't tweet that term
and, and that also suggests
-- that they have the ability to do
-- these
-- things.
-- It doesn't suggest that it proves it.
Ok.
Yes.
Come on.
It doesn't suggest that's like,
that's like the guy that was setting cars on fire on white Aven,
there's video of him doing it and then being tackled to the ground and arrested
and, and I get that innocent until proven guilty and all that. But,
you know, I love that the papers are respectful enough to say, you know,
the alleged blah, blah, blah.
And it's like I get that we do that because we are, you know,
we are society and we are better than these people,
you know. But, but like when a company does this stuff, it's like,
uh let's see what happens if I try to tweet it.
Oh, it tweeted it now. They've unblocked it.
Oh, man. Interesting.
Yeah. Oh, but it doesn't make it a hot link.
Interesting. Yeah, I tweeted http sf
slash
is it 996 dot IC U or IC U 0.996.
Got
back.
Maybe you did it wrong.
Oh,
that's embarrassing.
Ok. Here we go. This, yeah, it's dot IC U tweet.
They've unblocked it. It works again.
I guess, I guess the people losing their minds online works once in a while.
But yeah, so speaking of Twitter, like, obviously they can block stuff,
they have the technology to block it.
They at a minimum to do like a blacklist
of like you can't say these words or URL S
and let's face it.
Like you don't need sophisticated machine learning to spot these death threats.
Because most of them are pretty,
pretty.
Yeah, they're out there,
I guess, reporting the stuff beyond that. What
I guess really? Is there anything we can do?
Especially assuming if these major platforms decide to do nothing?
No,
there, there really isn't.
And this is a frustrating aspect of society right now and this
is something actually you and I talk about a lot and I,
I'll, I'll open the window a bit into our, I
guess, ridiculous personal views on things is
you, you look at the way people used to act and for example,
if there were places that would be,
say outright racist or against certain groups or, or whatever,
and
you look at now where, you know,
everyone has the racist uncle that we only deal with at Thanksgiving.
And historically,
a lot of these people didn't have platforms before and now
they have the internet where they can all come together.
And this is,
this is one of those things that you and
I always disagree on where you're talking about.
How do we help these people?
And I'm just like, I, I think they're a lost cause and I don't think we can save them.
And II, I really don't know the answer. I wish the answer wasn't give up.
There's nothing you can do. But I, I have a strong suspicion. It is and I think
it is up to us, I think as a society
to decide what to do about some of this and let's face it if we're
counting on the likes of Google and Facebook and Twitter to define how we handle,
I guess some of the negative aspects of society,
we have way bigger problems than those aspects. And that's kind of where we're at.
So we can't necessarily rely on society or
humans to kind of choose what's good because
historically and even today, there's still a lot of places that, you know,
are reasonably enlightened, like, say, Canada and the US
and yet we still have, you know,
states or jurisdictions with some really backward laws or, you know,
really backwards things being pushed.
And
I think just be, you know,
part of my concern with democracy is just because 51% of people want
to drink apple juice for breakfast doesn't mean we should do it.
-- I, yeah, I mean, Brexit, right. Yeah. Yes.
-- Brexit.
Fantastic, perfect example of 50 plus one.
Maybe, you know,
there should be somewhat of a legislative or some bureaucracy involved
to maybe slow it down a bit or make a,
you know, look at the 2nd and 3rd order effects and say,
have we really thought this through because
uh we don't have enough shipping, pallets or,
you know, warehouses to store medicine if we do decide to leave.
Right.
That's the sort of decision I feel like should have like a,
a two third super majority style vote, not a 50% plus one.
Yeah, I I would say at a minimum. And
it's funny to me that we have these arbitrary, like 50 plus, you know,
I remember the Quebec referendum,
like 20 years ago when Quebec was voting about whether or not to leave Canada.
And, you know, of course, Quebec was like 50% plus one. That's good enough for us.
And of course, the rest
was like, no,
that's not how that's going to work
and they got like, high forties percent.
It was, I remember we were all watching the TV,
with the numbers creeping up and it was like,
uh,
you know, because it was really a question of like, ok, so if they do vote,
if they vote themselves off the island, like then what?
You know, because that's, again, I don't, I'm not sure they had a plan for this,
but back to this sort of human nature thing, it's,
you know, even if, again, like 51 or
I'm guessing 90% of people would agree with, like, we should eliminate poverty,
right?
And so we hold a vote and we decide to eliminate poverty. Fantastic.
But like, how do we go about this? You know?
And that's, that's part of my concern is how do we, how do we go about?
We've agreed that this is a problem. We've agreed that it should be solved. Ok.
But how do we solve it?
And Dan Kaminsky was tweeting about some stuff about how, you know, people
kind of when you work for a place and you
don't like a decision they made just at some point,
be an adult.
Stop fighting it and do your job and implement it. And I was like,
I agree. But, and that's a part of adulting is there are, there are problems
where it's not that there's a solution that's not desirable.
There are problems where there is no solution that is even palatable
to a large group of people.
Right.
There are just issues out there where at least
one or 10 or 20% of everybody involved in it
will hate this.
-- Any solution you pick
-- and, and that's, that's true of everything, right?
I mean, like, like you talk about, we should vote on getting rid of poverty
and there's probably 10 to 20% of people who would vote against that.
I mean, as crazy as that might sound to us it, I guarantee they're there.
Yeah, this, this whole phone book, like I said, II, I read the bit at the back.
There's a couple, like there's about two dozen pages of this, of this weird content,
including their user agreement.
Like there's a long distance
dude, there's a long distance terms of, there's the general terms of service
and the long distance terms of service.
Uh Sorry, the general terms of service is two pages.
Do they have
the longest
button you can push with your finger or?
Yeah, I, I don't know, like by opening this phone book. Did I accept this? Because it,
wait, oh, I threw the wrapper away. Damn. It.
Did the rapper have a shrink wrap? Ya.
I hope
it
never occurred to me to look.
I hope it did.
And then they do have a, a thing on how to recycle this thing.
Well, that's good
since it's what I do
-- with all. And then
-- here's the weirdest thing.
There's a second phone book at the back of it,
the business listings for Edmonton and it's like
the white pages style with like 40 some pages
of just
-- like business name, phone number type thing. Yeah.
-- Yeah.
And, and the address in super fine print
and of course, it's not all the businesses because there's, there's more than this,
-- you know, it's, it's
-- probably the businesses that were willing to pay them.
Yeah, because I looked through for some businesses.
I know and I can't find any of them.
Like, not a one.
So,
you know what my thought is here is I,
I have a feeling this is your typical dying industry style model
where
even even the yellow pages people have to know
that their future is limited because let's face it.
The people who would use a phone book are
of a certain age will say
they're dying out. We can say it.
Ok, they're right,
they're going to die out and the young new
people coming up just are willing to use phone books
or the internet or anything else that is better than a phone book.
I can still think of one use for a phone book which is,
uh, but it doesn't work now because there's not enough stuff in here.
But it was, um, my mom used to keep a phone book in the car
for the list of gas stations
and I could still, that kind of almost makes sense like if your phone,
so you can find a gas station if it's late at night, you don't know where you are,
like kind of neighborhood wise.
-- You know, what,
-- how is that going to work? Phone books aren't, don't work like that.
You don't have like a map that shows you where the gas stations are.
Well, no, but you can look through it and look for a nearby address.
I, I live in a city with a grid system so it's real easy.
-- Or
-- you can just see your eyes and look for a sign that says gas station.
Well, and that's why I said it doesn't really work that well, but like it's,
it's like the one limited corner case I can sort of see for a phone book.
-- So,
-- no, you don't worry.
I thought you were going with this,
which would be the one corner case I would agree with is what?
Roll it up and hit people.
No, you could leave it in your car so you could have someone sit on it who is short
and they
could
see
out the window.
Yeah.
II, I don't know. I, it's, it's one of those things that
I think it has a value to the people who need it
but to the vast majority of other people it does not.
And
in, in my, I guess, typical tradition here,
I think we can look at this with our security glasses on
where there are many things we do in security
that don't really have any value to most people, but we still do them
-- and like, crappy password advice is a great example.
-- Just exciting news.
My partner works for the provincial government and
they change the password change requirements from,
I think it's quarterly to yearly.
-- So even the government is learning that's
-- better. I mean,
I could see once a year,
I could see once a year is not totally unreasonable
part of it too is that if, if you're not using your account, then, you know,
to flush the account,
like,
because they have part of the challenge is
they have logins on like 10 million systems.
Right. Right. Right.
So, and I admit, you know, I do similar things like when I'm trying to, you know, I,
I look at account activity and call it
or suspend them and see if anybody complains, you know, the classic screen test.
Right. Right.
And I'm, I'm ok with that.
-- But no,
-- I agree. Like, there's, there's so many things we do in security. Why do.
We do them well, because we do them
-- right.
-- I take the facts to the engineers, you know, to quote office space.
Yes. That's right.
That's right. And I mean, every industry is like this. I, I have no doubt
and
it's just, it, it's one of those things, you know, what the story I,
I always think of is,
is there was a, a doctor
long ago
who he was, he, he dealt with, I believe he delivered babies primarily.
And he basically got the great idea. Let's wash our hands between seeing people
and his peers actually ridiculed him and yelled at him like it wasn't enough to just,
oh yeah, they drove him.
Yeah, they drove him insane. Essentially. He ended up dying in an insane asylum.
Yeah. They, well, they put him in an asylum and,
yeah. Right.
And,
and it's one of those things like I see that all
the time where someone suggests something instead of just being like,
eh, whatever I don't care,
we actively fight against them.
And I mean, I'm sure this even happened.
-- I bet there was a time in the yellow pages were like,
-- oh, it's still happening,
Cesarean sections the way they cut,
they used to cut across and they're discovering now that it might be better to cut
up like, at 90 degrees.
Ok? Because it does less damage and it's a bit less invasive.
So even to this day, we're still like, why do you do it that way.
Well, because that's how we do c sections.
Like,
it's not like we've done a study to actually confirm this is the best way to do it.
-- It's just,
-- well,
I would hope somebody does do a study though and then they can make a determination.
Well, it's kind of hard to get pregnant women willing to do,
undergo experimental procedures for some weird reason.
Well, that is fair. I think
I, I won't disagree with you because I would not sign up for that.
Well, no, you, you're a man so you probably wouldn't.
I'm, I'm comfortable saying that when my wife was pregnant, if someone had said,
would you like to undergo this experimental procedure?
Her and I would have both given a
-- extremely energetic. No,
-- I was going to go with Death Claire.
It's conceivable.
She would have murdered somebody asking a question like that. But it is. Yeah.
Anyway.
And, and this actually is something that,
that came up for me recently as well is so I
was uh I was just at a conference called Cipher Con.
It's a hacker conference in Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
It was,
it was a lot of fun and there were certain things that came up
during just talking to people and attending some of the talks and whatnot.
It's just like
the, the gross lack of rigor in science behind what we do
is fascinating where there's just so much hearsay in
a we even lack
the,
that the scientific knowledge that the scientific method can be applied to this.
Right. Right.
And you ask people questions like that even,
and a lot of them don't even understand what you're asking.
-- Oh,
-- I got really angry responses. Like,
I mean, what we're currently doing with, with the CV E stuff, you know,
we're doing some surveys
and
a
great, this is actually a really good example of scientific rigor.
So we're doing some surveys to find out how people feel about some of the CV stuff.
And I've had something like an average of one response a day for three weeks.
So actually the answer is nobody cares about this particular topic regarding CV.
It's good enough and that's a fair answer.
Yeah, it's good enough. It works. Don't, what, what do we care?
You know, and, but some people are kind of like, well, but,
you know, blah, blah, blah. And I'm like a sample size of 21.
Number one isn't big enough to base a conclusion off of, especially since it's,
you know, self selecting,
like it literally is self selecting.
And number two, it's, it's also, it is a good indication of like,
nobody really cares which that's an answer.
It is.
And I think this is,
this is a realization that I've been struggling with for a long time.
And I know you, you've helped kick me down the road quite a lot.
But there are certain things that
and, and part of CV E is in this boat where the vast majority of people don't care.
Do I wish every security issue had a CV ID.
I do because it would make my life a lot easier. But the reality is
most people fundamentally don't care.
And so the issue becomes,
why don't they care
and the reason people care about things is because it gives them some sort of value.
Right. Let's face it. People do things because it helps them in some meaningful way.
And I think for a lot of organizations that don't use
-- CV E I DS see the value
-- or they use CV.
And it's good enough because let's face it.
All the major vendors like Microsoft, they actually do a really good job of it and,
and they do, but now here's, let's, I want to put my little little project hat on.
And so here's the thing and this is where
I struggle and I don't know the answer to this yet. But do they,
do they not use CV, E
because
they don't care
or do they not use CV E because it's too hard?
And it's one of those two, I don't know which or maybe both
I would say. Yes. No.
And it depends because part of using CV is, first of all,
you have to say what you mean by that.
Like, do they actually
assume the CV, data feed or do they buy a product?
No, I mean, I mean, publishing, publishing CV E ID
-- where I'm, I'm a project,
-- I would say part of it is,
it's not that they don't care,
-- it's that they don't even know about it and
-- that could be
part
of it like you and I pretend like CV E is well known.
It's not
even in the industry,
I still encounter people who don't know what that acronym means.
And I mean, people in the security industry,
not just like in the it industry in general
and, and that's probably fair. People in the it industry in general have no clue.
But again, and it's fair because there's lots of standards we don't know about.
Like, I know
a guy who works on medical
billing and coding.
Uh, and he actually works on the standard for medical coding and billing.
-- Yeah, that's a fascinating field
-- actually.
Yeah, I mean, the, apparently there's a lot of stuff around turtle bites.
I have no doubt.
I, I heard they added a new code a couple of years ago for, like,
getting crushed by a whale.
Which
is that, does that happen enough that you need a code for that? I don't know.
Well, yeah, maybe, I mean,
-- the Japanese and Norwegian are still whaling but I assume,
-- I don't know.
-- Oh,
-- there's one for walked into lamp posts that seems reasonable
that
I've done that more than once.
Oh, you know what?
Yeah, you're,
you're thinking of struck by orca initial encounter and I hate to say this,
but Seaworld.
Uh
oh, that's fair. Yeah. Yeah, that's fair. Struck by orca. There you go.
-- Hurts at the opera. It,
-- it happens. I'm sure people slip and fall or, or whatever.
I mean,
I, I get it
-- and
-- then, oh, here's a good one, prolonged stay in weightless environment,
which it's real.
But I feel like it's rare enough that you can
-- just put a note on the guy's file
-- that affects
astronauts.
I feel like that's not one of those things where it's like house where it's like,
why didn't you mention you ate a tuna
sandwich and got some weird parasite or something?
It's like, how did you forget to mention this?
Right.
I, I wondered, is there a medical questionnaire that's like,
have you spent one year or more in space?
Right.
No.
Yeah.
Just put it under other, the, the, this lack of,
and it's not even that we have a lack of scientific rigor, but we have a lack of just
even being concerned
that it's a thing.
And what really blows me away is because tech is
one of the few places where you can actually do
sort of proper, like control blind, double blind experiments. A B testing,
you know,
and the funny thing is the marketing and
sales side are really quite rigorous about this,
-- you know, A B testing to see what drives up sales.
-- Uh huh.
Now, here's the reason for that though.
I think is when you're in marketing, if the sales graph isn't going up into the right,
uh, they fire you and you don't have a job
in security.
What, how do we measure if we're doing our jobs?
How do we measure if we're not doing our jobs? And let's face it. A breach happens.
They're going to fire the co hire a new co,
and the reality is what the co fault. Well, no, not really.
But they needed to fire somebody. So they fired that guy
and, and can the co show it was or wasn't their fault? No, no, they can't.
Can the new co make changes to make something not happen again? Probably not.
And
I have a feeling that that's part of our, our problem here is we,
and, and let's face it, you can get fired as ac O and have a new job by the end of the day.
Right.
It's,
there's so much work for us right now that we have
an industry and at the same time we fight fires constantly.
I actually,
I, I had this chat just the other day with somebody is,
there's all this work I want to do
to make certain things better.
But I spend so much time just like keeping the lights on that I
don't have time to do these other things and it's super frustrating to me because
if I had the time to do this other work
it would alleviate.
So many of the other emergencies I'm dealing with on a constant basis.
But if I can't ignore the, you know what I mean? It's so chicken and egg.
So, you,
well,
the problem is you can't do forest management
if you're constantly putting out forest fires.
Yes.
-- Exactly. That's exactly
-- right. Like, resource wise. Like, I'm lucky in that,
you know, the CS A, we don't ship software. Thank
-- goodness. Although that's going to change at some point,
-- I
say,
aren't you working to fix that?
Exactly. And so,
so operationally, I've outsourced as much as I can to really solid cloud players,
you know, like we use github,
like I am absolutely not running our own source code repo. Uh You know, just no.
Right. I'm gonna use github.
Nobody shouldn't. But,
but the thing is once you reach a certain size, even just running github,
you've got people checking secrets in,
you've got people making commits in places they shouldn't,
you've got commit messages that shouldn't exist.
You have references the internal things and it's like,
oh, my goodness, it never ends.
No, I agree.
And I think I'm beginning to suspect a lot of
this boils down to the law of large numbers,
but there is a fundamental difference in security where you have,
say less than 10 developers.
And let's say you have 1000 or more developers.
I, I think the tipping point is even smaller than that.
-- I think it's a couple of 100
-- Oh, absolutely.
And I think this is true for a lot of businesses though.
Like, I see a lot of the way small businesses operate versus large businesses
or my classic favorite, the,
the government bureaucracy which can survive like massive political shifts.
You know, you,
you can literally go from like a right wing government to a left
wing government to a right wing government in the space of like,
months or years in some countries.
And the bureaucracy just keeps kind of chugging along,
you know, and, and the
country keeps plodding along and things mostly work. It's not great but it works.
Uh, and, you know, and then you look at like a small business where, like,
the owner goes away for a week and like, the place burns down basically.
Right.
You know,
and so I'm beginning to suspect, but part of the problem is
how do you learn that stuff? How do you, how do you implement that stuff?
And
the other problem is a lot of that doesn't work at a small scale.
Yeah.
Or it becomes horribly inefficient at the small scale, like, well, a great example.
Code reviews. But what if you only have like, two devs?
Yeah, you can't do that. And, and you don't, you only have two depths so nobody cares.
No, no, you're, you're dead on. And
I don't know. And maybe that's part of the challenge.
It's just security is an industry is reaching some sort of
tipping point and we kind of don't know where to go.
Next.
One thing I decided really early on with the product I'm working
on is we're not going to have one size fits all security.
What we're going to do is we're going to have a safest possible defaults so that
you can cut yourself with this product.
But you have to take, you know,
you have to take the knife out of the sheath to cut yourself.
And we're going to allow people to dial up
and down their security as they see fit because,
you know, some people might not want full privacy,
they might want to make some of their data public, you know,
that I have this certification or whatever
and
that's up to the user
and in some cases it's not, in some cases,
it's up to whatever their legal jurisdiction says.
And that's the other thing I'm realizing
is we want to operate globally.
So that means how many jurisdictions I, I don't know,
I was trying to Google how many different
jurisdictions that means we're operating in infinity.
And I couldn't even figure out like in the US, how many jurisdictions there are?
Like, I kind of thought it would be so
simple, like how many states are there? Plus federal? No, it's actually different.
It's a much different number than that.
Right.
You got with federal states, counties, local levels,
-- you probably have even special areas
-- even within states.
You've got different.
National Parks?
-- Oh, that's true. That's true. National Parks are
-- special.
You know, the White House lawn apparently is its own weird thing because it's
actually security is provided by the US park service.
From, no,
but from the fence on the grass to the building
and then the building is something different and it's just,
but there's all sorts of these weird corner cases.
I
have
no
doubt the US Capitol police,
you know, that's its whole little thing.
So, like I said, I was trying to figure out how many jurisdictions are in America.
And the answer is we're not really sure,
but it's a lot. Just assume it
pretty
much.
And this, of course, ignores the combinatorial problem, right?
Because the combinatorial problem, its ugly head. And then,
you know, it's like GDPR, a British national
dealing with a company in France,
but he lives in Spain and is currently traveling to America.
Like, no, no, I'm not thinking about it.
-- You just
-- made my head hurt and I think we need to call it like, so closing thoughts,
what are you going to do with your phone book, Kurt?
Uh Well, I'm not gonna burn it because that will result in a lot of ash.
-- So I have to go chuck it in the recycle.
-- I guess you're gonna recycle your phone book.
-- There you go.
-- Well, what else
would you do with it? I, that's what I do. I don't know.
I, I can't imagine you can tear him in half. I guess you could do that first.
I love that. It's incomplete. Like it's grossly incomplete.
That's the other thing. Right.
As a, as a source of information, it's grossly incomplete. So I don't trust
it. Right. Google Maps or whatever. On the other hand is,
that's a good point.
That is a good point.
-- Anyway, I don't trust it but people do
-- so you don't have to and ok. All right, man.
I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes,
you see Pound Os S podcast hashtag to find us on the social medias
and yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too, everybody. Thanks.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye.