Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
What's up, man?
-- It's winter. Finally. It's nice.
-- Nice. I hate winter.
It's better than everything being brown and basically dead
now. It's dead but covered in pretty white snow.
I don't have any snow yet.
My biggest complaint is just,
I really like to ride my bicycle outside and I can't do that in the, in the snow.
I have seen
-- people on their mountain bikes with the monster tires.
-- It is possible
it's dangerous as heck because cars don't respect cyclists here.
-- But
-- so I investigated doing this and there are special ice tires you buy,
you put them on your bike.
They're incredibly expensive because you can't like,
you can't cheap out on these because of what you're doing.
-- Don't cheap out on your winter tires, period.
-- Right. Right. But the point is
basically the consensus of everyone I've spoken with is that if you ride a bike
in the winter,
you will fall, there's a
multiple times and
I'm too old to fall off a bike. I'm gonna break a hip or something at this. Point.
So it is out of the question
to be riding outside in the winter on a bicycle for me.
Yeah, I, I biked to high school most times because, um, the,
the school express bus that went by my house was
typically full by the time it went past my house.
And so it would just,
it would just drive by. That's ridiculous.
Well, it, it's a city, it's city, it's like a public bus
and it's like full. So, like, what's the bus driver gonna do?
Stop and apologize and then continue without me anyway.
Yeah, it's not a school bus. Sorry? Yeah.
No, my high school basically had like a transit center right next to it.
So it actually had really good bus connectivity.
But like first thing in the morning, right, like,
weirdly a couple of 100 students want to go to school at the same time.
Very strange.
So I would bike to school and yeah, like, uh,
when I look back at those risks,
I took just riding in rush hour traffic in snow and ice.
I am amazed. I did not die.
Which kind of leads to our show topic of
basically
behaviors and beliefs that used to be correct that are now like,
stupidly dangerous or wrong.
-- All right.
-- So there's an exception to this, there is an article
that Kurt and I read the other day
that is the, the title is Experts from a World that no longer exists.
And I read this and thought this has to be a show because I love it.
So I will summarize this first before we move on
is the fundamental premise of all of this is that
obviously people become experts based upon some sort of knowledge.
Like you could potentially claim that Kurt and I are experts at, at security,
which we'd laugh at.
But
you know what I mean? We, we spent a career
building up this corpus of knowledge that we possess
and
our knowledge
is, I would, I would say it is useful at a point in time that is in the past,
but the the world is still moving into the future. So
-- if you don't, basically, you become an expert,
-- you have to re invent yourself.
-- But then
-- the world changes past your expertise. Yes, exactly. You have to,
you have to build a change,
you have to re invent yourself constantly, like shedding the skin, right?
And I think
the other thing is, well, let's, we're going to ignore the whole, what is an expert?
What decides an expert thing? Like is it a bunch of knowledge? Is it success?
-- Is it whatever?
-- Right?
Well, look, I, I think let's just, let's clarify at the beginning.
Everyone is an expert at something I'm
-- comfortable saying
-- that that's almost always true.
But
yeah, at something there is something that everyone is good at.
I feel like there are some people that are
just useless based on some youtube videos I've seen in
videos
that's maybe another show topic. But let's just say for the moment
that everyone is an expert at something, at
least one thing, possibly more.
Ok. Ok.
So
I have a story I want to tell completely related to this actually.
the Linux Foundation, you know, David Wheeler was on the show last episode.
They're doing their great M FA project
where they're,
they're looking to distribute a
whole bunch of
UB keys and Google Titan Keys
to the world. OK. And
I was in a call with David and, and like, basically, no one showed up.
It was me and him and a couple other people
that important to scare the N PM ecosystem. What are you talking about?
No, no, this is, this actually isn't related to this at all.
It was, I forget what the meeting even was now. Anyway, barely anyone shows up.
And so we're just kind of all chatting and having a
nice time and somehow this M fa stuff comes up.
And basically David was like,
I need someone to write how to documents.
Like that is the one most important thing we need for this project to go forward.
And I'm like, you know, man,
I've written a bunch of stuff about these keys in the past.
I will, I'll do it, you know, I'll do it to just
get it done and like my draft will suck and we can fix it.
But I'll at least get it moving out of the gate. OK.
So I start doing my research and obviously you've got the Titan key,
you've got the UBI key, they're not exactly the same.
And so I'm understanding features and everything and the only part of
the Venn diagram they really have in common is the 502 protocol,
right?
Which,
and then you learn the ugly secret,
what ugly secret that most places say when they support two of a and M fa with the
ki they're not supporting 502 they're supporting the
specific protocol. And so for example, it only works with
keys and not with Google Titan.
Uh uh some of them, some of them, but that's not the point of my story.
Well, but the thing is you got to figure out which is, which, well,
-- whatever
-- I don't care about that point.
So anyway, the point is I said, all right, I'm going to focus on,
on Fight 02 because that's what they have in common.
That'll be the easiest thing to write about
basically. And like Titan Keys basically do Fight 02 and
yikes
do like 100 million other things. OK? But I'm gonna focus on Fight 02.
Now, I've done a lot of, we did, we did podcasts about Fight 02. I mean, like
I would say, if you said, are you an expert on this? I, I might not say I'm an expert.
But I would say I know more than average. OK, I start doing my research.
There is so like there's so much new stuff in this space. It blew my mind.
Like, so here's the most, the,
-- the best thing I love
-- all
time stuff.
No,
no. That's boring,
-- dude. I can use my face to authenticate to a website now.
-- That's boring.
That's boring. Trust me.
So what I learned
is there is now support
in open SSH
to use the
Fido keys
to store encryption. So you can, you can ssh using the keys stored in your phyto
token. But wait, there's more. So anyway, I get this set up, right.
I'm like, OK, I can SS A and
then I learned that get
version 2.34 which came out
like 10 days from the time of recording. I think
that allows you to sign commits with an SSH key.
So now I can sign a get commit using a key on a Fido
token. I'm like, this is ridiculous.
This is so funny because I just looked up to get 2.3 0.4 release.
They hid that under the tidbit section on the
freaking headline. And here's my favorite part.
Sorry, I didn't, I never read this before but,
but the experience of using GP G and maintaining keys can be somewhat cumbersome.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
You don't say right, right.
Like now, now I will say
at this moment,
you cannot verify
SSH signatures with github
or GIT lab.
That's obviously the first thing I looked at,
but you kind of get the point is there's a
topic that I thought I knew more than average about.
And I learned so much working on this documentation and understanding how it works.
And it just, it,
it's funny because
it, it occurred to me shortly after I started, you know,
going down this rabbit hole and learning all this stuff.
I'm like, holy crap.
Like this is literally the thing we're going to talk
about in a couple of days on the podcast.
Like, it's so funny.
Well, what I love is like web off
now supports biometrics.
So literally, I go to websites and windows is like, hey,
do you want to use your face to authenticate to this website?
And I'm like, yeah, sure, whatever, right? You know,
it's
this whole thing of I think part of the challenge is
the world used to change in more of an additive way than in a transformative way.
And I think it changed really slow.
But yeah, also that like, but it was like, you know, A
plus B, not A replaced by B, right?
Like we had radio and then we got TV, and everybody still has radio and TV,
right? But now, for example, computers, like
the only reason I own A TV is because, well, it's
basically a cheap monitor for my Apple.
-- That's what I plug my video games into,
-- like, I haven't had cable TV for over 10 years.
I guess I technically own a radio because I own a car. Right.
But I don't actually own a radio
anymore. And that's the thing. Right.
These, especially in tech with cloud because we've made that transition from,
like,
products to utility.
Like, all my stuff is in the cloud now. I don't own anything.
It's been, it's completely transformational.
Like the CS A the only on premises gear we have is some ubiquity wi fi gear.
And I think like three printers globally. That's it.
That's our physical it infrastructure stack, right?
Compared to 10 or 20 years ago, right?
We would have had a server closet at each location,
a
co
location plus
probably something hidden in my basement in case everything burns down, right?
And now it's completely transformational because it's all in the cloud.
And, and that I think is the biggest problem is
because you said this, right,
we can teach developers new things but to teach them to
like forget or to stop doing old things is really hard.
I mean, it, it kind of is, I I do agree with that.
You've got me thinking now where you're talking about
the old world and the additive nature of technology.
And
I do feel like especially tech has been often very like rip and replace
where because you think a long time ago there were kind of mainframes
and then we moved ourselves into
like individual computers
and now we're kind of
moving back into the mainframe sort of world of cloud.
Well, no, no, we're not moving back to a mainframe.
We're simply moving to a utility model of computing.
I need computing. I like, I need water. I phone up Epcor and
agree to pay them X amount of dollars per month
for water and electricity and sewage and garbage pickup.
You know, same thing with the internet,
right? Internet used to be a bespoke.
Like I had a dedicated 14 4 dial up connection to the internet on 24 7.
I had my own phone line for it.
You know, when I work with my parents back when I was a teenager
and it was, you know, it was a disaster to set up and maintain.
You know, there were scripts to like,
restart it when it died every randomly minutes or hours.
But now it's just like, hey, you know, tell us or shock. Give me fast internet.
Ok, thanks. Bye.
I mean,
-- that is true. Right.
-- It's cars are similar, right?
Car maintenance or even even starting a car,
we went from crank starts where it might break your arm to
you. Push a button
or, you know, you don't even turn a key anymore. You just push a button.
Uh, I do have that. I, I it's so weird because my, my electric car,
I get into it
and then
I push on
and I would muscle memory be, like, trying to stab it with a key.
Uh,
so, you know, it's funny, I actually adapted to that really quickly.
Now, my problem is going back to the gas car having to put a key in it
and just like getting in and sitting there for a second.
Like, I don't remember how to do this,
-- like, Scotty at the computer. Computer.
-- Right. Right.
That's what I feel like every time I get into the gas car.
Yeah.
Yeah. Right. It's like, oh, I have to, I have to start it
like some caveman.
Um, but that's the thing. Right is,
and I think that's a big thing is, is in it,
especially corporate it if you have old system and
new system and if you carry both of them,
the cost is horrendous.
But if you can get rid of old system and just move to new system,
yeah, that's not easy and cheap and fun, but
not having those legacy costs and the costs of doing two separate
things and having two separate documentation
pass and process pass and everything.
Right. I mean, it's,
I've seen like, well, government's a great example. Right.
Government doesn't,
can't get rid of old it the way they would like to because some of, you know,
the papers legislated
and so they're stuck with this insane stuff that, like,
works because it abides by the legislation
and they're stuck with it.
Um,
yeah,
I wanna,
I wanna pull us back out of the show for
a minute because there's actually some things in this,
this article that I think
have have, I'm still not in, I don't know if I agree or not. Exactly.
But so the, the first one I think the most important
is
the, the author talks about Henry Ford
and Ford made a point of not documenting failures.
And now I know I have spoken in the past
about the importance of publishing failure because others can learn.
But in the case of Henry Ford, the reason he said that
is he said, documenting failure,
-- basically tells another person don't try this
-- depending on
the maturity of the person and organization involved.
I agree
because to have the maturity to look at the failures of the past
and actually maybe understand why they failed and maybe try it again.
Because a great example is we all remember
the before, you know, and just around the two thousands of all the online
web stores like pets.com and stuff that just
-- crater spectacularly
-- that's literally called out in this in
this
compared to how much money we all spend on Amazon
or or
so literally, I mean, from the context of pets.com,
I have a funny story about pets.com.
Actually the
the first job I had out of college,
everyone had pets.com that like dog with the
watch around its neck or whatever it was,
everyone had those like plushies all over the office.
So one day I'm like, what's the deal?
And it turned out that the office I worked in
was the old pets.com office.
And so they, they all the furniture, well, they just,
they locked the doors on them one day.
So, like all the furniture and there were boxes of like swag.
So everyone, they just like, used it.
But, but anyway, anyway, like,
so
pets.com
-- always have a special place in my heart. You
-- can
-- and use them to insulate your hobo shelter.
-- I don't have any anymore.
I, sadly I threw them all away when I left that job. But so
now that I'm old, I wish I did anyway.
So like pets.com is a great example where when
pets.com came out in the early two thousands,
it was a monumental failure.
It's like one of the most epic failures of all time.
But now there's a company called Chewy, which is literally doing the same thing.
And in fact,
I use them all the time to order dog food
because they have the one specific kind of dog food.
The vet was like,
you have to feed your dog because my dogs like getting
old and fat and they like feed it this special food.
I order, I use them all the time
and Chewy is wildly successful today,
whereas pets.com exploded in a blaze of glory.
Well, and I mean, I had a presentation I shopped around internally.
Red Hat talking about why clouds?
Why now and part, it's basically, it's the ecosystem
there you can't build in a vacuum and expect to succeed.
Right. Like,
like, I don't care how good your rockets are. Two.
In, in World War Two you don't have computer guidance. You have at best, really crap.
Analog computers and gyroscopes that are
not that good,
you know.
And
so I think part of this is people forget that.
It's, it's about the whole, I hate to say it's like a rain forest,
it's all interconnected, you know, and you touch one thing and it dies.
-- So
-- actually there's a really cool quote.
I just pulled up in this article from Mark Andreessen
and he says all of the ideas that the
people had in the 19 nineties were basically correct.
They were just early,
the infrastructure necessary to make most tech
businesses work didn't exist in the nineties,
but it exists today.
So almost every business plan that was mocked for being
a ridiculous idea that failed is now 20 years later,
a viable industry.
I mean,
you know what it kind of reminds me of sometimes is
going to the moon.
And I know I, I I've used this before in the past many, many times, but like
in the, in the late sixties,
we went to the moon
in spite of the technology
and it was, it was just like you just keep pouring money into that fire and we can do it.
Whereas now you look at space. You've got these private companies
and it's because it's become affordable and economical to be investing in space.
It's not a money fire, it's,
it's a viable business now because we have the technology to drive the business.
Right.
So I think part of it is experts
have success in the past and
they kind of coast on it.
I don't want to say coast on it, but, you know, they sort of ride it
and
the thing is you can ride on past success and
you can keep doing behavior that maybe is no longer that
effective,
but it's not a complete failure immediately, right?
Like it's these, these, these, even when these man, like the shift to cloud,
you know, 10 years later,
I'm still dealing with people who are like clouds.
A fad, everybody's going to go back to on premises. And I'm like,
I don't heard that in a while.
I still hear cloud is just someone else's computer, which is like,
I mean, everything is someone else's computer at this point,
-- but
-- it's a subtle difference.
It's,
it's somebody else's utility grade compute system.
I mean,
and there's a big difference between my computer
running in a colo closet and Amazon,
like,
Amazon is dropping $4 billion on a new
availability zone in Calgary just south of here.
And so it'll be three,
you know, physical sets of infrastructure located, what,
like 10 to 100 miles apart.
So that a tornado or airline crash or whatever doesn't wipe it all out
and everybody's losing their mind of mind.
They're like, oh my God, $4 billion over 10 years, that's a massive amount of money.
I'm like, no, it's not like, not for them. No, no.
A basic, a basic cloud class data center now,
like a single physical instance is a billion dollars.
That's the rule of thumb.
Right.
And, you know,
it goes back to like that corporate earnings call
Microsoft had I was on a few years ago where
they were talking about their data center sizes
and they measure them in data center miles.
Like how many
miles long is it?
Right. Because it's like Star Trek with their kilo quads.
Like we just, we make up a term to cover the compute amount because
like it just doesn't, you know, it's a meaningless numbers.
We measure it by floor space in miles now.
And that's the thing, right?
This, this is so somebody else's computer that's again, it's like saying, you know,
the Hoover Dam is just somebody else's
generator.
-- No, it's a bit more than that.
-- It is. But I'm also happy to use the electricity.
What? There's a huge infrastructure behind it that people ignore.
There's
a and I don't mean just physical infrastructure but people knowledge,
institutional knowledge,
corporate bonds to pay for the thing.
You know what I mean?
And so
I think with a lot of this expert knowledge,
you know, you can still sell people on premises. Compute
some, some people will still buy it.
But, you know, five or 10 years from now, man, that's gonna be a tough market to be in.
It's, it's, yeah, absolutely. I mean, I don't think anyone will doubt that
-- it's
-- people still
electric cars.
Well,
oh, man, I love my electric car.
I've spent so I need, I just need to say I've owned it for over a month now.
I have spent $20 in electricity and I've driven
-- like 1200 miles. Can you
-- qualify that?
Is that roughly $20 or you actually know that number to be true?
Well, I could calculate it to the penny, but we're talking,
it's probably 23 or $24 dot Whatever.
But I literally have a number I can calculate based on
the amount of electricity that has gone through my charger.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
So,
and I think that's one of the problems is,
is
expert knowledge is not binary, it doesn't suddenly become useless.
The problem is, it becomes less and less useful. There's like a decay function.
Oh, perfect example, setting up and running a mail server.
Is that still useful knowledge? And I would argue
it is if you apply correctly because I use my knowledge of how to build mail servers
-- to use cloud services more effectively.
-- Sure. Sure. And, and I agree with that.
I think
there is
a foundation of knowledge that's valuable and like especially in cybersecurity.
I think there's some foundational concepts that can be valuable. But I think
once you start going above the foundation, there's certain things like, I mean,
the favorite whipping boy is, is password advice, right?
The old misguidance. It was crap, someone made up. And I
you'll hear people say,
well, I think we should change passwords more often. It's like
there's literally evidence that says that is harmful.
Here is the evidence like, well, I just don't want to believe that. And it's like,
yeah, I love
you.
I love how nist literally officially recanted on
that and people still refuse to believe.
But here's the thing when you, I think you get that,
that expert mindset of these are the things I know.
And even when, I mean, I mean,
studies have shown when you present humans with evidence,
showing their beliefs are incorrect,
they don't change their mind, they double down.
And I think maybe there's that difference
between having the expert knowledge and how it's applied, right?
Because I have a lot of, you know,
DNS and email information because I've earned it through blood, sweat and tears.
But now I apply it through cloud services and getting them to, you know,
work as optimally as possible instead of standing on my own stuff.
And I think
maybe that's the second part is
the problem is, is it the information that is sort of right or wrong?
And it's not a binary state Right.
Like, it's a decay function, you know, like, flint,
napping is still useful if you want to do it as a hobby.
But, like, as a actually making tools kind of thing.
Like, no, just go to Home Depot and buy a sharp thing.
Um,
but then the application of that knowledge is, you know,
are you applying the knowledge in the old,
tried and tested way or applying it in a new, more modern, effective way?
I mean, I, I don't think when we think of experts from
a time now gone,
I don't think we think about people using their foundational knowledge
in a new way. I think we think about people
clinging to their expertise trying to hold back progress.
Well, like,
because going back to that example of all those
old business plans that failed in the nineties.
Well, yeah, now they're being applied differently, like instead of ok,
we're going to build an on premises data center to do XY and Z.
It's like, no, let's build a really cheap service infrastructure
and let's use
uh Well, perfect example, Costco, Costco doesn't do shipping,
they just pay ups to do it
right.
I mean,
and it's ridiculous because I literally just bought a utility sink and it's a
metal thing and it came in a giant box and it was heavy as sin
and shipping was included.
And I'm like, I cannot even fathom what it would have costed me to ship this box.
-- Across the city using UPS.
-- Right. Right.
It would have been ridiculous,
but I'm sure Costco has some amazing deal with UPS where, you know, they,
they pre optimized the, like,
they literally have everything ready to go in a perfect way
where they just throw it on the truck and they're done.
-- Right.
So, so the article calls out
a, a sort of similar point to what you just brought up is. So, for example, let's say
there were some wise investors who knew
the pets.com model would be sufficient in 20 years.
Even if you would have kept pets.com alive for 20 years,
it would, it would still fail because
basically all of the ideas from the nineties like the,
the infrastructure they built would no longer be applicable today.
So there is an importance in failure and rebirth
versus keeping it alive for a long period of time.
And I think this is even true of knowledge of,
I think sometimes it's acceptable to be like,
I need to forget what I know and start again.
Well, I have an active rule of thumb.
I've applied now to myself for the last few years,
which is anything sort of very specific.
Technically that I know that's more than three years old is suspect.
-- II, I can get behind that rule
-- and some of it like, OK,
like programming and Python and classes versus this and that, OK,
that's kind of timeless and probably still useful long term.
Not really though.
I mean,
but Python three has enough changes over Python two that
there's a generous amount of relearning that had to happen.
But I mean,
these sort of core fundamental concepts that are probably still mostly ok,
but things like actually setting up an email server, no,
Kurt will never do that again.
And, well, I will actively campaign against ever doing it again
because I will just pay Sendgrid or mail gun, you know, 100 bucks a month
and get api keys out of them. Part of it is, I guess
how do you recognize that knowledge is
bad or out of date or incorrect?
And that speaks to a level of maturity of
being willing to pre and post mortem your ideas.
And by premortem, I say, OK, I have this idea,
here's what I expect to happen
and then you do it and then you do a postmortem and
-- well, in theory, they should line up, right? Like
-- you should
-- have,
-- I mean,
-- predicted the future and made it happen.
-- I want to say that doesn't happen.
And I think there's always going to be exceptions to that rule.
And I, but I think it's something maybe we need to start doing.
But I mean, kind of talking about
at the very beginning,
we mentioned how expertise in the past was more
additive versus today where it's kind of just replacing.
And I think
it is very difficult for humans to undo something
they've learned and try to learn a new thing.
I mean,
I think this is where that whole concept of like, oh, there's, you know,
you can't be an old person in tech
and I think if you're going to cling to your skills of the past, no,
you can't be an old person intact because
you don't have skills that anyone wants anymore
versus saying
I'm going to retrain myself constantly and I'm
going to always be gathering new things.
But I, I don't think that's normal. I don't think, I, I think that's a really
-- hard thing for people to do.
-- There's literally neuroplasticity, right?
Neuroplasticity is a thing. It's, it's the, it's the ability of your brain
to change and relearn and learn new things and unlearn old things.
And it's like super well documented that the older you get,
the less of that you have
statistically, like, obviously there's exceptions to the rule and blah, blah,
blah.
And there's things like, you know, like, like literally like exercise,
there's certain ways of thinking and doing things that
can increase your neuroplasticity in the long term.
But by the time you probably realize you should
be doing that in your forties or fifties,
it's too late.
I mean, it's well documented that the human brain is wired such that, yeah, the,
you get the tougher it is to learn new things.
Like I think of trying to learn a second language now versus when I was in my, you know,
early teens and it's like, oh, my goodness.
No, that's, that would be a complete waste of my time. I mean, all right.
So, in the last couple of minutes,
let's assume this is all correct. Let's assume
that many of us are experts from a world that no longer exists.
Let's assume we have this foundational knowledge, I guess.
What do you do? Right. What, what do you do next?
I would say, well,
some part of it would be make sure that the knowledge you have is being applied as,
as best and correctly as possible.
Also
learn new things. Like, I mean, just on a tactical level,
no, just on a tactical level, you're going to have to learn new things like windows,
11 came out and people are kvetching about how much they hate.
Windows. 11 over windows 10,
my reaction is straight up. They move the icons to the middle.
I like
windows. That's all
-- I don't, I don't get all I hate. I like
-- it.
Like I'm like they moved all the icons from the
-- left side to the middle. I mean,
-- they look nicer too.
They're more appealing to my eye than the anyway. Anyway. Ok.
So I, I kind of have an answer I think I want to give for this.
That's very related to my story I told way back 20 minutes ago
was
I, I think getting involved in things like a, a working group
that's working on things for the future.
Like obviously, in my instance, it's the open SSF and then
volunteering to like write a new thing.
And now I think this is important though because for example,
there's a bunch of other documentation that's being worked on,
but no one wanted to touch the how to guide.
And I think that's because most of the other docs was basically copy editing.
So no one had to stick their neck out,
like stick your neck out
and write Docs about it.
You maybe think you know about
and don't write what you know, like actually research and do it as you do.
You know what I mean? I think that's
one of the ways to stay fresh.
See, that makes me really sad because that is literally what a
like what a college or university degree is supposed to teach you is
how to learn things and how to not just learn things for yourself,
but then how to learn things and also kind of explain it a bit to other people
and the vast majority of people do not have the skill and have not practiced it,
right.
You and I
are very weird. Like I wrote a magazine column for eight years.
It's, this is not a skill most people have or have the time to learn.
And
-- I, I,
-- no,
-- I
-- don't think it's good advice to put up only in the sense of I don't think it's real.
I don't, II, I, maybe, maybe you're right. But I think
I, I don't think it's a skill people don't have. I think the problem is,
and I was thinking about this because, because you and I,
we create something from nothing every week
when we do this show, for example, like we literally start,
well, well, maybe we could say we, we make nothing worse. But, you know, anyway,
the, the point is, I think it is scary
sometimes to, to start with nothing like, like writing a guide on how to use Fight.
02 tokens.
I started with a, an empty file
-- and it, sometimes it's like, what do I even do?
-- I call that blank page syndrome?
-- I mean,
-- yeah.
And now
I think for my instance,
I built enough stuff,
I'm comfortable just like crapping whatever onto the page and being like,
I'll fix it later and then I do.
But you know what I mean? I don't,
I don't think it's so much a skill people don't have.
I think it is intimidating sometimes to be faced with that blank page.
And I think part of part of being an expert and
staying an expert is becoming comfortable with the blank page.
Well, it's, it's the same thing as public speaking, right?
Literally, public speaking is one of the
most common, biggest core fears. A lot of people have.
I've seen studies that say like over half
of people fear public speaking and I'm like,
having done it multiple times.
I'm kind of like, huh?
-- Like, I don't get it.
-- I love it. I love,
I've
always like public speaking and
just
literally yesterday I learned that, uh, so 4h, you know, um, it's the,
the well traditionally rural club for kids, but now also urban,
one of their core components is
public speaking because they basically, like,
it is such an important skill that it's, it's a core component of
their program for everything the kids do,
whether it be raising cattle or doing like arts and drama or, you know, whatever.
But public speaking is one of the core and I think
honestly public speaking and public writing
and I, I, what I think I find interesting is open source is a form of public writing.
Like code is writing. Oh, I agree.
You know, and getting over that fear, like you've made the comment like, oh Kurt,
you know, I'm so glad you're willing to, like, put, like,
just write garbage code and put it out in public and I'm like, oh yeah, like,
wait till you see this stuff from my sandbox.
You know, the stuff that I, I know won't see the public like it's,
you think that stuff's bad?
Wow. Just wait.
But, and that's the thing, right? So many people are terrified
to put themselves out there because, and rightfully so
they'll typically get attacked and tore down.
Yeah. And that,
and, and that's terrible, I think,
and that, that's actually something
I, I, I'm gonna end on this note because we're basically out of time. But
so when you and I were young, it was very typical to criticize the work of others.
And I feel like that was just in the security industry especially,
I think that was expected, we'll say, right?
And I think
now I've reached a point where I try really hard to never criticize. I, I'm
comfortable saying
what if we worked on it in this way?
Well, you know, but I don't like just saying, but actually, or
well, you know, to counter this or whatever, it's like
when someone makes a thing,
it almost always adds to the universe.
And you can easily say, oh, it could be a little better if we did this
and I'm comfortable with that. But you know what I mean?
And, and telling people the thing you built is crap that is
-- unforgivable. I think in modern society,
-- here's the
really high quality good critique and constructive feedback is really
hard because you have to be such an expert.
You know, like if you're going to critique somebody's food,
you better be Gordon Ramsay.
So
he's
a terrible example.
No, no, just wait
so good.
Good critique
is
fantastically hard.
Possibly,
I would say harder than actual creation and the creation of course
is much harder than just bad critique in tearing somebody down,
right?
Bad critique in tearing somebody down is so easy. It's so easy.
In fact that I have a stack of like, you know, critical thinking cards, you know,
where they talk about a
hominid and straw man and all the fallacies and attacks that people use
in bad critique, right? Like literally, I have a set of cards that say,
you know, when people basically are doing argumentation,
this is how bad argumentation works.
And it's so common that, you know, there's posters and trading cards for it.
And I think maybe that's the problem is
also if you're not an expert, how do you differentiate good from bad critique?
And it's, it's, you know, and like these people saying
missed password rules or,
or
whatever, we want to change passwords.
Well, when I critique them and say no changing passwords is bad,
how does somebody judge if my critique is good or not?
By definition,
they need some level of expertise that they don't
have otherwise they would be doing the critique themselves,
right? And I think part of it boils down to trusting experts.
So like my argument would be, look,
Nist said this and then Nist recanted like Nist here's they,
they have a document now that says we were wrong about this, please.
For the love of Pete stop doing it
and people ignore it.
And so I like, I hate the appeal to authority argument, but in some cases,
the appeal to authority is the correct argument.
Like it is literally like this is how the world works.
There's stuff that's so complicated.
I cannot and will not understand it. I'm just going to listen to the experts on that.
Like, they keep telling me to put oil in my car but not too much and I'm, like, sure,
whatever, I'll believe you.
Because if I don't do that, I've seen the videos of what happens.
I mean,
yeah,
I agree.
I, I think,
-- I think that's the only answer. It's,
-- it's,
but how do we get that pool of real?
Like, we don't have Nobel Prizes to differentiate them
from the
security universe. No, we don't. And there's, there's loads of people I hear
giving talks on all kinds of topics that I think like this is,
this is outdated knowledge.
This isn't valuable anymore and, and it is like, I, I agree it's really hard and
I guess the one thing I will say to take away from all
of this is go read the article in the show notes and just
accept
that this is a fundamental truth of the universe and make a point to
continue to update your knowledge whenever possible.
Well, not just to examine your knowledge,
think about what you know and why you know it and how it works
and why it works and maybe why it doesn't work as well anymore.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah, I agree. All right. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show note CC PODOS
says podcast hashtag hit it up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
everyone.
Bye bye
the.