Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
my partner in crime, Josh Pressers and today, a special guest star.
Yeah. Fantastic. Thanks, Kurt. This is, this is Josh.
And today we have the honorable David A Wheeler here to
talk to us about the ci I bans project you're on
and say hello, David.
Hello, David.
Very good.
So I guess we,
we'll kind of get started is you and I have spoken in the past several times and,
and I really respect what you're doing with the banjo.
So why don't you give the audience kind of a the nickel
tour as to who you are and what you're doing and,
and why you're on the open
-- source security podcast?
-- Sure. Ok. Well, let's see.
Uh I've been interested in making secure software for a long time,
really starting back in the eighties
and, uh, and interested in open source software.
Uh I was interested in the eighties but really got more involved in the nineties.
So I've been doing this for a long time.
I'm particularly interested in things like how do
I develop secure software that resists attack,
that sort of thing.
So I've written over the years,
things like I wrote a book on how to write secure software.
Uh I actually teach a graduate class at George
Mason University on how to develop secure software.
Uh done a number of things, um reports and things about open source.
And more recently, uh really, in 2014,
the Linux Foundation looked around and noticed the heartbleed vulnerability.
Well, they, everybody knows the heartbleed vulnerability in open SSL.
And uh they basically said, hey, we've, you know,
there's a number of open source projects that are really important,
lots of people depend on them.
But um you know, for various reasons need uh some special investments in
improving their security. So they fired up this uh
organization within the Linux Foundation called the
ci I the Core Infrastructure Initiative.
Uh They've been funding some specific projects.
One of the challenges they had was that
there's a whole lot of open source out there, no matter what they invest in,
they can invest in some specific projects and that's good.
But
no matter what it is, probably no matter how obscure the program is.
If it's used at all, somebody's depending on it.
So
they also said, hey,
is there something we can do to kind of raise the boats for everybody?
And this brings us to the badging project.
Um The best practices, badge project is basically a set of criteria
we uh we developed for what a
what are the basics for doing a good open source offer project.
Happy to chat about what that means.
And then after that,
we actually set up a web application so that you can say, hey, I want a badge, I want,
I mean, and the badges are for the project and you basically
-- uh determine whether or not you meet the criteria and if you do you get a badge,
-- right?
So tell us about this criteria. Are we, how rigorous are we talking?
Is this something that
any open source project can get or is it, is it very difficult to get, do they need,
you know, some huge dedicated security team here or I guess
let's, let's set the stage for, for how crazy are we talking about to get a badge?
Right? How much work is this?
You know, that that was actually one of the earlier discussions and, and the
answer is
the goal is to make the criteria such that any project
um that's decently run even if it's a one person project can get a badge.
Uh We've actually got a number of different projects at different levels.
-- Um The Linux kernel project got a badge
-- and I've heard of that one before.
Yeah, you've heard of that one and,
and they have more than one developer on that project.
Uh On the other hand, on the other side,
uh curl got a badge and that's fundamentally a single person.
Um and he's been doing it for a long time.
So the goal was to make it so that their criteria that generally people would agree.
Yes, if you're doing an open source software project, you should be doing that
and it should be the sort of thing where
you don't have to have a dedicated security team
to achieve it.
Now,
in the, in the longer term, we are hoping to actually have multiple, you know,
badge levels to have higher level badges.
But right now, we've been kind of focusing on that first stage,
what we're called passing.
Um
because uh
you know, we basically went out,
we got a whole bunch of criteria and even if most projects met most criteria,
you know, I, I don't think it's terribly surprising if, you know,
if there are each criteria, each of them met, you know, projects met 90% of them,
uh sorry, 90% of all projects met criteria one,
the same for criteria two and then the same for criteria three.
It's a whole lot smaller set of projects that meet them all.
So a number of projects have had to make some little change,
some changes to how they work.
That said, hey, uh we've gotten a lot of projects now that have gotten badge,
a number of projects have gotten badges and hopefully more on the way,
do I walk through a couple of examples of, of criteria?
Maybe that would actually kind of help get a little more specific
you definitely should. And in fact, I know Kurt and I were discussing
one of them a little while ago
and, and I'll, I'll let Kurt cover that because as you can imagine
being security guys, we, we would love to bike shed this to death for our little nits
here and there.
Well, in, in fact, uh we've, um,
you know, I love the feedback. Um
In fact, I should note that the badging project, although it's
to
give badges to open source projects is itself an open source offer project.
Uh We actually take uh requests um or comments on our issue tracker,
we have a mailing list.
Uh You can actually see the code of the web application.
So, and you can certainly see the criteria and there it's all public. So we actually
went out lots of different places, books, talk to people, talk to projects,
what's most important
um
came up with a list of criteria, put them out on mailing lists,
got a lot of comment and feedback and then group them into a bunch of categories.
So let me just quickly read the categories.
There's basics, change control, reporting, quality
security. Those are the ones that focus especially on security and analysis.
So the basics one is actually pretty, pretty straightforward, you know,
where is your, what's the repo for the product?
What's the URL for the project? Where is its version control repository?
What license?
Um is it under because the whole thing is intended only for open
source software projects. It doesn't,
we, we focus a lot on how to help people get feedback from the rest of the world.
And that doesn't make sense unless it's an open source project.
Uh And that, that sort of thing
for the uh change control.
Uh Step one is the project must have a version controlled source repository.
It's publicly readable has a URL.
It's kind of surprising we still have projects today that don't use a version,
version control system.
And, and I guess to clarify as well for the audience is like, like github
-- is an example of
-- like
github
will be a place where yeah, like,
like uh uh
like Mercurio,
like subversion,
heck you could even use CV.
Si don't know why you would, but you, you could even use really old software.
But if you don't have your software under version control,
uh there's something wrong at this point.
Um they're freely available and it's just too difficult today to keep track of
modern software trying to do it all by hand with uh with files.
It's just crazy. Do
Yeah, that vast majority of folks today use. Get, that's great.
Um We use, get ourselves, you know, you gotta have a, you know,
identify your versions.
Um And you know, have some sort of change log when you have a release,
tell us what's changed
because people don't want to read through every line of code of change. Really?
Just give me the highlights
one,
sorry, two quick questions for you.
I'm just curious,
are there any sort of what you would consider major open source
software projects not using version control in this day and age?
Uh Unfortunately, yes. Uh Let me, let me uh hand out my um
my, my, my Shane Prize
um to a really popular fuzz called American Fuzzy Lot.
Um
uh They just, they just released Tar Balls. There's no version control.
There is somebody who eventually set up a get
hub and they just download the Tar ball and put it there, but it's not tracking
the individual changes.
Um
So yeah, it's uh
it, it's a minority but they're still out there.
Uh So moving on reporting, you gotta have a way to report
uh report bug reports and that sort of thing, what a surprise.
And these are for a lot of folks, if you're on github,
a lot of these are not hard to do, for example.
Uh uh One thing that we've actually found a lot of projects not doing,
but it's also really easy to change
is you have to tell everybody how to report vulnerabilities.
This turns out to be one of those that a lot of folks miss. It's trivial to do.
You just, you know, if you're on github,
for example, stick in your read be,
you know, this is how I want you to report vulnerabilities.
But the real problem is as soon as you ask projects to do that,
they have to figure out well,
if I'm gonna tell everybody how to report vulnerabilities, I mean,
you have to decide that
and then immediately gets to questions like,
do you want them to use the usual issue tracker?
Because for a lot of open source projects, those are totally public
or do you want to have a separate private reporting mechanism?
-- And
-- this actually comes up into the, the thing Kurt and I were talking about with,
with what is the line here?
We said, it said if private vulnerability reports are supported, the project must
include how to send the information in a way that is kept private.
And, and so this is kind of where, so if a, a
project doesn't want private vulnerability reports,
is that considered a negative or is that acceptable?
-- And
-- that
there's actually an, and we have uh for each of these uh criteria there,
you have to have either met or unmet.
Uh in a couple of cases, we allow N A which just means not applicable.
You know, if you don't have, if you don't allow vulnerability reports to be private,
you mandate everything to be public.
I wouldn't run a project that way.
But you can,
if you want to, we,
because there's a
number of projects, this is one of those different people who are very smart,
disagree.
-- OK?
-- And you have two of them right here.
Yes.
Well, and I would say we're even internally inconsistent,
you know, I for some projects,
I would say this is acceptable or even desired and on other projects, I would say,
yeah, good Lord.
No.
Yeah. So I, I should note that all of this is per project.
Uh you can have two different projects and have different answers and,
and you can even argue that maybe that's exactly what you should have because,
you know, project one is a completely different kind of circumstance.
But
uh there are projects like S
Iwin, which are very explicit.
We forbid all private communications including vulnerability reports.
It must be public.
OK.
Uh As I said, I wouldn't run a project that way, but we don't forbid it. It's just
if you want to have it private, you've got to tell people how to do it
because just saying, you know, why don't you send us information privately?
But we won't tell you how really gets to one of the problems.
A lot of uh security researchers have had,
they'll find the vulnerability in an open source project
and then it will take a disturbing amount of time to,
to have this back and forth discussion,
figuring out how to get the information to them.
And that's not the right time to have that to have
that thinking because for projects that want to keep it private,
but they don't know how to keep information private because
they don't have any set up to do that,
that's kind of a problem.
So we want projects to think about that ahead of time and whatever they decide,
tell people what that decision is.
-- Uh
-- just one quick question to clarify when you say project, what exactly do you mean?
Because for example, like
uh open stack, you know, they have over 100 subprojects.
So when you say project, do you mean like a
can that can a project actually choose to break it up? Like
I know open stack, for example,
they have like a security team for their
core of like what's shipping production ready.
And then I think they have like somewhere around 100
sort of projects in development that aren't fully security supported,
but they're also not like kind of out in the wild being used as much as the core stuff,
right?
I would advise people to split it down into those smaller specific projects.
I mean, I would treat the open stack core differently
from some of the other projects. I mean, they've actually made a cha uh
you mentioned specifically open stack, they've actually made a change in policy.
They used to be really picky about who could be officially an open stack project.
And then they decided that that wasn't worth the trouble.
So they're far more open about bringing projects in.
But that doesn't mean that that means of course,
that not all the projects are really equal.
So I would encourage uh folks to break it down.
But uh but on the other hand,
we have to be a little flexible because there's
i it's really amazing when you start looking at stuff across the spectrum.
You know, a lot of folks are involved in just a few projects
and as you try to look across a lot of different one,
it is just amazing how many different ways people do stuff.
So we're actually trying to be a little flexible.
But I think usually you want to be more specific and, you know,
pull out say the core separate from the other things.
I think one of the more obvious one is a lot of
projects have plugins when you first install your software with some,
with some standard set of plugins, that might be one set.
But it's not at all unusual for different
plugins to be managed as completely independent projects.
And typically you would want to have those
as separate projects going in for the badging.
I mean,
they might have totally different ways
of reporting vulnerabilities and everything else.
Is that sort of answer your question?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. So the vulnerability reporting process is actually an example where
uh the vast majority of projects that first
show up actually don't meet that particular criteria,
but it's an easy one to meet to meet once you tell people, you know,
shouldn't you tell the report?
We,
we've gotten very little pushback on the idea of
shouldn't you tell people how to report vulnerabilities.
I will say the projects that have already handled the
number one number of them typically already have it.
But a lot of the smaller projects which should not have not yet handled
a vulnerability report often don't have a way to uh report them.
So OK, add that no big deal uh under,
under our quality ones again, basically,
we first worked out the criteria and then found ways to group them.
If you've got to build your software, you've got to have a working way to build it
again, you can find software. Uh Names are escaping me right now.
But there's software out there where here's the source code, you can't generate it.
Yeah, if you, if you've just got straight up javascript
and you're expecting folks to run it great.
But if you're, if you've got C or you know,
some of the language that requires compilation,
it's not at all unusual to have software that nobody can compile.
And that's
because that's actually something I've run into a few times in the past.
But um one thing I'm wondering especially with sort
of the modern move to virtual machines and say containers
because one thing I'm seeing, for example is, you know,
people when they provide something, just the whole shebang in a container.
Now, when you say they have to provide a working built system, can they, for example,
provide, say a container and say, like, look you know, run, like,
pull this container, it installs the software like maven or whatever and then boom,
you know, source code goes in compiled object comes out,
do they?
Because one thing I've seen is where,
you know, they,
they provide something like that but there's still like some sort of like
little magic binary that gets slipped in from some other place or whatever.
Right. It's like, or download some,
you know,
random tarball from some guy's personal site because he finally got it working,
right?
Nobody else on the planet can get this thing working, right?
I think what you do have to do is you have
to go back to the uh the criteria text here because
we
uh you,
what you find is that we have written this text a little
carefully because of exactly the kinds of problems that you're listing.
So for example, you've got to automatically rebuild the software from source code.
So, hey, if you build it in a container,
I think that's exactly the right way to do it today,
but you have to rebuild it from the source code.
If all you get is the magic binary container,
which a lot of containers really are.
Uh then that's not OK because the goal here
is I should be able to change the source code
and get new executables.
And if you can't change the source code,
then you don't have a and get a something that runs.
You don't have a working build system.
Now, there's lots of magic. Now,
a
stupid example, if you've written
a, uh, you know, if you've written software in some programming language,
let's say Rust,
you know, your, you know,
your process within the container might involve downloading Rust.
Ok. Well, that's not the software that is in your project.
That's just a tool you're using to build it fine.
But if it's the, the software,
you, you know, if it's part of your project as opposed to an external project,
you're depending on, then you need to be able to rebuild it
again. I don't know if anybody who thinks that's a bad idea
and if you can't do that,
then you can't really edit the source code and modify it and fix it.
And if you find a vulnerability, you can't fix it either because you have no,
no way to rebuild it.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
No, I just,
I remember in the past I've run into situations where to build the software.
There's, you know, literal magic involved.
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
Uh And I will say that I've seen particularly in a lot of proprietary projects.
Um There is no way to rebuild the software other than this magic
box over here where they hope it doesn't break because they can't,
they can't recreate it and they can't
create the process to build it.
And this also turns, obviously you can't fix problems if you can't rebuild it.
It also turns out you can't run some tools because a lot of uh static analysis
tools for source code basically require that you
be able to rebuild the software again.
If there's no Burt working build system,
there's nothing that you can use to find vulnerabilities and fix them ahead of time.
And this actually gets us to the next step,
which is we have a whole bunch of stuff involving automated test suites.
And yeah,
we actually require, you've got to have an automated test suit.
We, we, we don't actually require much in terms of the quality of it.
And this has actually, this is uh based on a long discussions.
If you've got a lousy automated test suite,
you can use that framework and add more tests and make it better.
But if you don't have an automated test suite, then there's no easy way to get moving.
And if you don't have an automated test suit,
the one thing I'm sure about is that sooner or later,
you're gonna make a breaking change and you won't know it
because you don't have an automated test suit.
Really.
I think today it's kind of crazy that people are
trying to write software without any kind of test.
Well, I, I think it's worth pointing out here as well. David is that
a significant number of hosting facilities,
we'll say today have a lot of the continuous integration stuff just kind of built in.
So you're, you're loony not to be doing this because
it's going to
find bugs very, very quickly.
And, you know, I, I
mentioned earlier
publisher mentioned, you know, not only is the badge, web application itself,
open source, it does get its own badge.
Uh We, we made that as a, as an absolute minimum because uh it'd be,
it'd be ridiculously hypocritical for us to say here's some great criteria.
But, oh, whoops, we don't actually meet our own criteria.
So, absolutely. We, um,
uh, we use Circle C I and we've got a nice big automated test suite.
Well, big is relative. But, uh,
you know, we have what I think it's 98% statement test coverage.
Uh We don't require that for G criteria but
I, I think, you know,
having a number of tests and making sure
that the software basically does what it's supposed to
is I think a minimum level for software you build today.
One thing I, I'm, I've always wondered is, you know,
what percentage of people are you finding don't
do this because they simply don't know,
it's actually easy and possible now
versus, you know, the people that just flat out won't do it.
You know, it's hard to tell motivations. Sometimes.
I, I did have a lot of interesting long conversations with uh the O
A
ZAP folks
who, um, build a web application scanner.
It's, it's a widely used uh security uh tool,
a great tool. They didn't have basically any automated test suite.
And in fact, if you read some of the reviews of web application scanners by
Shay
Chen,
he found that most tools in this category
uh were failing to find stuff they used to find.
And although he couldn't see inside the source code of the proprietary tools,
it's his belief that
in general, in that category, most people were not uh doing automated testing.
In this particular case, it's because these kinds of tools are heuristic.
So people don't know exactly what the,
the answers should have been that the tools should have produced it.
So, as long as the tool answers look, ok,
they don't realize that the tool actually has some bad bugs.
And so, unfortunately, it's actually, it's a little more common than we wish.
Now, the zap folks didn't think that automated testing was a bad idea
in their case.
It was simply because, yes, yes, we know we should do it, but we'll get to it tomorrow
and tomorrow never happened.
And for them, actually, the gate, they,
they actually got a badge and this was one of their big prob, well,
big issues for them is they had to create automated tests
and they actually said they were very glad they did it and it was, uh,
very helpful to them because it finally forced them to do what?
Yeah, we know we should have done that a long time ago,
-- but now we're doing it and it's a good thing,
-- you know.
That's a great point is I suspect there is no project in world who's going to say, man,
I wish we didn't write those tests.
It's, it's just a time constraint more often than not.
And so I think holding their feet to the fire here is, is fantastic.
Well,
thank you.
I, I think so too. I think for a lot of this, it's actually that way.
It's this little list of things.
We, we don't get much pushback actually on the criteria.
It's the sort of stuff that, yeah, I should do. I just haven't gotten around to yet.
Well, one thing I've been finding is there's,
I mean, the technology has changed so significantly in the last five years, right?
With,
especially with the availability of things like containers and the C I testing.
And I mean,
I remember when something like Jenkins was totally black magic, right?
Like scary stuff. And now, you know,
it's like two clicks to get it running,
you know.
And for example, like with Jason, I mean, Jason now has, you know,
Json schema to validate Json schemas, right? And that's
sadly, relatively new.
I think it's only about a year and a half, two years old or something,
you know. And so that
literally didn't exist when
Json came into creation and
quite frankly, I didn't know about it up until recently, you know,
when I was Googling for it.
And I'm like, oh, it exists. Hallelujah.
Yeah.
Well, I, although I think tech software technology has helped a little bit,
I think frankly what's helped a lot more is, um, e economics.
You know, it used to be. Oh, I'm gonna have, you know, economics in time.
I'm gonna have to run the pro,
the test program all night.
I'm gonna have to dedicate specialized machines. Now, CPU cycles are cheap.
We're just overwhelmed, you know, we,
you know, we can easily run those tests. Why would you not do that?
I, I do think there is some debate on exactly the best way to test.
Um, I'm not against unit tests, but I do think that in many, many cases,
integration testing is often more effective, not always, uh, there's a trade.
Um,
but, but at that point I think you're asking,
you're at a completely different level of question
you're now asking what's the best way to test
and not. Gee shouldn't I have some tests.
It's, it's that latter question where she says, oh, my goodness, of course,
she should have
what is wrong
with you.
But, uh, but we've got a lot of folks who, and, and so I guess
my understanding from the people I have talked to is it much more the,
they know they should do it?
-- They just haven't gotten there
-- because the other thing I
was looking at is one thing I found is there's,
there doesn't seem to be a lot of good
educational information on this, right? Like sort of recipes. Um,
so for example, one thing that, you know, I've seen is
people,
you know, move their project to github and then they realize, oh, there's,
there's no concept of, you know, privacy on a public github
project,
right? Everything is open, right?
There's no hidden issues, there's no hidden commits.
There's no, it's just, it's all public end of story. Right?
And the only way to get away from that is to go fully private, which of course,
you know, you're really
out then on basically what
you
-- can do for you.
-- Right.
I, I think,
well, I, I do think, let's see, I can answer this one several ways
as far as testing goes. Goodness. The idea about software testing is old, old stuff.
I mean, I took classes in the eighties on testing and it was well known then,
uh, books by Boris Beer
and more recently by, uh, Paul
Aman
and Jeff
Offutt.
Uh, have lots of information if you really want to go into the theory of testing.
But for a lot of the, of the stuff
you, you, you don't need to go deep,
um,
you, you know, the basic functionality. So
we're supposed to do, check the, whether or not it does that.
Yeah. And I agree that there's some awesome tools that help.
And in fact, what, right after we talk about testing,
the next thing we talk about is warning flags
because most languages or,
or infrastructure has some sort of way just to warn you of bad things you're doing
and if people ran those and fixed a lot of their problems.
Yeah. Ok. Some of the warnings are just
cosmetic,
uh, or not that important. But if you work them off code becomes much easier to read
and you avoid some of the problems that in some cases turn
into security problems or at least make security problems harder to find.
Uh One of the problems that open SSL had
was it was hideously hard to read.
I, I, when Hartley was uh information came out,
there was a question about how the memory was allocated.
So,
and it was one of those, there's, there's a simple one, true answer.
So I went up, looked at the code and read it
and oh my gosh,
open SSL code at that time was hideously hard to read.
It turned out the information that most people were saying were incorrect,
but I totally saw how they got there because the code was so stinking hard to read
that. Uh You could easily go away thinking that something
basically that the memory allocations uh were um a slab allocator using a S
Malik
instead of
a Malik
for each new allocation.
And you know, it, it wasn't true,
but it was easy to think that it was.
And if people would use warning flags and quality checkers
and stuff that would at least get rid of the,
some of the nonsense and make it easier review.
Now, now, do you know,
did the ci I help address some of this as
part of their kind of more overarching Open SSL program?
Uh They did well,
projects that open that uh ci I actually has funded is specifically um open SSL.
Um And I think they've made a lot of progress, you know, in particular, you know, the,
the, the code was hideously hard to read.
They've actually changed how they're formatting to be much more normal,
like other programs in that in NC, which is the language they use.
Uh, they're using a lot more tools to analyze it.
Uh, they a,
they were falling dreadfully behind in the issues
which is obviously not good when it's,
you know, something that critical.
Uh, so they actually went back and, uh, worked those off. So I,
you know, I'm not gonna tell you that there are no more vulnerabilities in
SSL I Frank, but there's, um,
in
it compared to where they were
in early 2014.
So we probably ought to chat about the ones that's
most subject to the most relevant to the show,
which is the security related ones now
to be fair.
Uh,
the other stuff is relevant to security too
because obviously if you have version control,
if you're looking for quality issues, if you test that can help
with the,
I'm sorry?
No, I was gonna say I I think, you know, you,
you say the other stuff is also important to security and,
and I think that's something we forget
about sometimes in the security universe is that
we like to pretend security is a special snowflake.
But in reality, all of this stuff is connected and, and I try, I mean, I,
sounding a bit philosophical here but
fundamentally speaking, you can't have
security without having all this other stuff as well.
And, and likewise,
rather than pretending security is this special thing in the corner.
It should just be a part of everything. Right. I mean, that's the right way.
This has to be done and it's the only way this is going to work long term.
Yeah, I mean, if, if you,
I, I would think, you know,
security is a requirement and it's an emergent property and
there are some special things involving security but that said,
everything you just said is true.
Uh There's even been some studies which basically, you know,
if you worry only about the nonsecurity stuff,
you know, there's no guarantee it's gonna be secure, but in general,
higher quality software tends to have fewer security vulnerabilities,
which I don't think should be a terrible surprise to anybody.
Right. Right.
Uh As far as security goes, the first thing that we point we ask about is actually,
I think to some people a little surprising,
but I don't think it should be,
we actually ask about people.
So we ask, hey,
is there at least one primary developer who knows how to design secure software?
And is there at least one primary developer who knows the common
kinds of errors that lead to vulnerabilities and how to counter them?
You know, because basically, if you don't know how to develop, if,
if you have no clue about security and nobody else in your project is either
you're way more likely
to uh create problems.
Now,
we're not asking for somebody to be an expert in the topic and have studied for years.
But what we're asking for is do you know the basic principles we list them,
do you know? You know,
you know, if you're writing in c you need to know what a buffer overflow is.
If you're writing a web application,
you need to know what cross site scripting and cross site request forgeries are,
there's well-known methods to counter those.
But if you don't know what those problems are,
then you won't,
then you won't know that when you,
when you need to use them and what their tradeoffs are.
So you, you need to know something and so this actually gets to knowledge
and I think that's important
because the rest of it doesn't matter if you don't know anything.
Speaking of which one thing to plug a related project, um,
I'm guessing that you are familiar with the
CWE the common weaknesses and uh exposures database
involved.
Yeah. And I have some good news for you there.
I don't know if, you know, but it's being uh so the CWE project, the idea is to catalog
security vulnerability types, things like a buffer overflow, a buffer underflow,
a buffer,
overread a buffer under read and all these different types
of flaws to give examples of them and to give,
you know, uh some ways to deal with them.
And the good news is uh the project is essentially being, it's been stale for a while,
but it's finally getting rebooted.
And one thing there were, um,
uh, they're taking miter, the people who run this, uh,
are taking as some new types of bugs, right?
Because obviously it's been stale for a few years and
it's kind of missed a lot of the cloud space.
So I would suggest if
people have sort of flaws that they're aware of
that aren't really well documented or covered in CWE,
you can reach out to the CWE people now.
Uh, and they're basically making a list of, you know, things to be added
and yourself, I'm guessing you
have seen those things in conversations with people.
Absolutely.
In fact, I, uh, separately, I guess I should, you know,
I actually did a paper a while back about some of the more general issues involving,
uh, security and cloud.
Uh,
I've actually more recently been talked with N I because
they're trying to find ways to group the cwes,
I guess more effectively because one of the challenge.
The good news about Cwes is, hey, at least we're all agreeing on a lot of these terms
but it's not structured as, as um cleanly as a lot of people would like.
So, im
and some others are interested in, you know,
what can we do to make things better in terms of structure and that sort of thing
to be determined, determined what uh what if anything is a result of that. But,
but,
but all this is good news because you don't have to know everything.
You know, the numbers vary,
but anywhere from 90 to 99% of the vulnerabilities in
software is the same old stuff that's happened before.
It's not the amazing
clever new attack, no one's ever heard of,
you know, yes, when you're writing a web app,
you should counter your cross site scripting
and your cross site request forgeries because
every project,
every software program that's been built in that application space
has to have those kinds of issues or at least,
you know, somebody has had to counter them.
Uh So all you have to do is learn what those are,
learn some countermeasures for your situation and you
will eliminate the vast majority of your problems.
So after, you know, knowing things we also ask about cryptography,
uh but a lot of applications don't actually need crypto, they don't use crypto
uh in at least internally. So that's one of those things where if it's important.
It's very important and it's not, it's a whole bunch of nas not applicable.
We also require for the badge that if you have publicly known vulnerabilities,
they've got to be fixed in a timely way.
Uh If they're basic of their medium or high severity,
you've got to fix it within 60 days because really,
it doesn't make sense to have a badge and have,
you know, long known public vulnerabilities.
Uh One thing I'm curious is that 60 days
within the vulnerability being public or 60 days with,
than you being told of the vulnerability.
Uh We have, we had a debate about that.
Uh We decided that uh 60 days from being known to the public.
The reason for that is that it's very, very hard for us to measure.
When did you internally know about that?
But we can certainly measure when it's publicly known.
We would certainly encourage projects to fix within 60 days and frankly,
a lot sooner than that from the time they were told.
But if you can't fix it within 60 days after being publicly told,
there is a serious problem.
Yeah, I'm also just wondering,
you mentioned crypto and it looks like you do have a couple of things
that are essentially banned like MB four and MB five and Single Des,
which for our listeners, uh Single Des is a 56 bit key,
which means you can basically crack it in real time now on like an apple
wristwatch pretty much.
Um,
and I'm just wondering, do you have, uh, well, first of all, I would say,
do you have a list
or guidance on things that absolutely should never be used?
And also, do you have a list of like, sort of the white list of the things where,
you know, preferentially this is what you absolutely,
if you want to say store a password or,
you know, encrypt network traffic.
do you have a list of like, here's the essentially the best practices,
I guess would be the way to go,
right. Well, I guess the short answer is yes.
And we tried to bake them into the uh good cryptographic practices.
I mean,
I think probably the first things to start
with are the first two criteria where basically
you need to use, you know,
cryptographic protocols and algorithms that are
publicly published and reviewed by ex
because if you're creating your own crypto
algorithm, as
unless that is the whole point of the software,
that's a problem.
You know, you, you know, you shouldn't be creating your own crypto
-- algorithms as part of a web application that's just
-- can,
can I ask is why not just point to Nist
and say we do
with these smart
guys say,
well, in fact, we do. Um
so
um but the, but the first step is getting people to not do that crazy thing.
One challenge though is that NIST is important in the US
but they are actually a US organization and
not everybody is in the US unsurprisingly.
So we don't wanna say,
you know, you, you know, just do whatever nest does.
The one thing place where we do absolutely
mention N I though is NIST has a set of minimum requirements for uh key lengths
and we base,
it's not saying, hey, do whatever N
says it's for key
lengths, you've got to support uh the N
minimum requirements which are called crypto key
length.
Uh We can go through the details if you want. But basically N
has gone through, identified some links for various kinds of algorithms.
And we just say, hey, use those links, at least
you can do more, but at least that
in
light of
rat holding ourselves on crypto,
I suggest we continue moving because I know we
could probably spend the next couple of hours if,
if we wanted
and let's not do that.
Yeah.
Well, you know what, let's let's kind of just wrap it up and, and uh the,
the last tab is about analysis.
And basically we're saying everybody's got at least use one static
code analysis tool and we recommend using a dynamic one.
But um
a lot of open source projects right now are not using
any dynamic analysis tools for various reasons so that we,
while we want to encourage it, we don't require it.
But
it's pretty unusual to not be able to apply a static analysis
for, for the benefit of the audience, can you
describe the difference between static and dynamic analysis?
Absolutely. And it's actually defined in this stuff.
Static analysis is a tool that doesn't run the code. It's analyzing
dynamic means it is running the code that's analyzing.
So typically what static analyzers do if they're a source code analyzer,
which is pretty common
uh is they'll take all that source code, read it in do some kind of processing to it.
And typically they're looking for patterns that suggest a vulnerability.
Uh There's other ways that they can uh identify problems too.
Uh But that's a pretty common kind of tool and there's lots of these out there.
Uh Heck I developed one years ago myself and the key thing
is that these tools can't find everything but they can very,
very quickly find some vulnerabilities if they exist
in your software.
And so it's a really easy win to run the tools, look through its output and see if,
if the issues it's raising are actually vulnerabilities and if they are go fix it,
it's uh it's one of those things where you can relatively
quickly for a lot of programs make a real difference.
Yup. Yup. Yeah, definitely, definitely.
So
I'm looking at your list here and I guess
-- that's the end and then you've got
-- the future.
So tell us about the future.
Well, first of all, we, um we,
we certainly would love to hear feedback in terms of additional criteria.
We had originally expected that these would be
so easy that uh everybody would need to
get them all.
Um We, we were uh surprised
and the thing is, it's not a surprise in terms of people,
uh thought that they were bad criteria.
We actually haven't gotten that kind of pushback.
It's instead the, oh, we should test. You're absolutely right.
I guess we actually have to create, you know,
pick a framework and start writing some tests to meet that criteria.
So a lot of projects have gotten much, much of the way there.
Uh But you have to do a little bit work.
One of the other ones I didn't mention, didn't point out earlier was HTTP S
we've got a lot of projects still not supporting HTTP S
uh including a lot of really important ones.
Uh Savannah, which is used by the canoe folks, which is used for a whole lot of low
level tools CP, make all that stuff.
The project page is HTTP S the repo is not,
there is no protection of the code. Great,
interesting.
And, and for those of you who don't know, Savannah is,
I would compare it to kind of github,
but it's for the good new project.
That's right. I mean, there's a number of these uh uh
you know, uh repository hosting services. Github
is by far the most common.
Uh
but there's uh there's source for
or get lab, there's Savannah there's others,
you know, Savannah doesn't support HTTP S on the repositories.
And that's of concern because that means that somebody could intercept,
uh, the code and change it along the way. Unbeknownst
to the recipient.
So we're, we're, we're kind of hope.
We've been kind of working with various projects and
repository hosting sites to try to get them to
make improvements to make it easier for everybody.
So, one thing I'm curious about is um
with this, is there
sort of uh badges or, you know,
uh some sort of statement maybe about the things that these people rely upon, like,
for example, you know, I'm on
github and github
meets this, you know, minimum requirement versus like I'm on Savannah,
which does not.
Um
because I know one thing, like
with a lot of these sort of cloud based things, you know, is, is a lot of the,
in a lot of cases, the people just don't.
Well,
the whole point they're in the cloud is they don't want to run this infrastructure,
they don't want to deal with it, right?
They just want it to work.
Well. In fact, we go further, um if you're on
github, a number of these criteria essentially come for free.
So when you first click on and say, hey, get me,
I want to get a badge and there's a big button, hey, get a badge.
Uh If you're uh if you're part of the project,
uh you can basically fill in this form.
And one of the things that we do is we go out and try to determine
answers for a lot of the questions automatically for you.
So for, in particular, if you're on github and none
of these criteria just come for free and poof all of a sudden, you,
you're well on your way now, we, you still need to answer questions like, you know,
do you tell people how to report vulnerabilities?
Uh We can't at least today, automatic. We, we don't currently
automatically try to figure that one out.
But yeah, absolutely.
And in fact, for most projects I today,
I think you're better off using a hosting service
unless you're a really big project. In which case,
you know,
you've got the people in infrastructure and so on,
you've got the people and resources to go build your own.
But uh most projects today I think start on
github,
start on some other hosting service, go from there
and we can automatically figure out some of the answers for you.
And, and really,
I guess probably the one thing I want to make sure we talk men before we close out is
if you're part of an open source project, free software project,
we would love for you to go
to the um best practices.co infrastructure.org site.
Uh go click on, get a badge and
you know, go fill in the form and get yourself a badge and once you've got a badge,
you can show it off and put it on your uh get a
project page or elsewhere
because really the whole point is to encourage projects to do good things
and then
to help use potential users of those projects
know that those good things are happening.
So let me ask this, David is if I'm a project and I want to badge and I need help.
Do you provide some of that?
Do you have some guidance to kind of help
mentor these folks through this process or what happens?
Um The answer is yes and in several different ways,
um probably the simplest thing to do is right next to many
of the criteria is a little button that says show details.
And so if you're filling out, well, actually, I guess first step is when you,
when you say, hey, I want a badge, we'll automatically fill in some stuff for you.
Then as you're reading the criteria, you can click on the show details,
it'll help explain it.
Now, if that isn't enough, we actually have on the web and we,
you can actually go click on the, send an email,
it's on the bottom of every page or you can click on file an issue
and we're on
github. And uh you can file an issue on
github that says, hey, I can't figure this out.
We actually haven't had too many people with that kind of
not understand the criteria.
Uh But if the criteria aren't clear we want to fix that.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, and I mean, in all seriousness, this is
pretty
reasonable
criteria here. This isn't like crazy stuff and, and I think
that's important as well is if you make it too hard or too crazy,
people just won't do it.
And so obviously keeping it simple is,
is I think one of the critical features this project has,
thanks,
our,
our goal was to be
just hard enough that it's actually worth, you know,
having a badge is worth something because, you know,
getting a badge for breathing is just nobody cares.
But it should be those basics. It should be uh in general, people agree.
Yes, we should do that.
And,
you know, you know,
I thank you very much for the not crazy because that was certainly our goal and,
you know,
we don't want crazy
and, and, and really if you're a one person project, it's still totally doable.
Um I actually went over and for a,
it was a V I plug in, went in and it didn't take that long at all to get the badge.
Really the big effort, which I,
because I was doing it simultaneously.
So I had to write some test scripts, which I was gonna do anyway. So,
you know,
again, it's not like I'm gonna tell you, you shouldn't make your test.
-- Of course, you should,
-- I have to ask if, how do you test a vim plug
in
that turns out to be pretty trivial. Uh The the plug, it was fundamentally a uh Synex
colorize
a highlighter.
So basically you give it some inputs and you already know what this character,
this position should be highlighted with this color.
So you give it a whole bunch of,
you know, it should be there
and
it, it really, once you step back and start thinking about how do I test? It?
Really just comes back to the
given this input, what's the expected output? I mean, it really is that simple.
Uh So it really isn't that hard to do.
So I wrote, I wrote some tests and then, then script. Well, why not?
Fantastic.
So question for you.
I just did some looking, I can't,
is there a central registry of all
these projects and which badges they've achieved?
If you go to best practices dot Core infrastructure.org, that's the main site.
If, if you see the front page, it says hi, you know, get CIA best practice program,
you click on the big green one, you would get start the creating a new badge.
But if you go up to the top, right, you will see projects.
If you click on projects right now, we have 393 projects
that are working on getting a badge.
And if I
uh you can actually sort uh you can actually
do queries on how many badges are passing.
So, for example, at this moment that we're speaking, 45 badges are passing
and you can just click on badge status and sort that,
uh, you can also sort on, you know,
the ones who are 90% or more, including 100% and that's 80.
Typically, what we see is projects show up, they start filling the form,
you know, they, they fill,
they do a lot and then they discover something they're not doing.
Oh, I don't,
I'm not doing testing or whatever and then they
go fix that and then they continue their journey
and it's perfectly fine to start
and realize there's some things,
fix it and then come back and fill more of the badge as you go along.
You don't have to do it all at once.
Yeah. No, I see it now
and, and of course, I will put all these links in the show notes
that way people can easily figure out where they need
to go or what they want to look at.
But,
yeah, this is, this is fantastic. So, I guess
it's easy enough to add a new project. What about, are you accepting
volunteers for people willing to help, help out with the, the best practices
bing project as opposed to their own project?
Oh, absolutely. We're, we're an open
source project. Do we want help? Of course, we want help.
Um, really the, the best way to, to, uh,
to do that is we have our own little mailing list if you go to our Get Hub.
Uh if you go to the main site, Best practices.com infrastructure.org,
which you can go from there, you can go click to our Get Hub page.
And, you know, frankly what I would do is sign up for the mailing list
and then you can start discuss and
we can discuss all sorts of crazy things.
Uh If it's just a specific issue, just raise an issue.
There's another thing actually, if you, we actually do maintain
projects.
So if you go to that um
best practices.co infrastructure.org
uh site,
uh we actually track all sorts of data like um
how many projects over time and that sort of thing.
And
uh you don't need to do it right now.
But just basically, we've been seeing a, a uh steady growth.
Uh you know, we would love to see a hockey stick, but we're seeing steady growth,
both of the projects who are starting on that journey
and even at various levels of completion, you know, 25% or 50% or 7590 or 100%.
We're seeing that slow, steady growth of more and more projects as they,
you know, add more as they actually meet those criteria and then tell us about it
um or slowly on uh on the way to getting matches.
That is fantastic. Well, I think we're going to wrap this up.
I thank you so much David for,
for chatting with us and I congratulate you
on being our first guest and tolerating all
the silliness of figuring some of this out as I am not a professional podcaster.
So it's a challenge, but
this is a fantastic project and thank you so much for doing it.
I think it is one of the most
important security things going on today without question.
Oh,
thank you so very much. Appreciate it. And
I'm looking forward to hearing from more people as, uh,
as we try to keep making improvements on this as well.
Awesome. So until next time folks go get your badges
and, and let's make the world a better place, right?
Thanks for being on the show.
Thanks.