Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
-- So
-- I have a strange story to tell as part of this opening. And
it is, I guess a very typical story
with respect to the way I tend to
do new things. We say I built an antenna over the weekend, a, an aluminum antenna.
So when you say antenna, you mean,
like just a piece of wire that sticks up straight or something?
A little more fancy,
it's a little more fancy.
-- So this one does have some wood on it.
-- I wasn't that impressed initially.
Right.
Right. Of course. So
given my,
I guess more free time than usual I have at the moment I
decided I want to download weather satellite data with a software defined radio,
which I had a software defined radio
and I played with it for a little while and then I threw it in the closet.
I didn't touch it and I took it back out and I started my journey.
The first step of this was I needed something to pick up a satellite and
I found instructions on the internet to build an antenna out of old coat hangers.
And, and the thing is too, I didn't want to spend a bunch of money on something.
I didn't know if I'd even want to do.
So, I build my antenna
and, yeah, it's literally coat hangers and it works well enough. Right.
I could pick up some of the NOAH satellite I could get, I mean,
I think I sent you a picture on, on slacker signal or something.
I forget which, but anyway, I,
I could see the pictures and they were good enough and it was amusing to me and then
I started doing research and there are Russian
satellites also that send weather data to earth.
But they are, we say a little more complicated and harder to pick up.
-- And so I try picking them up my coat hanger
-- satellite.
Is that like an intentional thing or they just have like a weaker signal?
No, it's a better signal. It's, it's a digital signal versus an analog signal.
So obviously you need a better antenna to
just pick it up because obviously with analog,
like if I drop a bunch of data, whatever, I don't care, it's
-- a
-- smear bit in the image.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And so I went and bought aluminum rods and I built
like a nice antenna that looks good and it's still granted,
like we're talking less intense dollars and parts here.
Right. I had a bunch of material in the house, I had a bunch of the cabling.
I needed, I just needed two aluminum rods. I put it together and surprising nobody.
An antenna not made of coat hangers is about 10
times better than the antenna made of coat hangers.
-- This is
-- something that gets me is like the stuff
that used to be literally rocket science is now like,
available at Home Depot for five bucks.
Seriously. Right. Right. But
so anyway, I'm, I'm working on this.
I still haven't decoded any images off the Russian satellites, but I,
at least I'm seeing a signal.
I know I'm going in the right direction right now. But now
the next logical step in this
is now I'm looking for satellite dishes to buy,
why not?
And I just keep thinking it's,
I feel like I'm going to end up as one of those freaks with like 30 satellite
dishes and 12 antenna on the top of their house by the time I'm done with it.
Well, if the satellite thing doesn't work out for you,
you can turn them into giant death rays.
Right.
And cook chickens in them.
I always feel like this is something I do
or I just like start falling down this rabbit hole
and then it's like sunk cost fallacy. Well, I've already gone this far.
I might as well buy a satellite dish
now to pick up geostationary weather satellites.
I'm curious how big a satellite dish do you actually need
-- for this
-- basically like a direct TV size satellite dish.
Oh,
because I was going to say I literally have one on the side of
my house that I need to get a tall enough ladder to take off.
It probably cost you 10 times in shipping to get that to me.
-- No, I'm not
-- going to send it to you.
But I'm saying you drive around your neighborhood and find somebody
with one that's cut off and ask for it nicely.
That's exactly what I'm planning and
it is like,
and there's different kind. You can imagine.
This is a completely ridiculous space where there
is an amazing amount of things to do.
Like a great example is when I get bored,
when I'm waiting for satellites to fly overhead,
I'll jump over to the air traffic channels and
I'll listen to airplanes because I don't know,
-- like, I don't even know what's going on, but
-- I did do some binge listening of like,
at TC incidents and some of them are just comical.
Oh, ac you know, the assessment just taxied under us. Can you maybe let them know?
I haven't heard anything completely ridiculous.
But I, yeah, I believe that without question. It amuses me and it's fun
and
I've got some free time so I'll start building
antennas, I guess.
But anyway, anyway, this is,
I'm sure I'll work this into the topic of the day. But what are we talking about today?
-- Kurt? Well, it's
-- related.
So last week there was a big DNS kerfuffle, they made an exception.
But when you were querying these root level name servers and stuff,
it would just keep trying, like, like,
just an absurd amount of times instead of having like a, a reasonable kind of like,
ok, it's dead, Jim give up.
They basically removed the exception.
It's one of those classic security flaws where it's like, oh, that was a, you know,
why didn't you guys get rid of that sooner?
-- Right.
-- Right. And so functionally you could send a special request to a DNS.
You sent a normal request,
but then you had a whole bunch of unreachable
DNS records set up that it would cycle through.
It was because the root name servers were treated special by, well,
specifically by bind.
-- I'm sure other DNS servers do it.
-- I think power DNS and a few other.
And again, it comes back to that reliability thing of like,
and part of me understands this because if you can't reach the root name servers,
well,
then it's broken and it's not like throwing an
error is going to help because it's just dead.
So you might as well keep trying and back in the day. That made sense.
I think that's the launching point to this discussion
is if you look at the historical way,
basically anything on the internet works,
there was the old mantra of be very strict with what you send
and very generous with what you accept that sort of made sense.
A long time ago where, for example,
you could send a sort of broken DNS query to a server and it might
send you a correct response back because the server might be able to guess.
Oh, I think they're doing this. So I'm going to give them a response back.
And this was true of web servers.
You can send a lot of trash to a web server and it's going to give you a response,
which is pretty cool.
Even html,
web browsers were built like this where you can send a web
browser some seriously garbage html and it will render it into some
most of the time.
Oh Yeah,
like how many of us have been reading a web page and there's like
a bunch of garbled text in the middle and then it just keeps trucking.
-- Yeah,
-- because web servers are dumb and web browsers are frightening.
Well, and people make typos in their,
-- their html and
-- humans should not be writing html anymore.
But
the point is this was the historical view
-- of how everything should work.
-- I would say it was historically correct.
-- Except now
-- it's different. Now. The fact is if you have a client
sending a broken DNS request,
there's nothing wrong with just saying this is ridiculous.
Go away versus saying, well, I'm going to do my best to service this request.
This goes back to a bunch of our other discussions on, you know,
do you kind of punish people for not upgrading?
Do you punish them for running old broken stuff?
-- You know, like those Android phones that cannot do TLS 1.3
-- we need to punish them.
It's not a fine line though.
Not anymore because in the vast majority of these cases, you could argue, oh,
someone might have an Android phone.
I can't do this, but the reality is 99.9% of these requests are malicious.
They're not honest users with old gear and there are some that fall into that bucket.
But this is like the same thing, Kurt,
like a great example is I bought 100 year old house and I
had knob and tube wired in this house when I bought it,
which I did not know a knob and tube is ridiculously unsafe,
-- isn't it pretty much
-- exposed
conductors in inside the walls?
Yes.
And if like if my insurance company knew it was there, they would have been like,
you can't buy this.
You know, we're not insuring this house.
And literally as soon as I found it, I called an electrician, I said,
get it out now like I want it, I want this whole house rewired.
I don't care, replace everything. But the point is you could make the argument.
Oh, but the na and tube was good enough and no, that is completely invalid.
And I think this holds true of a lot of this old gear, like it is the same story.
My one concern is not so much the old gear
but the cheap gear being used in developing countries,
you can make that argument.
But again,
like is it ok to use subpar wiring in their houses that
are going to burn down a bunch of them and kill people?
No, we wouldn't make that argument at all. Why is this different?
Well, the reality is no offense.
But how often do people actually attack a man in the middle TLS?
1.1 and 1.2 connections compared to just like breaking
into the web server and taking over it?
-- I mean,
-- in the case of TLS, obviously, it's fairly low.
But,
and again, this is,
this is an instance where if you're an organization that
wants to service a place that maybe has this problem,
you can stand up old stuff.
Yeah, I'm saying like,
let's think in the context of building some sort of application
on the internet that's receiving something from somebody don't be generous,
be very strict and say if this is malformed, too bad, go away.
Well, and I think for me it's more of a two step thing.
It's, it's,
it's not so much that I want to punish people for having old gear out of support gear.
It's I want to encourage them to buy stuff from vendors
-- that actually support it properly
-- and that's very reasonable as well.
-- I think, yeah,
-- chromebooks are a great example.
They have, you know, from the moment a chromebook drops, it gets six years updates.
And so I made the mistake of buying a chromebook that
had actually been out for like one or 1.5 years.
So I'm only going to get 4, 4.5 years out of it.
-- But on the flip side it was like a $300 device.
-- which
yeah, they're really cheap. Usually
you
amortize that over four or five years, you know you're doing ok.
-- I installed Linux on my chromebook. Did I tell you that?
-- Like raw,
-- you mean like in the container or?
-- No? No, no funny story.
My, my chromebook, there's two versions of it
and the version I own was supposed to go end of life earlier this year
and I managed to sort of put the newer version of chrome on Chromo
s onto it through a variety of strange steps. But as part of this, I unlocked it
and I installed Linux
to an SD card in it. And yeah, it's running Arch Linux
now.
-- It's surprisingly usable actually
-- from the SD card, not the internal media,
right?
And I can still do Chromos and the internal media.
So I'm like, this is a win, win as far as I'm concerned.
Well, and the thing is like in past, I would be like, oh my
an
SD card, you can't do that.
But nowadays SD cards are like a, they're cheap, who cares if they die?
-- And b, they generally are pretty reliable and fast
-- now.
It's noticeably slower than the internal stuff.
But I don't care, like, it's, it's running a full Linux distribution.
I can do all kinds of wacky stuff on it.
And actually, so part of my SDR work I'm using this as my, like,
beater laptop in the field.
Yeah. If I drop, like, if a horse steps on the chromebook, I don't care.
Not that I've been anywhere near a horse recently but you know what I mean?
I thought you were doing this in your yard and
-- I currently
-- am. But I,
I also think about, oh,
if I drove up here I could get a better
view of the space station or whatever and it's like,
it's, again, it's going to get out of hand.
I have no doubt that at some point I'm going to have like a satellite
-- dish mounted to the top of my car
-- and I was going to say,
-- yeah, with the gimbal tracking, it's
-- going, it's going to happen.
Like I'm not, I
wouldn't pretend it won't
back to the DNS thing. I love
this because honestly, this is one of those,
this is actually one of those good DNS bugs where you
don't have to actually do anything other than update your software.
Right?
Like,
it's not like you have to go dirt around
-- with conf figs or whatever
-- and it affects servers.
-- It doesn't affect people, which is nice.
-- Yeah.
And, and realistically it's a denial of service attack.
Which the thing I love about denial of service attack is two things.
One by definition,
they're easy to notice because if you don't notice them
then your infrastructure is hard enough that it doesn't matter.
And number two, they go away. Right. Because it has to be an ongoing active attack.
It's not like I broke into your web server,
stole your data and I'm gone for a denial of service to work.
I have to keep pounding away and eventually people get bored and go away,
Jin. Yeah, that's true.
Most, most denial of service attack I think age out versus get stopped.
And what happens is either, well, you've got three real options.
Number one, they like, pay the guy to go, which hopefully people aren't doing.
Number two, they just eat the attack and they're out of service or number three,
they do something to their infrastructure to fix it.
Like they get behind cloud flare and cloud flare sucks up a
couple of 100 gigabits per second of denial of service for,
you know, your 20 bucks a month.
That's right.
So, yeah, I mean, it's, and, and for myself and most people I know, you know,
we don't actually host our own DNS servers anymore because
again, to do that correctly, you really, you need at least two
instances that are kind of separated network wise because, you know,
you remember back in the day, I think it was like Yahoo or, oh, it was Amazon.
Remember, I think it was Amazon had, you know,
their two DNS servers but behind a single internet connection.
And some guy denied the service that internet
connection and took the whole thing off line.
And,
you know, ideally you want like at least six servers globally spread out, blah,
blah, blah, like, man, no, you, you can just pay somebody or, well,
places like cloud player will do it for free.
Yeah, exactly.
I, I haven't run a DNA server in a long time and I don't miss it even a little. No.
No, it's, yeah, I remember editing those files by hand and upgrade. You know,
-- they
-- were so absurd too.
You know, the thing I always forgot to do is you have to increment
serial
number.
He never did that
and every time, every time,
whatever, whatever I don't care. Ok.
So, you know, it's funny because it's all this kerfuffle.
But what really gets me is, it's, there's a lot of these weird old exceptions,
that kind of made sense 20 years ago, but really don't anymore.
And it goes back to your analogy of like driving a horse and buggy on the interstate,
-- like, no, you just can't do that. I
-- think this is one of the unique failings of it.
-- We hate change.
-- Well, it's not even just hating change.
Like there's this strange obsession with keeping certain things alive forever.
Instead of just saying,
you know what guys like
it's, it's time, you know, it's load up old smokey in the trailer.
He's going to the glue factory.
Like I don't, I don't, I don't get it all the time and although I shouldn't say that,
well,
part of it is keeping old stuff running because there
are a lot of people using really old stuff.
But in this case,
this is like a reliability related issue that again has just not been in, it's,
it's not a thing anymore.
I mean, there's some of that to a degree, but I even,
-- we
-- clearly didn't need that exception.
I, I agree. Right. Right.
Or one of my favorite examples is there was some, this was an open SSL bug
-- way more specific
-- than that. Yeah, I know. I know. But I'll try to dig this up.
We might, I think we might have talked about this a long time ago.
There was a cipher that literally was broken
where if you actually tried to use it, it, it just,
it wouldn't even compile because no one was enabling it.
Obviously
that's an instance where take this out. Right.
No one's using it because it can't compile because the codes literally bad. They fix
a bug instead of just taking it out and it's like holy crap guys.
That is not the right thing to do in this instance. Just take it out.
It's obvious it was broken for like, 10 years or something. It was ridiculous.
If it's broken and nobody could use it, why would you fix it?
-- Like,
-- because our way is to support things forever.
-- Instead of saying this is stupid. Let's get rid of it.
-- See, I've got a rule now.
Like, where if I pack a box and then I move more than twice and don't unpack the box,
I probably don't need that box.
I agree with that 100%.
And I did that. Actually, I had some boxes of stuff that
I got rid of and I didn't look at them because I knew if I opened it, I'd say, oh,
but I want to keep this.
No, I don't need it.
-- And
-- I did a little bit of that because
there's a few kind of historical things in there.
But yeah, I got rid of like 80% of what was in those boxes.
The moral of the story is, don't be afraid to throw out old things.
You're going to make someone mad. But you know what? Too bad.
That's just the way it is. Quit using
-- 11 and IE six. That's,
-- well, I would say quit using IE, right. Like we're supposed
to use
Edge or whatever it's called. Now, the, or what's the one they're doing?
That's chrome based edge.
Well, edge was based on something else and now it's based on Chromium as the back end.
-- It's still called edge,
-- I think trident was their parts or that was their engine.
Ok. But yeah, yeah, edge is now using chromium on the back end.
-- You wanted to talk about web sockets also.
-- So it's kind of an interesting thing.
So web sockets allow your web browser to
it will make a connection out to something and ask for data
and it doesn't necessarily have to be like http or http.
And so it's kind of useful because contrived example,
you could go connect to like a weather
end point that serves weather
-- data.
-- I have a great example actually
a real example.
So
I have a Raspberry Pi
that
has a an old school B BS running on it that I can put in my bag, you can,
you can connect to it and
when you connect to it, the captive portal pops up on your screen
and
guess what's in? It is a little terminal, you click connect it SSH is into
the B BS, right?
And how is that happening all in the web browser? Well, that's a web socket.
That's basically it's literally running SSH in your web browser.
It's a cool technology and I like it.
And some of the browsers have decent security policies wrapped around it.
Like they won't allow web sockets to connect out to
10 dot star or you know the other reserve networks,
which is good because otherwise
attacker could put you on a web page that scans your network from the inside.
Yeah, that's right. That used to be an attack. Yeah.
And then they put those restrictions on
what's interesting though is apparently they don't
restrict web socket access to local host.
Which, yeah, I would have thought they do because I let me put it this way.
I can understand why you'd want to do that sometimes.
But I think the default should be not to allow that when my web browser is like,
do you want to give this website access to your camera?
I'm like nine times out of 10 unless it's squad caster. I'm like, no, thank you.
-- No, the answer is always no.
-- Do you want to allow this website to
you? Notifications? And I'm like, God, no. Does anybody ever click? Yes on that.
Yeah.
-- Old
-- people do an accident and then they,
they call me and they say my computer is full of viruses.
Josh come help me and I go and I'm like,
I don't even know where this is coming from and it turns out, oh,
it's the web browser and it's some dodgy website
-- you clicked allow accidentally
-- back to web talk.
It's been scanning loo.
So apparently there's a bunch of security packages that banks and whatnot buy that.
They run like a kind of quasi
antivirus. And I say quasi
antivirus because it's labeled as antivirus, but it's like usually
flaming garbage because they want to check the security of your browser
and cut down on their kind of fraud and hassle rate by,
you know, oh, you're running a really out of date web browser.
We're just not gonna let you do online banking or in this case, apparently,
if you connect to ebay,
you get a chunk of javascript that does a local host
port scan for a bunch of common ports like VNC.
You know, like the remote network viewing stuff. RDP.
I'm assuming they have a statistical model that says, you know,
if this machine has remote control software on it, then it's probably hacked
and somebody's probably like using that poor schlubs email or
ebay account to, you know, buy stuff and cause all sorts of problems for us,
which fair, you know, I get those statistical models but it begs the question of,
you know, informed consent.
-- Yeah,
-- I, I agree. Ok, I'm going to break this up into a couple of pieces and I think
the most important piece is that, I think we can all basically agree.
Web browsers shouldn't just let sites do this.
-- I would agree with that.
-- Yes.
Now we got here probably because no one was really doing it.
And so no one really thought it was a problem.
And now we know,
so now it's time to change that behavior.
But I'm, I'm ok with saying, yeah, you didn't really know this before.
So we'll let it go but fix it, fix it now because this is ridiculous.
I'm ok with websites doing this if
there is informed consent.
And I'm,
I've been thinking about it whether or not
they're allowed to do this without informed consent.
And I think
the answer is
no, because if you look at well, using the US as an example, you've got your, um,
what is it?
Computer fraud and abuse Act,
which you know, that
class
where, OK, the good news is we've apparently,
was it last year or the year before determined that terms of service on a website
are not essentially legally enforceable in the sense
of my website says doing this is illegal.
And if you do this now you've committed a crime. It's still a civil matter.
Well, it comes back to that whole contract meeting of minds.
Ebay says you can't go to ebay without letting
us do this really weird thing to your computer.
Well, do I, can I really offer informed or willing consent?
I guarantee that phone book of a terms of service, ebay made you click. I agree.
And you didn't
-- probably covers this in there somewhere
-- on the flip side.
Here's what it boils down to.
Does ebay port scanning localist actually result in any harm.
-- I mean,
-- so ebay doing it.
No,
but there are other sites that could definitely
-- do some damage
-- with that answer in mind.
I think it boils down to is we really need the web browsers to add this as a, you know,
sort of a security policy thing.
Like, you know, this website wants to connect to locals. Do you want to allow it?
Yes or no. Right.
-- With a default of, no,
-- I haven't done enough research into like, what, what
-- can he can't do it this? But I have a great
-- example.
You can do, it's a website, you can do anything
and you can send any data.
And what's interesting is apparently Firefox also
restricts access to ports 21 22 23.
-- So that's Telnet FDP and SSH, that's
-- fair.
But like a great example is there's tons of software. I've run that.
Their kind of default security model is we only bind to
local host until you set up a bunch of security stuff.
And then we'll let you bind to the internet. But
yeah, so it's bound to local host. But if a web socket can
into it and do
like your me
cash
-- or whatever. Right.
-- Right now, I've got a problem.
Well, and legitimately,
there are things that you can and do run on local hosts that don't have any security.
Like Mem
Cash D is my favorite example when I'm doing Python scripting and you know,
mangling a whole pile of data, I'll often use a locally running mem
Cash
D as a key value store. Exactly.
Because number one, that means I can very easily thread my code
and run it in parallel
and just, you know, have this magic mem
Cash D back in that just it can handle more connections than
I can throw.
It's magic.
But yeah, I mean,
if a web socket were to connect to it and kind of it could slurp all that data.
-- For
-- example,
I have a strong suspicion this is not going to be dangerous in
the context of kind of a wide net attack of the internet.
But if you are the target of an organization,
this would be extremely valuable.
I don't want to say for sure you can do
anything you want because I'm pretty sure you can,
but I haven't done the research myself.
-- Let's
-- say it's a Windows desktop,
right? That's a reasonable assumption.
There is stuff running down to local host. But at some point we have a security flaw.
I bet lots of Windows desktops have crap security for like
the internal network accessing a shared file drive thing or whatever.
Yeah.
Well, I, I mean,
I'm talking about like Windows services that are bound to local host.
I don't have a machine handy to nets that on. But there SMB.
Yeah. And so, you know,
yeah, at some point this, this could be used as a, as a vector to get.
Well, I mean, past the firewall in the net,
right?
So
I think the web browsers really do need to fix this and put on some decent policy.
I bet they do. Well, it's really easy. We already have a framework for it.
We've already trained users to click yes on everything.
So, you know, nothing's going to break and if it does break,
they can easily fix it by changing, you know, going into the config.
And oh, I do want to allow this website to connect to my web socket,
local host or whatever.
I, I bet they fix it. Web browsers are pretty good about being proactive in this way.
Whereas I think there are
actually, I have a funny related story.
I will tell that that is starting to become known and
this is a good time to whinge about this. Anyway, this is not well known,
but you can create a spreadsheet file and it can be a CS V file,
it can be like a legitimate
Excel file, it can be a Liber office file, whatever
that runs a command as something in a shell or in one of the field, the cells,
not shell cell,
right.
And this is literally functionality built into the spreadsheets.
And
-- so obviously lots of applications
-- spreadsheet per
se but into the spreadsheet application.
Yeah. Right.
Right.
And
so obviously lots of things export CS V for example,
that you can then import into a spreadsheet.
Well,
you can export a CS V that basically runs a
command on the system and then you can export it into
your spreadsheet application.
And now the fix they had was to put a pop up up that says,
oh this is going to do something crazy.
Do you want to let it.
And of course everyone clicks.
-- Yes, because that's what
-- people, I'm literally going to,
you just put equals CMD and then you put your command.
Basically, it's ridiculous.
And the thing is, and this is coming up because
people are starting to blame the applications exporting CSV as having bugs,
not the spreadsheet.
And I feel like a crazy person standing on the top of a mountain yelling
like this is a spreadsheet problem.
This is not the problem of the thing creating the CSV because I mean,
fundamentally I could export a CS V,
I could modify it and then I could send it to you
and you're going to open it and be like holy crap.
-- What just happened? This is,
-- but the thing is this isn't like some binary data.
This is just valid.
That's a freaking CS V file.
It's just an arbitrary text string. So here's a contrived example.
But what if I want to have a CSV file with an example of all the commands you can run
that are dangerous.
What do you, what do you mean?
So let's say I want to actually have a spreadsheet to document all this.
And I want to put in the spreadsheet
all the equals command blah blah, blah stuff.
-- I can't without the damn thing opening it up and actually doing them.
-- Oh
Right. Yeah, exactly. Well, you can escape it but right.
-- Functionally,
-- yes, you're right.
But I mean, again, why is the why is
not being like, hey, you just opened the spreadsheet. It wants to run this command.
Click. Yes, to allow.
Well, it does that now. It didn't used to, but it shouldn't do that at all.
It should say like, hey, this thing's full of like crazy garbage.
If, if you need to run these insane commands, go to this setting.
-- We've buried in this obscure place and click it.
-- Yeah, I could see that because
I'm guessing people do use this, especially in batch processing, you know,
like banks doing batch processing where a mainframe spits out a file,
something picks it up by FTP A
windows machine grabs it which cool.
But again, like you said,
you can have a setting where you can say like look enable this behavior,
turn it on by default or prompt by default or disable it by default.
Here's how I'm going to use this to tie up everything we've talked about today
where
this is almost definitely an obscure corner case
and you are damaging your whole ecosystem by allowing one obscure
corner case to exist now that it's coming to attention.
Instead of saying this is an obscure corner case, we should do something about it.
We're saying
the people creating
the files I'm going to read are the ones who are wrong. Not me. That's bananas.
It's worse than that because it's not only an obscure corner case,
it's an obscure corner case that is dangerous
and enabled by default.
Yeah. Right.
Like if they had that corner case and it was disabled by default but still available,
I would say like, oh, that's dangerous.
I agree with that, but at least it's off by default. Like thank goodness for that.
But like this is crazy that it's enabled by default and just runs by default.
And the worst part though is I'm dealing with legitimately
intelligent people that are saying this isn't a spreadsheet problem.
And I just, I feel like ripping my hair out with my hands.
-- It's not
-- a spreadsheet problem. It's a spreadsheet parser problem.
-- It is a spreadsheet problem, dude.
-- All my Python code doesn't care about this.
-- Your Python code isn't a spreadsheet,
-- Scott Import Excel. It's
not a spreadsheet.
-- No, but the point is this is an Excel problem. Not a spreadsheet problem.
-- And lever
-- office, I mean, functionally
-- office
-- does it
-- too. Yeah. Lever
office does it too because why not? Right. Let's all get in this crazy boat together
-- off the waterfall. Every, wouldn't
-- be one of those classic.
No Excel, but we have to do it too.
-- I
-- think that's exactly what it is.
But, but anyway, I this is,
this is where I want to end it and I feel like wrapping it all together is
sometimes
we have to cut that to that, that, that string that binds us to the past and say no more.
This doesn't make sense,
but at the same time,
the only way that happens
is if we have kind of a coherent
singular strategy we can all work with.
And I think this is again where like it becomes a
problem is if we all want something different and silly,
nothing ever gets done.
-- Well,
-- everybody wants defaults that serve their need versus, you know,
some globally optimum default that is safe, which
frankly is where we're going.
Like you remember back in the day, 20 years ago, you know, Red Hat Linux,
not Red Hat Enterprise but actual Red Hat Linux that you could like buy in
a box with a CD at like comp USA or Best Buy or whatever,
you know, came with all the services turned on by default.
And I remember
all the vendors did that because otherwise people would
install a Linux and be like Telnet doesn't work.
Why does Telnet not work well because you have to
turn it on and they would like lose their minds.
And now of course, it's the opposite.
Pretty much. I think every Linux now ships with like SSH is turned on. That's it.
You get to turn everything else on,
you know, so we did it, we did it at the operating system level.
Why can't we do it at the application level?
I think it's time to start doing these things.
And I think these are two great examples of why it matters.
And if we don't fix these problems,
things just get dumber and worse.
And these are, these are simple, simple problems to fix.
I mean, we know what we need to do. So. All right, I'm ending this here. This has been
a lovely conversation.
So I have one extra note as part of the outro I tell everyone to go to open
source security podcast.com and that's now hosted on open source
security dot io.
The website we have because the open
source security podcast.com website was hosted on blogger
and everything went insane
and the blogger interface is now unusable.
And so in a fit of rage while I was publishing the last podcast episode,
I
basically moved everything to the wordpress site we have so
everything is fine. Everything's cool.
It should all just work magically and you won't notice anything. But
yeah, you can go to opens source Security podcast.com. You can also go to opens
sources
security dot IO and you're going to end up in the same place.
But anyway, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to a website I just mentioned if you want the show notes, you can use the
Pound do
podcast.
Hashtag do hit us up on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.