Hang on a sec, hang on a sec.
I'll just record your typing and I can,
-- I can play that minutes of
-- typing information wants to be free is
an expression that means all people should be able to access information freely.
-- Dude, we're going to talk about that hacker manifesto.
-- Exactly.
It's more complicated than that.
-- All right. Anyway, all
-- right, I think everything is more complicated.
It's December 24th.
It is Christmas Eve for those of you who celebrate Christmas, those of you who don't,
you are so lucky.
-- It is so much stress.
-- Enjoy opening your presents.
That's true. I,
I do, I get coal every year anyway, December 24th information wants to be free.
I think it's more that it turns out information is really easy to copy
-- it.
-- Well, that's part of the freedom of it.
-- OK.
-- OK. Pretty much since Gutenberg.
-- So
-- this is an old saying and I will put a link in the show notes to the hacker manifesto,
which is very old and was a very, we'll say inspirational piece in my youth.
But fundamentally, this is one of my favorite things to talk about is
there's people love to say information wants to be freed.
It means lots and lots of things to different people.
But I think the single most important aspect of this
and this is something people don't always understand is once something is
public on the internet and this is even true in general,
but we're going to focus on the internet once something is public on the
that you can never take it back.
It is impossible to put that genie back in the bottle,
the copy ability of things once they're in electronic
format and another computer can access it is.
Yes. Well, and man, once it's on the internet, who knows where it's been?
Well,
-- and Google's going to find it
-- eventually in the internet archive
and who knows how many other archiving applications and your,
your document search that you're using in your company.
And it's just,
it's fascinating to me when people talk about taking
something down off the internet because I think what,
there's like all these right to be forgotten laws and stuff.
And while I agree,
I don't like that people's entire life
history is necessarily cataloged on the internet,
taking things off the internet doesn't make them go away.
It's interesting because I've, I've been through that,
remember with the DWF project and I had this thing where to
make a request. You, I needed to get
an agreement from the person saying,
you know, your information is going to be posted in this github
repo so I would send them an email, not just a click to reply,
but I need you to specifically say I, I think it was you had to specifically type out.
I agree. Like I had people send ok. And I'm like, no, you have to say, I agree.
Like I need to know that you actually read to the bottom of this
and typed. I agree.
And one guy, like 23 years later was like, oh my, my email address is in there.
I'm like,
yes
for the email you agree to.
And he's like, I want you to take it down. I'm like, no.
And anyways, he got Huffy and went to github
and lawyers and so I'd ended up taking it down.
Uh And what amused me is, well, it's still in the github
history.
And that's the biggest thing too, is not only does information want to be free,
but it turns out data structures that preserve the past
change logs or,
you know, change history and your
Google Docs or your word docs or, well,
basically all the major document formats now allow you to undo
and not just within a session but to open up a document and
just hit control Z 1000 times until you got a blank page.
That thing you erased.
My favorite is always redaction where people you know,
do the black highlight as a filter layer and
then somebody's just like takes off the filter layer
and, and actually in all
is I think the intelligence universe has gotten this one right?
Because if you take the filter layer off, they're like, well, we screwed up.
They, you know, they don't try to throw people in jail or create other problems.
This is why I always take a document,
redact it and make a screenshot of it to know that I couldn't have messed up,
print a copy and then scan it in at low dps.
-- Basically
-- what I'm doing
-- to put it bluntly
-- that
who did? Oh, that was the Mueller report in the United States. That's what they did.
They, they basically redacted it, printed, it, re scanned it at a,
at a horrendous quality and then published it.
The problem is there's so many things that can give away.
There was that PDF where they blacked it out properly,
but they left the index and so they were able to
remember, they said, OK, well, this word,
there's an index of words and we know this word is on page 117
and there's only like seven words blacked out and only one of them is about that long.
-- Right now.
-- We know that word
and,
and, and again, this is all part of that whole information wants to be free story.
And
my kind of
argument here
is that it is easier
to make things public on purpose
than trying to keep it hidden because someday,
no matter what it is it is going to
get out because information is constantly trying to escape.
If something is secret, I can blackmail you. If you post it on your website, I can't.
Right.
You know, and companies have learned this now stuff they used to hide,
they now post kind of quietly somewhere
and when somebody comes along and you know,
threatens them with whatever their response is,
go for it.
The other thing is when you go to the press and say
I have the secret information and the press goes to the company,
the company is like, yeah, that's posted on our website for years.
You, you even if it's eating babies, you'll lose that initial shock.
And that initial power
-- of the
-- disclosure as we end this conversation,
I want to clarify one important point is I do think there
should exist a certain level of personal privacy for people because obviously,
I don't want like my whole web browsing history going out in the
-- people trying to flee abuse of exes.
-- Exactly.
So this is definitely a delicate balance,
but I would say from like the corporate perspective,
make things open because it'll save you a lot of trouble.
Corporations are not people,
they're made up of people.
And so please don't yell at them on the phone because that's rude.
Fundamentally, corporations are an idea. They're not actual people.
I don't think the protections we give
people should necessarily be given to corporations.
-- Yep.
-- I agree. All right. I will see you tomorrow.