Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Conjoin.
Disjointed ideas. Josh Pre,
I'm
so as many of, you know, I generally don't let Kurt surprise me with topics, but,
-- but
-- every time I do, you're happy
life got away from me
and he snuck this one in. So I have no idea what's going on. All I know is I have
to share my screen at some point with
you.
That's gonna be the very end of the show. You're gonna enjoy it and I enjoy it. I mean,
ok, so I'm not going to list the third thing because that's the, that's dessert. Ok.
So we're gonna start with the,
we're gonna start with the entree and then the main.
So essentially
there's Bruce Schneier
has weighed in on the cybersecurity skills shortage,
right.
And so
do we even need to tell viewers what that is
or they're just going to be familiar with it because
-- to put it bluntly,
-- we should always be
in two years assuming we've solved all these problems,
no one will understand what we're talking about.
Well, but see, that's the point of this is that it's,
this has been a problem for 20 years, at least, maybe more like, because,
I mean, and, and when you and I started,
there was a legitimate cyber security skill shortage for the simple fact of, like,
it wasn't ta anywhere like you have to self learn it.
-- Right. If you were lucky,
-- you know,
and now I would teach you because we all hated it.
And now, I mean, there are university courses, there are professional courses
and still a massive gap
and,
and also even in like, even, um, people are talking in North America, you know,
there's this constant refrain of like, we don't have enough electricians,
we don't have enough truck drivers, we don't have enough plumbers
and
to point something out, you know, there's always number one,
there's always that solution of, well,
like if you pay a million dollars a year,
I guarantee you there will not be a shortage of plumbers.
That's right. That's right.
And remember back in the early aughts, like a lot of people gone into com sci
tech because of the.com boom and like, holy cow, I can make six figures a year,
like cranking out crappy websites.
And the answer is yes. Yes, you can
not anymore. Now it's prompt engineering. You gotta be a prompt engineer.
That's the current hot.
But
it just makes me laugh that we keep talking about
the blank insert here and it could be cyber
security could be plumbers or it could be electricians,
it could be whatever the skills crisis and shortage
and for something that's not completely new.
Like, I get, like, in a, I,
right now we have an actual shortage of A I security people because, I mean, sure
we just sort of are in the process of inventing it.
-- It
-- doesn't exist.
Right.
But, like, cloud security, like,
the cloud security lines had its 15th anniversary.
Wow.
Well, I mean,
yeah, and it's,
and for the organizations that have been doing it for a long time,
like Amazon Microsoft Google,
they're pretty darn good at it. Like they're, they're doing custom silicon now.
What did, what did Schneier
say? Does he agree there is a shortage or does he think there isn't,
uh
sort of
one of those things? Da da da,
da,
da, da, da, da da.
Here we go. Yeah, here we go.
And this is a different person, Kuer.
But anyways, uh what there is
is and I'm paraphrasing here because it's a little bit mangled.
What there is is a shortage of computer scientists, developers,
engineers and information security professionals who
can code understand technical security architecture,
product security and applications,
security specialist analyst with threat hunting and incident response skills.
And the one thing I've seen popping up a lot
more now is you and I come from this golden era
of we were just at that cusp of computers were simple enough to sort of understand,
but fast enough to be useful
and the architectures that you and I grew up on still exist
like X 86 and so on.
-- Yeah.
-- And, and like the way the internet works, I PV four still exists like my I PV four
R
I like how you
still exists
in like it's going to go away some day.
-- That's cute.
-- Eternally hopeful that I PV four will die someday.
I'm gonna pretend Kurt, like give this one to me.
Dude, there's going to be some space probe that they can't turn it off for
-- maybe,
-- you know, whatever the D
A or whatever it is going to be like, you know,
I PV four for like the probes we sent out 50 years ago.
I pe four will never die.
Yeah,
but
thank goodness I have all this I PV
four routing knowledge that's still applicable today.
Well, and it is because for example, it'll help you.
It's,
it's the foundation of I PV six and
it's the foundation of troubleshooting in general,
right? Like
I have a ton of email knowledge. And
so when we get some weird email problems,
I can usually track them down pretty fast because
I know how to read a raw email.
Like I looked at the raw email and I'm like, but we didn't send it
like literally we had a case of somebody complaining and I'm like,
we, we didn't send this like
it's been spammed through
Jira
through and,
and then our support person did a bit of a look up and it's like, oh,
they have an own spamming problem where, you know, people are free anyways.
Long story short,
it's like there's a knowledge based article saying like if
you get spam claiming to be from you blah,
-- blah, blah, sent to abuse, ok,
-- we're off in the weeds.
-- Let's bring this
-- back
back to this. So we're that golden age where we kind of have
like, I know what ac pu register is.
Most web devs apparently nowadays don't know what an http status code is.
And
we, you and I have privately had this discussion, but I realized
it, it doesn't matter for them by
right? They're, they're
like the, the fact when I show them how to set up a static website and hand it at HTML.
They're like, whoa, you can do that.
-- I'm like
-- my, my absolute favorite is when I call into an arrest API
and it returns like a proper http.
I forget what you call them. The, the statement to me, write a document
and inside of it, it says error 500.
And I'm like,
-- there's literally an HTTP status code for this every four
-- oh or is it 200?
Now? That's like, I'm sorry, we couldn't find what you're looking for
because seo
search engine optimization,
I don't want to give you an actual four
or four because then Google's gonna penalize me,
right?
So,
and that's the other thing, right is the web developers in today's world.
It's not the world that it was 20 years ago.
Thank goodness.
Like I literally had this discussion with my web devs where I'm like,
there are like two red lines in the sand for
us is we can never serve a virus off our website
because Google might deist us.
Oh, no,
I don't care about like serving a virus to people
so much as I care about Google delisting us.
No, seriously, I can recover. Like
I
suppose,
you know what I'm saying? Like if Google Dl Us,
that's bad. Like that's,
that's showing at Curt by a lot of people bad. That's
probably fair, you know.
And hopefully anyways and I forget what the second thing was. Um
oh, is that we should serve proper 40 fours and stuff.
But honestly, if we kind of return like uh we didn't find it here as a search page.
Sure.
Yeah.
Ok.
-- Whatever everyone
-- does it and, and in fairness,
-- it's quite a bit friendlier to the human viewing
-- it.
I
mean, you can return a special 404 status page,
right? Like
-- the
-- browser
and
do something stupid.
I don't think they do anymore.
Do you want to take that? Right?
-- Or you just want to return to 200 with the search page? Whatever
-- it doesn't matter.
Anyway, what is the purpose of all this conversation?
And this is uh
but this leads to the idea I've been thinking about is, well,
we've tried everything twice at the same time, the same way
and we have the same problems.
-- So, what do we do now? No,
-- we haven't tried everything at all.
We've tried nothing and the same thing keeps happening.
-- Well, no, but
-- we keep trying the same things like
people are like, well educate developers not to write insecure code.
And I'm like, no, like we did 20 years ago like the last and not even 20 years ago,
but 20 years ago in the same language that they're now still using.
See,
right?
Well, now C plus sauce or C# but people
-- are
-- using C
thank goodness
this is, yeah, C has
but there's a ton of legacy code like, well, there's a lot.
Oh yeah, yeah,
I mean github,
you search for C it's, there's a lot,
there's plenty
but it just, it's gotten me thinking of like what new things
you know, should we be trying and also the world, but the world changes with us.
So for example,
here we go
a British Air and this is from a few days ago.
Uh Literally, this is from uh October 20th.
Uh so a British Airways Boeing 787-9 registration blah blah, blah,
performing a flight from Tokyo to London Heathrow
was en route uh flight level 30 so 37,000 ft over the Beaufort Sea
northeast of Anchorage because they're doing the Polar road obviously,
uh when they declared pan pan pan, which was smoke.
Ok. Why,
-- why did they declare their smoke?
-- Why did they declare pan
pan pan and do an emergency landing?
Was there smoke?
Somebody dropped their cell phone
and then it lit on fire.
Well,
that's the problem is apparently now all these like massive seats
in first class have like gears and stuff to like,
you know, do the full recline and everything.
And if you drop your phone in there and then you recline
the seat and it chews the phone up all the ink.
Remember all the, the battery
out
potentially. Yes.
Uh In this case,
not quite that,
but they diverted and had to like take the thing apart to get the phone out.
So wait,
they diverted a flight simply because someone dropped their phone in the seat
and apparently they couldn't get it out.
This is a thing.
So the, the,
the recommendation now by all airlines is that if you drop your phone
and it goes into the seat and you cannot immediately retrieve it,
you have to notify flight crew
and then you're not allowed to move the seat.
And
essentially when they land the plane, then they have a,
a maintenance crew come and take the seat apart.
-- Yeah,
-- I'm ok with that. But why would they
land early because of that?
-- I, well, they did, it doesn't say if it was
-- unless the person moved the seat.
Oh, sorry, there was smoke in the cabin. Yeah, it did. So, it did catch fire
a
bit.
-- Oh,
-- there was smoke. So, if there's smoke that makes sense.
Like, smoke in an airplane is bad.
-- But it's
-- just a little fire.
No, there's no such thing as a little fire on an airplane.
Like, when you're on an airplane, if there's smoke, you land
like that's it.
And
what gets me is somebody built an airline seat with like,
moving gears and meshing stuff.
And clearly I won't buy a sofa that doesn't
have removable cushions for my Children because like,
I have to get food out of there.
I have to vacuum it. You, you have a dog,
you don't buy a sofa with cushions you can't remove. Right?
-- Because how are you going to vacuum it?
-- I would never buy a sofa with cushions.
I can't remove just because I feel like that would be
covered in filth
-- in like a year.
-- Exactly.
And like, I have two, I have two nice couches in the living room that, like,
the kids are basically not allowed to use because the cushions don't come off.
But
-- the really nice couches,
-- you just said you wouldn't buy a couch with
the
c
for
the one in the family room is like an IKEA thing. That's,
you know, look, here's, here's, you just, you just solve your problem.
You are special
so you can violate the rules,
but no one else can that is fundamentally the problem.
If I'm designing an airplane seat,
it better be like
people drop phones. Like I
-- remember reading and, but
-- they designed these airplane seats in what,
like in 1985 when no one owns cell phones.
These are pretty new.
These are relatively newer, like they were full recline bed things.
But I remember reading a report where it was like one
of the original reports where I forget which company it was.
But they commissioned report because they were getting a
lot more warranty claims than they had expected.
And they discovered people were dropping their laptops and like,
like straight up knocking them off tables and dropping them
and stuff and they were horrified because they're like,
these things cost between five and $10,000.
Why would you smash it on the phone? And they're like, because that's life.
-- It just happens,
-- people drop things and that's exactly how it works
or yes,
it's plugged in and you snake the cord and it
smashed. I mean, the whole make safe connector.
Like I love the make safe connector because
that was just not a possibility.
And I mean, I've seen cats pull devices off of tables because they grab the cable.
I feel like we're in the weeds or is this part of your proposed conversation path?
Well, this is the whole ongoing is like,
how have we not
-- solved this problem
-- because it's not the airline's problem. It is one of the look.
Fundamentally, here's the thing,
all of the problems in the world for the most part that
people look at and say, why can't you do this? And it can be
traffic in your city.
It can be dropping things on the floor and they break, it can be seats on an airplane.
It can be, why can't I hire an electrician for A
I like?
And fundamentally at the end of the day,
it all comes down to the fact that
the cost associated with these things are someone else's problems. So no one cares.
-- So it's an externalized cost, not my problem.
-- 100%.
So that is
guaranteed.
So I want you now in your open up your browser and share your screen with me.
I'm gonna send you a link
horrified by this.
It's just, it's a simple game.
-- It's you have to make a password.
-- Oh, is it that uh that one that has all the hilarious?
Uh
Oh, well, anyways pretend like you don't know what this is
the,
I don't think I've seen this one. Please
-- choose a password
-- so
I
can see
it.
-- I am sharing my screen
-- aren't I? No, you're not.
-- I thought I
-- was
no. When we started recording it went away like
it,
share entire screen
over the web
there,
you
see
it.
Ok.
I'll start over
-- and we'll put the link to this in the show notes,
-- obviously, of course,
choose password 1234.
So, ok, Josh has chosen the password password now.
Ok. So just hold
on a sec. So your password must be at least five characters.
Rule number two, your password must include a number. Ok, he's done that.
Rule number three, your password must include an uppercase letter.
I don't know that one. So I'll just do a capital P. Of course,
rule four, your password must include a special character
this
point.
Ok.
In your password must add up to 25. I approve.
Uh Let's see here. I got,
-- let's let's figure out. So
-- like the single digits.
So like 55555 or something like that,
I suppose I could just do five fives that would solve that.
That's easier than this
five fives
the month of the year.
Your pass
-- must include a month of
-- the year
must include one of our sponsors. I love it.
Pepsi, the taste of a new generation, right?
-- I'm actually literally drinking a Pepsi,
-- the Roman numerals in your,
I don't even know what Roman numerals are to multiply to 35.
And
-- so like
-- what if I just take that out?
V
and Vi
I
June
password must include a Roman numeral
35 what A V
five and what is 35
five times six?
-- No, but the Roman numerals in your password should multiply to 35
-- multiply. So I need
five times 67.
So like V times vi
I,
there we go Oh, and I've got the
capcha
PDYC eight.
-- But now you're, you got to fix the, the 25.
-- Very clever. So now I need to,
-- what? I've got to turn that into a three. No, two. Right. Wait, no,
-- eight and five.
Remove a five and turn a five into a three.
There we go. Ok.
No, that's wrong. Ok. There we go.
No, no, that's not. Right either.
The
digits
they must add to 25. I'm getting out of calculus. So
any, some of the people listening might know this because I brought it up before.
-- But I literally cannot do math in my head.
-- Well, arithmetic technically is the word
whatever because there's math
like I'm sure you can tell me what the area of a square is.
But like, yeah, you can't multiply 27 times five,
22.
There you go. There we go. Pastor must include today's veral answer.
The today's veral answer was given
-- given.
-- There you go.
Oh, and they got it right. I'm impressed they knew that.
-- Oh,
-- yeah.
No, this,
see, that's funny. I, well, Kurt was slow to the podcast.
I played Wordle literally while I was waiting for him. So that's why I knew that
uh the current phase of the moon is an emoji.
Oh, I bet there's a website for this current
moon phase.
OK. Why are we doing this? This feels like it would be boring for anyone but us,
I went.
-- No,
-- no. No, just keep going for a minute.
But the point is
you think this is bad,
this is what it feels like for a normal person with normal password rules.
I have no doubt.
Right. You and I just have a, a pain threshold for passwords. That is obscene
-- because we've been doing this for 30 well, 2530 years, whatever. I
-- mean.
Yes. And I agree with that and, ok, I'm going to stop sharing now because I'm,
-- I'm becoming bored of this game and I'm sure anyone listening to me,
-- oh,
it gets better there.
It's like you have to identify the country from the
photo and you have to do like a geographical,
like the, the
geo
hunt
and then there's, um, like, it just, it gets
very mean.
I understand what you're talking about when you say
this is what other people feel like
I'm grossly aware of that point whenever I can
because
I have pretty old parents now
and dealing with them with technology
is bananas sometimes. Like, actually I pawned this off of my kid yesterday.
So we had family pictures taken. My mom was like, I want a nice family picture.
-- So like everyone come and we're taking our picture like
-- we get a haircut. Get a suit.
No, no, I wore a sweater. We were out in the woods outdoors.
-- Yeah,
-- it was an outdoorsy thing. So I'm like, fine,
get the picture taken and then the photographer sends him a link of
like download all your pictures because they just paid for the like,
copyright and all that crap.
Instead of trying to buy pictures.
Then she's like, what do I do with these? I'm like,
Jackson, go help.
And so he, he went and he spent like two hours there and basically he, he, he was like,
do you have a flash drive?
They're like a what? He's like, oh, we have to go get a flash drive.
-- Honestly.
-- See my answer this week, I dump them into icloud Photos.
-- Well,
-- that's what ended up happening.
But they, they decided they wanted it on a flash drive but they didn't
flash drive, it turned out. So it, it turned into this whole big thing
as you can imagine. But it's like, I'm so glad I wasn't there. But at the same time,
I totally understand how
anyone who exists from, let's say, 20 plus years ago,
they don't have the skills needed
to accommodate much of this. Now, some people do. I'm not saying no one does because
-- you can keep up.
-- Dude, I spent yesterday fighting
to get logged into my Gmail account on my phone
and it
wouldn't work like I entered my user name and password because what
happened is I changed my password and I also set up a
pasy
to start working with it and on my phone,
I entered my user name and password and it
said you have to do a secondary authentication.
I'm like, yeah, of course, that's
how it's required,
plugged in my
UB key
didn't work.
Ok.
I
mean, I tried NFC, tried plugging it in, didn't work, wouldn't work at all.
Ended up doing the thing, you know, where you log on your computer,
go to the Google security thing or whatever and get a secondary code.
Sorry.
Oh, no, actually, no, I got the secondary code through my ipad,
through the youtube app of all things.
It's like go to the youtube app and do this. And I'm like,
because the youtube app is like a full fat
Google app that I guess does a lot of extra stuff.
It be. Yeah.
So anyways, but like I literally was on my phone
and I couldn't access my email
and I could not get locked back in
without having access to a secondary device to send myself a code.
But like I had my key on my key chain. I had my, my UB key that is and like
-- even II, I got locked out of my email for a little while.
-- It happens all the time, man.
-- I mean, like, what
-- the heck Google, like, why wouldn't it
work
-- well and look, and
-- I made sure that up key is set up and it works like it's,
that's the key I used to log in.
It's my daily key,
but here's the thing, right?
No,
the people have technology problems all the time and they
don't even understand how to describe the problem they have.
And then it becomes an insurmountable task because if you
don't have the language to even describe what you're doing.
And this is basically how everyone deals with security.
This is something I, I talk to the people I work with about all the time
is I, I tell them honest to God, like
I will help you with your personal security because we have entered a phase
where your home network is part of our corporate network, whether I like it or not,
-- the
-- CS A, we have a, a very much bring your own device culture. So yeah,
100%
sure. And look last pass got hacked
complex.
Well, not again. No, I mean, the big one, right? Was,
wasn't it
like they wanted their people? And
Octa got hacked and like,
-- remember Octa got hacked last week that
-- just got hacked. I don't know.
Well, last week we don't know when this is coming out. But
yeah,
anyways, Octa got hacked and they're supposed to be good at security.
And what was really amusing to me is on the hacker news story.
People are like, why aren't people? Like, why isn't cloud
FFL immediately dropping Octa even though they found the
hack and like took two weeks to convince them
and somebody pointed out
the Octa may not be bad. Like this might be as good as a
and from what
-- it, it probably is
-- like from what I know of these vendors. That's,
and, and look, here's the way I look at this. So like
Acor, I'll use as an example. Cloud security alliance would be another example.
Your security team is in the single digits,
right?
My security team is in the single digits. Like we're not a huge company.
Well, the fact that they have a security person is already,
they're at the far end of the bell curve.
Exactly.
Exactly. But the reality is
I cannot run
a single sign on solution.
We don't have the staff to do it and we don't have the budget to do it.
-- That's just the reality,
-- dude.
You, you couldn't run a web server reliably,
let alone something as complicated as an off server.
Hey, I could run a web server. I'm confident in my ability to run reliably,
but I didn't say that I said I could run it.
-- Right.
-- That's the thing whenever Dev is like, oh, we should blank and I'm like,
so you're gonna wake up at three in the morning to fix it and they're like, oh, right.
Right. Who's on call?
It's like I loved when we talked to Jerry Bell and I even watch him on Master.
He runs Infosec dot Exchange and he was like,
at
one point he said, I have learned more
about,
like system administration work running Infosec dot Exchange than I did in my,
like, entire 30 plus years of career behind me.
And I get that. I totally get that.
There's two things he's at the cutting edge of now
is the cutting edge of performance on a budget.
-- If you don't have a budget, performance is easy.
-- Exactly. 100. Right.
Yes,
I love all these security people.
They're like, oh, just turn that off and disable this and lock this down.
And I'm like, but I need the computer to, like, do work.
Right. And so I can't just
turn off all this crap.
Like,
sorry, every time somebody brings up holding BS D, I'm like, super
duper.
Yes, it's secure by default.
And what does it do by default? It ros packets and listens to,
you
have to install a web server and a web framework and a bunch of other stuff that,
that's one of my,
one of my favorite things right now is people are going on and on about, oh,
you know, the, the cool thing right now is like containers that are so small,
they have little to no vulnerabilities in them, right?
And
functionality. That's cool.
Except as soon as I start installing stuff to actually run my application now,
I'm right back where I was like,
this wasn't actually solve a problem. It looks good on paper.
And I, I mean, I think this is,
this is what it just drives me nuts about security people.
Is there are a nontrivial number of security people
that do not live in the same world.
The people they're trying to help live in.
It's, and it, it is a disservice to your users.
I would actually say the thing, a lot of security people forget
is that security exists to serve the business and the user.
No, I'm serious. And you laugh but
security exists.
Business and the user,
-- in theory, we don't,
-- like, let me put it this way.
If I have a choice between the business getting business done
and the business being secure and getting less business done,
I'm going to pick more business with less security.
Yeah, 100%.
Look, here's so, here's an honest to God conversation I have on a regular basis,
we could hire a developer who's going to have a focus on upgrading some of
the older packages that we know need to be upgraded and brought up to date
or I can hire a developer to add those features the customer wants.
So they'll spend more money with us.
This isn't even a conversation
and that's why
people use
Octa instead of writing it themselves or running it themselves because. Right.
Right.
But now, now here's the thing, here's what I want to say.
So it's easy to crap on security people and say like, oh, you don't have,
you don't live in reality, you know what's going on and a lot of them don't,
-- I'm not gonna, I mean, I was one of them for a long time
-- and conversely,
a lot of them do want to do the right thing
-- and can't do to budgetary or organizational culture constraints
-- for sure.
But like here's the deal.
So I'm not going to get a developer whose only job is upgrading packages, right?
Never gonna happen.
But what I can do
is I can put together a program that's like, OK,
here's what our current state of our packages looks like.
Here are,
here is an order I would like to see us upgrade this
stuff in and I would really like you developers to do,
like, let's say 2 to 5 of these per release
that would make me happy.
And you know what happened?
They do it because I'm nice to them
and it, it, they know we need to do this, but they also don't want to do it all the time.
One argument I've found somewhat successful in
keeping more up to date is that essentially
we can keep more up to date more often and have smaller delta, smaller change.
So, if there is a problem, oh, now it's one of these three things,
if we do an update every like two months,
well, crap, something broke. It's one of these 150 changes
-- for sure.
-- And
one of the,
that's one of the very few
usable arguments I've found with people because here's the problem is if you
constantly upgrade you absolutely, 100% will run into problems.
No, here's, here's, that's not, that's not the argument,
but
and that's the problem is people make that argument and they're right.
Like, if we constantly upgrade stuff, we're gonna be constantly breaking stuff.
And it's like,
yeah, basically. Right.
-- No, no,
-- no, I'm, I'm not suggesting we upgrade at breakneck speed though either.
But my suggestion is
is that we create essentially AAA risk.
Like these are the riskier packages.
These are the less because there's obviously things we're using.
-- But
-- the fact that you can say and assign some risk rating to them,
even if it's completely made up
is you're already
-- beyond most places comfortable
-- saying it's at least 70% made up.
But the
fact
that
like that's the thing that gets me is like if I looked at my webs s bomb,
you know, because it's rails. So it's, there's a, what is it packages dot
json
or something
like I, I would look at it and be like, cool, like, I guess I just see which of these was,
is kind of the most out of sync and maybe go with that or do a CV scan.
Well, they already do CV scans so we're good there.
But,
you know,
like literally the only real argument I can make is
that we can pay the delta cost in incremental pieces.
So it's less painful.
Like it's, the paint is smaller but spread out more or like a big chunk once in a while.
Right. Right. You know,
and then the secondary part of that argument is, and this is, oh,
rebooting phones. That was the other thing.
Remember that whole thing about, like,
people being told to reboot their phones to get rid of advanced
persistent threats that can't be gotten rid of any other way.
And I,
again,
I suspect it's for two reasons. People keep saying that is number one,
I have said in the past I reboot my service on a regular basis
so that
if there's a problem it's happening on my schedule.
Not, oh, I have to do an emergency reboot crap.
Now,
it didn't come up at two in the morning and now
I have to fight with it at two in the morning
versus like, ok, it's three in the afternoon. I'm gonna reboot it.
Now I have some time to deal with it
and fix it and, like, find out, oh,
I didn't enable this service or this thing wasn't turned
on or this thing has a type or whatever.
Right. Because, you know, you make changes and things
or whatever. And so I think that's part of it.
And then the second thing is especially on mobile devices. Like, what else can I do?
Like,
II, I sort of could run antivirus on my phone. But do I really trust that stuff?
I mean, it's not like I can pull the hard drive out and scan it.
-- Well, no, no,
-- I mean, look, this has to be
-- seen
-- to be doing something though,
especially if you're a security person being asked to fix a problem,
at least telling the user to reboot their phone.
They're doing something and they're maybe going to
stop yelling at you for five minutes.
I mean,
maybe look, rebooting phones
often works though because a lot of the malware
isn't able to gain that persistence foothold versus so rebooting your phone,
like, wipes it out and, and it murders it. So it makes sense in that context.
Well, and it's
in theory a relatively cheap, low risk security activity,
it's not even a low risk security activity. Like rebooting things often fixes them.
I mean,
there's like, I love the it crowd has that like,
and he tried turning it off and out again.
That's literally the first thing they say because it's true.
Well,
and the thing I've pointed out to people is rebooting and seeing
if the problem stays or goes away establishes something very solid,
which is, is this
like an ongoing problem or does it like, build up to it?
Like, does it happen after a month or a week
or is it like just if you reboot and is the problem still there? Oh, ok.
Now it's something that's like maybe a file got corrupted or
whatever, right? Like it happens,
you know, something got out of sync, whatever.
But
I think a lot of this boils down to is we don't have a lot of actual
really effective tools and methodology,
right?
And this is like this is exactly what the cloud security lines has
been working on for 15 years is coming up with methodology and tools
and practices
and
as much as we've done,
there's part of the challenge is things keep changing so much.
That is one of the big challenges.
Yes, like I look at road construction locally right now,
they're using all the GEO blocks so much like 1520 years ago,
you never saw a geo block.
So geo blocks are these giant styrofoam blocks
that they use instead of infill
because
geo blocks
have two really interesting properties is one, they don't compress
because
uh if you go watch a bunch of youtube videos,
it's actually really hard to make a layer of dirt and compact it.
So it doesn't squish more.
And like you get big divots in your road, right?
And number two, they actually, like, they really help prevent against frost e
which is an issue here. Yes, I did hear that as well. Exactly.
And they're relatively cheap and easy to work with.
They're just giant blocks of styrofoam which, you know,
anybody can literally pick up and place.
Yeah, they don't weigh much.
And so
like, but we don't have like, God,
we're on like which set of technologies again in the web right now?
Like we're on web three with,
I mean, OK, look,
here's what I'm gonna get on my soapbox here
for a minute and this is completely related to the
training problem we talk about
and there's not enough cybersecurity skills and all this stuff.
If you look at an industry like construction or
electricians or plumbers or any of those skilled trades,
especially the skilled trades,
they don't just get to do whatever they feel like doing
right.
There are like legal standards they have to follow. There's the guidebooks.
Have you watched a home renovation show where they
fix the problems that the previous person left?
And, but then
that's generally not from a contractor.
If you pull a building permit, someone is going to come and inspect the work.
-- I
-- disagree.
I've seen enough like homes on homes with
new builds that are fully inspected and look,
I'm not going to say it's always perfect, but generally speaking,
there are rules and process that have to be followed, right?
-- There are like literal, especially like when we talk about,
-- well,
there's supposed to be inspections,
-- right?
-- II I think large construction projects like roads, for example,
those are, and again,
there's always going to be things that fall through the cracks.
There's always going to be issues. I'm not saying there aren't,
but we exist in an industry,
the tech industry where we have virtually no regulation.
We have very few like concrete standards. We have to adhere to,
there's minimal like human harm from any of this.
So we generally don't worry about it.
Even the standards we have like sock two are kind of, like, everybody knows,
you just hire the auditor that will pass you.
I mean, there's some of that
and so we have that conflict of interest aspect as well where we
get to pick who audits us for a lot of these standards.
-- But
-- look, there's lots of people who fail so
too. I mean,
and, and let's,
even if you pass it,
like PC I,
one of my favorite examples was like every credit
card breach was against a PC I compliant company.
Right.
-- Well, I mean, the, where else would the data be?
-- Right. Right.
So anyway,
and of course, I'm not saying regulation will fix everything, right.
But I think
we exist in an industry that is
heavily unregulated.
It is, it moves quickly
and there's just honestly chaos all around us and we're
doing our best with what we have by far.
One thing that's been coming up more and more recently,
especially I've noticed with the whole web three crypto effort.
And now A I
is a lot of the larger companies are actively
diverting any regulation, they're actively campaigning against any regulation.
Well, of course, they are,
every industry throughout time has always said if you regulate us, we will die,
-- which I think at this point with crypto would be ok.
-- Well, I mean, that one's fine,
that one might because like illegal activity is generally illegal.
But anyway, like my favorite of all time
is the refrigerator industry
with the, if you don't let us have these like latching doors that
and like, ok, this is actually a perfect example.
I know I brought this up a couple of episodes ago and I'm going to bring it up again.
Right? Refrigerators used to have those like doors that locked from the outside.
And if, if someone got trapped on the inside,
they died
because
you
couldn't open the door.
And now the crazy thing is like, I think it was only like six people died.
It's an incredibly small number of people.
And then the regulators were like, fix it.
And the refrigerator industry was like, oh my goodness,
we can't possibly fix this problem.
Like there's nothing we can do. What was us?
And then they were like, oh, we'll just put bag this on the door.
It was quite a bit more than six.
How many was it?
-- Oh,
-- for example,
statistics for the 18 months from January 54 to June 56 show that 54 Children
were known to have been trapped in household refrigerators and that 39 of them died.
-- Ok.
-- So, I mean, that's quite,
but still here's the thing. 39 people
you think about how many people die on the roads or
die in firearm accidents or die in whatever per year,
right?
But roads are a great example in that the
deaths per passenger mile travel
-- has dropped.
-- It has for sure because of regulation
seat
belts and airbags and all that stuff. Absolutely.
And I mean, that's another easy one. Right.
But here's the thing in tech, how many people are we killing? It's not zero.
But we don't really know either. And it's probably not a lot. It's,
well, it also depends on your definition of killing. To be blunt.
Are we talking about outright killing or, like, shaving a year off their life?
No, it's got to be like, outright death. Right. Like,
I mean, you have to remember before we had
like usable pollution regulation,
rivers were literally lighting on fire until tech is killing
like literally tens of thousands of people per year.
No one's gonna care.
Well, like, uh how many Tesla deaths
because Tesla self-driving 17 deaths?
That's not enough to matter and they keep blaming the people.
That's the reality of it.
And,
but now what's funny is sometimes things work though, like,
do you remember lawn jars cart?
Did you have lawn jars when you were a kid?
That
one person died, I think from that and
ban them? Yeah.
But also like that's a risk to reward ratio of like we're gonna throw this
giant pointed spiky thing up in the air and like stare up at it.
It does feel
obvious
but
-- still like,
-- well, my favorite thing is this guy wrote
uh when uh the Apple smartphones came out and the whole app Store thing came out
and he wrote a game which using the sensor was how
throwing your phone in the air for the longest and like Apple put the
on that pretty darn quick.
I get that. Like that's,
we all know how that story ends
-- and that's
-- a
lot of smashed.
So, anyway,
anyway,
let's, let's tie this one all up and bring it back.
So, do you think there is a cybersecurity skills shortage? Car?
Yes, there is. Absolutely.
-- And I would say
-- yes. But,
well, and I was about to say,
but
the challenge is
like
there's a lot of other problems. Uh
I don't want to say that come before it, but that are tightly meshed with it. Like
cybersecurity pay uh access to training, access to certification, right?
Like, oh, I switched on security.
Remember tet did about the whole um certificates, blah, blah, blah.
And I replied that well,
like good or bad doesn't matter because certificates are the only thing that scales
as far as like cybersecurity training goes like,
yeah, they're not perfect.
People cheat and don't know the material and blah, blah, blah. But
the only way,
but they're,
they're one of the few things that will work at
a scale of millions or tens of millions of people.
Like
mentoring, mentoring is great. Mentoring doesn't scale to a million people,
easily.
Not,
it
kind of can, but it, it, no,
it probably does because if you look at like plumbing and electrical.
But how do you find mentoring?
Well, we'd have to have that whole apprentice system set up.
They have an apprentice system. Exactly like that is part of the,
the whole structure of that industry.
And in some cases like carpentry in Germany, you have that structure going back
multiple centuries.
Like my cousin in Germany is a proper carpenter and like he has taken place
or he's taken,
uh, he's participated in traditional activities like the VD,
but it's like a 500 year old thing that you do.
And it's like, well, you want to be a carpenter, you gotta do that tough,
you know,
and we have, you know,
people actively campaigning against any form of organization or
kind of forced, mandatory, required education or anything.
-- And I mean,
-- yeah,
I don't know
again though, this comes back to
Carol Nichols
who gave that talk
on the railroad safety brakes, the air brakes took 80 years,
-- 80 years to get there.
-- Well, and we still have, for example, now in Canada
where they had to pass some new regulations saying you couldn't leave
them like open to move the trains and stuff that you actually
um we had a problem with some runaway trains where they were like
leaving the train parked overnight and not getting the air brakes on,
man.
Yeah,
so like you have to engage their breaks now,
but of course the people working are like,
but our bosses are saying you have to do
this much work and get this stuff done quickly.
And if we do it properly safely. We, we can't get the work done
and we get yelled at or not paid or whatever. You know, it's like when you find out,
when do you think airline crews start getting paid?
Oh, it's when the door shuts.
Actually, I think the flight attendants got that fixed. Right.
I don't think so.
No,
-- not
-- sad.
-- But yeah, it's like when the door is shut and then like,
-- yeah, I know.
That's embarrassing. That makes me angry.
Like those poor people.
I'm pretty sure, like, if they're standing on the plane telling you where to go,
that counts as work.
I agree. Like, not just that. Have you watched people board an airplane?
Holy crap. I like,
-- oh, my goodness. I would,
-- it's been a while but I imagine it's worse.
I would rather be a school teacher
with Children than help people board an airplane.
And I would be a very bad school teacher. Like, that's all I have to say to that.
Yeah, for real?
Oh, my goodness. Just
never before in my life have I wanted to, like,
stand up and yell at people more than watching people board an airplane car.
Like,
-- uh, anyway, I'm not going to get into that.
-- Now.
My favorite is when they try and, like,
jam m, like, it's just, you gotta check your luggage. Like, I know it sucks.
And it's scary to check your luggage.
But, like, come on, you can't be bringing three pieces on board. Sure.
I, I'm not getting into this now because I could,
I could have a multi hour podcast of me ranting
about people boarding airplanes and I'm not gonna do it,
but
I think we're gonna call this one.
Thank you, everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt.
Go to Miss Social security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not Suzie Podos
S podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye.