Hello and welcome to episode 134 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt
Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
-- Well,
-- everything's on fire again.
-- Yeah. Isn't it
-- great?
I, I should go back and see how many times I've said that in the intro of the show and I,
-- it would probably make me sad if
-- I think it's about once or twice a month.
-- Uh It, it maybe a little less than that, but
-- it's,
I'd say it's less than half and more than a quarter.
Yeah, I probably,
probably,
oh, my goodness.
So containers they're all broken
-- for us actually,
-- actually. Yeah, that's the funny thing.
It is all of them because it's run C not just
this time.
So it's also Creole and
those are the only two I know offhand, but I think there was a list of what,
five or six of them
that are affected by this bug.
Uh So do you want to explain the bug or shall I
-- I will let you do the honors?
-- All right.
So paraphrase containers don't contain. So, containers
actually have
a lot of interactions with the underlying host system.
So for example, they, they share the same kernel
and on a Linux system, one of the, the cool things is everything's a file
and this has led to problems. So
this is a beautiful everything is a file.
And in Linux,
there's this file system called slash proc uh which is the process file system.
And it's basically
got some magic files
uh like slash prox slash self slash exe
and proc self exe is, is basically exactly what it sounds like. It's
the executable that's running,
you know, so the executable can essentially look at itself.
I I know that there used to be good reasons
for having this kind of prop interface to it.
But nowadays, I, I think it's incredibly dangerous and not maybe so safe
and it turns out
uh if you're in the container
with enough privilege, you can write to this.
So OK, you can write to your own process that you're running as well.
Yeah. OK. Normally that's not such a big deal, right? The process can modify itself.
It's not great but you know, not the end of the world, right?
You're not crossing a trust boundary, right?
In theory. Yeah, except in this case, you're modifying the run C binary that is
running all the other containers,
right. Right. Uh The fix is actually incredibly simple.
They just basically clone the binary so that
sure go modify it, that's your copy of it.
Uh Right.
Well, this is I mean, this is common in fork exec land.
I mean, this has been an issue forever in UNIX and, and unfortunately,
spawning child processes is in, it's way, way harder than it should be.
I mean, it's one of those things that at this point in time
they should just have a freaking system call that does this
correctly instead of relying on humans to not screw it up because
humans always screw it up.
And so yeah, basically it's, it's your,
I guess holy grail of container to host escapes,
which is basically when you're running a container that's as bad as it gets.
Well, that's kind of the whole,
I mean, again, people are generally trying to use containers to contain
as the name implies
somewhat,
right?
I mean, I, you know,
you can't really blame people for thinking containers would contain stuff.
That's
-- literally the name.
-- It, it it seems to be right.
It is, it is the accepted, I guess attitude.
So here's what I think is interesting about
this story.
There is the the
the issue was discovered, it was clearly coordinate in some way,
a bunch of organizations patched it in a timely manner
and
there was an advisory posted to the OS S security mailing list.
And as part of the advisory, they included a demo exploit.
And the thing that I think amuses me is the demo exploit is
it, it,
-- they talk about how it's not weaponized and it's like a two line fix to weaponize
-- it.
Even if they didn't release an exploit when I read the code, commit to fix this,
it's like, oh
you can write to the runi process,
the,
the run C process that runs all the containers
as again the name run C implies runs containers.
Like this is, you know, this is what frustrates me when people are like we should do
when people bring up that hole,
we should fix security bugs in secret and just ship the fixes.
Yeah, that'll work once in a while.
But honestly, the majority of security bugs are so simple and stupid.
Like this one is a perfect example of simple and stupid.
-- All right. So se Linux blocks it, which is, I mean, that's
-- cool. Yeah.
Well, if you're running the Def
uh, I think what was it on? Red Hat Linux,
if you're running the default policy with it enabled.
So it basically, and it's a,
it's a relatively simple same policy that says as I understand it,
like the runi binary should not be modified or written to which,
yeah, that makes sense. Actually, I think
I was actually shocked to, to read that app Armor doesn't stop this. It seems like
containers shouldn't be able to write to anything outside of the container.
Part of the problem is how App Armor handles
file paths and how it handles access to stuff.
Oh, that's right. Because it does something weird, doesn't it?
Because remember that was one of the OK. This is OK.
This is going to show how old and crotch.
I
so remember when the,
remember when the NSA tried to get Se Linux into the Linux kernel
and they failed the first time around because quite simply put,
they had to touch everything,
right?
They had to touch every single thing that they wanted to control access to, which
was everything, you know, network memory
file system, everything.
It was an incredibly intrusive set of patches and the community looked at it,
looked at the email domain it came from and went
no.
Right. That that's basically what happened.
And then the NSA partnered with Red Hat and kind of learned
how to community and got the patches and and you know,
turns out se Linux is actually not some evil backdoor from the N SAS E. Linux
does, I would say they do it correctly and unfortunately,
in this case correctly means horrendously
complicated.
Whereas App Armor tries to take a
very simplistic approach which I appreciate because
sort of
App Armour is really good at the application level.
But once you kind of cross past the application level,
App Armor just doesn't work really to put it bluntly.
Whereas Se Linux is,
is, you know, very much kernel level, so it's much more complicated, but it's
well, it's much more robust and
-- fine grained, right.
-- Right.
So now I I will say, I mean,
this is one of the downfalls to se Linux is just the
-- fact that a lot of people disable it
-- because it breaks things.
And obviously this is, this is a poster child for saying don't do that.
But it also comes down to, I mean, heck, man,
I've been there a million times if something isn't working,
what's the first thing I do turn off?
Oh, it works.
Right. And then I just never turn it back on because why would I,
and I,
hopefully most of the container hosts aren't doing that
because if you're running containers on the host,
let's hope that's all you're doing
pretty much it.
Yeah.
No, I, I don't know what to say and, and what's really depressing to me actually is I,
I kind of took a look at containers and container security ages ago
because that's kind of what I was in charge of for a while
and I wanted to do some threat modeling and attack modeling of. Ok.
So we've got this stuff running in a container and let's assume for a moment,
you know, these containers are running,
um,
privileged
stuff.
So it's not just running at a low privilege,
but it's running within the container as route.
And the general consensus was early on that. If you do that, you have no security.
Oh,
ok. That's unfortunate.
But what I wanted to do was map,
sort of where the container could talk back to the host os.
So for example, it shares a kernel. So
well, now you have the entire Linux kernel as an attack surface.
Fantastic. For whatever reason, it didn't occur to me to look deeply into proc
um which I have looked at before because proc is a, is one of those classic gauchos
of. Oh, it does what now
yet nobody would have expected this though. Man, I would not expect
a typical threat model to,
to consider this because would have just assumed that they're
forking the process correctly in a way that doesn't lead
-- the file the scripture
-- to.
Well. And so the problem is perfectly what you said.
So I looked, I actually just spent yesterday looking for attack modeling tools,
either ones that are sort of specific or ones that are more general like that,
you know, basically help you produce pretty pictures and,
and keep track of all the relationships.
There are a lot of tumbleweeds,
uh like there was, there was an attempt by
a
soap to create one called dragon and it hasn't had to commit since uh January of 2018,
Microsoft has one specific to windows. So that's not going to be very helpful.
That's basically it, there's really, there's uh I, I'm sure,
I think there are some commercial tools, but yeah,
I'm not going to go through the hassle of trying to get a
hold of a commercial tool and see if it works or not.
-- Um I mean, fundamentally, I
-- don't know how many there are,
I feel like I looked for this at one point and
I don't think there were very many and let's face it,
man, like what's the market for this?
It's,
-- it's pretty honestly
-- like a UML diagram is I suspect what most people end up doing
or some sort of graph, you know, this is related to this. OK.
Let's look at that relationship and see,
you know, what, what can I maximally expose or abuse there?
And then what is it changed to? And what can I then get access to,
you know, to create these sort of chains of dependencies like so,
you know, perfect example here is like, OK, I get access to the run C I.
Uh Well, even better example is I'm in a container that's less privileged.
I get access to the run seat.
Now I'm accessing all the containers running on that host.
I now access a container on that host that's running with privileges like, oh,
maybe they're running the Docker Damon in a container privileged to do builds,
for example, right.
That's not unreasonable.
Well, now I can access that container and that gives me really,
really easy access to the underlying
operating system and to, you know, take over the entire system.
-- Uh
-- Right.
Yes.
So there are some, some clever facts about this issue though, for,
for listeners who, who may not be aware, I guess so
the way it works is you end up overriding the run
C binary, right?
Meaning if you can
keep an eye on that binary, right?
If you're running in, in some sort of logging infrastructure,
you can set up a rule for the audit subsystem to keep an eye on runs.
If run C changes,
you know, make, make noise. Now, you know, something's wrong.
And the other thing that's going to happen is
most Attackers are going to overwrite runs sea with,
with garbage that's going to break all of your container orchestration.
And so that's something else to watch out for.
Now,
a clever attacker is going to overwrite run C
with something that is run C plus a bonus,
right?
That does whatever they want it to do
and then you won't be detected.
But I mean, that's something else to keep an eye on. So I guess
the one thing I keep thinking of here that kind of buys us a
little bit of a peace of mind is the fact that this is going to be like a filthy,
dirty export.
This is not something you can easily just, you know, escape from, from the,
the seeing eye of Saron
here
who's potentially watching our infrastructure.
Now, of course, if you have no logging, well, too bad, you're screwed. Go get some
-- right. That's the easy answer there.
-- Well, and more of the point too, like,
I mean, this is one of the reasons that as I understand Google compute engine,
the way they run containers is they run containers each one
-- in its own VM because they don't trust the security
-- boundary.
Yeah. I think it's worth talking about why is a VM safe here and why a container isn't?
Because
I know a lot of people don't always understand some of the fundamental differences.
Uh, well, so, I mean, the simplest answer is that V MS have 20 years of CV,
whack a mole and hardening.
Yeah, you're not wrong. I mean that's to it. It's
so not only that, I think that the real key here is the fact that a virtual machine
is
there, there's special hooks in the processors these days.
-- Well,
-- yeah, to make it even more secure and fast,
right? That, that basically we're talking about kind of hardware level hardening
where the the code is running in the processor in a way
that makes it
nearly impossible to break out of the I, I almost called it a container,
the virtual machine
that is in casing it,
right? And
back in the day,
virtual machines worked in a manner we'll say similar to how containers work today
and those had tons of problems.
And and of course,
just even even the KVM style technology had its fair share of issues back in the day.
And
I do think containers
could get better. But in all seriousness, the easy way out is to just
put them all in a virtual machine.
And I know Intel was working on this with clear containers at one point. I don't know,
I don't know if that project still exists, but it's,
it's definitely the way to go.
No, it's if, if you,
basically, if you want to use containers and you want
actual security
then you, if you want multi-tenant,
so you want more than one workload per machine that maybe doesn't, you know, need,
they, they're not allowed to talk to each other or interact with each other.
Uh in
an uh in a security sense,
then they need to either run on physically separate hosts or they,
you really need to run them inside of a virtual machine.
-- There, there's really, those are your two options.
-- Right. Right.
Now, my understanding though,
I don't do any of the container orchestrators make it easy to do this though.
I don't, I, I haven't really paid that close of attention.
-- I don't know, like can Kubernetes use virtual machines like this
-- sort of,
but not really,
you can make it work, but it's not
easy.
And,
and I guess there's also the issue of
when you're using containers in a virtual machine,
there is slightly more overhead in terms of just memory, we'll say,
-- and they do start up slower.
-- The annoying thing is they don't need to necessarily be
that way, right?
Because with memory deduplication and stuff like that, it should be just fine.
-- But then we enter into the whole
-- I, no, that isn't gonna work though.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna pick on you for this one because memory deduplication is actually really,
really expensive from a resource perspective.
And when you have a container that's expected to be up for, you know,
10 microseconds, 10 milliseconds, whatever.
Uh That's
-- never happening.
-- Oh, ok.
So you're talking about people actually using containers correctly?
-- See my assumption is
-- people are, yeah, if you're using it like a fat
or thin VM then yeah. Sure. V
MS.
Um Well, it's, it's I know some of the tele
telecom companies have done work around this, you know,
bringing up V MS and bringing them down real
quick and Amazon just announced it right last year.
Um that they have their, I forget the name of it, but
you know, they're, they,
they can bring you up a virtual machine and I think it was 250 milliseconds and they,
they, they were saying that they will definitely make it faster this year because,
well, with this exact issue, right, you want to service a request.
Well,
if you have to just wait a quarter of
a second before you can even service that request,
right?
-- So,
-- well, in a quarter of a second is a long freaking time,
that's how long the entire request handling should take.
Right. Right. Exactly. That's what is it.
I remember one time talking to somebody
about human interaction with like computer systems and
I think it's 300 milliseconds is basically what we can understand anything
less than that we generally can't perceive but anything more than that,
-- we totally see
-- human reaction time is a quarter of a second.
So anything below 0.1 of a second is, is instantaneous as far as we're concerned.
Right.
We just can't process that.
Yeah.
And up to 300 milliseconds, it's not very noticeable,
but for things like virtual reality that's not gonna work,
you're gonna start barfing everywhere
and anything above a half a second and you're,
you're now introducing enough control delays that if it's like a real time system,
like say you're trying to drive a car with a half second delay,
you're going to die.
Yeah, that's probably fair. That's probably like texting and driving right there.
Yeah,
because this is the brutal part of like virtual reality is like
a virtual reality system with a 0.2 or three second delay.
-- People are going to get violently ill. Uh
-- I would expect that. So
I, I am one of the lucky people that can't watch 3D movies
and
I have,
I forget I was doing something once where it was
like a VR like system and there was a noticeable lag
and I was
an unhappy person
almost instantaneously with it. Like II I struggled to deal with that environment
and
Yeah. Right. Anyway, why are we talking about VR containers?
Containers are broken, go patch your containers.
So I guess so here's the other half of it, right?
Is, is I just said one of the key terms, everyone's like, oh go patch your containers.
Uh That's not possible for a lot of organizations because let's face it.
If you're using containers, like they're kind of, you know,
poor man's virtual machines.
Uh you can't call them fat V MS. They're skinny V MS, right?
Maybe, I guess, I don't know, fat containers, skinny V MS, right?
Uh There's a lot of default cloud or a container images
that are like I was looking at some of them,
they're two gigs.
That's not skinny. Skinny is like
disco cheap. It's fine. Four men
are cheap
anyway. Anyway, so here's the deal. If you have long running containers,
you can't patch this because you have to shut down the fleet
and for a lot of people
that's not happening.
Like no way.
I mean, I guess the good news is you could maybe either enable Se Linux,
hope nothing breaks or selectively enable se Linux.
-- Like create a custom policy that just want let just protects one C
-- Well,
it depends how you've disabled it though.
I mean, if you've disabled it at boot, you can't turn it back on.
-- Right. You have to reboot.
-- That is very true actually. Yes,
there's nothing more infuriating to me. The people that are just like go
at
your systems people.
It's like, no, that's, that's, that's like saying stop being poor.
-- It's just, you can't tell people that it's not helpful,
-- I guess.
So, here's my advice of sort of the, the, the poor man's way to deal with.
This is go get like pie notify, py,
notify and it hooks into the I notify system of Linux.
So you can pie notify the run C binary
and you'll immediately get a note, you can set up a script to email you if it modifies
immediately.
Yeah, I mean, that's an easy way out if you lack proper logging,
which you should have.
And, and actually something else I was thinking of here that, that interests me.
Now, mind you, the trick is
when you, if you have a container host set up,
it would not be unreasonable to mark your,
basically your whole file system read only,
which would totally stop this also because let's
face it if you're running containers on a host
and in theory,
your container host should be as disposable as your containers are
where it's a matter of instead of patching your container host,
you should probably just be
spinning up a new container host that's
patched and then migrating workloads as needed.
But then that requires you to have your workloads correctly set up for containers,
which a lot of workloads are not
there.
Yep. Absolutely.
And so that's part of the challenge too. And, and I guess
this is, ah, man,
I just keep thinking about this and this is a horrible scenario.
There are tons of people that probably have no freaking clue what to do
and there just aren't a lot of good answers here.
Now, the one thing I will say that I think is advantageous to this is
many container workloads aren't running untrusted code.
You know,
that's not a reason to say I don't have to care because
obviously people can break into your containers and stuff like that.
But,
but here's,
here's the deal and here's something I was thinking about for how to exploit this.
So, first of all, you need the ability to get inside of a container. Right.
And
if you're,
we'll, we'll assume you can somehow break into an application or something and,
and work your way in.
Right.
-- Well,
-- the one thing to consider is the multi-tenant environments, like, say,
digital Ocean or rack space or whoever.
Right. Right.
And those are, they already have their own set of issues in those environments.
Right. So we're going to ignore that.
Well, hopefully they're doing the, the Google trick
of one container
because if they're not doing it, there's, they're
creek at some point.
Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
So, but here's the deal. So you got to get in,
then you got to get root.
Like, and again, here's one of those things don't run your containers as root,
but everything works when you run it as route, it just works.
Exactly. Don't do that.
Uh, oh,
you know what else we didn't mention if
you're using user name spaces this doesn't work
because what user name spaces do
is the run C process runs as a non root user.
And that means the, the container process
doesn't have the permissions to modify the run C binary.
So that is also something if you're doing that,
you can go drinking or something now, right? Because you're fine
anyway, so you got to get in, you got to get root
and then you got to modify RUN C and then it has
to kick off a new container image by running Run Sea,
right?
Which is
I, I'm not saying that doesn't happen very often,
-- but it's potentially not an attacker
-- controlled.
A very simple way is once, once you modify the runs,
you just kill the existing container, you're exploited and
being admins, they're like, oh, this thing broke, turn it back on.
Well, realistically when a container stops working or crashes,
do you do a security level investigation or do you turn it back on?
No, you just turn that back on. It's fine.
-- Right. Yeah,
-- there's no way you're gonna investigate every time something fails.
No, no, definitely not. And, and, but anyway, so there's, there's enough steps.
This isn't one of those, do nothing and get hacked.
-- The,
-- the real, I think the challenge is,
is for any provider providing multi-tenant container environments there
and they're not doing it correctly. Like no Se Linux or
you know, no container
wrapped in a VM. They're, they're up the creek.
But again, they're up the creek regardless.
Like some, it's like the, it's like all the Linux kernel vulnerabilities.
If you are relying upon the Linux kernel to be secure,
-- it, it's
-- not, yeah, all 3 million lines of it.
-- Uh,
-- 3 million isn't, I don't even know what it is now, I guessed.
-- Oh,
-- it's tens of millions. It's, um,
is it? Yeah,
-- I'm not surprised
-- if I hit, uh, let's see,
we got uh 2596 CV entries that match the phrase Linux kernel.
-- Uh
-- Whatever. That's no fun here. I can ask my phone.
Hey, Google, I'll say, ok, Google,
how many lines are in the Linux kernel?
According to
a
tech?
Shut up.
It says 13 million, 0, 15 million. Oh, wait 15 million lines of code in 2011.
Uh So it's probably more than that now.
-- So, I don't know. It's a lot, we'll just say that I
-- think it's 20 or 30
probably.
And that was 2011 was what, like seven internet lifetimes ago?
Well, and even if you got it down to like what would be used on a container host.
It still is
-- in the 5 to 10 million lines of code realm.
-- Uh
At least, at least. So. So anyway, I guess, uh the only advice you can get
people is patchier systems, which is terrible advice and una actionable.
And so in summary, we're doomed.
Well, I, I would say even more importantly, if you are going to use containers
again,
this isn't very helpful advice but start looking at trying to use them correctly.
And like this is a challenge I'm having, you know, with the CS A,
with our infrastructure,
I've at least very carefully now separated our state.
So although we're not using containers,
we are able to use containers because the
underlying application is just doing underlying application stuff.
It's actually there's no data there.
It's all in the back end database or S3 or whatever,
right? Like I can
actually transfer that application into a container
and not have to worry about there being some local
state that I care about like data storage or whatever.
Right. Right. And, and that's fair.
Well,
and the reason I did this is so that I could know I was properly backing everything up.
It had nothing to do with containers
-- and,
-- and that's fair.
But at the same time, man,
that's not really actionable advice for most people because
saying
again, you should, you should, you know, build your applications to
containers doesn't account for the fact that there's tons of currently deployed
applications that are let's face it never going to be updated.
Well, I mean there's, there's tricks you can do,
you can mount file systems within containers from underlying systems or whatever,
from a, you know, NFS or whatever.
Um So maybe this might be the evidence or the impetus you need to, you know,
get some time from your manager to, you know,
spend some time addressing technical debt
with any luck. Right.
-- Uh,
-- no, you won't because you're, you're busy patching.
Yeah, pretty much.
Oh, man. Although you know what actually is potentially good advice here is,
this is one of those instances where I think using a container service
can have immense value because you don't care
if someone else is running your containers.
Now, granted they're going to get shut down. Even if you don't want them to be
-- just given the, the current environment.
-- Not necessarily like with Google,
you know,
wrapping it in a VM, they, they're just like,
yeah, we don't care about this attack. It's, it's an on issue.
Yeah, that's, that's probably fair.
And I guess that's part of the beauty of it is if it's not your container,
ho you don't have to carry either.
The, the issue becomes if you don't want your application rebooted
and you, they're going to make you reboot
then, then it's your problem.
But yeah, for the most part, I mean,
this is part of the beauty of using like everything as a service I think is you can,
you can push a lot of the,
I guess risk and danger often to someone else.
Well,
more to the point you can push the risk and
danger off onto somebody else that's more competent than you.
I can't run a security operation center or
secure systems as well. As Amazon or Google or Microsoft can
even with a budget of a million dollars or $100 million
that's still less than the, you know, Amazon has custom silicon, you know,
the nitro chip in their new hosts.
Google has custom silicon, I believe Microsoft, I mean,
these guys are making custom add on, you know, watchdog, security chips.
-- Nobody else can do that.
-- Right. Well, in ignoring,
ignoring that
you have other work to do,
right. These guys have security people that, that is their only job.
I mean,
this is, this is one of the things II, I always tell people when they're asking about.
Oh, but you know, are these people a bunch of idiots?
It's like, well, they probably are but you have other work to do and they don't.
So even though they might not be the smartest cookies
in the pack like this is all they're doing.
So they have the potential to definitely do a
better job than you even if you're a genius.
Yeah.
Agreed.
So anyway,
that is that, I, I guess we can probably wrap this one up now. Put a ball on it. It's,
uh
for what it's worth.
My parting thoughts on this are,
I'm shocked it took this long for a flaw like this to happen
because, I mean, containers have been a big deal for what?
-- Probably 10 years now, I would
-- say closer.
Well, they've been a big deal for, I'd say more like five years.
They've been around a while.
But like this is,
I'm, I'm surprised this is the first one we've seen and
I'm sure we'll see another
but at the same time, like five years and only one, like super crazy escape flaw.
That's pretty solid.
Well,
the fear would be now is that people go looking for more of these and find a pile more.
Uh,
maybe I,
I feel like this is already a lucrative
enough security problem that people have been looking
and
I don't know how many more
people are going to find
just because it's, it's hard to find problems like this. And like this is
when you look at it, it's like, well, duh look how simple it was,
but the reality is actually finding it was quite difficult.
Well, I mean, by definition, some, I mean,
it was white hat guys, I assume they're white hats. They work for souza
found it.
Uh So, you know,
clearly other white hat hackers haven't found this and reported it because it,
-- well, by definition, it would have been dealt with by now,
-- right?
And
yes,
I would, I would point out
it was found by white hat or it was reported by white hats,
right?
It would,
it would not shock me if someone's exploit just got burnt this week,
right?
Because this is very simple. But anyway, we we shall not
speculate on zero day flaws. So,
all right, man, I guess. Thank you. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes,
you can use the P
OS S podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media,
-- Kurt. You have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.