-- It's December 10th. Everybody. Happy December 10th. Yeah,
-- so my
systems IP address is 182.168 0.86 dot something.
I'm actually just trying to pull it up but Josh wouldn't let me,
you knew this was coming.
So you use 192168.86.
Yeah, Google Google Wifi. 0.49. 0, I like 0.49 because that's seven squared.
That's a good number
and seven is the best prime as we've already covered.
It is
so
12.168 0.86 0.49 is my systems IP address.
So
-- now I'm
-- hacked. Oh no, you've leaked sensitive information on the internet.
Yeah, so the deal was
Apple's internal IP S leaked by its search bot
and guess what? Apple's internal IP addresses are
-- one
-- 92.168 0.1 dot ted,
-- the other
-- one,
the class A 10 dot
Or, you know, I would have also accepted. What is it? One
72.16.
-- That's the
-- worst, don't we already,
I've complained about this on too many occasions.
-- You
-- know
-- what I like that? One because nobody knows
-- the
-- worst one. It's the, everyone screws it up. Don't get me started anyways.
But, yeah, I'm like, oh, Apple's internal IP S and I'm like, oh,
what these are public?
No, it's 10, do whatever. I'm like, well,
yeah, those are,
every large company on the planet uses
-- 10.0 no, no,
-- no. Even better.
We were hosting a couple of servers out at, um,
a provider in Vancouver that was hooked up to tell us
and I did a trace route
and the trace route normally gets like two real
IP S like local switch then gateway and then like
it disappears into tell us' cloud
and then it like pops out into real IP space except
this time I did a trace route and it was like,
it was like, you know, 17 dot blah, blah, blah 17 dot blah, blah, blah 10 dot blah,
blah, blah 10 dot blah, blah blah.
I'm like, wait, what
that happens all the time. Yeah, exactly.
And they were routing the 10 dot So tell us used to use 10 dot star
for their
routing cloud and it just made me laugh because I'm like, well, who cares?
Like here's the thing if you know the IP address of a system and that is what
allows you to hack it.
-- They have no security.
-- Yeah, you suck. I agree completely.
You know, I'm not going to tell people where I live in the real world.
Because they're going to like order pizzas to my house.
Hey, if someone's willing to order me pizza, I'll tell you where I live.
I'm just saying,
-- but you're also expected to pay for it.
-- Well, no, no, you need to pay for it.
-- Send it to me for free. Oh, yeah,
-- in that case,
right. Can I put my address here?
-- Because I love
-- pizza.
We'll put Kurt's address in the
-- show notes.
-- Exactly.
So, like I love, you know, like, because I have like a gigabit feed so like
you could toss the bejesus out of my IP and it's probably fine. But, uh,
yeah, like these people were making all this kerfuffle about, oh,
Apple's internal web crawling bot leaked an internal IP address
but it's like a 10 dot whatever IP address.
Like, how does that help?
I, you know what, you know what it is though, I think there is a certain mindset
that is of, you should never give out any information of any sort about anything.
And I mean, I'm not going to say it's wrong,
but I think you also need to understand that there's certain things.
If it leaks out, it's really irrelevant and it's
who cares. And like internal IP S are one of those.
So I, I would agree and I,
I've dealt with ex-military people in a
previous job in the military information leakage
literally can kill.
And I'll be blunt,
a
-- web crawler search engine. Generally speaking, nobody's going to die.
-- I agree.
I think making a big deal about internal IP addresses doesn't matter.
I think leaking. For example, the operating system you're running is irrelevant.
There's, there's so many details that I, I will say.
-- Oh, Josh,
-- did you know I'm running Windows 10 on my desktop.
-- Yeah,
-- we talk about that a lot.
Right.
Right. But it, it doesn't matter. Right.
And now not giving, I wouldn't write it down on a list and say, oh,
here's everything I'm running in the IP addresses by any means.
But if it does get out, it doesn't really matter.
And I think insecurity, we're notorious for
trying, we, we basically treat everything equally when they're not.
And so we end up creating unnecessary emergencies.
Yes and no. Uh we do create everything equally and sometimes that is right.
So I've just been watching recently, a local lawyer who's doing
a series on police interrogations
and he points out that like
most people
can't decide or properly choose what is and is not safe to talk. Shut up, Siri.
Um Sorry, you better keep that
anyways.
Seriously.
My freaking watch is like I understand
Siri, stop.
So the point is this lawyer pointed out people during a police interrogation
cannot decide what is and is not important to talk about.
So you say on the advice of my counsel, I decline to answer that question
and that is the only safe answer,
right? You do not get to choose.
Oh, you're asking about the, the temperature today or what time it is?
Like, no, you're a squishy meat bag. Shut up.
Wait for your lawyer to show up and that's it.