Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 172
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, what's new Kurt?
-- Well,
-- reduce, reuse, recycle,
what are you reducing, reusing or recycling?
So, in classic terms, if you want to, you know, be a bit kinder to the environment,
number one strategy reduce, you know, like,
don't drive your car as much or maybe don't buy that, you know,
Hummer number three or whatever and then
use, you know, which in, in electronic terms is classic, right?
There's like, like, because let's face it right.
There's a lot of like five and 10 year
old computers out there that can still do something useful
for somebody if somebody that needs to browse the web
or whatever sort of or more to the point,
people that have old hardware that wants to talk to other
old hardware and they don't want to replace the whole system.
And so what Intel has done has been to remove a
whole pile of old software drivers off of their website.
Yeah, I read that, that,
that's kind of a nutty story to be perfectly honest.
Well, I mean, I get it because from a support point of view, it just,
it's increased support costs, not just in hosting it and providing it, but in,
you know,
keeping it curated and also dealing
with people who maybe accidentally download the
old drivers instead of the new drivers or vice versa or whatever.
But I suspect it's kind of more weasley in the sense of, you know,
if you can look at the old drivers for the old hardware, you can't use it.
Right. Right. And
we should probably clarify a bunch of this is. So
generally speaking, when you're using not open source operating systems,
you need drivers to make your stuff work.
And if you've ever used windows, which luckily I don't very often,
but you basically plug anything in.
And the first thing it will say is,
you know, we need to find your drivers and windows will look for certain drivers.
-- If you're lucky, you get that.
-- Right. Well, that is true.
Half the time it doesn't even recognize the hardware and you
got to give it the driver and then it's like,
00, what's that over there?
That is true. That is a very good point. And so
Intel
has historically and really every hardware manufacturer
that I can think of
-- has generally published drivers.
-- Well, the good ones, the legitimate ones.
Ok, that's fair.
But they generally publish drivers on the internet
and then you can go back later and download
some, like 15 year old driver for like the Scuzzy card you bought off ebay, whatever.
-- And then it basically works.
-- I've actually literally done that.
I've literally done that. I had some Scuzzy cards
that were like, it was like, it used an IBM chip set,
but it was on like a definitely not an IBM board because it was like under 200 bucks
and you could, like, flash them
into some L SI or something mode and get free
Nas to work with it with AJ, bought just a bunch of disks.
The longer the short of it is, is you could get crazy,
insanely high performance out of this $200 Scuzzy card with, uh, not scuzzy but sa a
controller card with like eight drives for like 200 bucks which, and you know,
your next
option is like 500 bucks,
right?
But anyways, yeah.
And so I guess part of the I'm going to make air quotes here.
The excuse is that these are mostly drivers for older
versions of Windows that are now end of life,
like Windows 98 Mexp
and older versions of Windows server like NT
and hm. Yeah, I kind of get it.
They are technically end of life and people shouldn't be using them.
-- But the reality is people are,
-- they sadly are.
And what's going to happen is people are going to type
the piece of hardware they need into Google with the word driver after it.
And they're going to end up on not
viruses.com
and they're going to end up mining Bitcoin.
Didn't you have a relative that ended up doing that for like a printer driver?
And that wasn't even like an out of date thing.
It was like, um, up to date, like they typed in what? Canon? Printer Driver X
-- and ended up in Russia somewhere or something. That,
-- that was my father And it took me
a long time to clean that mess up.
And actually he tried to buy a laptop last week and I made him
buy a chromebook because I basically said you can't screw this thing up,
you're going to buy it.
And we'll see, I have full confidence in his ability to break it,
-- but we're going to find out some
-- people have to touch.
He's one of them.
Yes.
Again, like II,
I actually know of places that still have like Windows 98 and me in production.
And it's actually not that bad because it's actually not connected to any network.
Like I don't even mean an intranet. Like it's just not connected to any network.
Like a great example, being a friend of mine had a $60,000 cell counting machine.
Like you literally put a Petri dish in this machine
and it counts the number of growth
in the Petri dish
and it talks arc net to a Windows 95 box.
And the option is they can replace it for like 100 grand or
there's still a place,
there's still actually a couple of places that make Arc Net cards,
like ISA Arc Net cards
because their Arc Net card died. And they're like, what do we do?
And I'm like, you buy a new cell counter and they're like, it's 100 grand.
I'm like, tap, tap, tap. Hey, there's these guys in Germany, Austria, Australia.
There's actually a couple of companies that are like, you know,
for four or 500 bucks, here's an Arc net card that is isa
with windows 95 drivers.
-- And I'm
-- like,
or you just go on ebay and buy a lot of 200 Arc net cards someone's selling for.
-- Yeah, exactly. And hopefully one of them works
-- $7 plus $54 in shipping.
But
funny story,
you buy those cards on ebay and you may or
-- may not get drivers and
-- that's a good point that,
that's different now.
So
you're not wrong.
-- This is this problem is a mess.
-- See, this is why now I obsessively download and keep
all the drivers and software that I install
on my machines because I've been bitten by this
before where I've literally had or I've had
the case where they have the modern drivers.
But for example,
I need like an earlier driver to get it bootstrap
like to literally to get like windows to install.
I need like an earlier driver to get windows installed onto the hardware
and then I can upgrade the driver.
I don't have windows 10, I have windows seven, right.
-- Windows, seven upgrades to Windows 10, that
-- end of life
-- in January. Like you got to get rid of that.
-- Yeah.
And you get a free upgrade to Windows 10,
which I did.
But the problem is I can't install windows seven on my modern living room machine.
I had to go through some horrific process to get it installed on that machine.
You know, with some
futzing around with drivers and stuff to get the, you know,
the hard drive recognized, you know, but once it's on and upgraded to Windows 10,
it's fine.
You know, that's the other thing. Just, there's that video of that guy upgrading.
What is it D OS one point? Oh, all the way up to uh Windows.
I think he starts at Windows 1.01
point upgrading it and it worked,
-- which was pretty cool.
-- It even kept most of the settings. So
there's,
yeah, I'm not going to give you tech support on the show.
But there, there's, there's things you can do to avoid this particular process.
But I mean, fundamentally last time I ran into something like this,
I just basically paid Microsoft for a new copy of Windows because it was cheaper
than whatever I was going to have to do to make it all work.
So anyway, the point of this
bizarre tangent
is the concept of planned obsolescence,
which is something Kurt and I talk about a lot.
I know we've talked about it on the show in the past a little bit,
but it's something I've been thinking about all weekend
long since you mentioned last week we should discuss.
This is basically,
is it ok to murder old things,
especially most likely in technology? Because let's face it.
My, my toaster, generally speaking, isn't going to become obsolete, for example.
Whereas the computer I have in the basement
there is a very high chance it won't work.
In fact, I used to have some X 86 machines, not X 8664.
And it reached a point where just literally running
anything on them had become so much work.
I was like, screw it and I got rid of them.
Well, on the flip side,
my mother has a 2011 laptop on Maca works
perfectly fine and it won't upgrade to Catalina,
you know, Mac Os 10.15.
Whereas my dad's newer desktop will. And so, I mean, no offense, but
that laptop will continue to do what my mother needs it for
for easily 10 or 20 more years if the hardware doesn't break.
-- But
-- here's the thing. So I, I get this and I'm, I think I'm ok with it.
I, I see there's two sides to this argument. There's the, you could say
Apple should support something forever, which I think is ridiculous.
Because, well, not necessarily forever,
but maybe we say some relatively long time frame.
Uh
Well, like your toaster, like, say 10 years,
I mean, because for example,
those smart TV s that come out and then get
like six months of support and then they're garbage.
You know, I will never buy a smart TV.
Uh You don't have a choice anymore.
If you're buying a TV, it's gonna have garbage on it. Actually. So funny story.
I, I recently bought a Samsung TV
and I bring it home and the first thing I did was I hooked
it up to the internet and I downloaded the update for it and it took
like three hours to update this stupid TV. I was, I couldn't believe it.
It was ridiculous.
Slow,
it updated itself and then I deleted all of its internet connections and it will
never ever talk to the internet again because I don't trust any of these people.
-- That's
-- basically my plan.
Right.
And there's, there's a youtube video,
I'll put in the show notes where this guy basically,
he, he put like a raspberry pie between his TV and the internet
and then he basically just like ran TCP dump on the raspberry pi and it is
-- bananas.
-- What he found. That's how they keep their costs down. Right.
-- Is, is through all this advertising and selling your personal data.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. Which is super annoying.
-- It's, it works for web browsers. It works for TV.
S, yeah, why not? And people think they're neat.
So, anyway, anyway,
ok.
So you're saying a computer manufacturer should
maintain their computers for 10 years?
Well, I, I don't know,
specifically 10 years because I think it should also vary because for example,
if I'm buying like an industrial piece of hardware that's like,
literally going into an industrial plant.
You know, I'm probably going to expect that to work for 20 or 30 years. And
conversely, I'm probably going to be willing to pay a bit more for it.
You know, if this thing is controlling my nuclear reactor or whatever.
What about, you know, computers and cars, right.
All the computer systems I've seen in cars
are garbage because they're immediately out of date
and like five years later they look absolutely
-- stone age
-- doesn't even take five years.
-- They usually look stone age by the time the car hits the show floor.
-- Yeah.
So I, I think part of it would be transparency of, you know,
how long will this device be supported for?
But I think in here the problem isn't,
it's not that Intel is having to support it or not.
They're doing something intentionally that
they don't have to like,
it's not like we're asking them to write new drivers for windows 10,
-- we're asking them not to throw out all the old stuff.
-- I do agree with that.
I think removing old drivers is super dodgy and I'm not a fan of that.
But I think that conversation is also slightly different from the conversation
of planned obsolescence because here is the example I will give you.
So
I buy a car.
I have a warranty period on my car
where after
three years or five years or 10 years or whatever,
I basically can't get it fixed for free depending upon what breaks.
And there's all kinds of, you know,
various legal ease around what does and doesn't count for the warranties.
And then after that, basically it's my problem to get it fixed.
And I can either, sometimes you could go to the dealership and they might fix it.
You might have to go to a mechanic.
But I bet you if you rolled in to a dealership with, let's say a car from the sixties,
they're going to say no way, get that thing out of here. We're not fixing it.
You know what?
I, I bet they would happily charge you whatever hourly rate they charge to fix it.
Actually, they might, they might charge you an astronomical.
I mean, getting parts might be a problem. But
the thing is, there's, there's no artificial
holding them back. They just have to find the parts.
There's no software, for example, that the right to repair with the tractors,
right?
All those farmers with those John Deere tractors
where they're like,
I just need to like diagnostically know which module to replace.
But because I'm not, you know, I don't, I'm not a John Deere tractor repair,
whatever.
I don't have the laptop that has the software that'll tell me, you know,
like your blank module or this part is worn out or whatever
and you need to, uh, you know, swap that out.
And so there's all that dodgy Russian software now, some other Middle Eastern or
European country
that
was the
most
comes
from.
Yeah,
I, I get, like, on the one hand,
I don't want the world to be full of really terrible old it gear,
especially if it's
to the internet too late.
But on the flip side, I mean, I remember staying at a hotel and it was in 1999
and the topic of their phone system came up and I'm like, oh, yeah.
Have you guys, you know, y2k, blah, blah, blah. Your phone
is like, no,
I'm like, oh, you know, you do know if it's going to work and I like, it's electro
mechanical. We're fine.
I'm like, yeah, you know what? Fair enough. You're not wrong.
I mean, it, because, you know,
it didn't have a lot of features like it didn't support voicemail or anything but,
you know,
-- it routed calls and
-- there's no bigger pet peeve of mine than when I go to my
hotel room and there's a red light blinking on the phone and it says you have a message
and I think I don't care.
I don't want the message and then I think I'm gonna listen
to this because it's gonna drive me insane just watching the light
and then it's always something stupid like an ad or they tell me, oh, you know,
you get to check out on Friday and it's like I know, shut up, leave me alone.
But whatever,
I've never understood the whole voicemail and phones in hotels,
-- especially now that we all have cell phones,
-- right?
Voicemail on all phones is terrible.
People who call me know there is zero purpose in
leaving me a voicemail because I'm not listening to it.
Yeah, just no,
-- but back to the planned
-- obsolescence. I mean,
planned obsolescence is one thing.
This is taking away a capability that existed and let's face it.
It's not like it costs until a lot of money to host these old files. Right.
-- This isn't costing them millions of dollars a year
-- maybe.
I mean, that, that's conjecture on our part.
We, we really don't know if they do or don't cost them any money to host,
but
you could make the argument in many different directions
that they should or shouldn't make them available.
But I think fundamentally removing these drivers is a,
probably a net negative for the universe.
Well, it's, I mean,
it's going to take something that previously is
kind of annoying and painful of like,
oh,
I've got to resurrect this windows 95 box
attached to some weird old hardware or whatever,
you know.
And ok, I I go to the, you know, the intel site,
download it, get it on a USB stick. Ok.
Get it on a slow enough USB stick that the Windows 95 machines.
USB one will actually talk to,
you know, all that kind of craziness.
But, you know, fundamentally you can get the driver, download it,
install it and you're on your way
now.
Yeah, you're going what?
You're gonna like,
look around dodgy websites and hopefully you're smart enough to remember
to send that file to virus total before you install it.
So here
is
my thinking on this matter,
this is new territory for us as a society,
we've historically not had this problem. We've had things
that you could say are end of life to where maybe the company goes out of business
or they just say we're not helping you with this product anymore.
I mean, like a great example is I have,
I have a lot of old video game systems in my basement,
right? Like it will pick on the Nes, the Nintendo entertainment system.
I literally have the Nintendo entertainment system I got in 19,
probably 8586 long time ago.
And Nintendo actually quite recently,
bizarrely enough said we're not fixing these anymore.
We're up until just a couple of years ago. I could have literally
mailed the unit into Nintendo and I'm sure
they would have charged me an astronomical fee.
See, and I would say that's a great example of a company doing the right thing. And
because I had one of those as a kid and I'm trying to think when they came up.
So that's at least 20 years of support right there.
I think that's for a consumer device. That is entirely reasonable.
I mean. Right. But I, I guarantee not every company works like that.
I mean, Nintendo is kind of special in a lot of ways, but I'm just gonna,
they're magic.
They are, they're, they're like, if, if Apple was awesome, they would be Nintendo.
-- So
-- anyway,
Apple with Nintendo build quality, that would be amazing.
Anyway, so
I don't think it's unreasonable for Nintendo to tell me we're not fixing your Nes.
And I don't think it would have been unreasonable
for them to tell me this in the nineties
because
that's ok.
But now we have this universe where we have these computers and
we have these devices that are a marriage between hardware and software
and sometimes services. Let's not even cross that bridge on this episode.
That's true. And yeah, I mean, that's a whole another story. Absolutely.
But if we just look at the hardware software perspective,
you could easily make an argument that like,
I have a 386 computer in my garage that I'm going to do some projects on.
I, I fished it out of a trash heap one day
and I was thinking it would be fun to have and the computer itself has no value. Right.
-- I need an operating system on that computer.
-- You say that? But I,
I'm guessing there's somebody out there that probably wouldn't mind having
386 in their spares pile to drive some industrial machinery,
-- but
-- they still need an operating system.
Right.
Well, they would hopefully have a backup of the one they're using. Right.
-- But
-- that's my point. Right. This machine
has no intrinsic value by itself.
Its value is derived from the software running on top of the hardware.
And that's a relationship we've never had before
as a society and we don't know what to do.
And you have two camps.
Basically,
you've got the one camp that says we shouldn't have all this planned obsolescence.
We need a way to keep this stuff alive and they'll say,
right to repair and running open source and whatever.
And that's,
that's awesome.
Now, I will say, I bet running Linux on a 386 today is probably not going to happen.
-- Uh
-- Depends. There's uh there are lightweight Linuxes for that stuff.
-- Actually,
-- this is, this is a project right here. Can I run Linux
on a 386? Actually, it might even be a 46. I don't know what it is.
It's old though, right? Can I run Linux on it? I don't know.
This is a project, I think.
Well, and by Linux, do you mean a modern Linux or are you going to go
Susan? You can go download Slackware 1.8
but that's no different, right.
Downloading the old version of Slackware I don't think is any different
then.
The, the problem with planned obsolescence of the old software I'm saying.
No, no, I want to see old hardware running new software. Right.
Because that's actually the,
the ideal situation here. I hear you typing in the background.
You're looking it up, aren't you?
Oh, there's, uh, you've actually got about a dozen choices.
What, man, I was hoping it'd be hard.
You know.
You know what the hardest part is gonna be is writing a freaking floppy disk.
Like I don't even know how I do that anymore.
Anyway. Anyway,
DD isn't the problem. I don't have floppies or a floppy drive.
Like I have no way to write a floppy.
Yeah, I see what you're saying.
I have no freaking
idea.
Anyway. Anyway,
actually, you can buy
-- like these uh floppy disks to USB converter
-- D
US missile command or whatever, end up using those.
Maybe where I can plug in like a USB drive and
it will make it look like a floppy disk to the,
but whatever, I'm, I'm off on if it's our tangent.
So you've got the perspective of people saying
like we should be able to keep this stuff alive forever.
And then you also have people that say, screw it, let it die, whatever.
And
I'm not going to say II, I see arguments on both sides of this. Right. I can understand
saying we should be able to use our hardware for a very long time because,
yeah, I mean, I have gear that there's nothing wrong with. I have a what?
Like 30 some year old Nintendo system in my basement that it works.
There's nothing wrong with it.
And
I mean, luckily there's no operating system on it.
A better example might be, I have a Nintendo switch
and someday there will be no support for that thing.
And so will I even be able to play some of the games I have on it
because a lot of them like to phone home and do things like that. Right?
-- I don't know. I don't know the answer. I lied
-- to you actually remember.
Well, I don't remember because I didn't care. Linux,
the Linux kernel dropped 386 support in like 2012.
So 46 and up only.
So you'd have to run some old version of Linux on it.
Ok?
But the point is there, if enough people cared,
it would still be there because people would take care of it.
But obviously people just don't.
And so there's always going to be some aging out of a lot of this old gear and that,
that is ok
in one way. Now, now I'm going to make it even more confusing for you.
So let's let's put this in the context of the electrical system
a
long time ago people had fuses in their houses
which were these little things you'd screw in.
Right.
-- Little piece of metal that would melt if it got too hot,
-- essentially. Right. Right.
And now we have breaker boxes.
Can you still have a fuse box? Like, is that even acceptable?
Yeah, I, the last place I lived had a bulldog breakers.
And, um, you can still, uh, the yacht industry still uses them
quite a lot. So you can actually still buy them.
Like, I can't buy them from Home Depot,
but I'm pretty sure ecall, uh,
that's like the major electrical supply place locally.
You know, they got like a warehouse full of fiber optics to everything.
Yeah. No, you can still buy those b,
like the, the fuses, the round fuses that you, like, screw in.
Interesting.
Yeah, like I said, like ships and stuff.
There's still a lot of industrial applications to use them.
I mean, well, look at car fuses, right?
Car fuses are still like a little two cent piece of metal
-- encased in plastic that you can see if it popped or not.
-- Yeah.
No, no, there's nothing wrong with fuses.
I'm just saying in a residential application
-- having fuses, dude,
-- you had knob and tube
wiring.
I know it was terrifying and I got it replaced
right away because I know how dangerous it is.
Yeah. And you can't, like, you can't,
I mean, if you, if you,
I actually kind of want to see what would happen if
you proposed building something new with that knob and tube wire.
You can't,
there's, there's electrical codes that say you can't.
And in fact,
it would not surprise me if you can't actually sell a house that has a fuse box in it.
Uh, you can sell it, but I'm pretty sure, like, you know,
if you ever got to get worked on, on it there, I think what it really boils down to is if,
you know, if like Home Depot or whatever doesn't stock it as normal, it's probably,
then it's too old for residential applications and you need to
replace it with stuff you can pick up at Home Depot,
-- which would mean a modern fuse box.
-- Here's my point of this.
They, they're called breaker boxes now, but here's my, here's my point is
when you have certain technologies they can become dangerous
and electrical is an easy one.
Gas is an easy one where there's lots of old gas equipment
that obviously you,
you're not supposed to have hooked up because it will either kill
you from carbon monoxide or it'll start a fire or whatever.
And
these things have real human safety concerns. So I understand it.
It's easy to say my house is full of knob and tube. Holy crap. Get that out now.
Whereas you could come back one day and be like this house is full of cat five.
Well, that sucks. Right.
Like who cares it's not, I don't dive full of Cat five which, uh,
plenum
rated versus non plenum
-- rated cable,
-- right? Ok.
Yes. Ok. I knew you were going to say that.
Well, it's funny because I actually just bought,
I bought some new category six cable and I decided what the heck YOLO.
I bought the cheapest 250 ft I could find on Amazon
and I'm going to put an end on, I'm just going to crimp a connector on each end and like,
you know, run some speed test stuff over it.
See what happens. But
I'm guessing even the cheapest category six cable
now will be totally fine for residential use.
So actually I was doing some research because I ended up,
I had to run a cable across my basement and no, you can still buy wire without plenum.
And,
but at the same time if it's one strand of wire,
you're, you're going to be ok.
Yeah.
No, it's when you have the rat's nest. That's right.
When you have, you know, thousands of cables, then the plenum is important.
-- So you don't die of asphyxiation if it lights on fire.
-- So yeah, to clear it. So plenum
rated cable, the plenum is the space above the hung false ceiling where the air,
you know, hotter, colder, whatever mixes.
And so Gle
rated cable doesn't give off toxic gas,
it just gives off the regular going to kill you slowly kind of gas not the,
I'm gonna kill you right away kind of gas.
And so, yeah, if you have an office fire with like traditional old cable, like, yeah,
that gas will kill you inside of a minute.
Right. Right. Right. Exactly.
So, so anyway,
man, we, we can help but the tangents today.
So anyway, the point is
computers are one of those things that generally
speaking don't have health and safety concerns,
I would say in general, in the past,
they didn't have these health and safety concerns.
But that has changed now, especially with the internet things and especially with
like computers on wheels, you know, self driving cars
or cars that have
computers that have a very strong component where
they can affect the steering and whatnot.
And, and I think that the,
the point is though kind of my long,
bizarre monologue I've had here for longer than I can remember now
is just the fact that we've historically not really had this problem,
especially not in technology and just generally speaking, not with any things
in general.
And so now this is a problem, we have to understand and we have to decide what it means.
And
I, to be honest, I have a strong suspicion
that
the government is going to be part of the answer.
And industry groups are going to be part of the answer
and consumer activity is going to be part of the answer.
-- I don't think it's going to be any one thing that
-- solves that, you know what
I'm going to go on a limb and say probably the
librarians will be the people you want to talk to here.
-- Well, librarians are always good. But why?
-- Well,
I run an industrial plant.
So probably I want to have somebody with, you know,
a librarian style skill set to ensure that
all the operational knowledge is documented and,
and we already do that right.
We've planned operation manuals and, you know,
don't turn on this machine and then this machine because you'll trip the breaker,
set the thing on fire.
Right?
But now, you know, let's make sure that we have spare parts and let's make sure
we not only have copies of that software but like backups
of those copies of software that we can get to.
Sure, you know, basically archival
of all the things we need to, you know,
keep this thing running and working because let's face it.
Right. Librarians, historically,
you know, they're
all about the preserving knowledge and ensuring we can still get
access to it and find it when we need it.
-- I don't
-- think you're wrong.
I need to think about this a little more, but I do feel like this is special
because old software
-- is problematic for different reasons than say old books are.
-- Oh, no, absolutely.
I'm just saying that that skill set though somewhat,
-- I can't think of anybody with a better, more relatable skill set
-- and Yes,
I think you might be right there.
But
I don't know, I'm thinking of
like, right now, what I do is, you know,
every piece of software I download and install on
my machines I keep a copy of because,
yeah, someday I might need to reinstall it or
whatever. And I've had software that, you know, where I prefer the older version.
I don't like the new version or, you know, something along those lines. Right.
I remember one piece of software they changed all the hot keys,
right. So, the interface, like, and I'm like, I'm not relearning this.
No,
-- I'm staying on the old version until I get rid of it.
-- Right.
I've, I've been there before. Yes.
And, um, I mean, I've made it a point to actually get rid of most of my old hardware.
I actually gave away like, a pallet full of computers about two years ago.
Yeah, I, I did the same and now sort of the oldest thing in my house or, you know,
I have a couple of macs and then like a Raspberry Pi four and whatnot.
But, um, as far as this,
I think what I find so offensive about this removal of the drivers
is that it just seems so unnecessary, like, sure it probably cost them
money to keep this thing online and keep it available.
But at the same time, the benefit,
you know, the amount of hours it saves and the number of viral infections.
It saves, you know, for these poor computers.
Unfortunately,
that's an external cost for Intel that they don't have to care about.
Right. Right. Exactly.
And let's face it. Even if they do this,
is anyone gonna stop buying Intel gear? Probably not, not because of this.
What's the thought?
What if they decided to monetize it and charge a bucket download?
Would we be more ok with that or less? Ok with that
than simply removing it?
Iii I think it would have the same effect because I think most people running
old stuff are probably running it because they're not looking to spend any money.
And so if you try to charge them,
they're going to just go back to Google and they're going
to Google for their driver and they're going to end up.
II, I think it would have the same effect.
I suspect you're right. I don't, I don't think it would be better.
I mean, from, from my perspective, I,
I'm sensitive to the fact that Intel's job is to make money.
They are not a public trust now at the same time,
like maybe freaking donate these things to the internet
archive or something and just put a website up.
That's like, hey, you need to find it. Go to these guys. Come on.
They would have loved to host this.
I'm sure they would, they, they have all kinds of cool stuff there.
But I don't know, man, this one is
I, I'm, I'm gonna say I'm not happy with Intel, but I understand, you know.
-- Well,
-- a close parallel is these companies that have their old manuals online.
Right.
Because, you know, I try to hold on to manuals for stuff I have,
which has really saved my butt sometimes
because it's literally like with the manual,
it's a 12th fix and without the manual it's like, oh, good Lord, what is, you know,
what is the brown wire?
Why is there like purple?
Are there supposed to be purple wires?
Right?
You know, but with the manual, it's kind of like, oh like this, you know,
this component,
whatever something failed or just reset it or here's how you reset it, you know.
And there are some companies I forget offhand but there were
a couple of companies that remember a few years ago,
they like just dumped all of their manuals online onto a website.
Like not
like it was like PDF scans of the manuals and you know what?
They were ugly and they were horrendous to read, but they were there.
And that's fair.
And I do love when people put old things somewhere for preservation purposes.
And even not from the perspective of I need this to do some work,
I think just from the archival perspective,
there's value to society and
this comes back to the librarian kind of conversation is there's
value to society as a whole to keep these things available,
not even to use as much as just it's part of our past and we're throwing it away.
Well, you get to see the progression in some cases, right. I mean, sure,
I get that.
There's also some clear distinctions in the market
between consumer devices and say industrial devices where,
you know, there's, there's that one Linux project where they're talking about,
you know, 50 year Linux,
like what happens when we want to install Linux on a device and then bury it
at the bottom of the ocean and it has to operate for 50 years without failing
because it, you know, it's controlling the pipe valve or something, right?
Or, you know, software in space.
You know, apart from, as far as I know, correct me if I'm wrong.
But the only time we've repaired a satellite really is the Hubble.
Have we really ever repaired another satellite?
Sort of
like, I mean, the Mars Rover, they did that magic software update.
-- When the thing hacked itself,
-- we've done software updates.
I don't believe humans have ever retrieved an orbiting spacecraft,
repaired it and then put it back into orbit.
I think the closest would be Apollo 12.
Well, no, the Hubble space missions.
Remember we went and fixed the Hubble and replaced the mirror and stuff a few times.
I think that's the only thing we, we've touched Hubble. I think what twice
there were humans went to it.
They, they basically pulled it onto the space shuttle did things.
The only other instance similar to that I can think of is on Apollo 12,
they landed near one of the NASA space probes
and they, like, walked over to it and took some parts back to earth.
And
for real,
that was more to see how the weather or something
because they were in,
they were on the moon for a couple of years and it was just kind of a research project.
But that's,
I'm not gonna lie. That's pretty freaking awesome.
So, anyway, I guess
it's time to finish this up.
And this has been, I feel like a rambly collection of nonsense, but I will,
I will give you the last word. But I guess my comment here is,
I don't have any answers because I don't think
we, we have any of this figured out yet.
I feel like it is one of our new problems
in society is to decide what does all this mean?
Yeah, I'm going to agree. I guess just, you know, pay real close attention and ask
awkward questions. Like, how long will I get software updates for this thing?
-- And
-- I guess also hoard software
because
you need it.
-- Email
-- it to yourself,
right?
Until emails obsolete. And what do we do then?
-- Uh, email will never be obsolete.
-- Oh, man, you heard it here.
Amos last words.
-- The only
-- push
protocol we have.
Yeah, probably. All right. Anyway, I'm calling it. Thank you. Kurt, thank you
for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes.
You can use the pound to as podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too, thanks
everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.