Was it today? Well, we don't know. No, it's, it's December 4th.
We can't say it came out today.
All right.
-- Anyway,
-- hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Seri and my partner thought crime draws brush shows.
Why
do you do a proper
or not?
It doesn't matter. It's all staying in. I'm going to do like no editing on this.
It's going to be a train wreck. It's lovely.
All right. Hiding from internet trackers door
-- before or are we hiding behind the door?
-- Yeah.
So this is part of the efs pen Optum
thing. So I clicked test your browser.
So the eff came up with a thing that essentially
there's like a ton of information your browser leaks that is specific to you.
And one of them that I loved was like, how much memory the system has.
And according to the eff cover your tracks,
I have eight gigs of ra M and like rest assured people I
have much more than eight gigs of ra M in my desktop.
Do, do you?
I do, I have 30 yeah,
I have 32 gigs because right now I'm sitting at chrome sitting at like 15 gigs of ra M.
Is that how much free ra M you have? Because Chrome has used all the other ra M or
uh
jeez. Chrome 100 and 30 no, actually, no, it's not too bad.
Chrome's only using 5.4 gigs of memory right now. Only
like I just don't care anymore. Like
all my systems are
at a minimum.
Internet tracking so well.
Well, not internet tracking. No, no fingerprinting.
It's the same thing.
Well, no, it's slightly different because tracking implies cookies and stuff.
And tracking is like, what's your screen resolution? What's your screen?
You know your color depth? How much memory do you have?
Which uh browser extensions do you have?
-- And the answer is between all of that, we know exactly who you are
-- right.
And, and so the point being that as you traverse the internet, you are leaving behind
digital fingerprints all over the place and there are companies
that are paid quite a lot of money for identifying the visitors to.
I mean, this is why when you do a search for like actually funny enough.
So, so my, my Children don't know this.
They're getting a VR headset for Christmas and I I
an Oculus Rift.
I set it up just to make sure it works.
And then now and, and I set this up on a Windows computer now on my phone,
I am getting Oculus ads all over the freaking place.
-- Oh, dude,
-- I did some searches, like, at various times I was like, researching,
you know, buying X for my house or whatever.
-- And then, yeah, blam just tons of ads for X.
-- They, they, that, this is how they do that.
And the best part is
I already bought X like, I'm, I'm never gonna buy X.
-- Sorry guys. Like, I can only buy so many, like, garage heaters.
-- I agree.
That drives me nuts when I buy something. And then
Amazon's like, oh,
I see you like refrigerators.
Here's my favorite Google has that thing where you can click the X in the end.
It's like this ad is inappropriate. This ad is spam.
This ad is deceitful or I'm not interested in this ad, but I, I wish there was like,
I already bought this. Don't advertise this to me because I already own one.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, that's like I, I have an Oculus now. I don't need another one.
Yes, you do.
I might, I'm gonna probably have fights.
But uh but yeah, looking through this,
we'll put a link in the show notes to cover your tracks.eff.org.
But it's, it's fascinating.
Like there's browser plugins, there's like time zone offset.
I'm like, oh, you know what time zone offset. Yeah, that narrows you
down
a
bunch. There is loads of information we leave behind.
-- We don't even realize
-- screen size and color depths system fonts
like there's, there's a whole pile of stuff and part of it is
you can't really
-- obfuscate it or, you know, really hide it.
-- Well. No, you can though.
This is the whole point of the EF F's tool.
-- But
-- by blocking it,
that adds to your fingerprint because the number of people that block, for example,
their screen resolution in depth is very small.
One person on the, uh, the hacker news thread pointed out.
Macs are good for this because Macs hardware, like all Macbook airs 2013, whatever,
they're all the same hardware,
that's it.
So I don't know that the solution is to go buy an
Apple hardware.
But
-- OK,
-- no, here's, here's the solution and here is how we're going to take this one out.
The eff link we're going to put in the show notes is for cover your tracks.
It's called and the eff has real actionable things you can do
and step one is education.
Right. That's what they do.
That this happens. Right. Right.
And that's obviously we're doing this and we're linking to the eff.
So go learn and then they have some, some actual things you can do
to make this problem better for yourself
and, and granted nothing is going to be 100%.
But
at the very least, I think awareness is the, the single biggest thing we can do.
You know,
I'm gonna say is the thing I've consistently seen is you
show people browsing the web without ads and they're like,
oh my God, that is so much better because
it is
so all I'm gonna, I'm gonna end this episode by saying
friends install ad blockers on friends computers.
And number two
-- give somebody to the eff they do good work.
-- Absolutely.
We will see you on December 5th.