-- Welcome to curtain Josh on 443.1 in the morning.
-- Why, why are you doing that?
-- That's not even funny
-- because we've got a soundboard now.
-- I, I
-- don't have a soundboard. I have
-- push the button.
-- All right, I will push the button.
There you go,
which will never be pushed again on this show.
So Kurt is impressed.
I got for Christmas,
I got a new microphone and then I bought one of those like little boxes you
plug the microphone into and then it plugs into the computer and all that jazz.
It's something called a Zoom
pod track P four.
The reason I got it is because I can take it like
on the road and you can record right on the device.
It has four inputs. Like it's a really cool little device.
But anyway, it has a sound pad so you can put sound effects in it,
which again, we will never be using ever again.
I'm sad now,
I'm, I'm sad now.
No, I'm not pushing the button
anyway.
-- Anyway,
-- at least what we're doing isn't as stupid as what Norton did.
Well, that's a very nice transition.
Come
on.
I mean, we could have, I could have gone with evil, but it's not evil.
It's just too banal to be evil. It's just stupid.
It's very stupid
before we move on. I must say, I know you watch Linus Tech Tips on youtube
and
so the his, his transitions are worse than what you just did. Typically speaking
and my kids and their friends, like, I guess it's become a thing in like the,
the geeky kid universe or whatever we want to call it
where they literally talk about bad transitions
on a regular basis because of Linus.
He's, he's so bad. It's good.
-- I know
-- it's awesome. I love it. Anyway. Anyway. Alright.
So tell us what Norton's done first and then we'll explain.
I haven't read all the details but it seems to boil down to.
Well, I'll just read the tweet,
why not Norton is installing a Cryptocurrency miner called Norton crypto
and crypto exe on end user systems without so much
as a dialogue during the install of its security product.
But um
I mean, that's,
-- that's like I don't know what else to say other than we don't
-- need a soundboard,
you can be the soundboard
anyway.
So here's what I've read so far at the time of recording which I'm sure this will
change and I'm sure they'll say it was the interns fault or something at some point.
But
no,
it's on the, it's on their website community dot Or
-- no
-- it's on their website.
But I think they, I,
I suspect they're going to get a lot
of pushback because this is so monumentally stupid.
But it sounds like what happens is when you install the new version of Norton
-- 360
-- it auto,
whatever, whatever. So you, you, you get Norton, right?
It installs an Ethereum Cryptocurrency miner as part of it.
They claim they don't turn it on by default and you have to opt in
according to their website.
But fundamentally what it sounds like Norton has done
is they have created their own Ethereum mining pool.
Then all of their users, they want to help them mine, Ethereum
and then the users get, let's say 99% of what they mine and Norton gets 1%.
That's how that would work.
Yeah.
And it's, it's, it's basically one of those classic.
I mean, because people probably don't remember the early OTs where it was like,
literally.
And I'm just gonna read it off on our website. Turn your P CS idle time into cash.
I'll give you a hint.
-- There's no good way to properly monetize an idol. PC. No.
-- Right. Right.
You're gonna spend more money in electricity than you're going to make an Ethereum.
Just that's how it works.
I mean, this is why when you look at current crypto
mining farms,
they're usually near a power source so they can buy really
cheap power and they're ridiculously huge because you have to be,
uh, actually it's not that they're near a power source.
Typically they're near
either they stealing power.
-- Well,
-- that's true that
happens or they do some dodgy
deal to get power
at effectively below cost.
Like there was one here in Alberta that wasn't registered
and it was like one or two shipping containers just making a howling noise.
And it was by an old natural gas plant that had been decommissioned
because it was no longer viable and they kind of restarted it.
And so, you know, the neighbors complained about the noise because it's just like,
literally, do you want to know what 10,000 PC fan sounds like?
Well, before people found out.
Yeah, it officially says that it's, you have to turn on Norton crypto,
but I suspect Norton crypto.
I'm guessing it's not telling you
all the details of what's going on and here's more to the point.
I'll be blunt and,
and this is official like this isn't my internal
guidance with the people I work with for Windows
use Windows Defender because it does the least amount
of damage to the system of an antivirus.
For Mac Os don't run one. And also for Linux
don't run one
and I've never run antivirus on a Mac in. Well, it's over 10 years at this point.
I don't understand how anti
or how viruses are a problem on a modern Mac.
If like, unless you're installing some,
like maybe you're getting your software off limewire still.
Right. I don't know that's antivirus.
And, and then the real thing is just, you know,
use a proper email provider like gmail
or something that actually filters out viruses
and use a proper web browser
with an ad blocker.
And that ad blocker
will
give you a much better internet experience.
Well, sure.
And it will basically block all the drive by ads, viruses.
You're not wrong.
But I don't want to talk about how to protect a system with antivirus because I think,
well, this is just for those people that are like, oh,
but you have to have some antivirus and Norton is good.
-- It's like, no, no, you don't.
-- Here's the thing I would say on this topic is
almost everything around the malware universe is opinion for the most part,
I've yet to find like good research that says if you run antivirus,
this is what happens if you don't.
This is what happens.
And here are the numbers explaining that because a lot of people, like,
you don't run antivirus and have had no problems and I know people that have it on Mac,
they have endpoint protection and they've had terrible problems and you're right.
Like, what have you done? I don't know. But it happens.
But anyway, the point is
Norton is installing a crypto miner that I guarantee
will lose money for the people using it.
And I guarantee they're going to make some money off of other people's computers.
But I think the, the most important part of this,
the thing that drives me the most crazy is that
if you think about the environmental impact of Cryptocurrency mining as it is,
and if you're using specialized hardware, you're talking about
probably
1 to 2% of the electricity. A general CPU is going to use.
So if all of Norton's users turn this thing on
the carbon footprint of this is going to be astronomical.
Uh So what's interesting is they require you to have a
graphics card with a minimum of six gigs of ra M.
So they, they're only doing it on systems that have a proper video card.
-- It's
-- still gonna be terrible, man, because
it's absolutely,
the return on investment is going to be bad. The electricity use is going to be bad.
And my guess is Norton is going to make, what, thousands of dollars maybe off.
I mean, I just, I don't see it being a viable business model.
-- I
-- think the reality is, it's, it's so
how do you monetize stuff on the internet?
And the classic way is you sell things to people and,
but that's actually really hard.
You have to have something people want or you have to trick them into buying it,
which I've been tricked into buying garbage on like Amazon, you know,
where it's described as one thing and then it arrives and it's like, well,
this is garbage
who hasn't
the second thing is a,
of course, which Google is in that trap of, you know,
trying to basically sell micro attention payments.
I mean, most of the big internet companies are. You've got what? Facebook Google?
Because it's one heck of a walled mode, like once you become a dominant player,
nobody else like
can assail you.
And then
the third and final one that especially Attackers
love is this whole Cryptocurrency mining thing.
So,
you know, we we we were increasingly seeing, it was funny as I was leaving Red Hat,
you know, the pattern used to be people broke into systemss to,
for example, send email and spam,
you know, or
to literally use it to provide web hosting for dodgy web things
-- and it was moving to, you know, installing Cryptocurrency miners.
-- Yeah.
Well, I mean, look at, look at log for J
most of the log for J attacks.
I've seen going on in the wild that aren't researchers,
which I think is most of the traffic now, but they were installing crypto miners.
What's the easiest most reliable way to monetize your attack?
It is now now I I want to clarify something else because I've
talked to people and there's been confusion about this in the past.
So one of the challenges to mining Cryptocurrency now is
so a long time ago, you could run like a Bitcoin miner
and you'd get your reward
occasionally, right?
These days, mining something like Ethereum or Bitcoin,
you would have to mine for thousands of years on one computer
to maybe get a
-- payout.
-- Right. Statistically it's, it's so close to zero.
Right.
It's statistically zero.
And so what happens is you have this concept called pooled Mining.
And so you have lots of computers
all pooling their resources together. Right.
And then you can maybe mine one coin if you have, you know,
thousands or tens of thousands.
-- So, that's what most of these
-- Cryptocurrency.
-- You mean mine? One block, one.
-- Yeah. One block, sorry. Not one coin.
Well, it's kind of
un the idea, right? All these, all these people pool the resources
and there are public pools which I know like way
back in the day I participated in some for Bitcoin.
And so basically they say, all right,
the amount of work you put in
is proportional to the reward you get.
So if you, if you're 1% of the mining pool,
when they mine say
100 coins,
you get one of whatever coin it might be, right?
And so this is because one of the, one of the points of confusion I think is
just running a miner on a system
like that individual system isn't going to mine coins, right?
They're going to pull all the resources together
and then they're going to mine collectively.
Like the phrase you'd have to be astronomically lucky
is what comes to mind.
-- Well,
-- so here's part of the, here's one of the tricks though
is when you're talking about something like Cryptocurrency mining.
It's not about luck. It turns into statisticss.
Right. Because any, any, you can have luck over a very, like an individual event.
But when you're doing something, 1000 or 10,000 or 100,000 times be, you know,
the number of computers in the pool
is not luck anymore. It's just statistics
and I'm going to point out the current hash rate.
So there was the big dip in July when China banned it.
But the current hash rate is back up to like 100 and 80
uh Tara
hashes per
Bitcoin
for Bitcoin.
-- And, and
-- it should also be said that the reason Norton is mining Ethereum
is because you can still mine Ethereum. My graphics cards,
Bitcoin can only be mined on specialized hardware now.
Well, it's, it's
what is it sha 256
shot 256. And these devices are doing
obscene numbers of hashes per second and shot 256 is really fast.
Whereas the Ethereum algorithm was designed to be harder.
And I remember there was a time when the Ethereum people said, oh,
this algorithm will never be workable in a graphics card.
And of course it is which everyone was like, yeah challenge accepted.
But
there, I mean, and,
and there are other coins that are purposely
not applicable to like mining in graphics cards,
for example, because graphics cards have lots of cores.
And so you can mine more things and, and whatever.
-- And
-- then there's also the proof of storage, proof of proof of work is not the only
solution, proof of stake, you know,
which is theorem is moving to and so on and so forth.
OK. OK. I'm gonna, I'm gonna put my foot in my mouth and say,
I don't think Ethereum is ever gonna move
to proof of stake.
-- I, I don't think it'll happen.
-- I'm not going to strongly disagree with you
and I keep a close eye on these things.
It's just,
yeah, they were supposed to have accomplished this one or two years ago.
And it's just,
I think the challenge is the people who've invested in
the hardware
that investment becomes less valuable.
I mean, that's just the reality.
Well, and to segue.
So, in, in, in this whole uh Cryptocurrency space,
it's what's fascinating to me is there's, there's basically three
key players
that really matter.
There's the people that hold a whole bunch of coin that are uh in past,
they would have been the Whales and now it's um well, corporations,
whales and institutional investors and whatnot.
Uh Number two is the minors
and number three is the devs.
And basically, if you're not in one of those three groups, you can,
you can just go away
like you don't matter.
You have no say you have no like you, you have nothing to offer to put it bluntly.
And
the, the Devs have
in many cases a lot more power than they should.
Yes.
Good. You're segueing for me into the next thing I want to talk about.
-- That's exciting.
-- And what's interesting is so, and the miners have a lot more
power than they should, but not as much as they would like.
Because ultimately, the devs,
-- how do I put this? The devs are usually smarter than the miners.
-- Uh It's complicated.
A lot of the miners are just running mines.
They don't have the talent to actually understand like
what's going on at a very deep level,
right there. A lot of them are kind of get rich quick artists.
Like if you watch the youtube documentaries on them,
a lot of them, like because the way they're building these things and the, you know,
it's pretty clear that they're not super technical and sophisticated
and you don't have to be right
because it's the wild West
or it was, it's, it's settling down now.
Um But the Devs have a lot of power because
uh they can, yeah,
they can roll out updates and changes
that um very fundamentally change the landscape.
OK.
Now, on the topic of Devs having a lot of power, which in theory,
they don't because the whole idea behind all this Cryptocurrency,
right was consensus and all this.
But
so I'm going to start by reading a tweet
and then we're going to transition into that.
I've been hacked
all my apes gone Oh
-- yeah, this
-- one
now now so
-- no, but
-- you got to read the reply to that tweet. It's even better.
What was that? Which reply? There's like
-- the
-- reply that was,
can you please change your profile picture since
you don't technically own that picture anymore?
That
one?
Ok. I want to explain what's
this is really funny.
I'm sorry, I shouldn't laugh. That's I'm sorry, this is like it.
No, no, there, there's an important part of it.
I,
I literally don't care about the NFT and what they're
worth and the value and some people will say it's,
it's too high.
It, whatever. I don't care. That's not the point. Pet rocks.
I, I agree. I agree. Look, someone thought this was a good idea.
People are buying it whatever.
Now,
here's what makes it so interesting though. So I kind of to fill you in there is this
NFT market where these things,
they're called board apes and they're just pictures of monkeys and they're worth
obscene amounts of money now, like
millions of dollars
in
aggregate
-- the board ape, yacht club, right?
-- Whatever.
So
the point is though.
So this person had a bunch of these apes which they
bought obviously before they were worth millions because I mean,
it reminds me of the art market where things go up for seemingly no reason and every
like, I don't get it but whatever,
-- money
-- laundering
straight up like there's
this how the CIA invented, like modern art,
we're gonna get murdered.
If we go down that path, we're just going to leave it be right.
-- You're gonna
-- fall out a window.
That's right.
I accidentally hit myself in the back of the head with a hammer 16 times.
But
so the thing is this, these apes got stolen
from, I think it was a phishing scam
and, and whatever.
Right, like that happens, this was a, a valuable item this person had,
it was taken away from them.
It was a theft. Now in the Cryptocurrency universe,
if someone steals your stuff like this, it should be gone
except
the people who run the NFT marketplace,
they, they froze
the NFTS, the Apes like what
that's literally not supposed to happen.
Ok. So if I steal your wallet,
I now have control of those coins nfts whatever
crypto
tokens. But for example,
a large exchange can blacklist those tokens and not
handle them.
And the funny thing is the same thing used to happen with physical cash, right?
People forget physical cash has serial numbers.
That's right. And
for example, when you were paying a kidnapping,
they would photograph every bill and send that list of numbers to all the banks.
That's
right.
Yep.
Right. And obviously that's not going to work like a physical scale because,
well, you'd have such a huge list of, you know,
these dollar bills were involved in crime.
So don't accept them.
But with technology with electronic stuff that
absolutely is very easy to implement.
And this is also for,
for anyone who's seen in the movies they talk about small unmarked bills.
That's what this is supposed to be, is untraceable cash.
Well, it's not untraceable. It's too much effort to trace.
That's,
and that's, that's, and that works right. Like it's, you know,
the cops can't spend $10 million tracing $50.
Well, not anymore. Now it costs like a nickel Computers. So, but anyway, go on.
So anyways, yeah, I mean, that's the thing. We all, all these places,
you know, the whole crypto
bros.
And I'll use that term. It's derogatory. And I mean, it,
the crypto bros thing of like, you know, the, like your, your keys, your wallet
cool until like, yeah, something goes wrong.
You delete them accidentally or it gets stolen.
But the reality is no, your keys, your wallet. But
you, you still have to find exchanges willing to traffic in your stuff
and you can very easily get your stuff blacklisted.
Well, and I mean, the other thing I think is so someone steals a painting
in the real world. Right.
There's, I know there's a handful of paintings that are still like,
being looked for.
Like if someone steals a painting, you can't show up at an auction house and be like,
oh, here I'd like to sell my painting, they're gonna be like,
you literally stole that.
Like you can't sell this
or no, no or it's, it's probably a fake because the real one was stolen.
-- Right.
-- That could be too. And in the case of something
like these NFT Apes,
there's a very small number of them,
like who's going to buy an obviously stolen? Ape.
Well,
and what's interesting is so one argument
for stolen art is that somebody can commission
a piece of art to be stolen so they can possess it and look at
it. Right. There's, there's a million heist movies with that trope.
But with NFTS, like, I think it's to quote Keanu Reeves, like, do you mean that thing?
I can just right click on and say
-- that's
-- right.
So, you know, like, if, if you want to go look at an NFT,
-- well, you, yeah, it's digital. You know
-- what makes it really funny though too?
Is there some people who I don't think understand that there's
a,
uh, death vegetable, one of the CDC people
was picking on someone at one point where he,
he changed his profile pic to someone's NFT.
And then the person was accusing him of stealing the NFT.
And it was really funny because the death Veggie was
going along with it and pretending like he'd stolen it.
And the person clearly had no idea what was going on.
And part of me was like, this is really funny and part of me is like,
please stop picking on this
person.
And that's the thing like crypto is hard.
Crypto tokens and currency are even harder because
so like uh the private key is not exposed but the public key is exposed.
Sure, that kind of makes sense for Bitcoin and Ethereum.
But with NFTS, the dirty secret is
the
object. The NFT is typically not on chain.
It is just like a JPEG floating around the internet somewhere.
And then there's this like piece of metadata that says, you know,
Kurt actually owns this file with this Shaw 512 sum.
But
well, I I've even written articles on this 20 years ago.
You remember we had for a brief period,
there was software that was designed to control
access to files so that you could send a file to somebody.
And for example, they could only print it but not modify it or save it.
-- Uh Those
-- still exist, I think you could get PDF S that work like that.
You can generally break them. But
yes, well, PDF S and, and there's,
there's actual like software where you have to download and install it and then it,
you know, it tries to, you know, have this magic box that prevents shenanigans.
But fundamentally people can, you know,
retype stuff in or point a camera at the screen.
Like that's one thing I have to do with my son.
He, he likes to take screenshots of stuff in Netflix on the ipad,
which has like copy protection.
So it just takes a black screenshot. So, well, he, he has an iphone,
he's breaking the law. Kurt, your son is a criminal.
You know, he just,
he likes to have the title cards of the stuff he likes
to watch because it helps him communicate what he wants to see.
Right. Right. Right.
So, anyways without getting into an argument about, you know,
making things more accessible.
The point is,
I think a lot of people seriously think NFTS somehow give you magic.
I'm gonna use this word carefully control over that NFT
and it does not give you control over that NFT.
It gives you a record of ownership within and I don't even
know what to call it a name space within an organization.
Like
to put it simply if I choose not to really rec like
I have to recognize yacht club's authority
to then take those NFTS seriously.
And I suspect that's actually where the NFT market is going to go
is to this sort of model of
like this is a Gucci NFT. Whereas this is like a Walmart NFT.
I mean, maybe, you know, there will be these higher end NFT organizations that have,
you know, like certificates.
Remember back in the day when you know that the the certificate makers were like, oh,
we charge more for our certificate because our
web certificates are better and it's like they're not
what
-- I
-- mean,
it was just as trusted as this other cheap one.
Well, they, they might have been, they might not have been,
-- but it didn't matter at the end of the day,
-- you know, and this is the exact same market,
-- like basically web certificates are NFT si
-- mean, kind of,
I want to tie this all together
now that we're coming to the end because I think you kind
of brought up an interesting point just now where you mentioned,
people don't know what this stuff is.
And I think this is true from the Norton perspective, from the NFT perspective,
from the perspective of a guy who got his ape stolen, which is still like, I'm sorry,
I keep laughing in my head every time I say that because it's just, it is very,
I feel very bad for this person because they, they genuinely lost a valuable item.
But there's a lot of misunderstanding.
My suspicion is the Norton leadership doesn't really understand what's going on.
I think normal people don't understand NFT SI think there's tons of confusion.
And I think what happens
is when you have these environments
that are ripe with confusion
and, and quite often the information is impossible to,
to figure out because there's so much of it on, on every side of the equation,
you end up with scammers,
right? Because they know they can take advantage of confusion.
They know they can do like pump and dump. Actually, I just listened to uh uh Vice.
Vice has a motherboard podcast called Cyber.
And this morning there was an episode, they talked about,
remember when the people tried to buy the constitution,
but through the Ethereum, smart contracts,
I forget, I forget what they call it. It has some fancy name,
but basically what ends up happening is it doesn't happen.
Most people can't actually get their Ethereum
back because there's all these high fees on
it and the amount of Ethereum they put in was less than the fees.
And so they literally planned on a pump and dump scam
to make their coins, their, their people
coins, they were called worth more. So they could like, not lose money.
I mean,
what? Well, dude, if all my money is invested in like Brix,
I'm for sure when Brix
starts to crumble, I'm going to be like, no, no, no things are fine.
And by the way, I have some bri
X stock to sell you.
Yeah, I mean, it,
-- it's like the story of humanity, I guess is I
-- have something really valuable here.
You want
-- it.
-- There's always,
there's a small number of people who if presented with the opportunity will take
advantage of another person even if it ends in that other person's demise.
-- Absolutely.
-- I mean, and
it makes me sad, but this is, I guess that's part of it too. None of this is new.
There have been grifters, there have been con artists, you know,
snake oil salesmen, carpet baggers, the
Cryptocurrency space. Everybody's like, oh, what about this new thing?
And I'm like,
yeah, we did that in the.com boom, like 20 years ago. Like we did exactly that thing.
But it was like with cat litter instead of, you know, crypto tokens.
Right.
Like,
you know.
Yeah,
I, I don't even know what to say.
-- Sometimes it's
-- probably don't invest in things you don't understand.
But then the problem is a lot of people think they understand these things and, well,
it turns out they don't.
Well, you, yes. Yes.
And this is one of the challenges is there's the fear of
missing out people who want to get in right away because this,
someone said this is valuable.
I, I'll never forget there was, I knew a guy who is always one of those,
this, this one thing like this is it. We're all gonna get rich. If we do this,
I'll never forget. He calls the,
he calls the house.
I was living in looking for a, a friend of ours who was a, he was a lawyer,
he went to college at my university and then he graduated and became a lawyer.
And he's like, oh, I'm looking for this guy.
Like I'll let him know when I see him next.
I saw him at a bar a couple of days and I'm like, oh, so and so is looking for you.
And he looked at me and said,
I would rather throw my money into the street than give any of it to him.
And I'll never forget just how serious and, and blunt he was about it. It's like, oh,
I get it, you know,
you know, anytime this person calls you,
it's, it's a complete waste.
And so you get some of that,
you have people who think they know what's going on and they maybe don't,
maybe they can confused, maybe they were lied to.
I mean, it could be anything.
Well,
there's also if you hop on the bandwagon soon enough and get in on that ground floor.
Yeah, you can
put your money
in.
I don't think that's true though.
My suspicion is the people who make a lot of money on this kind of stuff.
They know how it works.
They know how to talk about it in a way that's confusing
and you know what I mean? Like they're getting in
well before any of these other people, they know what they're doing.
So, a perfect example of this is,
and I need to assign a GSD for this because it's like a new,
it's, it's like a combination of scam and technical issue.
We'll put a link to the Tweet where the person explains it better than I can.
But basically
a few hours ago, a promising token called Dollar Sign Year was air dropped.
So airdrop means literally they send these tokens out free to people
supposedly because they like somehow help the token come to be or
whatever
anyways.
It was set up as a year in review of
your Ethereum transaction history less than an hour ago,
that turned into a painful experience for buyers of the token.
Here's how they pulled the rug in under six hours and
the, the basic long and the short of days you got this year token
and then
to kind of really exploit it, you had to buy
another Cryptocurrency that wasn't very liquid and it was through
a smart contract that had some shenanigans in it.
So basically this contract started out unverified, like all Ethereum contracts.
Then it got flipped to verified people basically looked at it, quasi,
audited it and said that looks fine.
Yeah. And it, there was a, there was an issue in it
that was intentional. A back door basically.
And so essentially they locked up all the money
sent to this contract and then liquidated it and,
and took the money and ran.
Wow.
And
you know,
this scam,
uh probably took weeks to set up and plan
for
six hours to execute
and
like it's gone now,
I mean, this is one of my complaints about Ethereum smart contracts.
The Ethereum smart contract language is turning complete
-- well and it's not only is it turn complete but it's not well understood.
-- No, I
know.
And so the ability to hide backdoors in it or even just accidentally put bugs in it is
it's, it's too difficult
and there's no way you can when, when
a, when a computer language is turned complete,
we currently lack the ability to do formal verification on that language.
Well, see, I think it's worse in a way because the theory contracts tend to be short.
People tend to think that they actually understand them
and then say, yeah, this looks good to me, you know, seal of approval and
you can have something very simple with a very subtle, very bad flaw.
No, I, I agree.
And I've read horror stories of people who've made subtle mistakes that
vanish tons of Ethereum because they, they,
it was like off by one type errors and stuff in their smart contract.
It's, it's, it's fascinating
and then worse, you have, you know, like the Obfuscated Sea Contest where
I love how there's always sort of two types
of general entries to the Obfuscated Sea Contest.
There's the ones that look like the line noise and you're like, how,
you know, how, how does this work? Right?
Like literally, you look at it and it's like this, this is, this is line noise,
you know,
and then there's the ones where it's like,
no, that's a,
that's a perfectly normal looking implementation of Hello world in seven lines
and, and then it like eats your computer or, you know, play the star
-- spangled banner
-- also more impressively. There's the underhanded C program
that
I was thinking of,
but the Obfuscated is good to be the underhanded was David Wheeler pointed me
where
it, it, this,
this is code that looks like it does one thing and
you can make it do a completely different thing and it is
amazing. But again, this is c is turning complete c can do literally anything
but
c at least we theoretically have a history of it and understanding of it.
E thee and solidity is pretty new
and there's very few experts in it.
Yeah. Yeah. Anyway, we should,
we should call this before we, we go down this rat hole.
I think that's what the problem is, is who are the experts in the crypto space?
And the answer is like, I don't know.
And I track this space and there's,
there's definitely people that are knowledgeable
but some of them I'm definitely suspicious of because they're, you know,
like Bitcoin or Ethereum maximalist.
So their, their motives are
little bit dodgy.
-- Well, I mean, look,
-- this is, here's how I want to end this.
What you just described is exactly what the banking system looked like 100 years ago
where there were tons of dodgy people, there were tons of people doing crazy things
and it had to be regulated.
And this is the thing I think about
the Cryptocurrency space is everyone always talks about,
oh, it's deregulated.
We can do whatever we want.
The government can't stop us.
If a large world government decides to crack down on crypto,
they're gonna do it and there's nothing you can do about it
because the places that won't like
as soon as uh like Europe or the United States or China
says no more crypto,
the price is going to crash and it's going to
become useless because you can't do anything with it.
And that's just the reality of it,
the black market. But yeah, basically,
yeah, but I mean, even with a black market, the value is going to be so low,
it's not going to be that useful. Right?
I
mean, that's just the reality of it. That that's how this stuff works.
I'm actually more worried about Bitcoin's deflationary
spiral that's built into the protocol.
That's another story. But again, the developers can fix that if they want to.
I don't know,
I
don't know the whole thing. I just,
here's what I keep coming down to.
What's something truly useful I can do with cryptocurrencies and people are like,
oh, you can buy stuff in like countries without paying fees and it's kind of like,
yeah,
kind of sort of, but not really.
I know.
Don't answer that question. We'll end it there because
we all know the answer. All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to over it's our security podcast.com.
And if the show know Susie Pound Os S podcast, hashtag hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.