Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner and having to change all their,
I can't say that word on the podcast. Passwords.
I'm seriously, I want like, I actually have a to do item now.
That's gonna take probably five hours.
I've been changing passwords for over a week now.
So the title of the episode is going to be last pass. Ducked up.
-- Oh, we can use the word duck. Right. Right. Autocorrect.
-- Yes, we can say duct
because that's what your autocorrect sent me last night.
Oh, I just got it because there was this one youtuber that made a,
he made a quack noise every time
I just got it. Oh my God. I am not that. Wow.
How did I miss that?
It's, it's one of my favorite auto. Corrects.
And I think,
I think adding duck to a sentence is vastly funnier now than the actual bad words.
So anyway,
we're gonna talk about last pass today, but I want to frame this.
I want to be very specific.
So there has been an enormous amount of writing
about last pass over the last couple of weeks.
Uh, if anyone who has listened to the podcast for any period of time
is that Kurt and I were, were last past customers,
past dance in the past and we recommended it
to people who'll rehash some of what happened.
What I really want to do is talk about how to get out of this
because everyone's complaining about what happened and I don't see a lot of, ok,
-- like they ducked up what
-- now?
And they, they not just ducked up,
but they ducked up bigly because here I want to read you something.
Ok. So this is from lastpass.com. Why do we need a password vault?
Unfortunately,
security breaches are becoming more and more common and it's almost impossible
to keep your information safe without the help of an online vault,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. How secure is the Lastpass vault at last pass?
Security is our number one priority with local only encryption.
Your data is encrypted and decrypted at the device level data storage
vault kept secret even from last pass your master password.
And the keys used to encrypt and decrypt data are never
sent to Lastpass server and are never accessible by Lastpass.
Ok. Cool
benefits of the last pass vault, secure storage, blah, blah, blah.
Now, what do they encrypt in the vault? Everything? Right?
Obviously, from reading this,
it
turns out no, they don't and see. And
I,
I mean, I was the last pass
customer both personally and professionally,
like at a corporate level for several years.
And I always assumed
that everything was encrypted user names.
URL S,
the passwords, everything. Because,
well, why the hell else would you do it any other way?
So, I was a personal, last past customer for years and a professional, you know,
corporate customer for years.
And I just always had assumed that
an encrypted vault meant an encrypted vault
like that everything was encrypted user names,
passwords
URL S the whole nine yards, like essentially like like this encryption.
When you know, when you encrypt a hard drive, you encrypt the hard drive,
not just like the file contents, but like also the file name,
meta data and everything, right?
And that
I have to say was I think this is actually
a big area where last pass ducked up and continues
to duck up by not making it clear what is
and is not encrypted because there's a lot of services,
for example, that use magic URL to log in.
And if you know that URL,
this has come out, I think pretty well.
I don't know if lastpass put it in their pr statement specifically,
-- but it's
-- not in their current I I just googled,
like if you go to lastpass dot column slash features slash password dash vault,
it doesn't mention this at all
on their website.
-- So
-- they have a APR statement.
One of their statements here is the threat actor
was also able to copy a backup of customer
data, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah
binary format that contained both unencrypted data such as website URL
S as well as fully encrypted sensitive fields such as website,
user names, passwords, secure notes and form filled data.
So they're not encrypting URL S and it
is not clear to me exactly which parts of the notes are encrypted or not
because it sounds like some of the notes are
encrypted and some of the notes aren't included.
You keep saying secure notes is
that different? I don't know.
Oh, so, oh, there's a, there's a thought.
So if it's a secure note is the secure note encrypted.
But if it's a regular note on another thing, it's not encrypted,
that would suck because in a lot of,
well, literally every time I enter a banking password, I have to add a note of like,
what are my three secret questions and my three secret answers?
-- And I add that as a note and I really hope those are encrypted,
-- right?
And people are adding
like their, uh what do they call the recovery recovery codes, recovery codes.
They call the recovery codes, recovery,
they're adding those to the notes in some instances.
-- So,
-- yeah, of course, because we're also gonna put them,
it would never have occurred to me that I would have to use a secure note.
I would just assume that the password record that I have
-- is an encrypted fault.
-- And you mentioned about some of the recovery URL S.
So this is another thing that,
that came up in some threads I saw in Mastodon where there were
like like account recovery and password reset.
URL S that were ended up saved in lastpass, which unencrypted
that still worked later because the company that issued them didn't expire them,
which is is wrong.
-- But,
-- but it's not technically wrong because there's no CWE for it. How do I know this?
Because I submitted one for it a few months ago where literally,
because I noticed that like people send out these links with like, you know,
here's a link,
reset your password or set your password or whatever
and you know, if it expires in a few hours or even a day or two,
ok, pretty reasonable.
But a lot of them like never expire, which is horrifying.
And so Microsoft did this research where what
happened is people would basically create an account,
you know,
using like Josh at breast.net and not confirm
the email obviously because they don't control it.
And then when you go to the account,
you get like a recovery of it. And
but I'm already in that account with a backup
password or a backup email address or something,
you know, things like that.
So
it's basically this is hard to do,
especially if you try to kind of compress the workflow,
but back to last pass.
See to me when you say this is an encrypted vault and you put your data in the vault,
it is strongly implied
that you put all the data in the vault, not just some of it, but all of it.
And, and this is where, and ironically, do you know why the,
like why we left last pass is because actually
we couldn't reliably retrieve the data when somebody left,
right?
Because their master password encrypts it and we had access to it
and we needed corporate data recovery, right?
Which one password offers?
So we ironically left last pass because it was in some ways too secure.
We couldn't, like I said, we couldn't recover accounts.
Ok? OK. You can't say that.
So
I
can't
say that
it's too secure.
Well, no,
it's not.
Ok.
I don't want to rehash all of the things that happened with
Last Pass in depth because it's been covered by many people.
And here is the fundamental takeaway. There, there'll be some links in the show
notes for anyone who wants to go read about this stuff because it's fascinating.
Don't get me wrong.
But the fundamental takeaway of all of this
and the reason I think last pass has
lost the trust of security people
is they are being incredibly weaselly
in how they're talking like this is
people are taking their press release apart using like lawyer speak,
saying this could mean this or this or this.
Like they're not, they're obviously letting lawyers write the press release.
And it's technically not a lie,
but it's definitely not the truth.
But it's like exactly like this features
slash password vault page on the website where
I'm left with the impression that everything is encrypted, but clearly it's not.
And they haven't clarified this page.
That kind of blows my mind though.
Why would they
-- to be honest and truthful and transparent?
-- But that's obviously not their purpose.
So, so here's what happens when there's a breach
and this is true of every breach.
There's basically kind of three paths companies will take.
There's the just pretend nothing happened.
Yeah. Shoot, shovel and burry,
right? No, shoot, shovel and burry, like foot and mouth disease. You just
never happened. I don't know what you mean. Like 10% of the cows disappeared.
It's a thing. Probably wolves. UFO
S
UFO S is better like, ok, so
do nothing. Right.
Then there's just we're going to tell you absolutely everything that happened.
-- And there, there have been good instances of that
-- well
clad clod FFL consistently.
Yeah,
-- they were, they've been very truthful.
-- Well, you know what, I'm going to point out
how they handle breaches is typically the same way as how they handle like oopsies,
almost certain
it's a, a
100%.
And then you end up the third path. The middle path is what last pass is doing
where basically the lawyers have taken over
and they're not lying,
but you have to like put on a lawyer hat
and try to interpret everything being said
because nothing they're saying is what you think it means. Like,
that's the thing that eats me on the inside is they are
purposely misleading people
-- there.
-- It's essentially a cross between advertising and a badly written contract.
Yes.
And they, they,
they know they're doing this because you don't create this sort of communications
without knowing exactly what you're saying. I mean, I have been part of groups
that have tried to spin things in the past
and,
and I will say like this is one of the best things that
like Redhead had going for it is we would try to be like,
how can we make us sound less dumb?
And it's like
it's open source, we literally can't do it. We just, we have to just tell the truth.
There's no escape hatch to this at all and we're like, all right, fine.
I guess we'll just tell the truth
and then it all goes away a week later
because it's not this.
That's the thing that always gets me is like, especially something like this. It
most breaches are not really ongoing.
And I mean that in the sense of
yes,
a lot of breaches are ongoing in the sense of they
get personal data and they use it to do bad things,
but nobody cares because that's just kind of a normal day now,
-- right? Like I just as well
-- and look the story isn't the last past Breach.
The story is how bad they're effing it up and lying about it, you know.
Well, and to be clear they're not lying about it. They're just using very
specific language in terms to, you know,
create an impression that is maybe not entirely,
I don't want to say it's not correct, but it's, it's easy to misconstrue, let's say
it. It is purposely designed to misconstrue
much like their password vault page. I like, I literally still read this
and I still, my gut says, yeah, everything's encrypted.
What are you worrying about?
Exactly.
So that's,
that's enough. That's enough.
We know last pass is not acting in a way that I would say is upstanding or trustworthy.
And if I'm going to use a password manager,
I need to trust those people. Ok.
Now this is where let's move into the next talking point of all this is. So,
what, what next? Like, I'm a person, I'm literally a person who is using lastpass.
My family was using lastpass. Now we have to figure out what we do next.
So rule number one is you continue using a password manager?
-- Well, no,
-- I'm serious. Right.
Like, because I've, I've seen people who are like, oh, password managers are bad
and I'm like, cool, like, what are you gonna do? Print it out and like, go with that.
I'll just buy one of those books at the
supermarket where I can write my passwords down and
that actually would not be a bad, that's,
I would consider that to still be using a password manager.
-- I'm ok with that.
-- I agree.
I actually have no problem with that.
-- Like, if your elderly parents want one of those, by all means,
-- dude,
if you're in my parents house looking in at the password book inside their desk.
All right, we got bigger problems.
Oh, absolutely. 100%. 100%. Ok.
So there is a very nice write up from Tavis or
that I'm going to put in the show notes and he basically
explains the, his problems with a,
like online
cloud based password manager and it's not that they have access to the passwords.
It's what the password manager plugins do
to the HTML on your website. And I I, his concerns are
-- completely valid.
-- Has there ever been an attack through that mechanism though?
-- Probably
-- not. And, and I think, I don't, I think it's relatively
unrealistic for there to be.
And so before we go on the thing you have to understand is there is no
way to work with user names and passwords that is we'll put secure in quotes.
There are tradeoffs and there are risks.
So, like, here's an example, someone will say, well, I'm only going to use key
pass
XC
because it's only on my computer
and it doesn't go anywhere and I feel that's safe.
So, yes, you can make the argument that my pass
word hasn't gone anywhere else. It's only on my computer,
but now you are responsible for keeping that backed
up and keeping it synced in all of that.
So there are risks and rewards to every solution.
I wanna be clear that this last pass problem has
nothing to do with the cloud capabilities of last pass.
This is 100% structural issues with last pass.
In fact, if you read what everyone is talking about,
no one is claiming that being in the cloud was the problem,
right? The problem is last pass response.
Well, but and also the fact that they,
they created the situation by not encrypting all the things
as was implied. Like I literally was
a
customer for years and I just assumed
that everything was encrypted because
why would you only selectively encrypt some of it?
-- You know, that's a, that's like
-- a but we're not,
we're not worried about the failures.
I don't care about the failures. We talked enough about those.
We, we, the value in this show is what to do. We can whinge for hours on why they suck.
This is one of the reasons why you need two fa on your high value accounts
because at some point, your password might get disclosed.
We'll get to that, we'll get to that. You're jumped ahead too far,
we're still deciding what to do. Now,
there are going to be people listening and there's going to be people, you know,
who can't stop using last pass for some
reason or another that is not inherently wrong.
For example, it took us months to move out and we literally had to start
off that date because like I moved my stuff out of
last pass and it took me several hours of dedicated work.
-- It is going
-- to take most of us days or weeks. And that's the other thing to keep in mind.
This is a slog.
This is not fast.
I have to move my family.
It
is not going to be an enjoyable experience for me.
-- We'll
-- say no, you got to reinstall apps, get them logged in. That's
fine.
So anyway, even if you're using lastpass,
you need to do the things we're going to talk about even if you keep using it now,
which password manager you choose to replace lastpass with.
So you do that
is
it is up to you to figure that out.
I'm not saying everyone needs to go like key pas XC,
everyone needs to go with like a paper book in your drawer,
-- whatever figure it out. Well,
-- one benefit
that is kind of magic.
Now is there is things like icloud and Microsoft, Onedrive and Google Drive.
But there's a lot of options
do allow for very easy file storage and synchronization between multiple devices.
And
if the app actually encrypts all the data securely.
Well, let's hope it does well.
And we know keypads X does that because it's open source.
It's actually really easy to say like, OK, here's my keypad
X file and as long as it's protected with a good, you know, master encryption key.
Yeah, you just throw it into whatever file because I,
I hope our listeners are using some sort
of cloud based file drive storage backup because probably
like those family photos are important, please, you know, take care of them.
So I would suggest though, for anyone paying attention,
probably look at one password or bit one.
Those are the two I would suggest and they're the two. I'm a biggest fan of
due to we'll say human constraints of people who aren't me.
I'm moving my family to one password.
If it was just me, I'd be using bit
warden is how I would describe that for a, a long list of reasons.
-- This is what
-- frustrates me is like Chrome
has a really good built in password manager,
so does Firefox,
but it only works for Chrome and I still have things that
-- are not a web browser and same thing for Mac
-- keychain.
But, but my, my specific need,
the most important aspect of password managers to me at this time
is the ability to share and manage family passwords
because
I have a variety of needs.
Not just that like I, I have a variety of needs with my Children for,
for dealing with them, they're, they're forgetful.
There's a lot of reasons Right. So I, I, the,
the features one password has are on family management.
The thing I need, I mean, that's, that's why I went to last pass because at the time,
last pass had family management stuff and no one else did.
And so that is why I landed there.
So now the first thing you need to do is obviously migrate
all of your passwords from wherever they were into wherever you're going.
And there's a lot of instructions to do this.
So I'm not going to talk about it, go find them for your password manager.
Fun fact, at least when I tried it last pass,
kind of made it a dark pattern to get your data out of there.
And you can't, I had zero problems and you can't
have, you actually tried closing your account though.
We'll get to that, that, that is impossible. And that's ok.
That's, that's part of the story, right? That's at the end that comes at the end.
The first thing you need to do is get
your passwords into your new password manager system.
Do not use the same master password you used with last pass
because the Attackers may or may not have your vault. We don't know
and your vault may or may not be encrypted
with like there. I've been read so many things about
last pass claims. Everything was 100,000 rounds.
Um No, it's,
the modern stuff was 100,000 rounds apparently.
-- The old soap was like 5000 rounds and of course you can't,
-- maybe
there's, I've heard reports of people with one round.
They found out like it, it's unknown.
So anyway,
change your master password, right?
Don't use the same one.
And then you need to start changing passwords for your services
and you need, your goal is to change every password in your password manager.
And that is ridiculous because like, I have 400 accounts in my password manager.
Right? It is bananas.
-- How long it is going to take me to change those? But
-- I have
377 and
-- only 370
-- seven. That's my personal one. There's also work,
uh actually not too bad, 321 in work.
But you gotta remember, I have a aggressively pushed sso at
the CS A.
-- Right.
-- Right. And, and
that's part of the story obviously is if you have sso good job now,
you need to prioritize what you're going to change
because
things like your bank and your email are
probably the most important accounts you have.
-- And
-- obviously,
I know email is the most important full stop because that's the recovery mechanism.
-- E
-- email is hands down the most important 100% because
if an attacker can gain access to your email,
they own everything.
This is another reason I would highly suggest using two factor authentication
on your email because even if an attacker has your password.
They still can't. Well,
they
hopefully can't log in
you.
You put the, the codes in your, your notes, in which case they have those too.
No, the number one would be your email, followed by your cell phone
or other phones, then your banks and everything else because
the, the email and the phone are the recovery method. That's the critical path
-- to everything.
-- Yeah.
So email, telephone banks and look,
this is up to you to figure out what the things you think are most important,
easy because most password managers will kind of show activity and
just go by activity by what you use the most,
which doesn't always work because like,
I pay my taxes once or twice a year and that's also an important account.
Uh, that's a good point.
So there are things anyway,
look
through the financial stuff,
anything dealing with money or, or I guess meet space, right?
Anything in meet space.
That's the stuff you need to care about because
you've got obviously real world consequences to those passwords being
taken.
So, ok,
so we got our master password, we got a new,
we got a new password manager, we got a new master password.
We started changing all our passwords and that takes forever. Right.
I'm not going to say it doesn't, it takes a very,
very long time and it's terrible once you have all of your passwords changed now,
you have to think about what do I do with last pass.
And I would suggest not removing your last pass, I guess,
account until you have things mostly sorted out in case you have to go look back.
One thing I would say though is definitely
remove the last pass extension because I ran both
last pass and one password extension simultaneously for like
a couple of days in my web browser.
Can
you do that?
And it was a nightmare because they
basically fight for control over those form fields
with, I mean, this is something Tavis Orman.
He points out in his thing, you know, with the shenanigans that go on there
with their, you know, they inject code and stuff and it was just,
it was beyond a nightmare.
Like again, we just had to say drop dead date and just do it.
I didn't even know that was possible.
It is possible and it's very, very unpleasant because
the way they um sort of attached to the field
and where they put their pop up is different.
So they, they literally fight each other. It was the
do not
even a little, I'm impressed it worked it all.
I would have expected them to explode or something,
but whatever
-- doesn't matter.
-- Well. But the other thing is
this is the other advantage,
get it out of your uh chrome extension and turn the
app off to essentially force yourself to be moved to whatever new
password manager you have so that you're not sort of accidentally
using the old one and you think you've moved out of it
because that's, that's another thing we have.
I, I, you know,
because I had one device where I totally forgot about the device and it was like, oh,
everything works.
-- And then I'm like, oh, this, I totally forgot to set this device up.
-- Ah, interesting.
I,
so funny enough, I, I did that I disabled
last pass and enabled. Well, I, I was testing bit
worden in one password
and so I just turned last pass off to try the other ones to decide which one,
the things I needed to do.
And,
yeah, you're right though. I mean, make sure you do that right away.
I think that's really good advice.
Well,
this is one of those things where you can think you've moved everything out of it
and like you can do an export and how do you know you actually got everything?
Yeah. Yeah.
And, and you might miss things, but again,
as long as you have the email address sorted,
you could probably do account recovery.
You know what I mean? Now,
here's why
one thing we didn't say at the beginning here
is why you need to change all your passwords.
And, and even if you are using last pass today, you need to do this
because Attackers acquired backups of the last pass bolt.
So you should assume an attacker has access to
all of your passwords in your backed up vault.
This is why just shutting off your last pass account
is meaningless in this context and why you have to change all of
your passwords because the Attackers already have the data while I think it is
going to be unlikely they crack a lot of vaults.
-- I think it is still best to assume they can do
-- it.
Well, I mean, we have a lot of, sort of, I want to say unconfirmed second hand reports,
but there's kind of enough of them
from enough people that are sort of generally competent that it's like
there's a lot of smoke here. I suspect there might be fire.
Maybe I'm hesitant to say that because I know back when the,
when the breach was first announced,
like, you knew some people that had
-- incidents with data, they thought they only had in last
-- pass.
Well, yeah,
because I got an email from github saying
an access token was used improperly to blah,
blah, blah and we've locked it out
and so did a couple of other people on master like,
-- and,
-- and, but here's the thing, here's what gets me
all of that happened, like, right away
and I haven't heard anything of it since.
And so I wonder if those tokens were in the note?
Well, exactly. Yeah. If they were unencrypted, then they're all too easy.
Like, literally too easy.
I would have assumed the note was fine.
You know what? That's a good point.
That's, yeah, because back then I was operating on the assumption that,
like, it's an encrypted vault, you put everything in the vault, it's all encrypted.
Like
the fact that they really still weasel about this
drives me nuts.
But that's why
last pass has lost my trust. It's not the breach.
-- Oh, yeah, they'll never get it back. You
-- can have a, well, I wouldn't say never but
have a breach.
And if you're honest about what happened,
I'm not going to knock you because everyone has breaches, everyone makes mistakes.
But the fact that they're trying so hard to weasel out of everything is the problem.
Stupid question. But they've never said once, why is this crap not encrypted?
Right. There's no good reason.
It's probably for marketing purposes or something. I mean,
well, actually, you know,
it's probably so on the web you why you can search and stuff?
-- That would be my bet. It just makes it easier
-- to, I had someone point out
that with last pass. If you went to a website that
had, you had an account with
the prompt, last pass gave you was different than if you didn't.
You know what I mean?
Where it was like, oh, log in with your last pass versus like,
we don't know anything about this.
And so they think that's one of the reasons they captured this,
but obviously there's way better ways.
Ok,
-- so where are we at? We're at shutting down
-- last.
So one thing I'm gonna say
is while you're doing your password rotation,
consider enabling two fa And it's funny because
I actually just had the experience of
almost being locked out of an account.
Uh So I went to renew my, I got an email to renew my Nexus pass, you know,
my Nexus card to get into the US without having to go in the line of, you know,
silly people who don't know how to take their shoes off.
Uh, no, seriously,
that's why I got the Nexus pass was so I can go on the people who know how to travel line.
That's it.
And it's funny because when I told my mom, she's like, what? And I'm like,
and she's like, oh, I want to go on that line too. And so she got hers.
I went to, you know, login.gov, which man, I love that site that is so well executed
and it's like, you know, oh, good.
My user name and password, you know, and then it's like two a, a code and I'm like, uh,
or my, um, my hard work key and it's like, I just rotated my hierarchies and I'm like,
I forgot that one.
I totally forgot logging.gov because I only use it like,
every four or five years to renew it.
Luckily they make you do a code on your phone and then let you do the key like Mastodon.
And so I'm like, on my phone I'm like login dot A. It's there. I'm so happy.
So
definitely, if you're setting, if you're, you're using hardware tokens,
make dang sure.
See, this is what I hate about hardware tokens.
Even if you have two hardware tokens at some point in the future,
if you want to rotate them or lose them or something,
are you going to be sure that you got all the sites that you log in using the tokens for?
Because it's not like
the token will
export a list or tell you of what's in there, right?
That, that's a possibility with 502, there's the discovery protocol,
but almost nobody uses it.
-- Well, it can only hold a set number of keys as well
-- also that, yeah,
but the point is like given a token, I can't query the token for like, what,
what did I set you up for again?
Because I don't honestly remember.
That's right. That's right. Yep. Yep.
So be careful setting your two fa up. Make sure you have,
well, like set one up on your phone or, or
one password conveniently also does TA
P stuff, right? You can,
you can put the thing into one password,
you know,
which of course scares everybody because now your
two fa is like dependent on one application,
but hopefully it's actually encrypted and they don't get breached.
It's complicated. It's, I'm not gonna say it's right or wrong again.
This goes back to the very beginning everyone
has tradeoffs for everything you need to do
and losing your second factor
may be realistic or expected
versus putting something into one password.
-- That is a totally normal thing for people to do. We've had it
-- happen for most people.
It totally is like,
we're freaks because we have multiple backups,
which that's actually really hard to do.
But one thing that came up is I realized is like S MS
was a fine to fa authentication method until Attackers started attacking it.
And that's the thing with these password managers
in theory. Ok.
Something like bit warden is pretty hard to attack
because it would have to be a targeted attack.
Right?
I have to go after you to get to your machine to
get to your encrypted vault to download it and crack it.
That's really unlikely in theory.
Things like one password and last pass,
they're really good at security and they would prevent this.
Well, oops, as it turns out,
realistically,
I would say,
putting all your eggs in one well protected basket is
fine as long as that basket is actually well protected.
And the problem is we don't know that it is.
Right.
It's whatever the company says it is and maybe they're lying,
maybe they're telling the truth.
And then the second thing of course is,
uh, you know, a tree doesn't fall in a forest until somebody cuts it down. Well,
until Attackers actually start going after one password.
-- Yeah, one password's pretty
-- secure.
I mean, we think it is, it seems to be their security.
Well, until anybody tries to attack it,
it's fine. But once people attack it, maybe it's easy, maybe it's really hard.
Don't know.
And that's the problem here is we're
trying to make security trade offs and judgments
with unknown risks,
very unknown risk. And so
I personally shove everything in one password because I'm just like, you know what?
I, I know, I'm absolutely 100% likely to accidentally delete all my data.
Much more so than,
you know, like a last password breaking.
I agree with that
and it, it was more likely until it wasn't.
And now it sucks
-- like the time that guy drove into my house.
-- Right.
No, it never happens until I get home. And I'm like,
look,
here's the thing I keep telling myself as I'm
going through the pain and suffering of changing passwords
is
this is a Black Swan event. Basically.
I don't expect to have to do this for at least a year.
Right.
I know it could happen again. I'm completely aware of that,
but there's a big difference between having an
incident with your password manager every month versus
every year or every decade.
And I think anything a year or more can justify
the multiple hours of pain and suffering we're going through
because this is just the way it is like
advantages I get from having a password manager vastly outweigh
the probably day I'm going to lose my life changing all my passwords.
Well, I've changed most of them.
I,
so the way I've approached this is rather
than like sitting down and slogging through,
I have been changing, we'll say about a dozen a day
for,
it's been weeks now that I've been working on this and,
and the other thing I do is every time I log into a site
I change a password, if it hasn't been changed already, which
like I just did that this morning, I got an email from fedex.
That was like, oh, we have a package coming for you.
You should log in and see what's going on. I log in.
And I'm like, oh, good, I'll change this password, you know, and it took 10 seconds,
10 seconds time to billion.
-- And this
-- is one of the advantages of I've been using password managers for a
better part of a decade now.
And all my passwords are computer generated
or
pretty random in that I just mash, you know,
text into a notepad and then cut and paste it and
store it because I don't have to remember the dang thing.
Like,
I only have to remember my icloud and my one
password pass and my Google pass and everything else is
damn, I better get access to that one password file where I am up the creek, you know,
and that's the advantage is I only really have three passwords for, well,
and my local login password.
So I have four passwords to remember. And so they can actually be good because
there's no way I'm gonna remember 800 passwords even remotely a little bit.
Ok.
You just reminded me of something it will end on this note is, well,
there's two other things.
So first of all, shutting down your last pass account, like do it, but it,
it isn't really going to matter
is kind of my, my takeaway there and it's gonna be hard to do.
They already have your account.
-- The horse has left the barn, the horse
-- has left the barn
last pass is not making it very easy to disable accounts.
-- They've definitely done some shenanigans.
-- Oh, it's always been that way.
It's, it was
literally to get our corporate accounts turned off. I basically, like
it was
an arduous process
that doesn't surprise me at all. I'm, I'm
given everything we've seen. I expect it.
They used to have a lot of dark patterns on their website and from a quick glance,
they still seem to have most of them
and I, from what I've gathered, it's gotten worse.
I believe that
I think they might be in the Doom
loop.
This kind of behavior says doom
-- loop. To me,
-- it, it, it might be, I mean, I,
I don't think they need to do
Loop. I think this incident is just doom.
-- Well,
-- but now people are actually leaving and that's the thing.
Like, because you got to think password managers are one of the stickiest apps.
I mean, we're all seeing why it's horrible to change.
The only thing stickier is probably your email address.
Like we have cell phone number portability.
Your email address is super sticky.
So,
like the fact that people are actually talking
about moving and some people are moving,
like, especially in tech circles.
-- Yeah, you, you're done ducked up
-- bigly. Lots of people are moving.
I mean, everyone I talk to, that's like, what should I do at last pass?
I just keep saying, like, get off it, don't use it.
You can't trust them,
you can't trust them. And that's the thing.
One, password storage and management is kind of a high trust activity.
-- It's
-- a
-- very high trust. Exactly. Exactly. That,
all right. So, anyway,
uh, yeah, I guess my,
my one thing I want to leave with that I should have talked about way at the beginning
is master passwords.
Don't your master password should be like 20 plus characters long.
It's a pass phrase, right? Don't use short ones.
Even if you think like, oh,
I used a letter in a symbol or a number and a symbol or whatever.
Like, no,
you something very, very long.
There's many, many places, I'll try to find one.
There's a really nice one, Bob Lord actually sent along uh uh some days ago.
But
there are very nice examples of how to generate pass phrases out on the internet,
like look one up and use it and generate a long good pass phrase.
I don't care
how many symbols you used. Like anything less than probably 25
ish. Not, I shouldn't say that. Maybe what, 10 to 16,
anything less than that
as a password is just way too short. Now, we have, we have too much stuff to crack.
It depends on how it's stored. So for example, if they shaw 512 hash it,
that is super insecure because Sha 512 is super
duper fast
on modern hardware because it literally has a Shaw 512 in silicon implementation.
-- Whereas you're getting
-- to, no, that's not helpful advice.
The helpful advice is use a password,
use a
password because the,
and again,
this is back to you're trying to make a security decision based on unknowns.
Now, if it's something like, you know, key
pass
X, you can actually check and verify that. Yes, it's storing my ma
or it's doing X encryption with the master password.
But with last pass, like for all, we know it's ro 13 in it.
-- Uh
-- I
think there was work done on that, but whatever it doesn't matter, we're out of time,
I guess.
Good luck everyone.
If you're in our boat, we know exactly what you're going through
and it sucks and it's a marathon,
but keep with it
and you definitely won't regret it. So
that's that I guess
I just
thank you for listening.
I just keep coming back to like,
there are so many things I'd rather be spending my time on than this.
And I'm actually, no,
I'm actually quite angry towards last pass because I actually moved out
of them months ago and I still have to deal with this.
And I'm quite angry because
this is a chunk of my time in life. I'll never get back
because the downside of dealing with like if somebody gets into my bank account,
that's gonna be even more hours of
it would be way worse.
It
is what it is like. Sometimes it sucks and we just gotta do it.
-- This is like eating vegetables, deal with it.
-- Not if you deep fry them.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go over our Security podcast.com.
The show
notes, G
Pound
-- Podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of
-- your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.
The