So one thing I wanted to work on the show couldn't figure out a way to is so, you know,
c sis the Canadian Security Intelligence Service.
Uh, sure.
So they have a parking problem. Their big office out in, uh, wherever it is in Ontario
doesn't have enough parking.
So they've been parking on the side streets and getting tickets.
And so they were asking homeowners to like,
let them pay to park on their like driveways and
some of the homeowners actually, like, paved their backyards to provide parking.
And so of course, the city then got pissed off and like,
you can't sell parking on private property without like this huge
list of insane stuff and like a million dollars of insurance and
blah, blah, blah.
Anyways, it's in the papers here. It's awesome.
Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast.
Episode 181 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
-- How are
-- you doing, Kurt?
Pretty good. Pretty good. It's not minus 30 anymore.
-- Minus 30
-- seven doesn't really matter. It's minus 30 F is also cool.
It's really cold,
like, just below freezing and I'm just I'm so looking forward to,
-- you know,
what pleases me about these conversations about the weather is somewhere someday
someone is going to be listening to this in a lovely place
that never gets cold is going to be like,
why do these idiots keep talking about the weather?
I'm not sure that's going to be the case because,
uh,
you know, with all the CO2 it as a species,
I'm not sure there's going to be any nice weather anymore.
Well, there, there might be,
but it's probably where we live because it'll go from just
hot to less hot as opposed to dangerously hot and murderously hot. But anyway,
so, sim swaps that's been hot on Twitter.
Yeah, man, I, it's one of those things that I have a suspicion, the,
the idea of SIM swaps and S MS two factor off and just all
the dangers behind it is going to keep coming up and keep coming up.
One quick note, it's not just S MS two factor, but there's also the, you know,
where they actually phone you and read out the six
pin number. So
let's use the term S MS off because I think that's what everybody knows it does.
But just to be clear to everybody,
we're also talking about the more general case where your phone number is,
they're sending something to your phone number either via voice or via text and,
well,
-- hopefully it's you and not some bad guy receiving it
-- and we can discuss it more later.
But it's even more than that because for example, you could call the bank and be like,
oh, I'm Josh to prove it's me, call me back at the number on file
and then they call my mobile and it's like not Josh, but whatever, we'll,
we'll get to that.
But anyway, yeah. So,
so sim swaps are hip again.
-- So we figured it's probably a good episode to talk about it
-- in fairness.
Those people actually have some data, right?
And this is one of my biggest complaints about
all these whingey complaints about cybersecurity and information security.
My comment is always ok. So you've made some conclusion, what data is it based on
and the answer is they, they
went out and it's not a ton of data.
But this is one of those things where it's kind
of a pain in the butt to generate the data.
So I'll give them that,
but they actually went out and what was it something like 20 different providers?
And they,
they basically went and tried to execute some swap attack
against an account on each of these 20 providers.
That was pretty cool.
And they were and what and also to clarify,
minor thing is they executed like a social engineering type of attack, right?
Like they,
they basically called in and you know,
I am Josh,
I want to change my SIM card to this guy in Canada it's totally legit. Yo. Exactly.
So, because I think we mentioned in a previous episode,
I forget about Laura Shin talking about her SIM swap experience where
this attacker basically
fished and compromised a, uh,
like a phone company employee,
like somebody who works at like one of those mall kiosk
style phone stores
and then use that access to get on a PC that to do, like they do mass sim swap attacks.
Like they just,
it's like, um, it's like credential stuffing. Right. They just,
they, they get into, you know,
dozens or hundreds of people's phones, phone numbers rather not into their phones.
Their phones are, I'm gonna say, hopefully safe.
And, um, and then as I understand it,
they literally just go to Facebook and go forgot
my account and plug in all the phone numbers.
They've just
hijacked.
Yep. Yep. So we should
maybe start by discussing like, what is a SIM swap attack?
Because I'm sure there's some people who don't know what that is.
-- Well, let's back it up real quick. So, what is a SIM card?
-- That's
true, actually.
Well, I, you know, it's one of those things where everybody has one but like,
do you know how to change the transmission flute in your car?
No, nobody does.
-- I do know how to do that
-- because you're weird
and
I know how to change my SIM because actually funny enough
now, I mean, everything has it in the US for the most part now,
but there was a time when we had
-- iphones, they have virtual sims
-- now.
That's different.
But I'm,
I'm talking about CD MA technology which did not use SIM cards and
there was GSM technology which did in Europe was full of GSM.
And I remember I was very specific about like I want a GSM phone,
obviously meant I had to use a GSM phone provider so I could
go to Europe and swap my SIM cards out while I was there.
Which was awesome.
The idea is basically a cell phone and I'm going to say a modern cell phone.
So let's not talk about CDMA because who cares? Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Who cares?
Basically if it was, if it wasn't GSM or later, it didn't happen. It was terrible.
That's right. So as a complete aside, I was watching this documentary on at and ts
early cell phone technology where they had like
10 radio channels for all of New York.
And so basically only 10 cell phone calls could happen at a time.
But what was most fascinating about this documentary is they show
everybody using these giant brick phones or not even brick phones,
but like phones built into their
while they're driving and like staring down to like use a rotary dialer and stuff.
And it just made me laugh because we've gone from like all these people saying like,
oh, this is the most convenient thing ever.
I can make phone calls while I'm in my truck.
My work truck going from site A to site b, I don't have to pull off and, like,
find a pay phone, blah, blah, blah.
Now, as I understand it pretty much everywhere in the western world is like, yeah.
No, you can't be holding your phone.
That's like here it's, I think it's 170 bucks and three points on your license.
Like, it's, you know, they're, they're pretty serious about it.
They were simpler times.
Yeah, it's kind of comic to me how it started out
and now we've gone full pendulum. But anyway, so a SIM card, the idea is your phone
has, well, basically a Mac address, right?
An IME I number something mobile, something, something I forget what it stands for.
I don't,
I couldn't tell you what it stands
-- for either
-- international mobile equipment identity.
So it's basically a Mac address for the phone.
And the cool thing is, for example, with that, if your phone gets stolen,
you can register that.
Iiime I number as stolen and in theory,
no legitimate provider will then provide service to that phone.
So if somebody buys it, they can't use it. So that's cool.
The phone has an identity. Cool. But
the phone is not necessarily me, like if I drop and smash my phone,
I probably want to go get a new one
-- and have and not change phone numbers.
-- I mean,
-- that's the idea or
-- more to the point, like you said, if you're traveling to Europe,
right, you maybe want to take your phone.
And,
you know, my mom does this every time she goes to Germany, she pops out,
her SIM card gets one from like, well, T Mobile actually,
because that's who you buy stuff from in Germany
for like 10 or 20 bucks.
And then she texts me and she's like, you know,
this is my new phone number for the next three weeks or whatever.
And it's super convenient and cheap
because I remember actually this is only even 10 years ago with my
most phone providers in Canada,
it would basically be cheaper to buy a phone free and clear in Europe than it is to,
like, use my, my roaming plan over there.
Oh, I have no doubt roaming used to be ridiculously expensive.
I mean, I remember probably
-- 10 years ago
-- you forget Canada,
we paid the most amount of money for cell service anywhere in the world.
That is sad because actually I have, like, I have European roaming now.
It's, it's a couple of bucks a month to add on to my plans.
So when I go to, in fact, when I was in Canada, just
what was it like, three or four months ago.
Yeah. Like my phone worked as if I was in the United States.
You probably paid less for Rome here than I pay.
I paid, I paid $0 to go Roman Canada Curt, because it was just included in my cell plan.
It's lovely and same thing in Europe. I go to Europe. My phone just works.
It's, it's awesome. My only complaint
is that when I'm in Europe my phone knows it's on roaming and every time I,
I have a pixel three, every time
the
pixel. Oh, no.
What's that?
That's like a
Google
Android
-- phone. Yeah, it's
-- a Google phone. No, it's pixel two. I apologize. Not the three.
It's a pixel two.
And when it's in roaming
it is trying very hard to find a home tower. And so my battery drains very, very fast.
But other than that,
oh, because it's trying to find your native carrier. Not like, oh my God, who's this
guy?
I wish I could be like, I'm in Europe. It's cool. Stop.
-- Can
-- you, I know in an iphone you can set your preferred provider. You can reset that.
So I, I kind of, I can pick
a, like a, I forget what they call it. Like this
name of a provider.
But when I'm walking around towns, I jump between different providers
and it's just, it's really wants to phone home.
Right.
So it would, if I, if I said, like, only use this one provider,
it would almost certainly cut out at some point because I would stop using
that tower and need to switch to a different tower and it wouldn't,
it
wouldn't
-- work. But
-- whatever in Europe, they're pretty dense. Yeah.
Right. So, anyway,
so that's the phone. And then the SIM card basically has
your identity,
like your identity, like in the form of like your phone number.
Because theoretically speaking, if you, um, so phones can be locked to carriers,
which is what they used to do
to, well, basically get you to pay your bill. Right.
So you couldn't just, like,
get a phone on a plan and then like hop over to some other carrier that's cheaper,
you know, because they're subsidizing the phone by having you on the plan,
whatever that's all changed in Canada.
I don't know about the US. It
kind of in the US. You can't sell locked phones anymore. Yay.
They, it's, I don't know, I think they can sell them but you can get it unlocked.
There's some weirdness.
-- It, I know the
-- same in Canada used to be, you could get it unlocked,
but like they would charge you 50 bucks to unlock
it and they would only do it if you were,
you know, you were paid for, but now it has to be unlocked because it just,
it was way too abusive to consumers.
Yeah, it's terrible. The SIM card
also has data storage and that's kind of the cool thing because for example,
I remember
my first phone with a SIM card and then I upgraded phones,
popped my old SIM card into my new phone and boo,
there's my context there's all my addresses and all that stuff.
I remember those days, you know,
trying to enter all of your address book into like a T nine smartphone
-- like, oh so T nine is oh yeah, let's go back way in time here folks. What?
-- No, we're
no, we're talking about sim swapping like
we're going to end up talking about iron ore pretty soon at this rate.
So SIM cards basically separate your identity from the physical phone,
which is good,
you know.
And so
the problem becomes though is that the SIM
card separates your identity from the phone.
So if I can
essentially, I can go buy a SIM card for like what five or 10 bucks,
like a blank SIM card
with pretty much any carrier will sell them now for five or 10 bucks.
And then, well, the trick is I need to get your phone number pointed at it.
And
well, there's a couple of ways to do this.
The, the I'm not going to say the easiest one,
but the most straightforward one would be a social engineering attack
where you phone up the phone provider and you say like,
oh, my phone got stolen or lost or whatever, right?
When
AWOL I need, you know,
you to direct my phone number to this SIM card which has this serial number and
it's got like some really tiny print on the back of it with a serial number.
And you know, they, they quote, unquote, verify your identity, big air quotes here.
You know, usually, like, what's your name, date of birth?
If you're lucky, maybe they'll ask you like,
how much was your last cell phone bill or something?
They're not going to have a ton of great ways to authenticate you.
But honestly, most people can't, you know, find out about you on Facebook.
Right. And that's, I mean, that's super common where, I mean, what do they call it? Os
N open source intelligence where you just do searches about people
and you can generally find an insane amount of information.
Yeah.
-- And so
-- then I get your phone number pointed at my SIM card, put my,
put the SIM card in a phone and I
can start recovering passwords and accounts and whatever.
And that's that there are people with accounts that are protected by two
factor authentication in the form of S MS or phone message or whatever
that are, you know, that literally have a lot of money in them like bank accounts,
-- brokerage accounts,
-- Cryptocurrency exchanges, man,
I was going to say Cryptocurrency exchanges
because once that Bitcoin leaves the wallet,
it's gone.
Yeah, exactly. And like it's never coming back
and what gets me, what kind of annoys me. So I, I like that this is resurgent on twit
because they actually did some work and studied
it and got some data and that's great.
But like my local police, the Edmonton police service who you know, is not
some super high tech FBI NSA C si whatever crime fighting force, like they're,
they're technically competent but, you know, they're not cybercrime, they're,
they're like city police guy.
They
not only have had multiple warnings about SIM Swap,
they have a giant web page dedicated to it.
That's pretty cool. Yeah.
So they talk about SIM swap fraud.
You know,
identity theft and identity fraud are on the
rise and oftentimes fraud or fraudsters will override your
privacy rights by gaining control of your cell
phone and stealing the valuable information in it,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
A. So here's one, I'm not sure if this is correct.
But anyways,
they say a SIM card does not contain highly personal and sensitive information,
like pictures and videos.
I'm actually pretty sure modern SIM cards,
some of them have a lot of storage and can actually store that data.
I would be shocked if any of them do though.
I mean,
you can store phone numbers on SIM cards but I have never heard
of a SIM card storing anything other than text messages and phone numbers.
I would like.
The problem is I was trying to Google SIM card and storage,
but it keeps coming up with like cell phone plans.
Yeah, that doesn't,
you know what this is a good task for the listeners.
Someone knows of a way to store anything other than phone numbers and text messages.
-- I'm
-- pretty sure one of my early phones.
Let me store my pictures on my SIM card because that was one of the,
also the selling points is the SIM card had a couple of megabytes of storage.
I seem to remember
maybe it's a false memory.
I don't know anyways and, and then they talk about what a SIM card uh
does contain which is yeah, your text messages back up a bit.
A SIM card also does not contain, they say your home address,
your bank account number, your doctor's name or other details.
Unless you specifically write those details into a text S
MS message or specify those details in your contact list.
And the reality is
I'm pretty sure most of us have our home address in our contact list because well,
we just do,
I wonder if I do actually, I don't know if I do. I probably do.
It's well uh with an iphone now Siri data minds and you know, does suggestions,
which is kind of cool because like I get a phone
call and it says probably so and so based on a,
you know, email and it's like in the footer of email, the person's phone number.
And I'm like,
that's actually pretty nifty. I like that. Thank you.
Yeah, I don't, I don't have my doctor in here but I,
but then they say what it does contain, which is like, yeah,
it's all your text messages.
So that's, you know, especially for younger people. That's,
that's everything your phone contacts, history of calls, blah, blah, blah.
Certain cellular carriers state that application transfer over certain cellar
certain,
ok, they mangled the sentence. I don't know what this means. Certain,
I'm assuming cellular carriers state that
applications transfer over maybe onto the
SIM card. Whatever.
Anyways, the last location of the phone,
which is often useful in locating missing people.
Cool.
Yeah, if I can hijack your SIM card, I don't care about the date on it.
I care about getting your phone number so that I can be you. Right.
But that's harder to explain. I suspect when you're
not a security weirdo.
I mean,
I, I understand
why they wrote that stuff down because it's technically true and I
think it's more relatable to more people because if I tell someone
I can sim swap your phone
and I can basically make and receive phone calls from your cell phone number,
most people would be like, who cares?
They talk about how to conduct a SIM swap,
you know, talking about like the social engineering side,
how to instructions for future criminals.
-- And
-- then they also talk about signs of a swap,
which I think is pretty fascinating because this seems to be a universal thing is if
your phone receives no signal or says emergency
calls only even after restarting the phone,
then use another phone to call your provider
and have them check the status immediately.
And this is a common thing I hear in all the SIM swap cases is everybody's like, oh,
yeah.
You know, my phone went kind of wonky and like, oh, whatever,
I'll deal with it in the morning.
So I went to bed
or, luckily they're like,
I didn't go to bed and I called my provider to figure out what the heck was going on.
And they're like, oh, no, it's cool. You, you changed your SIM card?
Yeah. Right.
Yeah,
they talk about,
here's what fascinating they talk about how to prevent phone takeovers.
And they basically, and this is the number one thing that
pretty much is,
I think the only real piece of advice is putting a pin number on your account.
And what's fascinating is about a month ago, I was
doing some cyber hygiene stuff and I went into my account,
didn't have a PIN number. So,
so I have a pin number that I never remember
and they always reset it for me when I call the cell phone company.
It's embarrassing.
-- I put mine in last pass now.
-- I don't even know what mine is, nor is it in last pass. And
so actually I think I feel like we might have
talked about this on the show a couple episodes ago,
but I had an incident where I needed to log into the
website for my cell phone and I didn't know my secret questions.
And so I called up the company and it ended up being
a huge weird snafu because I actually know the questions but whatever
I called the company.
And I'm like, I don't know these questions like, well, we can't help you.
I'm like, what do you mean? They said we can't reset these.
I said, well, what do you accept me? Expect me to do that? And they said,
oh, you have to register like a new account with a new email address.
I said, I even said, I said,
I'm literally going to switch cell phone providers before
I create like a Gmail account just for this.
Like for real.
And they, they, they didn't care and they couldn't do anything about it.
And then funny enough,
I tried logging in the next day and it didn't ask me
the security questions and then I changed them to something I knew.
But it was like this is been beyond ridiculous.
And so, well, at least with my provider,
I can only set a four digit pin and I'm
guessing you get three or four attempts to guess it,
which means
there's a reasonable chance you can get somebody's pin number.
-- It's not great, but it's not impossible,
-- whatever. Let's assume not.
Yeah.
And then I love this second piece of advice.
Do not publish your phone number on your public profile on social media,
which I agree with in principle.
But you know, some people kind of have to like, say my lawyer
for some weird reason, my lawyer puts her cell phone number on, like,
all of the website and stuff.
-- Wow, that's wild.
-- She travels around a lot. Right.
She's not stuck in her office all the time.
-- But
-- if I was a lawyer or really any sort of business person,
-- then
-- how would you get your phone calls from your paying clients?
I would have like, some sort of answer.
You know,
there's those answering services you can essentially use where like it can
bring your cell phone or you'll just go to a voicemail.
I guess that would be a solution.
But honestly, I,
I feel like it's a lot less hassle to just have people be
able to call you on your cell phone like a normal human being.
-- And that's,
-- I mean, sure, I, I'm not going to argue that one hardcore either way.
And, and look, man, I would say I'm a, I'm a great example of my mobile.
I've had the same mobile phone for like 20 years now
and
I've met
a lot of people, I've handed out a lot of business card and honestly finding my,
my cell phone number isn't very hard at all.
And I bet if someone like DM Ed me on Twitter, it was like, hey,
what's your phone number?
I want to call you.
I bet there's a 99.9% chance I'm going to reply with my cell phone number.
-- So
-- what's interesting to me is I actually do
keep a tab on my cell phone number to make
sure it's not showing up in Google with my name.
Now, obviously, my phone number shows up in all the
reverse directory searches,
but it doesn't have any data other than the
generic which carrier belongs or used to belong to.
So I've actually been pretty successful with that over the years.
But anyway, so number three is review your credit card bills,
bank statements and phone bills if something doesn't add up,
report it immediately.
Yeah,
except I don't get those for like 30 days and sometimes Attackers
will line that up at the beginning of a billing cycle.
So that you, yeah, it's like four weeks later. You're like, whoops. Yep. Yep.
So, and then number four, I actually like,
but I don't think they took far enough is do not
use the same user names and passwords across several websites.
Make your passwords long complicated and difficult to guess. No.
-- Use a password manager.
-- Well, yes, but
don't. Yes. Yes. Yes, I agree.
So, honestly not the worst advice and then general tips to keep your device safer,
you know, password protect your device.
I'm always shocked when, like,
when my kids were younger they would pick up anybody's phone and start, you know,
trying to play with it.
Right. Because phones are awesome
and the number of people where
their phone wasn't
like locked,
like they didn't have a PIN number or anything. I was just like,
-- what, like, who are
-- you? I still know a lot of people that don't
and
I think the fingerprints and the biometrics have
made that a lot easier because I've noticed
now most people I know with a biometric sensor will at least have their phone locked.
But, yeah, I mean,
a couple of years back I knew lots and lots of people especially will say
people of a certain generation.
Yeah. Ok.
But,
but they, uh, they often did not put locks on their phone and whatever. Either way.
I,
that's one of those situations where
if you, as long as you have your phone, it's not a huge deal. Yes.
If you misplace it or someone steals it or whatever.
-- But
-- I feel like it's in the same category of not locking your front door.
People should not go into your house and stealing your stuff.
But at the same time I personally feel a bit stupid and embarrassed if I just left my
door unlocked and got robbed.
Well, your insurance company isn't going to pay for anything either.
-- They're going to be annoyed
-- with me. Right.
If you're like, oh, someone broke in and stole my TV. And I didn't lock my front door.
They'd be like, well, that was neat. You know, you're on your own.
What really gets me with the SIM swapping thing is that there's a
large class of SIM swapping attacks that I cannot protect myself against.
They're done at the carrier level. Right. Like that case with,
you know, where they, they fish,
an employee of some phone reseller that
where the phone reseller legitimately needs to
be able to go into carriers and reassign SIM cards and stuff because,
you know, people want to port their number over.
Right.
Like the last time I actually changed cell phone providers a couple of years ago
and, you know, ported my number over
and got a new SIM card along with that.
Yeah, I mean, that's,
and now granted I went to like the phone store of the phone carrier.
I didn't go to like some independent one.
But
so there are very legitimate cases where you need basically like
random 18 year olds to have access to port SIM card,
you know, to port sim numbers.
Otherwise they can't sell SIM cards or phones
with, you know,
porting the number over which is nobody wants to give up their number.
Like my parents have had the same phone number since, well before I was born.
It's like literally one of the three phone numbers. I know I can dial 911. Pizza 73.
And my parents
wait, did you say pizza? 73
pizza, 73. Dial 4737373. Pizza 73.
Boom,
dude,
they're open till four in the morning.
That alone makes it worth knowing that number.
It's terrible. Pizza
doesn't matter,
-- but they're open till four in the morning
-- as long as there's two important things,
if you're a pizza place, people have to know how to get a hold of you
-- and that you have to be open late because you have to be
-- open past bar close.
Yeah.
Exactly. Exactly.
-- Especially when it's minus 40 outside.
That's right.
So,
-- you made my daycare? That's awesome.
-- Yeah.
And it's also the phone number I use when I don't
want to put my real phone number in a form,
those poor people, you better tip them well, for all the crap.
Oh, they've got some giant call center that works from home thing going on.
It's actually pizza 73 is actually, well,
I don't want to say an early technology adapter but they've been pretty,
like they have their own app.
They have, you know, their call center people work from home, like they're,
as I understand it.
They're pretty on the ball. Yeah.
Anyway,
so, you know the question because so right now at the,
at the cloud security lines actually looking at this because basically to
protect a whole bunch of accounts or just for billing info,
they require a phone number which
I don't have the choice of not using for account recovery.
Like, that's just how they do it, right. These various vendors.
And so we're trying to find a phone carrier that has, like,
really strong security so that our SIMS don't get swapped.
I doubt that's possible.
Doesn't exist. Yeah,
doesn't exist.
So, what we came up with is essentially we're going to go with cash to like,
7-Eleven or whatever.
Buy some, you know, essentially buy a burner phone.
Like a drug dealer would from some random carrier,
a couple of them and just never publish the number anywhere, you know, and just,
and just use social security through obscurity basically.
And that's all I got. I mean, if anybody wants to, you know, email
-- and tell me I'm wrong and there's a better way to do it, please
-- do.
I mean,
maybe the only problem I could see there is if
for some reason somebody forgets to pay the bill,
it goes on a corporate card and actually with the prepaid,
it's even better because my son has prepaid through 7-Eleven,
the money expires after one year,
but you typically have to top it up every six months or whatever.
So it doesn't run down to zero.
So I just have like a monthly email to
check his account and make sure it hasn't expired.
So
I have to put money
-- in
-- that part isn't the issue. The problem is going to be if you get the emails
and then you get hit by a bus.
Well,
that's why and that's the other reason for centralizing
it is because right now that's the problem,
right.
All this stuff is hooked up to my personal phone.
Well, and that's fair then. Right.
And so, for example, we're going to,
I know you're not supposed to share user names and passwords, but in this case,
we're actually going to share the user name and password amongst, you know,
the two or three tech people so that we can all make sure that, that, yeah,
-- that phone is paid for
-- Lastpass Enterprise is full.
-- Exactly.
-- And that's what we use. Yeah,
that's fair.
-- That's fair
-- because exactly, that's the other problem with cell phones.
Cell phones in general are locked to a person.
Yeah, I mean, that's the idea.
Well, and especially I'm up in Canada, they're down in the US,
like them trying to deal with my provider
because like me trying to deal with my provider is enough of a pain.
-- Yeah,
-- they're all terrible for the most part.
So, you know what part of this is as well is that
this is, I,
I love it when this happens because there was a problem
that needed to be solved and it basically resolved around identity
and somebody realized what's the one thing basically everyone
has now in that a cell phone number and,
and we built this infrastructure around a cellphone number, right?
And it totally,
it, I understand why. But obviously, like the cell phone
infrastructure and networking ideas were never designed for all of this. Right.
Well, neither was the social security or social insurance number, right?
There was meant to be your tax ID.
Not, well, you actually have to give that up to get a cell phone. General.
-- Well, used to when they were on plans I don't know about now.
-- Right. Right. Exactly.
They still ask, but at least in the US if I don't give it to them,
they get grumpy but you still can pull it off.
-- But, yeah. Yeah. Yeah, exactly. That's exactly
-- right.
What alternative do we have the answer is we don't have one.
No,
that's the other thing is phone numbers tend to be unique. I say 10
unique.
I did some research into this and it's not necessarily 100% true. Always.
But by and large they're unique.
Right. Right.
Well,
I think it's better now because I don't know how
it was in Canada when you were a wee lad.
But in the US
area codes were a huge part of phone numbers. So obviously
you'd have seven digit dialing in most locations.
Whereas now it's 10 digit dialing because everyone
just uses area codes all the time.
We had that happen a few years ago because Alberta used to be one area code 403.
And then we split Northern Alberta became seven.
All of Alberta was one area code a
million people. It's enormous
and it's like we have two cities and a bunch of farms
and some nice mountains.
That's true.
And now we've got 78 0, the 587 and then a new one I can't remember for the life of me and
who cares even because with, with cell phone portability now
it's always funny because
I live in one area code and myself
one
from another. And so any time I start telling people my number, I always start with
area code first I say area code and then the area code because
otherwise they just assume I have the same area code as everyone else.
I haven't heard, like, even locally, well,
locally everybody does area code because pretty much
all the new cell providers use 587,
not the 780.
got you.
See, I'm in a location that still primarily is one area code for the most part. Right.
Right.
But no, I get that.
Yeah, but you're in a big city.
-- I mean, I'm
-- not, I mean, honestly, like,
when I went into my account and found I didn't have a PIN number.
Yeah,
I went and set one and honestly beyond setting up your
pin number on your account and not having it be 1234.
I don't really know what you can realistically do to quote, unquote,
protect your phone number to protect your,
there's actually something I've been meaning to do
that.
I, I haven't even verified if this is real,
but I use T Mobile as my provider here in the,
and according to rumor,
I can call them and basically tell them you have to put a special setting
on my account that I can only go into a store to make changes.
I cannot do it over the phone.
I don't know about the specifics of it, but Laura Shin talked about that.
How there are various carriers now have like this phone number is like a,
there's a safety risk or a security risk.
And so there's extra precautions put on it to prevent porting or
swapping.
And yeah, I honestly, here's what's going to happen. If you do do that,
It's going to be great until you travel to Europe and
break your phone or lose your SIM card in Europe.
-- And then you're going to be so annoyed
-- maybe.
But then if that happened,
I would be shocked if I can buy a SIM card in Europe and
call T Mobile in the United States and get them to enable it.
You probably could because
you have Mobile in Germany.
They're different companies though, even though they have the same name,
they're technically different companies.
Which makes, because it's funny last time I was in Berlin,
I was not connecting to T Mobile Towers, even though I was in Berlin,
which obviously has like t mobile,
like every phone you see has a t-mobile sticker on it.
Well, t for telecom, right?
Has a T sticker on it.
And I'm like, this is hilarious because I, I think I was using Orange
Towers maybe. But yeah, it wasn't, it wasn't t mobile.
It was awesome.
But anyway, anyway,
-- this is
-- what I really frustrates me is that
a lot of vendors have extra security but it's hidden
because it incurs an extra cost on the vendors. Right.
It would be a huge cost on them. Could I mean, you know what I always think of?
I always use my parents as like the test of if my parents had this feature enabled,
what would that look like?
And
yeah,
if they couldn't call the cell company to do anything like God bless the
poor person that has to deal with them when they walk through the door.
That's,
that's all I think of because it's like, oh my goodness, every,
every time my dad says the computer's networking, I just say what you do.
And he's like, I didn't do anything.
And then after five minutes of asking him questions,
I realized he totally did something.
But
anyway, we are nearly out of time. So we should wrap this one up.
-- I,
-- I think put a pin number on your account,
try not to advertise your phone number too widely.
If you're using it for things like crypt,
I would say crypto exchanges are probably the highest value target now
because it's just so easy to disappear the money and it's gone,
like with a bank, they can kind of claw it back.
They, they can totally, I mean,
-- it'll take a while but they'll get it back
-- unless
you move it through a money mule or whatever.
-- But beyond that, I don't
-- know. I, I think, you know what I would say to this
is that
everyone's gonna tell you to get a UB key and to use
two factor authentication applications on your phone or
whatever and don't use S MS and,
and I'm ok with all that advice, but the reality is S MS is here to stay.
Well, my bank doesn't give me an option. It's like I can use S MS or, or they can call me
on my phone number. That's my option for two
A
and I'm like,
I have
so many UB keys and I just bought the Google Titan,
which is actually the Bluetooth on.
The thing is really sweet.
-- I don't have one. I haven't tried it yet.
-- I highly recommend it.
I, well, so going off on a tangent, the Google Advanced account protection.
Honestly,
if you're willing to live with a little bit of hassle, totally worth it.
They do some stuff that would definitely apply
to people who are being targeted attacks.
So for example, under o
off they disable some of the more dangerous API S
reportedly like things like access to your actual email content.
But basically by and large is what I love is they, they
don't force but they strongly encourage you during set up to have two keys
-- like a master and a backup.
-- Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah, everyone should do that.
Yeah.
Well, and because I hate the providers that do two factor authentication
with Fido or UTF or whatever, good thing that I can use with my UB key or my Titan key.
But I'm only allowed to register one key because
he
guys, I'm just like, well, I am,
I guess we're falling back to my phone number.
-- Exactly.
-- So
that was a useful exercise.
-- Yep. Yep. That's, that's good advice.
-- So, I guess
if there's one thing I want to say is if
you're going to support two factor authentication with hardware tokens
for the love of all. That's holy. Please let us register more than one token.
That's right.
That's right. Ideally three or four.
Because I now with Google, I've got five tokens registered on each of my accounts
and I can put one of them in my safety deposit box and forget about it.
Five seems excessive.
Well,
I have three UB keys because I used to have a personal one and a business one
and then I bought a spare one that I never was going to give to somebody maybe.
And then
the Google pack comes with, you know,
the Titan USB Bluetooth key and then a regular USB key.
So here I am with five,
I'm just gonna end it there.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening.
You go to over
social security podcast.com. Hit up the show note, Suzy Pound.
It says podcast hashtag do hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks.
Everyone. Bye bye.