Emojis one give up.
-- I used to care. I don't anymore. Emojis one.
-- Hello and welcome to the open source.
It's not that we lost. It's just that the, the world moved on from us.
-- Like rock didn't lose to bronze. It's just bronze is better.
-- I guess
-- emojis are better. That's the
-- answer. Mitchell and Webb. Anyways,
-- emojis are
-- better.
There's something
whatever.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in probably not a crime.
-- Josh Pressers, whatever.
-- You can't prove that.
Exactly.
And that's kind of the point of today's episode.
Also, I'm leaving,
I'm leaving your first attempt in your first attempt is staying because it was,
it's too funny.
OK. Fair. Anyway. Anyway,
what are we talking about? Ok.
So we're talking about the Note I PC thing where basically one
of the devs got a bit touchy about the Russian invasion of Ukraine
and put it in a code update that as I understand it does a go IP
check
like, I guess some external database
and if you're in Russia or, and I always butcher the pronunciation of this beer.
Belarus
is what we call it here, which means it's probably wrong.
Basically,
I think,
was it,
it originally displayed a warning and then on the second part it wi it tried
to arm our f your hard drive or was it the other way around?
I have no idea.
I just know everyone's losing their minds because it's actually deleting data.
Yeah, I think that was the
anyways, whatever. And again, it's kind of like,
yeah, that's,
that's what happens if you just pull down random
code from the internet and run it without checks.
-- Like that is a real possibility.
-- I mean, look, I think there's a general perception
that downloading anything from any of the major language package,
registries is a relatively safe operation.
Ok.
-- Would you say that putting a CD in your system is a safe operation?
-- What's a CD?
Ok. Well, exactly. So
maybe a USB drive.
-- Remember Sony BMG? No,
-- I, I agree.
And that was completely ridiculous and they got sued and lost.
No, no, they didn't lose.
No, this is one of those situations where they technically lost.
But who cares because I'm going to read it to you. So,
the Texas,
the Texas lawsuit didn't matter. It literally didn't matter.
Class action suits were filed against Sony BMG in
New York and California on December 30th 2005.
The New York Times reported that Sony BMG had reached a tentative
settlement of the lawsuits proposing two ways of compensating consumers who had,
who have purchased the affected recordings
according to the proposed settlement,
those who purchase next CP CD will be paid $7.50
per purchased recording and given the
to download a free album or able to download
three additional albums for a limited list of recordings.
If they give up their cash incentive district, Judge Naomi Rice
Buchwald entered an order tentatively approving the settlement on January 6th,
2006.
Now, here's my favorite part.
The settlement was designed to compensate those whose
computers were infected but not otherwise damaged.
Those who have damages that are not addressed in this class action are
able to opt out of the settlement and pursue their own litigation.
How exciting
that's like saying, oh, Kirk got a speeding ticket lost. Yeah.
And I paid it online when I got home,
like, you know, like for you and me to get $100 speeding ticket is
who cares
for Sony to get, you know, some settlement but $7.50
per affected customer, who cares?
-- I mean,
-- yeah, but don't forget the lawyers made a fortune.
Yeah.
Well,
and you, you have to sue them yourself if you want to claim damages,
-- like you
-- can
-- take them
-- to like small claims court in the United States.
I mean, because I think less than $1000 maybe you go to small claims court,
they probably wouldn't even show up.
You'd win automatically.
Yeah. So if you have less than $1000 in damages. Who really cares?
-- I mean, just eat it and move on.
-- Maybe
like
so here's the thing
and, and here's the thought experiment.
Let's put it bluntly,
let's ignore all the contract issues and let's just cut to the heart of the chase.
Open source developer is something you strongly disagree
with that you think is malicious and nasty.
So you opt to sue them.
Number one, you have to prove damages. Ok?
-- Let's assume that you can
-- prove, oh,
no one's no one's gonna sue an open source developer.
-- No way.
-- Ok.
And I'll tell and do you know why they're never
going to sue them because they don't have any money?
Yes, I was about to say there's, they're judgment proof
because I mean, if, if,
if you can prove that you've lost
more than $100,000 somehow,
like if you've lost between 10 and $100,000
it might be worth suing them theoretically.
But until you get to $100,000 it's not really worth even thinking about.
But here's the problem.
You now have the $100,000 of losses plus the
probably 50 to $100,000 or more of lawyers fees.
At least you sue the open
source developer, you win. And I guarantee you
almost no open source developer has a
quarter million dollars in assets lying around.
Probably not.
I mean,
I I'm honestly less interested in that aspect of this
and that would only be one affected person suing them.
There are multiple, usually
like 100 times a quarter million is a big number that
let's put it this way.
If an open source developer has those kind of assets,
they're probably on a beach somewhere.
Well, and they're not gonna,
they're not gonna purposely hijack their, their library because they have assets.
They know they're gonna lose them all in the event. This goes sideways.
So this whole thing is beyond,
-- in my opinion because no, no,
-- I don't think it is.
I think you're thinking about it in the wrong way. I think here's what I'm seeing,
talked about. There.
There is,
I think the legal aspect of this is interesting from an academic perspective,
but I don't think it's a realistic conversation topic at all.
What I'm seeing people say is OK.
-- So it was colors Js and then it was, I forget what the other package even was.
-- Baker Js.
This is the other one
F
or Js.
And now it's this thing, like, why does this keep happening?
And it's always been a thing, has it though?
Yeah.
Over the, it happens about once or twice a year,
-- people get all kerfuffle up but
-- we're like on three a year and it's March.
OK.
The shareware days,
how many different shareware had like a virus put in if you didn't,
you know,
pay for it or some kind of copyright protection that did something malicious.
I'm not aware of
very many of those that actually did something malicious. Not
awfully willful malice. Remember that's the key.
It's one thing when something dumb happens, it's another thing when you will
-- cause damage.
-- And, well, the Sony BMGC DS
-- and
-- I agree that was willful malice. And Sony went to court and lost. Right.
Like there. That is an open and shut case.
This one, if it went to court would be open and shut.
It's, it's not important though.
I think the real question for people is there's going
to be people who say is my open source software safe
to be running.
In my opinion at this point is just that question doesn't matter because it won.
But I think for our purposes,
this is a legitimate question. Like why does this keep happening?
So here's the thing,
I think part of the problem is people are forgetting the law of large numbers here.
There we go to put it bluntly if you take a billion people.
Yeah, somebody's gonna stub their toe today.
-- Why do people keep stubbing their toes?
-- How many node packages exist?
Yeah, there's over a million
million. I think it's 2 million now.
I bet it's way more than that.
I think it's about last.
Oh no,
I remember when they announced 1 million and
I think currently somewhere between two and three,
my suspicion is it's way higher than that.
And so yes,
that is the key is there are so many node packages.
And I think node also given the way their ecosystem works.
Node encourages very small packages
and very small packages and lots of dependency chains.
And so what that means, very small packages also mean very small development teams.
-- Usually one person, one person can do this
-- actually, usually less than one person
if we're a
fraction of one person
-- that's
-- fair.
And in many cases,
a lot of these are borderline abandon wear with one
person who's maybe got like 10 or 20 or 100.
I literally took over a fedora package at one point because I needed to
change about four lines of code in it to get it to work again.
We've all
been there.
I was not maintaining this thing properly, like I got it working and then I,
-- you know, I just ignored it.
-- I
just had that happen to me maybe three months ago or someone emailed me and was like,
hey, are you still maintaining this package?
It's like
I haven't committed anything for this package in 10 years,
years. What do you think? I mean, I'm clearly not. But right.
And so this, I think is the important point
about everything we're seeing in open source.
I think you can easily make the argument that larger
projects can potentially have more structure and security and,
and no one's going to argue with that point.
But I think the important part is when we look at, especially the node ecosystem.
There are
an infinite number of points of failure
in nearly any project.
And so someone will say, oh, but some important project depended on this one.
Everything depends on everything in the node world.
It's common to have hundreds to thousands of dependencies.
Well, and let's go on a quick tangent for a moment. But let's say for the moment
that I changed my code so that nobody in country X can run it.
Like I don't do something like, you know, actively
damaging to their computer. I just say like,
you know, if you're part of this IP block don't run.
OK? And you can argue that's malicious but whatever, let's ignore that for a moment.
Now, here's the thing. So what are people in that country going to do?
Well, they can basically
ignore the license fork,
the code and kind of grab it and take it themselves and start using it, right?
And here's the thing from my perspective as a developer,
that's my everyday. That's normal. That's what's going on.
People are grabbing my stuff and giving me nothing in return.
-- Yeah, I mean,
-- that's how
sources works though, right?
And that's why so often these, you know, successful programs like
NSA, for example, great example, this guy,
French guy Renaud poured his heart and soul into this piece of software and it is,
it was one of the best security scanners
and a ton of companies made a ton of money
off of it and he got exactly nothing in return.
And so he went, well, saw this and he basically stopped kind of working on it.
Open source wise, commercial and, and took it commercial
so he could, like, eat food.
Yes. And I, I support his decision to do that 100%.
I mean, it really sucked because it was a great tool.
And now it's, you know, the, the, the plugins and libraries where um you,
it was anyway, Tanba owns it.
Now.
It was nice when it was open source.
It was less nice when it was closed source or not closed, whatever.
But the point is from
99.9% of developers viewpoints.
I wrote this thing, I released it to the world and
well, I got exactly nothing in return and that's normal.
And so for their perspective, when those people are like, oh you know, if people,
if you do something stupid with your code,
people will get angry at you and like fork it or whatever.
And it's like that, that's already how they live their life.
Like they're not getting anything helpful in return from these people
the majority of the time that's not a useful threat.
I don't understand what the point of this tangent is.
The point is that one of the main arguments was that if you do this, the,
the community will reject you and will stop helping you.
And I'm like the community already has stopped helping most of these people.
That's why they're getting ticked off and doing these things.
-- Like that's why the color and faker guy did this. I
-- mean, that's a moot point.
I think, I don't think that's realistic as, as an excuse.
I think there's this perception sometimes that there's way more cooper
operation in the open source world than there really is.
I think for the vast majority of, of libraries and applications,
it's one or two people and nobody helps.
It's just,
it always, it always amuses me when people talk about the community
and it's like it,
you have to build a community community doesn't just show up like there is no,
the community that will come and do a bunch of work for free.
The community is
hundreds and hundreds of hours of enormous effort to build.
I mean,
we're seeing this with the GSD project we're working on like
it is a phenomenal amount of effort to bootstrap a community
where III I knew this at the beginning and I'm not
at all surprised by how much work it's it is.
People seem to think there's a whole bunch of
magic resourcing out there just wanting to help but somehow not being allowed to or
not like a perfect example. OK.
I'm looking at this one random N PM package, 87 million weekly downloads
for collaborators.
That's normal. That's how N PM works, man.
Well, now remember too,
there's another angle to this that makes N PM kind of wonky is N PM.
Also heavily relies on things like C I CD and unit testing and all that jazz.
So
the number of actual downloads,
most of this stuff has is actually a really small number.
-- Most of that is like C I CD Magic but
-- still 90 million is a lot.
It is. No, II I agree.
It's, it's definitely a popular package.
-- I also just found one that had five,
-- 5 million or five downloads. No,
five,
-- like 1234,
-- five. I mean, ok,
but when you have millions and millions of
-- packages, that, that's the long tail.
-- Right?
Anyways, what frustrates me is that this is rare enough.
It's like a plane crash that it actually makes the news
and that I think is kind of a good sign.
This is literally rare enough that every time it happens
we talk about it on Twitter for like two weeks.
Well,
and I think there's another part of this that often gets lost and
I talk about all the time whenever this happens is I view the
open source universe,
especially the security goons as a sort of like immune system for the internet.
Now, when, when a pathogen attacks you,
like the immune system doesn't immediately get the pathogen, right?
It takes a little time.
And so any time there is,
uh let's say malicious package or security event or whatever,
there's going to be some lag time between
something being back doored or hacked or whatnot and everyone figuring it out.
And, but I think if you look at open source,
this happens pretty fast for the most part.
I don't think there's many examples of this taking months
and months and months for someone to sort out.
Whereas you can read some of these stories of close source and
it takes like sometimes years for someone to sort this out.
I think there are a few, a handful of ones that take weeks or months to sort,
but usually there are things that like nobody cares about or uses.
So it's literally,
it's like the case.
So if I found I was downloading security advisors from a
vendor and a Linux vendor and they had like three broken links
in their page
and I
tell them and they're like, oh yeah, we'll fix that. Sure. Done. Click.
-- And like nobody had complained in the one page was from 2015. Well,
-- look, man,
the GSD project is the first organization.
I think that's actually looking at a lot of this data.
And so we're going to find a lot of that, but you're right. It doesn't really care.
It doesn't really matter.
Well. Exactly.
And I think so, like if, if a flaw happens in a tree that only two people care about
well, and, and that's just it.
Right, you're gonna see backdoors and malicious code in
little use software and now, I'm not saying that's not important because if,
if it's a targeted attack and you're one of
the four organizations on the planet using it,
like you have a problem.
But I think generally speaking,
when you have a relatively well used piece of software,
as soon as something like this goes down,
it's noticed pretty quickly and I think this
is one of the superpowers open source has,
is the lead time between bad thing being inserted
and bad thing being found is pretty small.
I think it's more important than that. In that
with open source,
there are
very
visible public feedback channels that cannot be
ignored or rather if they are ignored,
somebody forks the project on github
and says I am the new real color dot Js
and everybody goes OK. Cool. Yeah.
Yeah, we trust you more than that weird guy that did that weird thing to the program,
right?
And that's the thing like these feedback loops matter and
they don't exist in close source because in close source,
you submit a bug.
Yeah, I, I don't know what step two is like, step two is whatever the company decides.
It is. Good luck.
And if you don't like it, you can take it on Twitter maybe.
But especially like in the sort of github
that, you know, structured ecosystem with issues and stuff,
it's really easy to file an issue, get it made public, put it out on Twitter.
And even if the upstream tries to ignore it.
They can't, or rather the community will not ignore it if it matters.
Like in this case.
And I think that's one of the differences is it's less about the many eyes.
These open source bugs are visible.
I think it's more that with this open source in structure,
once the bug or the prom is discovered, it cannot be ignored.
-- I mean,
-- you know what,
I think that is a better rule than Linus's law because of the whole,
with many eyeballs, all bugs are shallow, which,
which ironically I've read something that, as
people look, it, it, it does and it's, I think history is shown it.
It's not the case, but you're right. I think
-- it can't be ignored. Well,
-- like tab, so
he put out this thing with the whole, um, uh, what was it? The square root
something, something square roots certificates. I don't know, whatever.
Go read his advisory. It's great. Probably
ss
and, but the numbers were shockingly low. It was like 13 and like 690 something.
And somebody's like, wait,
couldn't you just like brute force fuzz that like 1000 times 1000 times,
1000 times 1000 you could try every combination
from like 0 to 1000 for each of those four numbers in like a trillion
tests.
Which,
yeah, I might take a week on a laptop. No big deal.
And it's kind of like, yeah, I guess nobody bothered to check whoops.
How, how would you check that? There's not a lot of people who can do that kind of work.
True. True. But I mean, and that's the thing. I think a lot of the bugs require
not a lot of expertise,
but like you need to understand c or you need to understand some math or you
need to understand a basic bit of crypto which let's face it almost nobody does.
You know, I'm always reminded of house inspections who, you know,
hands up in the audience who's had a house inspection
and then you moved into the house and found something broken like a week later
that the house inspector missed
-- all of us.
-- That's normal.
I mean, the, the real purpose of that,
I always get ticked off with house inspections because
they hand you a phone book of stuff.
And it's like this is basically like is the foundation ok? Is the roof ok?
Is the house gonna collapse?
-- Like that's what it's really supposed to be about
-- is the foundation ok?
It's a finished basement.
-- Who knows? Well,
-- that's why you hired an inspector man.
Like part of their job is figuring that out.
Well, I'm just saying, like, for example,
like without tearing the finished basement apart or digging a hole outside,
how do you inspect the foundation of a house?
The answer is you don't,
you just hope it doesn't leak.
No, I think the important thing is these feedback loops where,
because the shocking, like the majority of security bugs
are
once they're understood, assuming that they're complicated and,
and the majority of them are things like cross site scripting or
like a logic error. Logic errors are kind of self evident.
Like, oh, if you do this and do this and do this,
it allows you in through authentication when it's not supposed to because of this.
Oh,
yeah. Huh. That's bad. Log. OK. Let's fix that versus
something like complicated, like, you know,
stack guard in the Linux kernel where it's like, oh boy, you know, go get Florian,
make them deal with it, you know, because I'm not going to understand this,
but the majority of security bugs,
like once you show them to somebody,
like I would say, probably 80 to 90% of them are, you know, a five minute two line fix.
Make sure it didn't break anything or make it worse.
That would be an interesting statistic.
I know you're pulling that out of your butt,
but I would be really interested in knowing if that's real or not.
Would you agree? I'm a terrible programmer. I mean,
-- you
-- see,
come
on,
I feel bad agreeing with that. But
yes,
but here's the thing I have analyzed on
the order of 50,000 security vulnerabilities since 2000.
Probably.
I did the math once between eyesight partners. I defense
Red Hat.
Um
Yeah,
I've done on the order of analyzing and looking
at 50,000 security vulnerabilities and the vast majority of them
were not that complicated.
Like even, oh, I'm going to pick on the DNS for a second bind. Right.
They would always ship those security updates as
part of like a 200 kilobyte patch set.
Right.
And it would take me who again, I'm a terrible programmer.
-- Take me usually about 5 to 15 minutes to track it down.
-- I mean,
yeah.
-- Yeah,
-- based on a one entry and a change log and here's a 200 kilobyte diff.
And I literally just do keyword searches until I find like, oh, look,
they like fixed a buffer array.
That's probably it.
That's what I love about open source is the majority of these.
Like, that's what I love about the loss kernel. They're like a bug is a bug.
We just fix the bugs, maybe the security,
maybe they're not, we just fix the bugs and move on. Cool.
Run current. Good luck with that.
Ok. You know,
or run their LTs if you want something a little more stable,
even their LT si checked last time was up over 400 versions.
But, um, I, I think that's the important thing is versus reporting a bug to a,
a close source company.
And
it's just like, well, now what?
Well, I, so I think that's kind of the,
the point of everything we've talked about so far
is you're going to have people saying Oh,
open source.
What's going on? Can we trust N PM?
Can we trust the community who's paying attention to what's going on here?
And the reality is I, is it better in the closed source world? No, maybe we don't know.
-- My guess is not. But here's
-- my simplest response. OK. Stop trusting N PM.
-- Go read it yourself. Come back and tell me how that goes for you. No,
-- I, I agree.
Well, and that's, that's the real, that's the reality of it is just
the, the value of this software is immeasurable.
It's a number with so many zeros we can't fathom it.
No, it's, it's not even that. It's,
I can't make my own pencil
or, well, the, the TED talk where the guy tried to make his own toaster.
You just, you can't
-- do that.
-- You can, it just takes like a year.
Yeah. Like the reality is you can't
make anything from scratch and that's, that's the ugly secret with software,
right?
With software.
Unless you, like, if you want to build it yourself, you're starting from scratch.
Otherwise you're pulling in libraries and dependencies.
-- Yeah. No, I, I agree. I just, it's not realistic to talk like that. It's
-- ridiculous.
-- Like, and that's, that's the story.
-- Like you don't have a choice.
This is like, saying,
disagree with the modern economy. I don't want to live in the modern economy. Cool.
Even if you try to live in a cabin in the woods you're
still going to have to interact with the modern economy to some degree.
Oh, yeah.
-- Totally.
-- Or instead of the modern,
I, I don't want to do capitalism.
I'm going to ignore capitalism and do something else. No,
you
can't.
No, I know.
I know.
It's the, it's the world we live in then.
That's where I come back because I,
I think what this boils down to is it's one of those cases where
this is bad,
not that bad, but it's kind of bad. But
we were happy ignoring it before and now you made us
look at it and I don't like to look at it,
you know,
and they have to reconcile that cognitive
dissonance of. Do I, I can ignore this and pretend like nothing happened or
I have to pay attention to it, but I can't say
uh we can't really do anything about it.
So let's just live with it because that's my response.
Like I literally look at this N PM note thing and I'm like, yeah, whatever.
-- That's
-- normal. Wait, what, what's normal?
Someone back door,
-- a library is normal to have
-- once in a while a person puts a back door in or
um, like my favorite thing is every time Microsoft has a really bad security bug,
everybody's like, ha ha ha Windows is so stupid.
I'm going to go use Linux. Cool, go do that.
Except Linux has a really bad security flaw at least once here and there was, I mean,
jeez,
there was that one in what net filter like two weeks
ago where it's like local code execution and net filter.
I still don't.
-- Anyways,
-- we just talked about that
-- like we literally did a whole podcast on it.
-- That was like 100 vulnerabilities ago.
I
know, I
know it
sounds like it was a year.
No, no, I
think your spot on is
this given the open
source ecosystem,
especially in the node ecosystem because it's so
large that when you are architecting how your
open source just is going to function in
your company and everyone should be doing this.
If you're just like,
if you're just grabbing and praying, like you got other problems,
you need to actually manage and take care of your open source.
-- It's, it's a bit like a puppy.
-- Well, you need to at least be aware of what it is and
yeah.
-- Right. Right. No. Exactly. Yeah.
-- Absolutely.
I honestly grabbing and praying is fine. I'm not that opposed to it.
-- No,
-- I don't think it is. I don't think it is. I, I think,
I think any reasonably sized development group can't be doing that.
I think if you're like five people, you can maybe get away with it.
But once you're of a certain size that's, uh,
it's an untenable position to be in. You can't do it.
The challenge becomes as soon as you start pulling indep dependencies.
Oh, my goodness. Oh, Wow. Ok.
I'm just looking at the yarn lock file for the main CS, a website.
-- Wow.
-- Oh, it's probably a disaster.
-- Yeah. This thing is bigger than I
-- remember.
Yeah, you should, uh, you should get the,
get the gripe vulnerability scanner and you should run
it on that and see what it looks like.
No, I know they're fine because they use the yarn audit,
bundle audit stuff and I think there's like, oh yeah, that works too.
I would say on average they have like 1 to 3
CV S kind of outstanding that they're dealing with that.
They take on average about a week or two to get rid of them depending on whatever.
-- But you
-- also, I, I know that's a relatively small team.
It, things change depending upon your environment. And in the case of the CS A,
you can basically just stay up to date and you're probably going to be ok.
Not everyone can do that. And I think pretending everyone can is preposterous.
Oh, yeah. I love when people like, run current and it's like, cool.
I run my favorite is there's that Linux design for like pipeline equip
that is both one completely inaccessible because it's literally at the
bottom of a hole at the bottom of an ocean.
And two, it needs to be there and work for 50 years to 100 years.
It's probably fine or
just don't hook it up to the internet, it'll be fine.
Except we need those reports,
whatever. But, um, anyway,
you know, and that's ii,
I get that telling people to run current is absolutely not a realistic solution.
Especially once it's like medical stuff or
industrial stuff or like light bulbs.
Like, I don't, oh, my favorites. Remember all those people were talking about?
They bought those grills and they don't turn the grill on often enough.
So it's exactly like you with your pre tripp,
you upgrade your software so that when you go up on stage and turn your laptop on,
it's not like, hey, there's an update,
I'm just going to go do this for three hours and like.
-- Right. Right.
-- Good luck with your presentation.
Right.
If you're on Linux, this doesn't happen. Just saying. But
no, no, I, I think anyway to, to bring us back to where I think we need to go to end.
This is, this is
a reality
and I think any competent architect in any competent,
just I guess whoever's in charge of your development team,
you have to expect this and plan for it.
And I think this is part of having good process, having good tooling,
having good expectations and understanding and you can say, oh,
this is preposterous.
I shouldn't have to deal with this and you can say that,
but then you don't get the benefit of infinity dollars worth of an open source.
Yeah,
I'm just looking at it looks like we have
a ballpark figure of 2001st order dependencies plus then
whatever they pull in
no package
like dot Json
is everything
-- ok. So then it is 2000
-- every layer.
If you look at package dot
Json, that'll tell you your dependencies.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Sorry. That's where my brain was going.
It's ok. It's complicated. I do this every day.
Yeah.
Oh, there we go. Yeah. Sorry. I thought, you know what?
I actually thought I was looking at package
Json but I said the other one, didn't I?
Yeah, you said package lock? Oh, I love this package dot
JSON is only like 4045 things. It's just some of them are like node
-- like we pull a node. What's in that? No, that's
-- what node does.
I, I actually have a nice demo.
I give of this where I take I,
I create an Express project which there's this thing in node called Express,
which is like a little web server thing
and it has six dependencies N PM installed, gets you to like, I think it's 90
then you put it in a container and you're up to like 1000
and it's like
this is how it works.
-- Like that's just life
-- better safe than sorry. You might need that spell check.
I mean,
-- anyway, anyway,
-- I just remember when I did an audit of that,
that Rails product that Red Hat bought and it was like American date that it was an
N PM thing called American Date and it was like 10 lines long and it just converted
-- normal sane rational dates into the American format, which is
-- stupid.
-- It is completely stupid.
-- I agree.
And I'm like,
it's probably not a security vulnerability and has been updated in eight
years and I hope it's complete and it's like 10 lines.
So it's probably ok, it's probably fine.
I just keep going back to the whole, like, what's the alternative?
Write it yourself? Like,
-- I don't
-- have the alternative is you have to plan for this. Like that's it.
The alternative is this is going to happen.
You have to expect it to happen and you have to plan
-- for it to happen. That is how it works. Like, welcome to the future.
-- You know what?
There's always going to be another log for Jay in
-- N PM or something
-- log for J wasn't in NBM.
Basically there's going to be a log for Jay in something you use.
No, but I'm saying there's going to be a log for J situation in whatever you use
and,
or a rude word you have to get rid of from your code base or something like that too.
I think we covered this multiple previous podcasts. But if you can't,
you need to be able to do emergency code updates and changes on a,
without it being some heroic effort that burns your people out.
That's right. Exactly. Exactly.
Well, the beauty is if you do this and accomplish this.
You will be so much faster and able to do major features or sales comes along and says,
hey, if you can do this thing quickly, we can make this big sale.
Right.
And now it actually matters because you can make money.
Yep. Exactly. All right. I think, I think we got to take this one home.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna get the last word in which is just,
I think
we had the benefit of being able to ignore all
this stuff for a long time and that's done.
-- You can't ignore it anymore.
-- I bet you a dollar in two years.
If we ask people about this, 95% of them will be like, what, like the Sony BMG root kit.
-- Remember? Why
-- would they? No, no, it doesn't. That, that's irrelevant.
No one is going to remember anything. Our memories are very short
but the reality is,
I think we have ignored
open source security for a very, well. I shouldn't say security.
We've ignored open source risk for a long time and we've treated it as free software
and the reality is it's not free. It has risk and you need to understand that risk.
-- That's it. And
-- the other reality is you have to use it. Yeah,
you have to use it. That's, I'm going to start saying that you have to use open source.
-- It's not a, it's not an option.
-- Microsoft ships it.
Microsoft owns it. Like they own github
if you github
is open source now.
Yeah,
I know. I know.
And oh man, that last episode, like I want to like you Microsoft, stop, stop it.
Anyway. All right, I'm calling you. Thank you.
Thank you for listening. Go to
open
our security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, Suzie PDO
Podcast hashtag hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Happy spring, everybody.
Let's hope so. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.