Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast number 20 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
It's, we're almost old enough to drink in America.
That's right.
-- Awesome.
-- Or most of America.
-- Uh So, yes. So we have, uh well, we have something, I think a little bit of fun today.
-- Uh
Santa.
Uh
No,
no,
not more fun than Santa
uh
all
way to bring it down.
-- No, the Santa episode was the, I think the best you've ever done.
-- True, true.
I have to admit I,
I'm actually really looking forward to wrapping my kids' presents.
I got them some sweet stuff.
Make sure you play with it all first just to test it.
You're testing. Uh
Yes. Yes. Yes.
But, uh
yeah, so this, uh this episode we are going to uh throw P GB under the bus.
Well, we think it's dead already.
Well, you know what it is. I, I don't, I don't think it's dead personally.
I, I know it's pretty much dead because quite frankly,
um,
I, well, I, for the listeners out there,
I used to do CV assignments on the open source security man list.
And I signed all of them so that nobody could, like,
impersonate me with a fake CV assignment.
The only reason I cared about that was just,
I didn't want to have to deal with people complaining to me.
There's no actual security thing really. It was just a convenience thing.
And so I signed my email religiously for like,
I think it was three years and then I stopped one day
and nobody noticed, nobody
knew
well,
except for the three people who had been complaining about my
signed and encrypted email because it was inconvenient to them.
And I'm lucky enough to have one of them here with me today. Josh.
I don't,
I don't think I ever complained about your signing of email just because
-- the encrypting of it.
-- I
totally used to complain.
-- You used to encrypt email to me all the time, even email that didn't matter. And it
-- is
just a blanket setting.
So I have two,
two complaints about this on one side,
anyone who signs and encrypts, all of their mail has their key
two available,
right? Because in order to do this correctly, the key needs to be difficult.
Ok.
Which means, and, and let's face it.
I'm pretty sure because you were doing this before UB keys readily available.
You had a file on a disk which means your key is acquirable.
Ok.
We'll just
me.
Right.
I don't like typing in my
password.
This is,
this is part of my point.
OK.
So you made it too easy to get to. But then conversely on my side,
my key is incredibly difficult
to get a hold of and decrypt things. And so I was happy to decrypt
important messages,
but when it was like day to day stuff, it was a nuisance to me. And so I told you to stop.
And this is, I mean, so let's face it, right.
This is part of the problem with P GP is it is hard to use
correctly.
-- It's very
-- encryption
in
general.
-- That's
-- right.
I mean, with, with, well, let me rephrase
with public private key encryption.
Yeah, like you said,
the key needs to be
difficult to attack and, and quite sadly, that typically means it's also that
securing a key. So it's difficult to attack,
typically impacts the usability heavily. Um
You know, like at a minimum,
you should be putting it on like a sort of an HS MA hardware security module device,
you know, where it can't be easily exported.
Uh which then becomes the question of like, for example,
how do you back this stupid thing up?
-- I
-- could
-- tell you a story about that if you like.
-- Is it a happy story? No,
-- no. It's, it's what I do.
And, and part of the historically speaking, I've not been
open
talking about what I do with my P GP keys and
how I protect them and what I've done because obviously,
well, I'll say obscurity.
S
security.
While security,
that is a good word. S security that we'll make that one up.
But while security through obscurity generally doesn't work.
In the case of key management and your processes,
it's not something you want to talk about.
So anyway, here's what I've done in the past to deal with all of these problems and
I created the most ridiculous Rube Goldberg machine one
could possibly create for dealing with P GP keys,
right?
So first of all,
I have a computer, I have an old line
just to confirm these were your personal keys, right? These weren't like
right important corporate keys are like keys used for like nuclear codes or
-- signing software or anything like that, right? This was your personal set of
-- keys.
This is the Josh Bresser's P GP keys. You can download off of the key servers
like like this is, this is my stuff. Exactly. Just what you,
so first of all,
I have an old laptop
that I've removed the disc out of
and all it has ever done is generate and load P GP keys for me.
Now, I only, every time I need to do any sort of operations,
I burn a new CD live image of a Linux distribution.
I boot into this machine
with no hard drive.
I do my key operations
and then I load them. It's gonna get crazier. Don't worry,
no stupid
question. But where does this machine get entropy?
To generate good randomness from
no,
no
network
into a,
there is no network. That's right.
I boot into a, a graphical workstation and then I purposely like,
play solitaire for a little while,
like, like, like for real, you know, to build the entropy. Um
Right.
I told you it's gonna get crazier. I'm not done yet. So anyway,
machine, not connected to the network. No hard drive.
I do my key operations off a live CD. The live CD is then destroyed.
I never use it twice.
And
yeah,
seriously. And I'm not done yet
because
you burned a CD and said it. So it can't be
tinfoil tinfoil
hat
because
it's not about using it again elsewhere or anything like that.
It's not about writing to it.
It's the fact that if the disk somehow has some sort of secret back door on it,
I'm not going to use it for the next set of operations I might happen to do
with the keys. Right. Exactly. It's
in this
and for what it's worth.
Like, I, I literally sat down and thought, how could I tinfoil have this
to an 11? And I, I'd say I've probably done a good job.
So anyway, generate the keys on this, right?
And then I have my Yuba key now which I store them on
and essentially I load the keys into the UB key,
right?
-- Which is fine.
-- And what exactly is the up key for our listeners
who
-- that's fair.
-- It's, um,
it's a little device there on something called UB
four. It's,
it does Hotp for authentication.
It does, it stores RS a
private keys for things like P GP and I can, I, I store an sh key on there for logging in,
for example.
And it does you.
Yes, it's a USB device and it's just a super cool little
doggy. I'll put it in the show notes. A link to the UBQ
four, which if you don't have one,
you should certainly get one. They're amazing devices.
And for what it's worth these days, I basically use it for
my HOTP log in uh U two F for things like github and Google.
And then also
it does uh uh my SSH key,
which is obviously that way I can uh whatever devices I connect to.
I never have a key on desk and I can remove the, the key
and then I can log in or not log in, I guess if it's not in.
So back to my keys. Now things continue to get more bizarre is so
I, I obviously I generate keys on this special machine.
I load the keys into my UI
key, but I still need to back them up.
And so what I did is I essentially tar up the
uh GP G, what do they call it? A key store keying, keying. It's called the keying.
And then
I have it encrypted with a password
that is
incredibly long. I'm talking about like
multiple lines long
and I don't know the password,
but I know how to generate the password because the password is
created from some physical objects by putting together the pieces of them
and, and certain, you know what I mean? Like like words
pages.
OK.
-- So
-- you're saying because there's physical objects
with words written down on them that you
basically,
I I
there are certain books in the world
that have between additions,
there are certain words, phrases and things in them that do not change.
Like for example,
let's say the names of chapters,
right? Of your book.
And so imagine this, I've basically taken a handful of physical objects
in, in my case books. OK?
I, I don't even care because like I don't use P GP anymore and I, we're,
we're proclaiming it dead.
So whatever,
essentially,
I've taken words out of books and put them together in
a certain way that I could not tell you the password,
but I know how to put it together and it takes about half an hour to do.
So it's like it is expensive for me
to decrypt my master keys.
And then those are obviously stored at a vault at the bank on
a USB drive which I never go get because I don't need.
And so
I suppose I, I should probably check on it every now and then just to make sure it's not
not going missing
but yeah, that's my,
that's my crazy G GP story.
Did you use have master keys and then you generated sub
keys that you actually used on a day to day basis?
Or?
In fact, I, I wrote a blog post about this.
I think about all the crazy things I did around the, the sub keys and whatnot because,
but again, I mean, this is part of the problem with P GP, right? Is
it's not obvious you don't like generate one key and use it.
You've got your master key, you've got your encryption key,
you've got your signing key,
you've got your authentication key and you're supposed
to rotate them every now and then one
key
now nobody does. And it's just, it's so
I understand the intent
because they wanted perfect.
-- But
-- yeah,
-- they want
-- perfect from, well, here's the problem,
I think they want it perfect from a cryptographic security point of view,
which is even more insane than a security point of view,
right?
Probably
because like let's face it, right? Like
for example, one of the challenges is, let's say, for example,
you accept encrypted email,
right? And your key expires at some point.
Well, you still have to keep that key around
to decrypt your old email and look at
it, right? Same thing with all these sub keys.
If you actually rotate your sub keys a lot,
you still have to keep them around.
So you can look at your old encrypted data, you know,
uh unless you, like, take all your old encrypted data,
decrypt it and re encrypt it with a current key and then keep
doing that every time you roll keys over which let's face it,
like nobody's like that, that would be a level of effort.
But, wow,
I just
think
about it. You heard my obscene story about key management?
Like there's probably somebody who does that. It's not me.
It's
see. And, and I think here's what to me is, I think
for most of what, and this is sad for most of what P GP was meant to be used for
it. It, it's, it's unusable, it's so it's effectively dead.
I mean, email being the primary example, right? If I want to
uh encrypt email to somebody, the first problem, I mean,
how do you find somebody's key? Right.
That's the first problem with P GP is they went with this decentralized web of trust,
supposedly.
And the idea being, you know, is that like people would get together,
sign each other's keys.
And so I would be able to say
I found a key for Bob Smith and Bob Smith's key was signed by Jane Smith
and Jane Smith's key was signed by Josh Presser and I trust Josh Presser's key.
So there's, you know, this transit of trust property except
I have no idea who these people in the middle are. Like I know who Josh is
and beyond that I have no clue.
So then to deal with that, you know,
they have different levels of trust when you sign a key, you know,
I ultimately trust this key like or I minimally trust this key.
But
as far as I know, there's no really good description of what that actually means.
No, it's never been clear.
Yeah.
Well, and then my favorite is when they do have key signing things, they're like
you should verify the person's identity.
Well, first of all, I don't know of any way to prove somebody's email address.
Like I, it's not on your passport,
right?
Like there's no piece of government ID that has your
email address printed on it as far as I know.
And more to the point,
I don't know how to validate
identification.
Right?
Like I don't,
I couldn't even validate my own driver's license or
passport that I carry with me all the time.
I, I vaguely know they have like a shiny
thing of a jigger on them that you can see in the light when you know, it reflects.
Right?
-- Yes, that's, and I'm pretty sure that can be
-- fake.
Very good.
II I could not pick out a fake ID
you could probably show up with, with something you drew with crayon. I would,
I would,
every time those, you know,
those door to door sales people come and they have like an ID,
I'm like,
I, I don't know what ID for this company looks like.
Are you kidding me? Like,
you know, I know people that work for, like,
the cable company locally and if you ask me what their ID looks like,
I would have to guess that it probably has the corporate logo on it
and their name and that's, that's all I can write reasonably. Yes.
You know, but I would have no clue how to validate that ID
or where to phone, you know. Anyway. So, moving along.
So that's my, you know, that's my first big concern with P GP is it's
just right off the bat.
If I want to use it to like encrypt email to somebody, I have to go hunt down their key,
which means basically I'm gonna go download it from a key server
and have absolutely no way to validate it
really, you know, unless it's like,
unless it's an exceptionally rare well known key, like,
you know, some like Linus to
vault or something.
And the other thing I noticed is I, uh,
one time I downloaded my own key from the key server and it was signed by people.
I don't know.
And
it's crazy.
Well, and didn't,
isn't there a key somewhere that someone has, uh,
like, like an obscene asking picture
they've attached?
Yeah, somebody, uh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
So what it was, was, um, in a, in a key signature,
there's like a line of text or whatever
and they basically signed their key like 50 or 60 times
generating like these custom signatures to, yeah, have an obscene, ask your art uh,
picture, which I guess
I guess we should link to in the show notes.
-- Are we allowed to do that?
-- I'm not going to,
ok,
you'll have to Google it yourself, figure it out. Um
But yeah, so anyways,
so
right off the bat, we essentially,
I'm just downloading random keys off the internet that are, you know,
associated with an email address.
Hopefully
yi I do that all the time.
The the few times I've used it or I love when someone sends me an a an assigned email
and it asked me, do you want to download this key?
-- And I'm like, yeah, that sounds great. Download
-- the key.
Yeah,
and that always struck me as like the perfect way to insert your
key like for an attacker to insert a key into somebody's key ring,
right is just,
you know,
email a whole pile of people as being from the victim you're wanting to intercept
and you know, get your fake key put in there.
The other problem is with the key signing is that like, you know, it's,
it's only in the last year or two that they fixed a bunch of problems that allowed
you to make what looked like.
Basically you could create keys with the same
short ID. So a key has a fingerprint and the full fingerprint
that they just told everyone to stop using the show,
they didn't actually fix it. They just, well, no, but in,
but in GP G, if I remember, right, they now default to using
the fingerprint rather than the short ID. I think anyways,
the point being is that, you know, you could,
you could force a key generation with specific key ID.
So you could have a key with the same key D as your victim's key
and you could do that for all the signing keys, right?
So you could create this key that basically looks exactly the same
from a signature point of view and everything and you know,
it would be very annoying and difficult to validate.
Um
Now, uh I know P gp.com used to do this and I don't know if they still do,
but they ran a service where you basically
could validate your key to a small degree where
you'd essentially submit your key to them. And they would email
the email addresses like on those keys saying, you know,
do you actually control this key?
And did you submit it for signing? And you would click? Yes.
And then they would sign your key,
you know, by the P GP global key signing key or whatever it was.
And they would email you,
I think every couple of months just to make
sure you still had control of that email address,
right?
And so if you look at like my one of my keys, for example,
you'll see there's like several years worth of that, you know, signatures on it,
which is kind of handy.
Um,
so that was kind of, well, basically, and that's the thing, right,
that basically boils down to like a domain validated SSL certificate,
right?
Where you just, you do a minimal amount of verification where it's like,
essentially you look like you control this email address and
for us to actually validate that you control this email address
properly.
We we can't really do that short of like coming out and beating you with a hose.
Um, because quite frankly,
if you can reply from that email address and
you can receive email to that email address.
How else do you validate that somebody
should or should not control that email address?
That seems pretty fair, right?
Like,
do you phone the provider and ask for personal
information of which they really shouldn't give you,
you know,
it's
right. I mean,
you know,
so, ok, well,
let's assume for a moment you've managed to find the other person's key.
Ok, hold on, hold on. Let's go. Let's back up one step though is
when you talk about this service from P gp.com,
which I just typed P gp.com into my web browser and it goes to Symantec now.
So I
assume that's no
longer the whole thing.
But anyway,
the kind of the intent behind all of this was to have no centralized authority.
And obviously, once you have this sort of validation system, which,
which I think we've reached the point, we kind of agree that
it is the right way to go,
which will probably get to let's encrypt at some point,
which is a great example of this.
But I, I think
there were legitimate concerns about some of this
back in the day when this was
when they were attempting to build this.
-- But I think we've reached the
-- point I think was also historically,
running a very large global scale service
was really difficult.
You know what I mean?
Like, I mean, like 1520 years ago running, say, well, for the sake of argument,
running a public database with say a million
entries that could be queried several times a minute
was actually a really difficult engineering problem
right now. Of course, you could do it for about $5 a month.
Well, ok, so I think there's two sides to that is you're right,
is it was difficult to do.
But I think there was also the concern about
what happens when
the service goes rogue.
And that is, that is always like
it has always happened and it will always happen.
You look at every service that is basically ever existed.
And at some point
they go up for sale or they get desperate or something happens
and they start making
terrible decisions,
right? Things that are designed to benefit themselves and damage the users.
And so
like, like in the instance of let's encrypt someday
they will become evil.
Ok.
Someday I'm gonna say that and,
and I will gladly accept the criticism that will come with it.
But I think we're also starting to recognize that
it's not that hard to change.
You know, remember when Source Forge is where everyone was hosting their code,
does anyone, you know, still host things on the Source Forge?
There's actually still a couple of things that are there by default,
but really, right. It's all github
now and someday this will happen at github
and we'll move to the next thing.
And I think that's part of the magic we're
starting to see now is the tools and the environment
are becoming
such that we can move around.
Whereas in the past,
I think the thought of moving away from some things was
completely out of the question and it was crazy talk.
I would agree.
I mean, if you look at the history for example of instant messengers, what was that?
Oh Jeez, I'm blanking. What was the name of that
cross application protocol?
Jabber
-- or X MP
-- P?
Yeah, whatever was
actually,
yeah.
So, well,
there was an actual low level protocol that was
supposed to be sorted by multiple messenger applications.
So that for example, like AOL could talk to Yahoo could talk to whatever else, right?
And of course, those things basically like, well, you know, became walled gardens.
And when I think about how many different instant
messengers we've been through over the last 20 years.
Like,
you know, does anybody actually remember IC Q?
I remember their website was like the biggest train wreck I'd ever.
It was so full of garbage. I remember
-- the color scheme was, yeah, I remember it was
-- pretty.
No, I do. I, I remember IC Q was hip when I was in college. That was the thing.
Everyone, because some people used AOL instant Messenger.
But those were like the old lame people. But the new exciting thing was IC Q
and of course I'm on IRC being like,
you
know, I'm way cooler than you guys, you know,
jokes on me.
-- You were cool before. It
-- was cool. That's right. That's right.
Exactly.
So anyway, so, and you know, that's the reality. We've, we've been through
a
dozen major
uh
instant messenger platforms. And I mean, a great example now is like signal,
you know,
uh signal is a new encrypted end to end,
you know, messenger app
uh that people are using and, you know, when it dies,
we'll move to something else most likely.
Um But back to P GP, I mean,
so the problem is you have this key
discovery and validation problem which,
you know, they, I
here's what frustrates me in the quest to create. Perfect.
They like just
didn't allow good
or, or near perfect to exist, right?
Um
So there's like no way at all to
in many cases get a real decent validation of this key.
Um or another great example is, you know, key expiry, right? Keys.
A lot of people set their keys to expire
and then the majority of P GP,
you know, apps and related
will then refuse to use that key once it's expired, right?
They'll refuse to decrypt stuff,
they'll refuse to encrypt stuff and you have to like
hit it with a hammer, you know, and get it into submission.
Um
So I actually remember a case where somebody reported a security
issue to us and they wanted to do encrypted emails.
So
I replied to them,
they replied to me and then the next Monday I
replied to them and my email client wouldn't let me
because their key had expired over the weekend.
Nice.
You know,
and so I was faced with a choice of either bludgeoning this thing into submission
or, you know, what, fine we're, I'm doing it plain text
and I imagine
you
did plain text,
-- right?
-- Yeah. Well, I mean, I just,
you know,
yeah, it's just, I mean, and obviously from, you know,
a usability and security perspective, it would be much better to use a
key that's been expired for 24 hours than to do clear text.
But, you know, in the quest for perfect, they decided that we don't want to,
you know, allow any potentially dangerous activity.
Uh So we're just gonna block it,
you know,
and in doing so they, well,
they make it very difficult to do something reasonably correct.
You either
can't do it at all or well, you can ignore it and do clear text, right.
Um, and, and there's a lot of other issues too, like for example, there's the, the,
the dirty little secret of all the key servers that we do have
where for example, if you're checking for key revocation,
which you probably should be doing right?
Because, you know,
maybe the person revoked their key over the
last day or two because it got compromised.
Well, if you check for key revocation every time you use it, you're now
broadcasting to the world somewhat that hey, I'm, you know,
I need to know if this key to this person
is working because I want to communicate with them.
So
what
is key
revocation?
-- So
-- key revocation is well and
Josh, you probably did this. But if you have a secret key
and it somehow becomes discovered or public or somebody, you know,
manages to get a copy of it,
you want to tell people to stop using that key.
And so you revoke it, you send out essentially a well,
it's essentially a signed copy of your key saying that this key is no longer valid,
right?
Which you know should be on the key servers. And
so when you check for that key,
you get this key that essentially has a special message saying, you know, hey,
it's don't use me, I've been revoked,
you know, it's like we do this with uh SSL and TLS certificates, you know,
in the form of the uh online certificate
status protocol O CS P
um and things like that.
Well, you want again.
So
I'll fill you in on some of my dialing up to an 11.
I have my revocation certificate for my P GP key printed out
at the bank
just in case I for some reason lose all access to the digital private key.
I have my paper copy that I can then OCR in
and then send it to the key servers.
See, and, and that kind of goes to, you know, when I think about this.
So like we're kind of lucky SSL and TLS is a bit easier in the sense of it's more,
you know,
temporal data and that it's data that
we're not gonna keep encrypted for a long, long time, right?
It's only encrypted over the network.
Whereas GP G we're,
we're using for data that's encrypted at rest and may exist for years or decades,
you know, so that is a bit of a more tricky problem space.
Um
But let's assume for a moment, you managed to find Josh's
key and you've now sent him an encrypted email.
Uh You know, we we're still not done with the problems like,
you know, what do you do when the key expires? Right?
You go bug Josh for a new key except it's signed by an expired key.
So your software automatically by default doesn't really trust it that much,
you know.
Um
So again, you're stuck with kind of bashing it into submission typically.
And then, you know, if you're checking for revocation,
you're leaking metadata and,
and then there's the key management from the user's perspective, right? Like
every time every application I've ever seen that does email
signing requires me to sign and trust the key,
which means I now have to go get my private key out
so I can send you an encrypted email, right?
You know,
and of course, I end up
uh having to set the thing to full trust because I, I don't have a choice, right?
Otherwise by default, most email apps will be like, well,
you don't fully trust this key.
So I'm not gonna
email to this guy,
you know, and it's like, damn it,
you know, anyways, sorry for the language. But uh
I think from a, from a usability point of view P GP failed
for email terribly. Now,
what's funny is I'm actually looking at
uh requiring signing of the git commits for
all the DWF uh the distributed weakness, filing related work and
miter and the CV project
are also looking at considering this because
it's not that it's 100% secure,
but it basically means instead of the attacker, you know,
sending false kit commits,
they now have to compromise a person's workstation, at least,
you know, to send in fake CV. Requests and fake CV S and stuff
which let's face it, right? An attacker
able to do that will also just send a fishing email which, you know,
would you'd have the same end effect even if you're, you know, doing true,
proper key security.
So we're looking at doing that just to basically add like a significant road bump
-- uh for Attackers.
-- Now, here's what
we
have
to get
to, what you're doing
is you are
you have a central authority,
right?
And that's why
P GP
signing
with GIT
commit
is functional. Well, no, you do have a central authority though because
you have
the
right
github, you add users, users add their GP G key and then github
basically says, holy crap. Where did this signature come from?
I don't know anything about this,
right?
Well,
we won't be using github
-- strictly. But
-- yeah,
I mean,
so essentially part of it is becoming when you become involved with the CV project.
One of the things assuming we go with GIT signing is you'll,
you'll have to provide a key,
right? You know,
and
so we'll have a copy of key of the key.
So we don't have to deal with this discoverability, you know,
and, and part of what I'm thinking about is do we require keys to expire?
Do we say please don't use keys that expire because,
you know, let's face it, you know, this isn't like super secret squirrel
stuff,
but here's the problem and
I, I don't,
I have to think about this.
I can probably give you some really good advice
on this at some point in the near future.
But,
but the fundamental problem with P GP keys
is there is no method
to easily revoke them.
And so if you, if you don't have the keys expire
and the key is compromised, which is certainly,
and I don't mean necessarily stolen, I mean,
you lose your U key or you lose a USB drive or whatever.
And you are concerned that this key material is now in the universe.
What do you do if the key never expires?
We see and what we, what we can do,
of course is because we have a copy of your key in our system,
we can just sort of manually expire it.
Right.
But obviously this doesn't scale all,
this wouldn't work at global scale with everybody doing email, for example,
you know,
-- within
-- a
-- single organization
-- it'll work. You're absolutely right.
And you can just revoke it because you know what G
gets you something very similar to the Blockchain
because you can't go back in time and change things.
Not without monkey. Well, not without breaking all the signatures. Right. Right.
Exactly. Exactly. And so,
ok, yeah, as long as you have
basically everyone signing commits,
you will never have to worry about
the sort of like a replay attack where someone goes back in time mucks with your repo
with with say stolen key material?
-- Ok.
-- Well, see, and here's the secret, right? The dirty secret is, this is
simply about adding the requirement that then the attacker
has to compromise and break into a person's workstation
in order to monkey with our system.
Which essentially
do you know
what my primary reason for requiring key signing is
it solves the spam problems?
Oh,
well,
-- yeah,
-- that solves the spam problem.
Right?
I don't have to deal with wonky requests.
I just check if they're signed, if they're not signed properly, I ignore them.
That's, you know, what else actually is as you talk about this is
we're calling this the death of P GP and we're talking about the,
the ability and use of P GP.
So,
but, but not only that you've, you've created an artificial
uh barrier of entry.
So, you know that it's,
if someone is serious about working with you,
they're gonna learn what they need to know.
But if they want to just be one of your typical drive-by trolls, that's too much work,
which I guess will span.
Right.
Exactly.
Uh Part of it too is, yeah, I mean, like you said, I mean,
for people getting involved in the CV project, I want them to have at least, you know,
you must be this high
to be involved, like to get on the right sort of so to speak
and, you know, being able to generate a P GP key
and use it minimally, like
to configure your g for signing,
you know, literally, if you are technologically incapable of doing that,
then chances are
you're not going to be a good fit for the project.
That's pretty fair.
So,
and like I said,
it basically solves the spam problem and sort of the trolling problem in that.
It makes it really easy to,
you know, if somebody violates community standards,
we, when we remove them, we it makes it really easy to, you know,
essentially filter them.
Right.
Sure.
Well, I guess so, here's the other thing that, that just came to my mind, right,
as you explain this and, and I'm thinking about it is
the, the kind of the benefit and purpose behind P GP was that decentralization
and
treating the user as the authority of themselves.
And
the model you're talking about is really a lot closer to kind of the,
the TLSC a model of.
We're, we're going to decide these people are in charge
and we're gonna put enough trust in them to just say what they say is OK is OK.
Right. And so fundamentally what you're talking about here is
I wonder if git has the ability to deal with like X 509 style signatures
where then you could do some crazy magic around
uh signature chaining or not signature
but certificate chaining and verification,
which could be really fun to research.
Uh Fortunately, I don't need to do that because I have solved that issue
in the DWFS process around how CV S are assigned and requested from subsidiaries
and, and this doesn't, this without question would be incredible overkill.
It's just,
it sounds fun.
So I try
to think about it.
Yeah.
But,
uh,
you know, and that's the thing too is I don't want to make this so painful that it,
you know, becomes
onerous
because II I don't want to have to deal with it.
So that is one of the advantages
that, that GP G brings
is you type literally like GP G, you know, what does it generate key?
And it asks you what four questions and you get a key.
Like that's cool, right? If you've ever had to generate a proper TLS certificate,
it's a nightmare unless you use lots of crypt,
right? But
that thank goodness like put all the horrible problems in someone else's bucket
and, and the people just have to wait. You run like one command and magic.
Yeah, it's a self updating Python script. That's pretty ugly.
-- But you know what it
-- works? Who cares, man? If it, if it works, it's great.
Well, that's, yeah, that's the beauty of it, right is,
and that's one of the things with security people, right? Like
a lot of security people will
are willing to give up usability in favor of like
perfect security and we end up with these systems that are
so unusable. You end up with an
unusable
-- from them because nobody
-- uses them.
It's not,
you don't give up usability for perfect security.
You give up usability and get crap. Like that's what happens.
Yeah.
Like, uh, many organizations I've dealt with, you know, I,
I kind of wish they would sign email because, you know,
we're sending around requests and,
you know, please do this, you know, sensitive things and
-- no,
no, no.
You say that, you say that, you say,
I wish they would sign the emails because I'm doing these sensitive things.
You didn't
hear the
-- second part.
-- How many times is there a problem?
Well, exactly.
And so I wish they would sign emails in a way that was super trivial,
super easy to verify, super easy to manage.
It just doesn't exist.
But the alternative is
nothing and things are basically doing fine
-- so
-- well, except, you know,
when we get those phishing attempts trying to
get us to pay $10,000 invoices or whatever,
right to some dude and like
uh where was it? New Mexico or something?
Well, I guess this is where
depending upon what you're doing,
it kind of dictates how many, how you should position your checks and balances.
And in fact, there's a lot of compliance,
especially around things like uh PC I
and Hipaa
and,
and even Sarbanes Oxley to a degree where the very
sensitive operations have significant checks and balances in them.
But the things that are less sensitive, it's like, eh, good enough. Right.
And that's kind of the right way to think about it.
Well, the problem is you can end up.
Uh, so for example, there's a local college, uh, what is it? Northwest College
they put, they had an,
it guy who was allowed to essentially
expense stuff under $50,000 with no oversight.
Really.
Uh, so it turns out they're missing, I think it's $2 million.
Is that all 50,000 is a pretty,
that's a pretty
crazy ceiling.
Yeah. Yeah.
So he was, like, expensing, you know, uh, licenses for software that, you know,
from a company that he also owned, you know, things like that.
So,
you know, and, and again, that speaks to the, just the,
the ridiculous lack of financial controls because,
um, they didn't find out about this until there was
a,
essentially a privacy related issue.
Uh,
and then they, um,
you know, sort of found out about the accounting issues, right. So they had,
anyways, it was just, basically, it was lack of financial controls.
Like you read about the, there's been that spear fishing campaign,
I forget what they called it.
But essentially the bad guys are targeting like CEO S CFO S accounting departments,
you know, and, and getting them like,
and basically the two main things the tricks they're using, which blows my mind.
Number one, here's an invoice. Please pay it
and some of these companies do.
Right? Just to random bank accounts and stuff.
And then the second one is a little more detailed.
They go, you know, hi, I'm your existing supplier of X.
And our banking account details have changed from this to
this other bank account in like some other place with,
you know, much less law enforcement.
Uh ironically and so
people change the banking details and continue to pay invoices, you know, for,
I'm guessing
3060 whatever the uh payment terms are before the actual supplier goes.
Hey, uh where's our money?
You know, and then of course, the company goes, well, we've been paying you.
I can only imagine those are some awkward email threads
and it just blows me away that uh there was one
company uh we'll have to put in the show notes,
but I think they were taken for $68 million.
Oh man.
But, but so, so here's the deal, ok. Here's the deal with. This is
all of those problems could be avoided if somebody picked up a telephone,
if you
have a secondary. And, and this is part of this is the important part here is
if you're communicating with someone via email,
you need another way to contact them, that's out of band.
And that's where you don't use the phone number in the email.
You know, you go to the rolodex or the phone book, the phone book still exists.
But anyway, you know, you go, you find a way to contact them
that is out of band
and you can verify it. And that's,
that's the thing. A lot of people forget is
email isn't the only way to get a hold of people and let's face it.
Even if we had signed emails
and even if the bad guys manage to sign it,
that doesn't thwart a phone call.
Well, the problem is people would still, for example, you know,
because domain names change, for example.
So you get an email from company name. Hyphen
something.com. Well, you know, how do you know if that's the actual company or not?
Uh, you know, that's one of the dirty secrets of, you know,
especially things like SSL and TLS is
the majority of SSL and TLS certificates are sort of low validation.
They're like just the domain name is validated like this is walmart.com.
We don't know if it's actually Walmart,
right. It's just, it's walmart.com or it's whatever.com,
you know, and some companies, well, like say paypal.com, I know for sure
they have, uh, you know,
the extended validation certificates where they actually have to, uh, submit,
I think some business records or like a
done in Bradstreet business listing or whatever,
you know, to actually verify that we are paypal.
Uh, but then of course, that raises issues like, well, I'm sure,
you know, trademark lobbying what it is.
And, uh,
there's probably like countries in the world where
you can register paypal without too much trouble.
Well, but here's the thing too is EV, two certificates are also very expensive
and so a Cron artist is probably going to be less inclined to do that. However,
most people don't
understand the difference between a regular certificate and an EV certificate.
So I don't think that has
a huge,
I, I guess benefit
to the organization.
I think it's, uh
in many cases more about just shifting the cost of
fraud when there is fraud because then you can say,
look, we have an EV certificate, you went to the site that does not have one
too bad,
you know, you should have checked.
Um
Yeah, so anyways back to P GP, I mean, the,
the problem I have with P GP is it's actually, you know, it's good encryption.
Um
but it's pretty terrible usability,
especially when you want to talk to somebody you've never talked to before.
Yes,
which is
the
-- point of email
-- that's still a problem and even things like signal.
I mean, that's one of my biggest complaints about signal is I can't
easily
give someone contact details without handing out my cell phone number, which
I mean, in my case, I'm like, well, it's, if you want to call me,
it's not that hard to find, right?
I've given up on protecting my cell phone number,
but I know not everyone feels that way.
And so that's one of the challenges I think.
Yeah.
Well, and the thing is too, uh for example, there, I mean,
that's one thing I'm very specifically doing with the
DWO from the people that work for it.
You have to at a minimum register like a primary
working email and a secondary email because let's face it.
Right.
People's primary address sometimes changes, you know,
if people use their corporate account, people do change jobs.
Um,
and I'm actually thinking of changing that
and tying the identity more to something more permanent like a
Twitter account or a Facebook account or a linkedin account,
which let's face it.
People get those and hold on to them,
you know, that
that's
fair.
Uh
And then the second thing is beyond that, I don't care who or what you are.
I just basically need that email address. So anybody
with questions about what you did can, you know,
contact you with relative ease,
you know, for that transparency piece of what the heck happened.
And,
you know, so I've,
I've essentially taken identity management and fixed it by not doing it
right. And that's,
you know, and, and that's not available to everybody, unfortunately,
but for myself, luckily it is because I, you know, I looked into what it would
take to properly do identity management. And
I mean, basically,
you're the only person that I would be able to actually verify and
that's only because I've worked with you for like over five years,
right?
You know,
you know,
I just discussed
identity management
issues with, with who's going to be my future brother in law.
This weekend we were at a Christmas party and
of course we're sitting in the corner discussing identity management
while everyone else is, you know, drinking beer and, and talking to each other.
But
normal.
Right.
We were normal for our area of the room.
But it, it is, it's such a crazy, horrible, hard problem. And there is
no good answer today
to solving some of this stuff.
Well, and even if you solve identity management, there's still a ton of problems.
Like people's names change all the time.
You know, they get married, they get divorced,
they legally change their name for other reasons.
You know,
identity management is a crazy hard problem.
It, I
don't want to say it's impossible, but it might be impossible.
I think it's one of those diminishing return issues
where you can do it like well enough.
-- Yes,
-- for most cases.
Well, oh, you know what I mean?
I just realized we're talking about P GP and the fact that the decentralization
of it is what really is its downfall. And once we look at something like
the way you're using signed G
commits and now we have a central authority and it becomes usable.
Identity management is not unlike that where today
we are trying to solve a problem that is
completely disjoint.
But if we had some sort of central identity authority,
which if I said it's the government,
I'm going to have people send me tons of hate mail about how terrible that is.
But you kind of get the idea,
I think without a central authority it is an unsolvable problem.
Well, the reality is outside of my small circle of people. I actually know.
You know, and, and saying, you know, that whole seven degrees of separation thing,
you know, once you get past two or three degrees of separation, it's, uh, you know,
it's really hard, like who's that guy in Guatemala?
I have no idea,
you know,
and the reality is, like I said,
part of it is I'm looking at it from just a pragmatic point of view is
see, for me,
it's less about knowing who they actually are and it's
more about just tying it to an identity to an entity
and essentially saying,
look as long as they do good work and don't violate the community rules,
I'm happy with them.
And if they violate the community rules and do bad work, we kind of, you know,
talk to them
and if they keep doing it, we boot them out.
Yes. Right.
So it's,
I actually care less about their actual identity
and more about just identifying that this identity is
like
this identity.
And like I said, I'm, I'm seriously considering
moving from my previous mindset,
which was like email address was sort of your primary identifier online
and moving to these more social networks like Facebook, Twitter, linkedin,
whatever,
you know,
like I said where people tend to get an account there and they tend to hang on to it.
Yep. Yep.
I would agree completely.
And you know,
the dirty little secret there is essentially what it
boils down to is URL S as identification,
right?
Twitter.com/kurtz
Fried or twitter.com/whatever Bib
Bob.
I, I think though, you also have the advantage of,
you have a very tight scope
and so you're not trying to boil the ocean, which I think is
when you have a clearly defined problem,
you can create a clearly defined solution for it, right?
Is we're seeing that in action here. And
I think that's probably also one of the other problems is
everyone tries to solve the world's problems.
They don't try to solve their problems
when they get to something like identity management
and, and even even P GP kind of fell into this of
instead of solving one nice problem, let's solve all the problems.
Well, I think basically they, they didn't solve any problems.
They built a framework where it's possible to solve these problems.
Maybe
you're a freaking genius.
Yeah, but um they didn't, I mean if you look at it given,
well, let's say for example, P GP with no key servers
you have now really the only people you can
exchange email and stuff with are people that you're,
you have a phone number for or meet in real life.
Uh You know, I remember P GP with no key servers is.
In fact, some of my first uses of it were
via bulletin board systems
where
we would con uh in,
in this was obviously we were setting ourselves up incorrectly to begin with.
But it's essentially, hey, I'm Josh, here's my key, you know, hey, I'm, I'm Bob.
Here's my key and then we could start sending each other messages.
Now, granted,
given it was a local small bulletin board in, you know, Northern Wisconsin,
there was a probably limited trouble of, of anyone really getting in the middle, but
it would not be out of the question for a malicious sis
a
to have done that.
And I, there's no way we would have known and this is someone I've never met in person.
It's just we happen to be
on the same bulletin board and we happen to need to have a private discussion.
Yeah. No, I mean, these are very difficult problems to solve and
I don't wanna say they're unsolvable,
but I don't think they're solvable in an economically viable way
and more to the point. I'm not sure these problems need to be solved.
Um, for example, your bank, once your bank is legally established who you are,
you know, they sort of let you do what you want with your account, especially online,
right?
Anybody that has your password and secret questions
could log into your account and do whatever
and essentially they've done what they have to do legally.
Uh, yeah, it's Oh man, this is such a crazy problem.
So, I mean, for example,
I love now that I can email money to people and all I
need is their email address and then I have to get them,
you know, the answer to a secret question
which I typically send them by email because I have no real other way to contact them.
So
yeah, I mean, but you know, it's convenient, right? And
I'll take convenience over
completely while not having anything,
-- you know, to pay my bills.
-- That's,
you know, I think that's kind of the lesson here. Right.
And this is, you should probably get this wrapped up at some point. But
it really comes down to
convenience, outweighs security
every time.
And that's really almost always
-- every time
-- there are things I just won't do because they are, I can't do them safe.
You won't, I will never go base jumping.
That's not convenient. Kurt, like base jumping is less convenient.
That's another conversation
for a different day.
But I think so.
-- So
-- I guess in general,
-- I would agree 99.8% of the time over
-- the course of this discussion, we
declared P GP dead.
And now it's not because we're using it with G,
but I, I will agree that I think for private communications,
it is certainly a less than ideal
solution.
And I'm glad to see things now like signal coming out that are making this much,
much easier
to solve.
Well, and more to the point.
Right, is we, if we really want to solve these problems,
we can't just solve them for people who are technologically competent
because that is a really tiny subset of humanity,
you know, even within our industry. Like,
I, there's so much stuff I don't know about how to, you know,
I'm now at the point where I know what, I don't know. And it's like, it's a lot.
That's
right.
Um,
and things like signal, you know, it's like you just need the person's phone number,
end of story.
Now, it's going to be encrypted, end to end.
All right. Well, with that, let's, uh,
let's call it quits for now
and we can all think about P GP
and, and the terrors that come with it.
And I guess until next time, Kurt,
thank you very much, everyone.
Uh, open source security podcast.com, check the show notes
and until
that's right, hashtag Os S podcast,
you can, we'll, we'll keep an eye on it and you can chat us up on Twitter
until next time. Everybody. Thank you much,
Merry
Christmas.
Bye bye.