Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Bresser.
-- Hello, and I'm super excited. We have a guest today.
We have Jeff Mitchell who's a principal engineer at Hashicorp,
who's joined us to talk about hashy
Corp boundaries. So welcome to the show. So,
-- Jeff,
-- thanks for having me.
-- Glad to be here. Awesome.
-- So I guess, tell us what you've done. Why are you here?
-- So
-- we released two weeks ago now, hash
Corp Boundary and Boundary is a,
a tool as a piece of software for essentially doing identity based access,
network access of resources.
So
the idea being that, you know, it's not simply sufficient to
be on the same network or have sort of direct
uh network connectivity to a service and to have credentials.
But in fact,
you need to have each individual session that you want to make, be authorized.
And one of the nice things about having an approach like this is that
you can actually essentially use this as a
bridge between public and private networks or,
you know, within fully public or within fully private networks as well.
So
you can use it to basically
have
an ingress point into your network that is doing a just in
time authorization check for every single connection you want to make,
making sure that you are the right person, the right authorization.
And in the future, there will be other things that are layered on top.
Some of which we've sort of talked about already and some of
which are just kind of on our long term road map.
Awesome. This is, I'm so excited about this, what I read about. So I guess let's start
at the beginning.
Sure. Tell us who hatch
Corp is because I, I have a feeling not every
-- knows and if you don't know, you should and you're going to find
-- out,
especially if you're storing secrets on your web.
Exactly.
Yeah. So, so Ash
Corp was founded, I, I actually, I'm gonna get the date wrong,
so I'm not going to say it.
I, what I can say is I joined five years ago and um, and at that point,
there were already several different products
and there's sort of a predictable key of products that are all kind of along the dev
ops tool chain. And so
one thing that Hashi Corp was doing and actually
what brought me to the company eventually was that
they were looking at each individual aspect of sort of
getting from I have application code and I want to
get it to an end system and then I need to actually like run it in an end system.
And they were figuring out how do we make a tool
that, you know, for each step along the way,
actually solves a specific need and very much in the UNIX model of like, do one thing,
do it well, so, you know, our, our, our,
our mantra is better together,
but each individual project should be able to stand on its own.
And so this encompasses, you know, vagrant,
which is something that a lot of people probably know.
Um So vagrant is,
is a mechanism for sort of uh uh it's a
DS L for describing virtual machine images and then you
can sort of do a vagrant up and you have a uh A VM ready to go on various hypervisors.
And so
that's sort of the at the very beginning of sort of that,
that DEV op step of like the actual DEV work and having a predictable environment
and then it moves along to, to like Packer.
So Packer is a way of building machine
images for all sorts of different targets from,
you know, a similar configuration language from there.
You have Terraform, which is probably one of the most well known products.
And Terraform is essentially a DS L that allows you to
do infrastructure as code and it's extremely well supported in industry.
It has a lot of different providers that provide different
functionality for different clouds and systems and you know,
you can do everything from, you know, manage EC2 all the way down to like DNS.
Um There's all sorts of things that terraform hooks into.
And then from there, we have a couple of runtime products there,
console, which is
console originally started out basically as a key value store,
uh a consistent key value store.
And it's really, and, and on top of that,
they built a service registry and now that's turned into a,
a lot of different things.
But, you know, it's, it's a full on service mesh at this point. And
uh and so that's, that's finding a lot of um really interesting use cases and,
and it scales extremely well.
Uh There's nomad which is a scheduler.
So Nomad is extremely fast and extremely scalable and handles
all sorts of different things that it can deploy,
not just containers.
Um So there are a lot of people that use it for very, very demanding workloads.
And then probably I, I would guess outside of terraform,
the other most well known product is vault and vault is
a Secrets Management platform. So it started out kind of as a uh
uh with,
with sort of a couple of interesting notes.
So one is, you know,
originally started out as consular is key value store and
we want to encrypt things that are living in consul.
And so it,
it really was about building that initial root of trust.
And then they had this idea about something called dynamic secrets,
which are basically why don't we just mint credentials just in time and have vault
be responsible for the lifetime of those credentials and revoke them as we go.
And over time,
vault turned into more and more of a platform where you have kind of this core of
auditing access control, replication and scaling and all these things.
And then each different aspect of it,
it provides essentially an api upon which you can build all sorts of things that,
that need high security.
So
there's encryption as a service, there's, you know,
just kind of a key value store that, that encrypts things to go through.
There's database credentials that can be generated, it can act as a PK I like a,
a certificate authority, et cetera.
So that's sort of the,
the, the
that hush
products take you on.
And a lot of people actually find it in a way similar to what I did, which was
I was working in a coma
at the time and I was working on as an infrastructure architect,
working on kind of green fielding infrastructure for one of the groups there.
And what I found is that every single time I was like, OK,
here's the way that I want to build this, I want something that does X
and basically every single time I said I want something that does X, it was,
it ended up being a house
product.
So, you know, first I was like, I need this,
I need some way to do like distributed evening and
oh console lets you like send events out to nodes.
OK? And also has key value store so I can send configuration through it.
And then it was like, OK. Now I want to do do Docker in an item put way oh look terraform.
And, and so kind of every step along the way.
Uh I just ended up finding myself using Hushka
products and eventually
I just moved over there and started working on products myself.
So when I took over, I, I basically came in and, and I sort of took over primary
engineering on faults starting just before the 0.3 release.
And then we kicked off boundary in earnest about a year ago.
We sort of had been thinking about it uh for quite a bit longer than that.
-- And I sort of moved over to kind of spin up and kick off the boundary project.
-- That was
a fantastic
retelling of hay
Carp.
-- Great. Glad you like
-- it. Thank you. Iii I learned quite a bit.
I thought I knew more than I did, which is always a pleasant surprise.
II, I will say I left way point
doubt which I shouldn't have, but only because it's so new.
It, you know, it's not part of this sort of traditional hush group story.
I've been so steeped on boundary.
I'm not even sure I fully understand the way point myself. So I'm gonna,
I'm gonna leave it there.
It's actually, it's,
it's very interesting approach for sort of tackling the build,
deploy run sort of a cycle in a way that makes it extremely easy for
you to sort of tackle any kind of workflow there,
like across any platform and make it very easy for developers to be in control.
So, Waypoint is really interesting project to check out as well.
It's funny that you mention that because I think that's
one of the biggest things missing from a lot of
security is that processes that allow people to shorten those
latency loops and make it easier to do these things.
Because both Josh and I have worked at companies where, you know,
-- pushing out emergency updates of software is, you know, Death March
-- that it can be.
And I, I also want to add
that
virtually everything
has
a
Corp does
is open source on
github, which is awesome.
So we, we have
open core model and, you know, I I think that
there,
there are obviously people that would like everything to be fully open source and,
and just go with support.
But you know,
there are different approaches to sort of building a sustainable company
and we want to make sure that we're around for our,
our users and our customers.
So, you know, so we have an open core approach. Um
The way that we try to look at it is we try to put kind of the,
the core functionality for any individual technology that, that a product is,
is sitting in and essentially make the core technology open
source and then focus on uh I'm not,
I'm not gonna go into details because really that's more on the,
the sort of product side
and marketing side and I don't want to say anything that's gonna get,
that's gonna not be what, what they would want me to say.
But, you know, I, I think in general, I can say that the way we think about it is sort of,
you know, if you,
if you have specific needs that really
are catering specifically to large enterprises,
which is a, a large subset of our kind of customer base or, you know, fortune 500 C,
you know, companies, then that's really where we want
to, you know, figure out how to monetize it because they,
they want those extra features, they want that support.
And meanwhile, it means that we can put kind of all the base tools that,
uh you know, if you're just a home user and an open source user, you know,
another open source project, let's say that that's available for you to,
to make use of.
So it's always a delicate balance as you can, as you might imagine.
Yeah, totally. Well, I mean, Kurt and I have long histories in open source.
I, I work at Elastic now and it's, you know, gotta eat man.
Exactly.
II, I get, I get it. OK. OK. So let's, let's
on boundary. I read about how boundary works and it sounds amazing. And
in, in the zero trust world,
one of the challenges is always how do you restrict access?
And I've seen a variety of methods and the age old
trope of just put a firewall in front of the network
is I think anyone still relying on that is fooling themselves.
I think part of the point it's not restricting access,
it's doing so efficiently nowadays,
right? Because the great example is, you know, oh, all of a sudden
everybody's logging in from home
and, and that's like that.
And that used to be, I remember having these arguments with, you know,
in companies where like, no people need to be able to work from home.
Like, no, we'll make them do it on site now.
It's kind of like, yeah, now that, that argument is over.
Yeah, we, we actually saw that with my, my wife's company,
which I won't name but they, they actually just switched products,
but they were using a VPN product.
And essentially people would just be hopping around
during the day to all the different,
like configured VPN end points at some point,
she found that things were so overloaded. It was actually faster for her to go to a VPN
ingress point
in I think London
than it was to go to like Cincinnati. So, yeah, it, it's
you know, you need something that scales, you know, when you're bridging networks,
like, like you generally do the VPN S, although there are obviously are, you know,
security features in VPN S to kind of keep people isolated, you know,
put them into V lands, things like that.
But when you're bridging networks, then,
you know,
there's a lot of assumptions that end up getting made about what people ought
to be able to do or what people can do and sort of what,
how that should behave.
You know, there are some, there are very good use cases for it.
You know, if I'm, if I'm coming into my home network, I,
I do have boundary running locally, but if I'm coming to my home network,
I often want a VPN,
I just actually want to access my, my own home network as if I was sitting at home.
You know,
I want access to all the different IP S and the different
ports and services and things like that that I have running.
But, you know, if you're an enterprise and you're like, OK,
I just want to allow somebody to ssh to a single machine,
right?
Getting them in and essentially bridging networks is
not really the right way to do that.
It, it provides a lot more access than you really want to give.
And so then essentially what happens is you're falling back to,
you have that network access layer. But once someone's in on that network.
The only thing that's left is either sort of IP whitelisting, you know,
allow listing, deny, listing kind of things or you get, you know, credentials,
right.
You know,
it's still a journey for a lot of companies to
get to a point where credentials are more ephemeral,
um where they rotate rapidly or they're sort of just in time.
One of the things that we're going to be doing with boundary in kind of the near term,
and we've sort of this is on a public road map is vault integration.
And part of that is that we want to,
you know, to make it easy.
So that not only can you connect into
a machine through boundary and only through boundary,
right,
you can set up your firewall such that only
boundary worker nodes that are proxy traffic can actually
allow you to make a connection into the node. But on top of that
boundary can manage the lifetime of a credential that's minted from vault.
And so that way you can say, OK, I want to connect to, you know,
some machine I want to connect to a post Chris database.
I have to go through boundary.
And when I make that connection through boundary,
the boundary will in the near term,
it will return to me a set of credentials that I can then kind of seed into, you know,
into the the client.
Oh, nice. If you're using our helpers, we can see it in for you.
And then eventually we'll get to a point
where we're doing protocol decoding for various protocols and
then we can actually inject the credentials and you as a user never see a credential.
Oh, nice. The way it should be. Right.
And so that way, you know, if you, if you don't have a credential of your own,
then you can't, even if you manage to get onto the network,
you literally have no credentials that you can use to authenticate to a service.
That's awesome. All right.
So let me,
let's discuss some use cases here because I read about this and I'm super excited
and I want to make sure I understand it as well because I always worry that
I either
am overthinking or under thinking this problem. So I guess,
let's say
I, and this is a very typical setup where I have a
corporate network.
I have a VPN and I have,
we'll say everyone working from home and obviously,
people need to access a resource.
So let's say I Josh need to ssh into a server
in the corporate network.
And traditionally, the way that would be done is I connect my VPN.
I basically my computer in my living room now becomes part of the corporate
VPN as well as whatever botnet that my kids have installed on the computer.
And so now I basically have unfettered access into the corporate network.
So how would you say is the better way to do this with boundary.
So with boundary, the way you would do this is you would,
you would have a boundary client on your machine right now.
We just have cli in terms of actually making connections,
but we are working on a desktop client so that
you'll be able to sort of browse through available,
what we call targets, uh browse through available targets, then, you know,
pick one to connect to.
So what you would do is you would, you would authenticate the boundary and
that will, again, this is very early days, this was our 0.1 release.
Um So OO I DC support is coming shortly.
That's one of the major things we're working on right now.
And O I DC is what
uh O open ID connect.
So that that's essentially become kind of the
standardized way of doing single sign on.
So
for the most part, it's replaced Sam Li, I mean, not,
not in a lot of kind of bigger institutions, but
you know, it, it's very, very widely supported and it's I,
I think in many cases much easier to get set up than, than Sam L is
-- sorry, I've, I've tried to set up Sam Ml and yes, I I was
-- being nice.
So the easiest example here is when you see those like
log in with Google buttons everywhere or log in with Facebook,
that's open
-- ID connect, right?
-- It can be or it can be OO
two, which is what open ID connect is based on
um open
ID connect is, is more or less, it's a way of sort of taking
something called OO
two.
And if you've dealt with oo,
you know that
oath ain't oo,
which is a very frustrating thing about it, which is that
in many cases, there are
the, the RFC, I, I've,
I've actually written an OO two servers so I
can speak with slight amount of authority here.
The RFC is under spec to be, to be gentle. And
uh as a result, there are, there's a lot of leeway.
And so you find out that if you want to interoperate with various providers,
you have to like
do things slightly differently and especially in,
in the information that comes back.
And so
what OIO I DC does, what open ID connect does is it sort of takes that
oath workflow,
but it, it codifies the format of a returned token into a jot
uh
JSON web token. It's a sign token that, that has embedded
Json in it.
And so this allows you to convey a lot of information just by looking at that
sign jot and then make ensure that it is valid by checking the signature.
And so there are only some codified claims, what are, what,
what the keys there are called.
There are only some codified claims that you have to support,
but there's a whole lot more that you can add.
And so it just kind of makes it a lot easier to actually kind of consume identity than,
than straight up.
Oo
uh you don't have to sort of know all
the different API S for all the different providers.
So what you would do just going back to the kind
of the original example is you would on your machine,
you would connect to,
you know, go through O I DC and authenticate And probably there you would have,
you know, an M FA challenge or, you know,
a security token challenge or something like that,
you would connect through O I DC that
would authenticate your client that's running on your machine
to boundary to boundaries uh controller servers and which are like the API servers.
And so then
you would be able to say, OK, what are the targets I can connect to or just,
I would like to connect to this particular target
and then you go and you say, please authorize me.
And at that point, you know, the, the initial step of I DC has authenticated you,
but it hasn't authorized you.
It's only at that point when you actually want to run a command that we say, OK,
given who this person is, let's, you know what they're trying to access,
let's load up the set of grants that have been applied to
them and let's make sure that they're allowed to make this connection.
And so that happens every single time you want to make a connection,
you have to do that. Let me, let me clarify something, connection versus session.
What we call a session can actually have multiple connections allowed.
This is because there are lots of programs that actually
in the course of essentially making what you might think
as a single connection actually have multiple different T uh TCP establishments.
But so really, it's a session is authorized which might allow
one many or unlimited connections. And we also have a time bound on top of that. So
you can say, you know what I want to allow unlimited connections, but for 10 seconds,
so that might be good if it's like I have the shell script,
I wanna run it just pipelines, you know, SSH commands through.
And so I wanna make a bunch of connections, but only within the space of, you know,
if the expected run time is two seconds,
I'll allow it for 10 seconds.
And so there would also sort of
effectively be an implicit firewall because it's doing
stuff at the application level like obviously letting
you ssh into a host or whatever.
Right.
So, right, right now, the only, the only sort of target type that we have is TCP.
And so anything that you can run on TCP can be proxy through.
Now, there are, there are gas
and there are things that are, that get,
you know, kind of complicated and there are,
there are things that cannot easily be supported now.
But where we will be addressing those in feature for something like SSH, you know,
it's a single TCP connection.
And so we are not currently protocol decoding.
SSH, that's something we will be doing going forward.
So right now, it's simply are you allowed to make this TCP connection?
And you know, the nice thing there is like, say that you disconnect that session or,
or let's say that that session times out,
right? Once that session times out,
you can't just connect back, right? You were never on the network to begin with.
Your traffic was being proxy.
And so you have to go back to the to boundary and say, can I please
connect again?
And it has to decide whether or not to authorize you and that, that might,
you know, that might be based on right now.
It might be based on sort of like specific specific grants applied to you.
But you can imagine if you're aware of like Sentinel,
which is kind of a policy as code language that's in many of our other products.
You can imagine the Sentinel will eventually make its way into boundary and that
will give you kind of A DS L for doing all sorts of checks.
And there are a lot of other integrations that we have planned, you know,
at some point in the future with, with other systems that can help you with that logic
-- you'd mentioned you were going to be doing protocol decode later in SSH,
-- right?
So that,
so that would be for that initial connection
from your client to that that end target,
there are different sub commands or sub protocols, an SSH.
So like one is actually just a command. And so
you could say you're only allowed to run commands and that
basically is run this command and then give me back,
you know, the output from the command like the standard out and the standard.
-- So
-- it sounds almost like a pseudo layer on top of it.
-- Yeah,
-- it kind of depends on what you want.
-- Well, in the sense of like with the command restrictions and what not
-- sure.
So, so the way that, you know, I, like I said, I, I spent time in
Aai and I, I, you know, I talk to people in their knock quite a bit
and
one of the things that I had in mind was sort of that, that, you know,
when we were designing boundary was like that knock use case.
And so there,
you know, the knock users are trusted but they're not really trusted, right?
Akamai
at the time, had 100 and 40,000 machines,
the world and they didn't really trust knock users
to just like get onto the box and do whatever
crypto mining.
Yeah, exactly.
And so what they had was they had dashboards,
they built up and those dashboards had essentially scripts,
like you could hit a button and say like, ok,
run this script and the script would go out and, you know,
that would be authorized through some of their means and
would run like a very particular set of commands.
And so
the knock,
like they had kind of recipes for how to try to try to tackle various problems.
And then if they, if their recipes didn't work,
they would escalate it to engineering.
And so from that perspective,
you can imagine that like you could replace kind of the traditional,
like I must be on the network or I must have sort
of some back channel with something like boundary where you can say,
I actually, you know, in my knock, we're only going to have
a knock
network operations center. Um I should have
dis
that, but
you could say in the knock, like I'm, I'm going to have a similar approach of I,
you know, I can take certain actions and those actions kick something off.
But now those actions can be kicking off a
script that actually uses boundary to make that connection.
And so each,
each individual command is not only something that's like a script that you know,
that they
in theory cannot access or modify,
but also then has to match like a particular command that's allowed through
to that end. Toast.
And so when you're protocol decoding, you can do things like that,
that you can't if you're just looking at a TP stream
and I assume then also logging and whatnot because I
know that's one of the biggest things I saw with,
you know, the setting up the whole SSH jump box.
It was,
I would say for me, it was always 5050 you know, access control and 50% like logging.
What the heck happened?
-- I,
-- I will say that that is something we are keenly interested in.
I'm familiar with this problem
for anyone who doesn't know elastic search is one of elastic's products.
And logging is
one of the primary use cases for the system.
So I have a great deal of, we'll say experience in the logging space.
-- So logging
-- is important.
It's hugely important.
And, you know, it's a funny thing is when,
when you start going down the path of compliance, basically,
access control and logging are the only two things anyone seems to care about.
If you don't have those two things though, you can't have compliance,
like you can't secure what you can't measure.
I,
I finally have learned this now because I used to not understand why
the auditors were so hell bent on locking everything because I'm like,
really doesn't matter that much.
Yeah, it does. That, that's all I have to say about this anymore is log everything.
Data storage is cheap. Chuck it in an S3 bucket encrypt it
-- and ignore it until something bad happens and then send
-- it off to glacier.
So it's even cheaper.
-- Exactly.
-- Yeah. Until you have to take it back out.
Oh, yeah. Well, there's that
dude,
-- I
-- actually downloaded my cloud trail logs once and
I tried looking at them and I'm like,
there's just,
there's, we don't even do much and just all the automated events firing, you know,
it's millions of events per hour, day, whatever, it's bonkers
because when I saw boundary, you know, at first I was like, ok, well, this,
this seems like
a
option than an
H jump box.
And yeah, I mean, if you're going to have things like logging in the future,
then that really, that, that makes a big difference.
Yeah,
yeah, we, we are definitely looking into those, those capabilities.
That's all I can say for now.
I, I will say as far as the jump box, you know, I there, there are definitely, you know,
having a jump box is, it's a very ssh specific way to do something like this.
Um And I think that's one of the main drawbacks is, you know,
it's ssh specific and so you could port for
and so you could have tunnels to then get to other things. But in some ways that kind of
almost like defeats the purpose.
I I if you can sort of use that to then do sort of arbitrary protocols and things,
then that's,
that's not ideal and that's not saying that boundaries
is necessarily better in that regard right now.
But again, we're 0.1 and we have we have plans to sort of help address those,
those issues in the future.
And then there's one of the thing that I found out, you know,
working on this is when we were going after, you know, writing documentation and,
you know,
as we got near the end and needed to come out with all the information about like,
what is this thing and how does it work and all that.
Then I kept seeing people say like, oh, you know,
so it replaces this fashion host sort of approach.
And I was telling them like, you're,
you're giving too much credit to fashion host like
II, I was like, well, no, no, no. So let me explain. So
in my experience, I, I think I just was only at places that had very,
very locked down fashion hosts because I'd be like, oh,
you go into a fashion host and then you can do one of like three things.
It's like
ssh to a set of a particular set of boxes or do this or do that.
-- I've never seen a lock down properly.
-- Exactly. And so then people are like, what?
And then, so I was like, what are you talking about?
And then I would explain this and they'd be like, what are you talking about?
Bastion hosts are just like an open thing.
-- You just get on it and now you can get anywhere.
-- Yeah. SSH N And if you want to SH VPN you,
-- you do that?
-- Yeah. And so, and so that, that seems like a, uh, you know, I think that's,
that's an area where I actually didn't even
realized kind of the current state of the world was less secure than I thought it was.
And so I think that boundary is a good alternative to that kind of fashion,
fashion host.
I mean, that doesn't surprise me though. You exist in a world where anyone
coming to Hashy Corp for these tools is probably in the top 10% of organizations,
-- one
-- percent,
-- percent
when I, when I talk to people about Secrets Management, number one,
they don't realize it's a thing.
And number two,
like they generally understand that you can't put your Aws credentials in github
publicly like they get that.
But, but then, but then the question becomes,
-- but what do I do?
-- Just put them, put them in a spreadsheet? It's fine
-- like they have
-- no idea.
And in fairness,
like if you haven't heard of Secrets Management and Vault and you're,
you're not aware of these products,
you know, it reminds me back in the days with Telnet
and when ssh, you know, tattoo loan
and came up with SSH, like people were like, what do you mean?
There's an alternative to Telnet?
No, like really? Right. Like there was a time where like Red Hat didn't ship Ssh,
you know, like there was a time back in the olden days
where all we had was telnet.
And so I, I feel like that's kind of where we are with a lot of this,
especially this infrastructure type stuff is,
yeah, I mean,
-- you gave me a problem, give remote access to people to the network. So I
-- did
and, and security is always hard. It's always hard, like proper security.
There's no, there are no real shortcuts. There's no real sort of easy mode. Right.
Right.
If you're used to thinking about things like, and, and, and for what it's worth,
I think that that's something where vault, for instance, you know, I,
I worked on vault for many, many, many, many years.
And
so, like,
I have a deep and abiding love for it and what it does that said it's not the right
solution for everybody because some people have so much
simpler needs that there are simpler products out there.
Whereas vault is really the, I need to have a lot of different use cases.
Like I need to encrypt and generate certificates and just do KV, storage, you know,
maybe I need to also be able to do this with like a single api across many,
many different clouds.
That's obviously one of has
groups, sort of bread and butter. Is this sort of we work with you
on prem or any cloud, you know, as you make that journey to cloud, you know,
there are people where it's like, ok,
my secrets right now are in an S3 bucket unencrypted.
And so right now, the,
the thing that I just need to do is maybe I turn on like server side encryption
on that S3 bucket, you know, tied to an AWS policy.
And like at least now it's encrypted.
Like at rest, if you aren't authenticated, there, there are baby steps for sure.
The more that you, that you sort of layer in security,
the more and more complicated it gets as, as I think all of us know.
So I
want to, we are, we are nearly out of time.
But I want to ask one more question about what you said
at the very beginning about boundary has the ability to ease the
VPN like scenario where we are connecting to, we'll say in theory,
protected resources.
But you also mentioned public cloud.
How does,
how do you envision boundary fitting into a space where
I can connect directly to the machine in question?
Because it is literally sitting on the internet,
even if you have something sitting on the internet
and granted source IP spoofing is a real thing,
but that's why you have defense in depth.
But even if you are sitting on the internet,
let's say, let's say that you're going from, you know, you have a public host,
you want to connect to another public host and you have,
you have boundary that's running in, you know, some other, you know,
public IP space.
You can still say, you know, what my end target
in addition to maybe, you know, one of the best things you can do, for instance,
if you're running on a public IP address
with like SSH is move ssh off the port 22 right?
That stops the vast, vast,
vast majority of like random attempts to break into your box.
So you could do something like that where you could say, OK,
I want to connect through boundary,
I'm gonna move it to this other port and I'm also gonna restrict the source IP S
to only come from my boundary workers.
So even though everything is on is, is public, you still have some like, you know,
not only are you sort of hiding the service a bit, you know,
from kind of the the commonplace Attackers by putting on different
and yes source IP spoofing is a thing.
Although, you know, in a lot of like internet infrastructure,
it's relatively decent.
Like you still have to, you know, there's a lot of checks in, in places to sort of have,
you know, a source IP in a destination IP coming back like it has to sort of match.
But, you know, you can basically say, look, I want to
restrict the set of, you know,
incoming IP addresses to only my boundary worker notes.
And so then
you're saying, OK,
to get in, maybe I still need a credential to actually get onto that service.
So I as a user need it
or needs to get generated from vault.
But on top of that now, even though it's all public on top of that,
I'm still going to restrict
at a network level to only the workers. And so,
you know, I have to, if I want to get around that,
not only do I need to credential for the box,
but I have to be able to essentially either get on to that worker network
or I have to spoof source IP S and also be able to route back.
And you know, it, it sort of enhances that tax service.
It makes it a, a smaller tax service, right?
It makes it harder for you to actually satisfy all
requirements to launch a successful attack. And so,
you know, going public to public and, and that's the same thing,
private to private as well.
If you're like on an internet, you know, it's the same thing,
like maybe everybody on the internet,
maybe you assume that people get access to your internet.
Like if you have a big enough company network, you got to assume that somebody is,
somebody is on it.
But you can still say, you know what, but these critical infrastructure, you know,
ssh on these boxes like that still has to go through this set of nodes.
-- So yeah, it, it, it can, it can be used in all of those scenarios.
-- That's awesome.
That's awesome. All right, we are fresh out of time.
So I guess Jeff, I will give you the final word. Take us home.
Uh
Sure.
So, yeah, I mean, we, we really love hearing feedback.
It's very early days of the project. We have a, a forum discussed at Hash
group.com
and we also have github.
And so, you know, by all means, feel free to
drop by, tell us how it's working for you, what needs to get fixed, you know,
what you're looking forward to.
And uh and we're, we're very responsive and we love seeing all of it.
-- So please
-- check us out and, and I would also like to add that you're getting started.
Guides and information
is surprisingly good for her. How early stage this project is? Thank you.
-- Well done to you guys.
-- I'll pass it up to the education folk.
-- They'll be happy to
-- hear it. Cool, cool. Ok, good deal.
I'm going to call it then I will say thank you, Kurt. Thank you, Jeff.
Thank you, everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, use a Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
We'll of course,
have plenty of show notes and a link to Jeff in the show notes that doesn't make sense,
whatever doesn't matter.
And I guess
Kurt and Jeff have a marvelous rest of your day. Thank you. You too.
Thanks, everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.