Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in allergy suffering Josh Pressers.
Ok.
So before I hit record,
I made a comment to Kurt that everything outside
is covered in like a thick yellow dust and my
allergies.
I, I used to not have allergies and now that I, I guess I got them and it,
I'm a bit stuffed up today.
And so anyway, Kurt claims this is my city's fault,
which I of course said, what are you talking about?
And he wouldn't answer me until I hit a record. So, what are you talking about?
-- It's actually
-- shockingly simple. Female trees have seeds, male trees have pollen.
Guess which one is easier to clean up from the city's point of view.
I assume the male trees.
So at least in most of Canada cities prefer to plant male trees rather
than female trees because there's less of a mess for us allergy sufferers.
-- It's terrible. Interesting.
-- I wonder if that is true. And now that you say that
I feel like there are,
I have some trees in my yard
that drop mass quantities of crap
this time. Of year. But you're right. The trees the city planted along the roads,
-- I feel like, don't drop tons of garbage
-- because they, they
generally speaking
professionals who do this kind of thing prefer the male plants
because they don't make a mess.
I mean, pollen. It just gets washed away in the rain. Interesting. Right.
I have a female tree in my backyard and, you know, those, like, helicopter seeds
and it just, every year
I love those things. They're a mess. But they're fun to play with
and they're sharp when they're dry.
-- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
-- So,
you know, tradeoffs, less pollen.
But now I have all these little sharp things over me
in the fall. Is it fall or is it spring? No, it's spring. They fall. Right.
-- It's
-- all year. It's all year.
I
remember
I had an L shaped house once and someone planted
the biggest maple tree I've ever seen probably closer to the house than is safe.
And, yeah, it was, I was, I cleaned the gutters.
I bet 10 times a year at that house because the
tree was dropping something into the gutters at all times.
No, it's, it's, this is a perfect example of your original
hypothesis. I don't know if you want to share with the group.
-- What was my original hypothesis?
-- The humans make everything worse?
I mean, who's, that's not a hypothesis?
It's like that's a fundamental truth.
So, we're going to talk about
the
colonial pipeline disaster because it is not well known,
-- but I am in fact a pipeline
-- expert.
I'm not shocked at all.
No, I'm not at all.
Have had more exposure to this than I should have also through my childhood.
So actually you might know something because you live in an oil rich place.
I'm I'm more making fun of the fact that if you look on Twitter,
most of the people who have been what supply chain
experts and probably election security experts and then epidemiologists,
they are now shockingly
experts
at pipeline security,
which is just what
Yeah,
-- to which I say if you don't know what a pig is. GTFO
-- that is the only thing I know.
And the reason I know that is from watching documentaries about
pipelines and I only thought it was funny because so,
ok, I will let me explain,
you can correct me because this is something I'm actually like giddy about.
Obviously, you've got pipelines,
they go into the ground or wherever and they go from point A to point B.
Right.
And you can imagine
that you can have issues of like keeping them clean and there
can be clogs and you got to make sure like how,
how is the pipe doing?
Is there something wrong with it?
Whatever they have these basically like probes they put
into the pipe and they call them pigs.
And the reason they call them pigs is because
the original things they would send through the pipelines were
made of leather and made a squealing noise as
they traversed the pipe because they fit really well.
They're kind of meant to clean it.
And that amused me to no end thinking about a pipe
squealing like a pig.
-- This probe moves down
-- it.
I mean,
what I really love about pipelines is that the
majority of them are quite old and pretty much
on their last legs and ready to like blow up
internal, a lot of
them
and they cross bodies of water, they go under creeks. There's just
like, I know people who work for remediation companies and
it's,
I mean, they, they generally try to do a good job,
but
when you have thousands of tons of soil that's been contaminated,
like what do you do with it?
Well, and, and look, I mean, this is actually in there,
there's a bunch of interesting parallels here.
I think we can touch on, but I think in that particular
parallel is pipelines are legacy infrastructure fundamentally, right?
Like the dependence on oil is decreasing,
we know we have an oil free future in front of us.
It doesn't like this is not a political statement.
This is just the honest to God's truth about oil consumption.
Well, it's a bit more complicated than that,
but I would say it's more like the amount of oil we're
going to need in the future is going to be relatively minor.
It'll be a fraction lubrication pharmaceuticals.
Like, we'll always need some amount of oil, but we won't be setting it on fire.
Right. No, seriously. Think about it. We have this awesome resource.
It's like trees. We used to burn trees all the bloody time.
Yeah. And we still do a little bit.
My neighbor, for example, heats his house with wood and I, like,
we live in the middle of a city.
You get to smell like campfire all the time.
Yeah, I straight up do. I've gotten used to it. I kind of like it,
but
we went camping a couple of weeks ago because camping felt safe in COVID times.
And
my kids haven't been around a campfire in a while and they're like,
everything smells like campfire.
What do we do? It's like nothing. You can do nothing. You smell like campfire. Now,
that is the literal definition of camping. Everything smells like campfire.
That's right.
Anyway. Anyway,
so
there's a lot of angles to this and I
don't want to specifically focus on pipeline security.
-- You know,
-- my favorite angle is,
is that from what I've read the colonial pipelines company essentially again,
made a humans made a choice
to make the situation much worse because it benefited the company.
Well, I mean, maybe so,
this is one of the many points of contention I think fundamentally from
the perspective of what happened with this pipeline at the time of recording,
there is so
much conjecture and just made up crap that
I don't believe anything I'm reading right now.
All we know for sure is a pipeline is
down and it has been admitted that it's ransomware,
it's fault and that's
it. Maybe it was ransomware.
Maybe it was, there's,
there's rumors of like a second order where humans
turn the pipeline off because of some other system,
the ransomware affected, you know, like I have no idea.
Well, it, it's from what I've read the most,
-- like the current sort of the most well reasoned and
-- you have to
say
at the time of recording,
at the time of recording from what I've read,
it looks like their billing system got really hit hard.
And so, rather than, you know, deliver product and not be able to bill for it,
they decided to turn it off so they could
-- fix their billing system and
-- I wouldn't doubt that.
But I will assure you if that is the case when the congressional testimony begins,
they're going to have a bad day.
Here's the thing.
They,
they'll be easily able to claim that
they wanted to protect the pipeline infrastructure
and, you know, the skater systems by turning them off.
But this is what always drives me nuts about ska
and about a lot of sort of enterprise things is that people build something
and it operates something that either cannot be shut down or
is so incredibly expensive to shut down that you essentially need
like sign off. From the board of directors to turn it off.
You know, things like nuclear reactor plants, uh, oil refineries.
Like, I remember we had a windstorm once here and they had to shut down the Scott
for refinery, like, as an emergency.
Oh, man, that
was like,
that was a major problem.
Think of the stuff in the pipeline and the inertia that it has.
-- Right. Right.
-- You do not turn these things off unless you have to,
we don't know
all of the stuff we don't know. Right.
That's, that's basically what this is like running a pipeline.
I have no idea how that works. Shutting a pipeline down. I have no idea how that works.
It's not like a garden hose where you just kind of turn a knob and, well, that's it.
You, you can't because it'll break because of the inertia of the product.
All of that in
all industrial systems have
like a billion moving parts all at the same time. Right.
And you can't just turn one of them off.
Usually what happens is you end up with catastrophic failure somewhere
-- down the line
-- or just a really big maintenance bill.
-- Yeah.
-- But in the 8 to 9 figures, kind of maintenance bill, I mean. Right.
Right.
So, like my example I always use in, in this instance is when I was in college,
I worked in a paper mill in the summers to
earn my beer drinking money essentially.
And I remember the the machines had to be shut down every now and then this,
this mill I was in,
had like eight or nine big machines and it took 24 hours to shut it down.
Correctly. Mind you, it did, they did go down once because of like
a
power failure.
And that was, that was, that took a long time.
Then it takes 24 hours to start them back up when they shut down Catastrophically,
it takes like a week to start them back up.
But the other thing,
the thing I never thought about and I was talking to
the engineers one time when we turn the machine off,
every time they turn the machine off,
they have to replace some of the motors because
the motors just won't ever start back up again.
Which is kind of nuts if you think about it.
What always gets me is, well, I mean, I just went through this with my computer.
I upgraded the CPU
lost my, uh, memory profile and
there's a lot of computer memory, for example.
But, yeah, will it do 3200 or 3600 mega, uh, megahertz?
Yeah. Will it do it consistently day in, day out 24 7? No,
people forget. You know, this isn't a car that's only run 10 hours a day.
This is a machine that's running 24 7
with vibration with heat.
When you look at this stuff, it's just,
it's got to be massively overpacked or not overspeed and a whole lot cheaper.
And the reality is, in a lot of these cases, it's a lot cheaper to use parts that at any
sufficient scale it becomes statistics
and you just roll with it
like it's cheaper to replace that motor once every
couple of months than it is to buy a motor
that will never break because that motor that will
never break will break at some point as well.
So you just accept the fact that
I I think what it boils down to is you at scale.
You accept the fact that certain pieces are essentially consumable
that normal people would think of as being forever.
Well, I mean, you have to plan for that to a degree as well, right?
I mean, and this is true, let's think about it, infrastructure, right?
How many, how many it infrastructure plans
basically say
when this thing fails, this is what happens to everything else, right?
That like that never happens
because why would it,
it's well and, and, and but also you get organic growth so you get
things that depend on it that it didn't depend on it before and so on and so forth,
right?
Like these, these pipelines are a perfect example of,
one of the challenges of my provincial economy is that we have a
ton of oil that we extract from the ground and sell to people.
Well, why don't we refine it?
Yeah, ask me,
you want me to ask you,
ask me why we don't refine it locally and sell refined products at a higher value.
And why don't you do the thing you just said?
-- Because we can't transport it to market,
-- you mean the refined
oil
or gas or whatever?
I guess we have infrastructure pipelines to
ship the unprocessed or slightly processed product
to Texas, for example,
which then refines it and has
things like colonial pipelines to actually distribute the gas
-- to the east coast.
-- Right.
-- Right. Well, when we say gas, we mean petrol for the rest of the world
-- gasoline.
So
like,
yeah,
and so for example, if Alberta were to
do the value add here,
the only option we really would have is to ship it via tanker car,
which is quite expensive compared to pipelines and
also quite hideously unsafe compared to pipelines.
Well, and I have a suspicion that
refineries probably pollute like crazy.
-- And
-- dude, this is Alberta, we're ok with that.
Yeah.
Ok,
because I know in the US most of our oil refineries are in places that
will say have lax environmental regulations would be the polite way to put it.
Edmonton has grown up with oil refineries now in city limits like there's
facilities, well, they were inside the city when
50 years ago,
like we have, you know,
we have Fort Saskatchewan which has the highest incidence of asthma in Canada.
I'm sure it's not at all related to the oil refineries out there.
Total
-- coincidence.
-- Yeah. So, no,
no, no. Like I, I can drive 2030 minutes and go look at giant oil refineries
like they're on the other side of the city.
So, no, the environmental concern is, that's
ok. We're good with that. But yeah, so the, the problem boils down to
people. Think about,
you know, a tank full of gas. That's cute.
What do you do with a million liters or for you?
Americans say a quarter million gallons of gasoline?
Well, you could ship it via train. Ok, but what do you do when you need that every hour?
-- I mean?
-- Right. Right. And is true of technology.
This is true of any, any industry, right? Any industry at scale creates challenges.
A normal person cannot fathom, toothpaste, toothpaste pipeline sounds epic.
Yeah, there was an XKCD.
We'll have to link to where he did the various sizes of pipelines for,
for various things that are needed, including toothpaste.
That's awesome.
-- I've not seen that one.
-- No. So the reality is as much as we hate on this stuff.
Pipelines are basically the least worst way to transport this
stuff at scale and bulk 24 7 without interruption.
Probably because you don't have to worry about, you know,
cars sitting on the tracks or
well and, and look my complaint isn't the pipeline like we have pipelines,
whatever I enjoy living in a modern economy.
Do I hope we stop using oil and gas someday, like, sure it's easy to say.
But, but fundamentally the issues I see are kind of multi
tiered of, first of all, we have the usual experts
that don't know crap about what they're talking about,
which is frustrating because they muddy the waters and they make a mess.
Right. There's that going on.
You've got the fact that humans probably made this worse
in some way because that's just what humans do.
All of this boils down to economics. Right.
You're not convincing these people to spend a ton of money and worse.
A bunch of outage time on upgrading things.
It is really hard.
You know, it always reminds me of hospitals where people are, like,
why don't you just upgrade all the software and stuff of hospitals?
It's like, yeah, so you just want us to, like,
shut the hospital down for a day or two and do software updates
that
checks out.
I don't think, I mean,
that kind of happened when, what was that? Not pet?
Yeah, that shut down the UK hospital system.
Yeah. They fell back to paper charts and it was, it was a proper mess.
What frustrates me the most is the majority of people have never had
operational experience running a system that has to work.
Not like, oh, it goes down. I get a call.
I have to bring it back up but I'm talking about systems that
have to work.
Like I said, nuclear reactors, oil refineries,
stuff like that where you can't just shut it down for a few hours.
Right.
I think they grossly underestimate how complicated this is
and how from a security point of view,
they mostly like the rest of us.
Kind of hope nothing bad happens.
-- I mean,
-- I think that's
kind of how everyone
works.
Ok. I want to, I want to also bring up one other thing that I think is bananas.
I will link to this in the show notes. But Rob Kaki,
who was on the show some time ago for the book, he wrote with Dick Clark,
he posted a thread on Twitter today pointing out that the
TS A the people at the airport in the United States,
the Transportation Security Administration is
responsible for pipeline security.
It
makes sense. That
doesn't make sense. I have no idea.
For example, most rail companies in Canada have their own police.
That doesn't surprise me at all because railroads have existed for
hundreds of years and things were pretty dicey at the beginning.
And not only that,
but you're dealing with crime where it maybe happened
on a train in between two towns in some
-- in the middle of nowhere may not even be a jurisdiction
-- that wouldn't shock me at all.
-- Well, and there may not have been back in the day. There might be
-- now.
Well, there would have been RCMP but you know you, how are you going to get some RC?
You know, just finding the guy and getting them on the train to deal with.
-- It's going to take days.
-- Right. Right.
-- And communication was slow and whatever I get that
-- there's a
lot of us departments where if you look at their responsibilities,
it's like, well, why are these people in charge of X?
And while it's just, that's how it is.
It's like one thing that always blew my mind was the secret service.
What is their mandate? Exactly. Again,
I forget what it technically is,
but they have like a hodgepodge of responsibilities.
-- Yeah,
-- it's like protecting the president counterfeiting
and just a couple of other really oddball.
-- But
-- I mean, look, this is,
so this is one of the other funny aspects to all this is when you have
a, we'll say long
standing organization of any kind.
It doesn't matter if this is a business, it can be like a, probably a church,
it could be a government, whatever, it doesn't matter eventually.
Just because of the arrow of time you're going to
end up with groups doing super weird things and reorganizing.
That is often a political nightmare that no one wants to deal with. So nobody does.
Not only that, but you hope you'll probably have regulation and law written.
Well, in the case of governments.
Yeah, there's totally going to be laws, you have to deal
well, or even the quasi
governmental bodies. You know, a
great example, the BC registries, you know they do the corporate registries, so,
company names and whatever.
And so I wrote an article about this.
Haven't published it yet,
but basically this lady wanted to register her company name in her native language.
-- Oh, right. I remember this
-- BC registries is like, yeah, cool. Sorry we can't.
And everybody's involved is kind of getting this hate on the BC registries.
And I went and I read the Act, the Act legally specifies
English and French.
That is what they
are to support. It's not that they have to support that and can do other things.
It, the act specifically says company names are English or French.
Stop.
That's it.
And so like they're not trying to be jerks.
It's just, you know,
we operate through a regulation and the regulation says English or French.
That's it. Sorry. Like we're not allowed to do anything else.
-- We're not trying to be jerks. It's just,
-- when was your regulation written?
-- Oh, good Lord. Oh, quite a while ago
-- before unicode.
-- Well,
-- before, you know, we,
we sort of started seeing the indigenous peoples of Canada's people.
Yeah, that too. I suppose that's a good point.
But I mean, right, this is, this is a fine example of there's always these multi like,
like
2nd and 3rd order things that happen in any
situation and like this is totally no different.
Like,
you know,
what else is really funny is I found a story talking about now that the
east coast of the United States knows there's going to be a gas shortage.
People are all going to hoard gas.
And so now they, they created a gas shortage and it's like you idiots did this.
-- It's toilet paper all over again.
-- By the way, if you have a pool, go buy your chlorine.
-- Now, now
-- there's legitimately a chlorine shortage I heard,
but I'm sure anyone with a pool knows that at this point,
the one main factory that produces sort of
chlorine pucks and chlorine Granules for pools.
It's in Louisiana
-- and I quote, it burnt down a little bit after the hurricane last year.
-- Oh, good.
That seems nice.
It's funny because I actually got like a small grove mount above ground pool for
this year for my kids because all the pools are going to be shut still.
Yeah.
It, the week I bought the pool a few weeks ago and then I did my research, you know,
I'm going to do chlorine and salt or bromine or whatever.
When I went to buy the chlorine stuff,
it's like the shelf's looking pretty picked over
it. Supply chains, man. And again, I don't want to be a jerk.
So I bought like the biggest bucket they had also.
It was, well, no, it drove me nuts because the small bucket was like 40 bucks.
The bucket twice as big was like 50 bucks.
The bucket twice as big as that was like 60 bucks.
It was one of those situations where,
you know, do I buy the? I have, honestly, I have no idea how much I need to use.
-- It depends how much crap you have in your pool. Well, exactly.
-- Yeah,
how much use and all that. So, anyway, anyway, but,
and I don't want to be like a jerk and like,
h chlorine, but at the same time it's like I want to run my pool this summer.
So I bought the biggest bucket I could.
It is hilarious to me how
fragile all of our supply chains are across everything.
-- Well, it's just
-- in time delivery. Right. Here's something nobody ever thinks of.
Ok, you're a car company and everybody's like, oh,
the car company should have had extra chips and parts and blah, blah, blah,
every time there's like a storm.
It's like,
it's like you want to have a warehouse full of $50 million of inventory of parts.
And they're like, yeah, then
I'm like, that is a
pile of $50 million cash sitting there doing nothing.
-- Well, and in the case of technology it's getting old. Right.
-- Yeah.
It's devaluing, like, like there's a little counter running down,
except in the case of my video card,
I checked my video cards actually appreciated 50% in the last year.
That's a different problem.
But, I mean, even, even all the busted technology supply chain stuff. Right.
I mean, it's just,
it is,
it is comical to me
how all of this works. And, and again, now everyone's a supply chain expert.
So they're saying, oh, you should have had stock,
you should have known this was coming.
You should have this, you should have that. And it's like
nobody expected a pandemic.
Nobody realized any of this was going to happen. It's just it, it
is what it is. And unfortunately,
historically, when you're not in a pandemic,
it is possible to maybe switch manufacturers, spin up resources, whatever.
But now all of that is 1000 times harder than it was before.
And so there's obvious lags in anything that happens and it's, it sucks. But like,
-- it just is, you know, like,
-- honestly, people are and I get that it really does.
It's very unfortunate right now, especially like, again,
locally in my province because we suck at handling COVID.
Everybody's doing school from home for the next three weeks
and I get it like, people need computers at home so their kids can do school from home
and that's really difficult right now.
You know,
I finally managed to source a Ryzen five CP
for my desktop and holy cow totally worth the upgrade
as, as quote unquote bad as it is.
We're not talking mass starvation levels of supply chain disruption.
Well, and that's just it. Right.
I mean, for the most part,
I would say most of what's happened has
been inconveniences versus like famine and plague.
Well, there's been real economic effects and hardship
but
it's, it's, we'll be able to recover from this.
It's not gonna be pretty, but it's not the end of the world.
Right. Right. And I mean, this is, we're marvelously off top.
Well, I guess, do we have a topic? Not really,
but, I mean, this is, this is part of it. Right.
It's like you look at like our, our pipeline mess right now.
Is it going to end the company? Probably not? Are we going to recover? Probably.
Are we gonna have a crappy couple of weeks?
Definitely.
-- Well, I'm, I'm not on the east coast, so I think we'll be fine. I mean,
-- well,
if you have a refinery in the middle of town, you're golden. You know,
I mean, luckily I fill my car up with gas once every three months right now. So
it's pretty ok.
What's interesting to me too is again the trade off? Ok.
So we want to have a more robust system. Ok.
Well,
that means we need to allocate large amounts of money
and resources to buy stuff and set it aside.
But, but is it worth it? And exactly. And,
and the thing is that has a real cost,
not only do we have to buy the stuff and stick it in a warehouse and store it properly.
Right. Because
again, people forget like you can't just,
you can
just have a pile of auto parts sitting out in the rain.
You can't just like computer chips.
You have to kind of store them a little bit carefully, you know,
you don't want them to get wet or cold or, you know, whatever or stolen
or stolen.
And then there's other stuff like food.
For example, I love watching Steve MRE 1986 info.
You know, the guy that does the MRE eating and reviews and even the good ones,
you know, you're looking at 5, 10 years lifespan and you got to rotate them out.
Right.
And this is like my perfect, a great example.
Diesel for diesel generators for data centers,
you have to rotate the diesel because diesel and gasoline goes sour,
it acidifies over time.
Yeah, I have this problem every year when actually.
So I just had to start my lawn mower up for the season and, and I was,
I have done no maintenance to my lawnmower in five years now and every,
every spring I hope this is the year I get to buy a new lawn mower because, like, I just,
I refuse to buy a new until the other one's dead.
And
I
empty, I make sure I empty the gas out every year because if I don't empty the gas out,
it's a nightmare to start.
And I dump in my new gas.
I pull it and first pull it starts and I'm like, well, crap. Like, no, that's not nice.
-- I want a new lawnmower.
-- Well, just do it.
I'm a cheapskate. I'm not buying a new lawn mower till I need one.
-- But I mean,
-- and that's a perfect example. A small scale.
It's easy, just empty out your lawn mower, put fresh gas in whatever.
But when you're a data center with, you know,
50,000 or a couple of 100,000 L or gallons of diesel, what do you do?
Do you
ship some on site and then a month later, sell it back to the company for like,
90% of what it's worth.
-- You know,
-- I actually don't know what, what companies do about.
So I know my experience from long,
long ago is I work somewhere that had a small diesel
generator and we just ran it once a year and,
you know, used up the diesel.
But I, you're right, like, in these enormous data centers,
I wonder what they do with,
you can't run
like a week's worth of diesel, you know, that would cost too much. Yeah.
Well, exactly.
So, I would assume that they're selling it back or selling it off to somebody.
-- I don't know.
-- That's a good question.
If someone knows, like, tell us, I would love to, I'm too lazy to look,
but I would love to know the answer.
Yeah.
Well, there's a variety of strategies depending on, also part of it is how much,
right?
Like,
you know, and this is one of the reason, um,
a lot of these data centers are going to renewables is
because renewables tend not to fail or when they do fail.
Renewals are interesting in that a lot of renewables, especially solar kind of fail
gracefully and gradually like two or three solar panels fail. Ok. No big deal.
You know, your steam turbine at a nuclear power plant fails. Oh, boy.
Yeah.
Right. Right. Exactly.
I suspect
what is happening is the clever people will try and find better,
more efficient solutions that also dovetail with more robust systems.
Nah, I don't think anyone cares.
I think in a month we'll forget about this and it won't matter.
Well, solar is taking off and solar plus like,
well not tesla power walls or whatever, you know, energy storage
that will result in a very
robust, gracefully failing grid.
Oh, wait.
So you're suggesting because of the fuel shortage,
people are potentially going to look at renewables more at this time or
they're going to realize that maybe depending on this stuff isn't so great.
And so for example, on the spreadsheet of solution A and Solution B oh,
maybe we need to add some costs to because see one
thing I hate about oil and the petrochemical industry is it's so
heavily subsidized in so many weird ways that the true cost of it isn't apparent.
I mean, yeah,
that's right.
And I think as people, as a, you know,
global warming being a bit of an issue, you know,
those polarized caps in Greenland melting, we're becoming aware that, oh,
there are some real risks and costs to this that
we need to take into account when looking at a power solution, you know,
do we go with renewable or diesel generator?
-- I mean,
-- look, that's,
I think so far down this path. It, it's not even, there's nothing we can say.
I think from,
if you just pull back to the immediate threat of you have infrastructure,
infrastructure is down, are people going to make concerted
internal changes to make sure they're not the next colonial pipeline?
And I think the answer is probably not.
Oh, absolutely not because there's no money in it.
You'll have a handful of companies that look at this and they take it seriously.
But I think for the most part it was solar winds and then code
COV
and it was not you before that and it's a pipeline today and it's just,
I just think this is, this is the, this is it,
this is, this is how it works now.
But for example, Biden did commit to electrifying the US federal fleet, right.
The car fleet, the truck fleet. Sure.
And for, for example, that is something now that in hindsight is like, oh,
that's actually a really good choice because these pipelines
were not as reliable as we thought they were.
Well. Sure.
Right.
And I'm talking about those kind of decisions where,
what I'm saying is people are not going to actually,
I think it's actually better not to solve the direct problem in front of us,
but to find a new technology or a new solution that makes that problem obsolete.
Like the horse poo problem in London.
Right.
Something I think about a lot
is you look at kind of any internal process in any organization
and do you know how you get change?
You usually get your change by changing the people? Right. Because
new people have new ideas and they don't want to do things
the old way or they just might not know the old way.
And this is the same thing with kind of like technologies and
stuff is if you think you're going to slowly upgrade your legacy,
you're probably wrong,
you need to Greenfield that crap and eventually just like throw out the old.
And I think all of this, all of this infrastructure, all of these supply chains,
all of everything is the same way.
We're not going to fix the old stuff.
Now, at the same time, it's super easy to say this,
but it's obviously very difficult to create change.
I think this is part of why start ups are so successful is because start ups
tend to find a totally new solution to a totally new problem or a problem.
-- People didn't even know they had
-- sometimes and then a
giant company buys them and destroys their business monologue,
which is unfortunately part of it.
But
I there was a time when Amazon was not the world's
-- biggest company or Apple or Google
-- Amazon always lost money.
Remember that
they were perpetually in the red
except for what,
like November and then they would make money because of Black Friday or something.
So I think that's part of the solution space here is, it's like rewriting Firefox
isn't the solution. It's finding maybe something better than web browsers.
You know, it's that kind of thinking.
I think that will actually get us propel us ahead.
Right. Because
no amount of securing pipelines is fundamentally going to fix the problem.
But moving to an electric fleet of vehicles will basically
-- make the problem go away
-- to a degree maybe.
And, and I just think securing of this industrial infrastructure is,
is a ridiculous problem that I can't even begin to understand
or trying to make it environmentally.
I'm not even going to say environmentally friendly but environmentally neutral.
Probably
there's just
pipelines leak. That's
-- just that, that's reality,
-- which is
not at all related to ransomware.
Yeah.
Well, computers, I guess here's my one parting thought because we,
we are out of time, but kind of all of this is
the one thing I think is becoming completely obvious from all of this is
we like to talk about cybersecurity and meet space as two different things.
I think
this
is the irrefutable proof that there is no
longer a separation between cyberspace and meets space.
It's all just reality now.
-- Self driving cars or computers attack, like with a car wrapped around.
-- Right.
It's all the same cybersecurity or cyberspace is meets space.
Everything has a chip in it now,
including me because I had my COVID vaccine.
Wait, I don't. Did you get mind control or tracking? I forget which one.
-- No,
-- five G, five G, five G
anyway.
Oh, all right. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to opens
sources, security podcast.com. Hit up the show at Suzy
Podos Podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt, you have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.