Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 139
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Pressers.
Kurt,
uh, just watching the Brexit train wreck and trying to, at this point,
I'm not even trying to understand what the outcome is.
I'm trying to understand what it is. Like what it,
-- it makes no sense. None of it. It makes
-- perfect sense if you look at it in the right way
and I'll recap for the listeners. What I explained to you prior to hitting record is
basically they were told, pick a number 12 or three and they said I pick four
and then someone else said, no, you can't pick four. You have to pick 12 or three.
And they said, no, no, you don't understand. I picked four and that's pretty much it.
And that's all of the discussions that have been happening since then is one
group saying you have to pick 12 or three and the other people saying,
but I picked four and that's pretty much it,
I guess. Yeah, that actually summarizes it nicely.
It makes me sad that,
that is 100% accurate when describing the
conversations that have been happening around Brexit.
And now the one interesting thing and I don't,
this podcast might come out after the, what is it? March 29th date?
Deadline?
-- Right.
-- If it, if it does,
-- I'm not see, I'm not even clear what that deadline is for.
That's when like they're out. Right.
And if they don't do anything, well,
unless they extend it and apparently the eu has said we're not going to
allow you to extend it unless there's some material benefit to that extension.
Right.
And, and, but anyway, at this point, when I looked at the betting markets,
the betting markets all think
the UK is going to leave the EU with no deal. And
so a hard Brexit and for what it's worth, I know that's sort of voodoo,
but the betting markets get this stuff.
-- Right. A lot.
-- Well, markets do
you know the wisdom of markets? It's not always 100% but
it's definitely better than
probably what's on CNN or, you know, the BBC,
almost certainly. Right.
Because most of these people, like, if, if you're running a betting organization,
they have skin in the game,
right?
You have to do real research because you're
actually going to lose money if you're wrong.
Yeah. So, anyway, let's move on to,
I guess, more depressing topics.
All right.
Well, speaking of which another, well, we're just gonna cover this quickly.
Uh, voting, the Swiss came out with an electronic voting
system thing that they then, uh, allowed the public to take a poke cut
for security testing
and guess what job?
Which is cool.
But guess what happened
exactly what we would expect to happen.
Yeah, they found flaws and they found backdoors and
the whole thing is just a flaming turd. Basically.
I'm, I'm shocked that that was the case,
-- possibly predicted.
-- Well, here's what's even worse. It's a flaming Turd.
But by, by honest honestly, by,
by software standards for voting software,
it's actually probably one of the best things out there,
you know, and people found flaws in it and they found a back door in it
and in related news,
DARPA is building a $10 million open source secure voting system.
Now, I like that. They say it's a secure voting system,
right? Because I mean, II, I think that was the problem, right?
The Swiss built a voting system. They didn't build a secure voting system,
right?
They should have just named it Secure Voting and
then I'm sure everything would have been fine.
So I think DARPA got it here. Like
it's a secure voting system.
-- So I think we're good.
-- I,
-- you think 10 million is enough? I don't think so. I think they need a few more
-- zeros.
I think 10 million is actually too much because they're gonna,
the fact that you're paying people to build this, you're,
you're not going to get the best and brightest who care deeply about this.
Maybe more to the
point, maybe,
you know,
building we've talked about this before but building a voting system that is,
has properties of being secret and being verifiable and being accessible.
Because what about blind people?
-- That's, that's a very, very complex problem
-- actually, it's not.
And I will take the 10 million and I will give you a ream of paper in the box.
Elections. Canada figured that one out. Thank goodness.
Yeah, I, I love elections, Canada for that.
It's you, you make your X in the circle and sorry, not an, is it an X or a check mark?
No, it's an X. Not a checkmark and that's it.
And you fold it and you shove it in the box and yes.
And they,
and, and if you accidentally make a check mark, I bet you're ok.
No, you have to go get a fresh paper.
Oh, really? They like they will not accept a check mark. You have to write an X.
Yeah. Yeah,
-- fair
-- enough. And part of me was always thinking, you know, honestly, if you can't
meet that barrier of entry, then maybe you shouldn't vote. But on the flip side.
Yeah, I don't know. I
Yeah.
So
my, my whole take on electronic voting is number one. It's,
I'm not sure what problem it solves.
Like really, I'm not sure what problem it solves.
Number two, it's horrendously complex. And complicated to do.
And number three, every single one of these systems,
even the good ones is a flaming turd of security flaws
or backdoors or God.
Um
And pretty much doomed to failure.
So that's that. Ok. So we're done with e voting. Thank goodness,
great
from
-- so
-- yeah.
So now we actually have some interesting stuff.
So
browsers
have actually been doing some cool stuff this week,
which is awesome. Yeah.
So I think uh well,
let's lead with and I love that this is still
a problem because it's just still such a problem.
Ok, Josh, I got a one gigabyte file.
I want to send you and I sent it to your email and it didn't work.
Uh it, it would work because we both use Gmail. It's fine,
right?
So it's still shockingly difficult to send somebody a
file over the size of a few megabytes.
-- Yep. Yep.
-- And so Mozilla has this cool new thing called Mozilla Send
and it's
sorry, Firefox. And,
-- and uh it allows you to send a file to somebody,
-- right?
And it looks like it's one gigabyte kind of anonymously
or you can have an account and do 2.5 gigs,
which is, that's a pretty big file.
And what's even cooler is you can do things like it.
The file expires after one download,
which is quite often what most of what us want.
You know, I want you to download
goes away and you can share it with specific people, you can encrypt it.
My assumption is that this is piggybacking on the work
they've done around encryption and storage of the user profiles.
Because Firefox does some really,
they built some really cool technology
around encrypting and storing your Firefox profile
so that
you can log into your Firefox web browser.
And it goes to Firefox gets your profile data decrypt it and
you have all your bookmarks and your
stuff, extensions, whatever
it
is magic and works.
Yeah, this is uh and this is free and it, it appears to be quite simple,
-- which I like.
-- No, I agree. I think it's super awesome
because honestly, this is one of those real world problems that
we still either we have to agree on.
Ok, we're going to use Google Drive or we're going to use Dropbox.
We're gonna use box.com or
I'm going to physically mail you something
and all these things take time.
I have to set up an account and you know, what are the options? And blah, blah, blah.
And I literally just want to send you the file.
Yeah, I'm, I'm very familiar with this problem.
And in fact,
we have this all the time where if we
need to transfer like audio files between each other,
it would we use usually Google Drive and it was kind of a pain in the neck because
if you don't have the fancy infinite amount corporate accounts,
-- what's that?
-- It was a huge pain.
Yeah.
We're both
Google users.
Uh Yeah. Yeah. It, it was not fun.
So I'm, I'm glad
they've done this and this I feel like is
Firefox is in a unique position as a
web browser because they're essentially 100% consumer focused,
right?
You look at say Google or Microsoft or Apple or
other things and it's kind of part of a bigger ecosystem
and I think something like sharing files is unexciting and there's
basically no way you're going to use that to generate revenue.
And so I have a suspicion that's part of the reason it's just never been solved.
Well, it's been solved, but it's Balkanized, right?
You have box, you have Dropbox, you have Spider
Oak, you have
Google, you have icloud, you have blah, blah, blah and,
and within each of these, you know, like with an icloud, I have,
I can set up family photo albums and share them to other icloud accounts.
But
I don't think I can just share them to random people unless I make them public. And
so, you know, and, and this is why every time somebody's like,
why do people post their photos to Facebook where anybody can see them?
And the answer is because it's basically impossible to share them with your family.
Otherwise,
do you remember trying to share photos before Facebook?
That was the solution.
-- It
-- was impossible.
Yeah. No, the solution was, I didn't share them.
I remember when my kids were born, we set up a, I set up gallery on a private server
and it was, ah, it sucked so hard
-- to keep that thing updated in gallery,
-- like gallery. Is that PHP?
Photo album software? Right.
Yeah. And there was, like, always remote
remote code execution flaws in it. And I was updating it constantly.
And I remember at one point like this obviously had nothing to do with work.
And I was like, can I please just help you guys with your security stuff?
Let me give you AC be ID, then I'll write your emails because
I'm tired of finding out about this in the wrong way.
Yeah, there's
a, there's a lot of CV
S for gallery,
-- like a lot.
-- It was, but it's PHP. Right. It was very hard to write PHP code.
That wasn't terrible.
And thank goodness, no, doesn't have this problem, you know.
No, doesn't have CV S.
That's true.
It's true. They don't have CV E so they got that going for them.
Yeah. No, this is good. This is because I think part of the problem is, you know,
I want this stuff to be so simple that my,
my parents and my kids can use it without having to think about it.
-- Yeah,
-- I agree. I agree. And, and this is, this is sort of one of those things I hope
and
I mean, this is,
I think this is something for the security industry to pay attention to is how
can we make tools that make people's lives easier and not make them much,
much worse.
And we, to date, I don't think have very many tools that do that.
I think part of the problem too is these tools have
to be built in and part of the operating system.
Like think about the difference between
a command prompt on Windows and a command prompt on any
Linux UNIX
Mac Os system.
And there's a huge night and day and Windows
is just finally catching up with powershell and bash.
But it's, you know, for 20 years, I was installing
sin and doing all sorts of hor horrendously complicated
things to replicate a UNIX tool chain on windows.
And then I finally just gave up and bought Macs.
And as much as I'm annoyed by Mac,
you open up a terminal
and you have a command shell that actually,
yeah, it may not be new said, but
you know, at least the set is reasonably
san
right? It it exists
-- and with brew, thank God for
-- brew. It's a low bar. But
yeah, why they shipped a knot Gnu set is beyond me. But whatever,
because those lines
because
it's Apple
and shut up, they know better, right?
That's except line returns work differently between the two and it's just anyways.
So,
so I think part of it is this stuff has to be built
like if you build something into the web browser now everybody has it.
Whereas if you require even an extension,
maybe 1% of people have it.
Right. And that's part of the thing is,
you know, well, like your story with, you know, trying to get printer drivers. Like
the other, I,
I finally broke down and bought a Windows 10
machine to run steam and games for my kids.
And
I know to type in like gigabyte driver, you know, what is it?
Uh B 450 MD S3 H whatever the heck the motherboard number is.
And I know to make sure I'm at gigabyte.com
before I click that link to download these,
you know, zip files.
And then I open these zip files and I'm like,
ok, two of them have a setup dot exe. Ok, double click and hope for the best.
And then the third one, I open it up and I'm like, there's, there's no setup dot exe.
Do I have to like go into the device manager and dip around with this or?
Ok. Open up. There's a zip file in the zip file. Open that up. There's a setup dot exc.
Ok. Double click that and hope for the best.
And it, it actually runs and it's like,
do you want to install this like version 18 of these A MD drivers
or do you want to download and install version 19 of these drivers?
And I'm like,
I probably want the newest ones, right?
So I,
I chose that and then I install all these
drivers and reboot it and the machine still works.
There's no errors in the device manager. So I'm like done. I, that's it.
Like
if any of these drivers auto update, then that happens. But otherwise,
unless like the screen starts, you know, half the screen is pink and flashing.
I'm never touching these drivers again.
Like, and I'm a techie, I, you know, and, and I'm afraid of this breaking this thing.
So I, I'm really beginning to understand where people are like, oh,
you want to share this file?
Simple,
just download this extension and create an account over
here and sign up for this and blah,
blah, blah.
It's like, no, that's not gonna happen. Right.
Yeah.
-- Yeah, I hear you, man.
-- It's the best part is
this machine
with an HDM I cable. You can access the bios and you can see windows boot,
but then the screen disappears.
So I had to buy ad V I cable to plug the monitor and buy ad V I.
So I can actually log into windows and finish the setup
-- and I still haven't.
-- Windows wouldn't work over HDM. I by default.
No,
I saw the little Circle Booth thing and then it disappeared.
And so I think, I think now that I've installed all the drivers, I think it will work,
but I haven't actually tried it yet
and I might just have to live with the DV cable. And again,
I'm,
I'm done. I don't care. I just, whatever
I give up.
Right. Right.
I'm just gonna pick whichever cable works and I'm not gonna fight with it.
-- This is computers. I love it. It's always broken,
-- dude. I have an M CS C and NT four.
Like, I, I've been doing this for 20 years
and I still,
you know what I mean?
Like, if, and if I plug that DV, I cable in and I hadn't got a screen,
-- I don't know what I would have actually done to make it work.
-- Go find a VG. A cable man.
Motherboard
doesn't have,
I guess I would have bought, I would have,
I was seriously like looking online for an
old enough video card that has native windows,
10 drivers,
I guess, would be the next stage, right?
-- Of grief and bargain.
-- I, I,
I don't even know what,
what to do and I'm not even going to think about it because I don't want to,
it's working.
It's,
it's, it,
-- I'm gonna glue those connectors
-- on.
-- Never touch it again and everything so
-- much.
Anyway, anyway, that, that's enough windows talk for a while.
So, what else is new?
-- So
-- also in browser news, apparently. Uh So alphabet is the parent company of Google.
And one thing I'm not clear on,
are they naming all the companies in alphabetical order?
Because there's this new one called Jigsaw is launching a chrome?
-- I don't know.
-- Are they
-- that would be interesting if
-- they were something Google or alphabet would do
anyway.
So Jigsaw is launching a chrome extension designed
to help moderate toxic comments on social media,
which
I mean, I, I like that because we've had um shadow banning, you know, via,
on forums and stuff.
Well, some forums for a long time,
um but it would be nice to kind of bring it
to the browser and it's funny because they're talking about A I
to, you know, filter these toxic comments.
And I'm I'm honestly thinking most of these toxic comments there just like
a couple 100 keywords,
you know, if you see more than two
of
them,
-- but chances are it's a toxic comment.
-- So I, I think about this one so much. So
I approve
of the, the idea behind this.
But the thing that always concerns me is like especially in the
case of Google or in the case of nearly any group,
do you trust them to decide what is or isn't a toxic comment?
Like are they going to decide that
people saying bad things about Google
-- is a toxic comment?
-- Yeah. And I mean, OK, so 100%
mistakes will be made intentionally or otherwise
unquestionably
part of the challenge is
we're now like ad filtering is typically I don't want to say easy,
but ad filtering is somewhat simple.
In the fact of you're blocking domains, you're blocking certain known elements,
you're blocking, you know, sort of
images of a certain,
you know, size and properties
but blocking comments.
Like if I'm looking at a thread of 100 comments, am I are any being blocked?
Like will it give you a hint?
Like will it show you a blank space saying like like a little overlay saying,
you know, there's a toxic comment, click here to see it
or does it just sort of silently disappeared into the cornfield?
-- Yeah,
-- I don't, I don't know what the answer to that is going to be and,
and even ignoring that, let's say it does tell you something's blocked
what
it, it's, I just keep feeling like
there is merit in trying to stop terrible people from saying terrible things.
But the issue always becomes what I think
is a terrible person saying a terrible thing.
Another person might not agree with
-- that
-- who decides
well, and the reality is,
how do I put this nicely?
-- All speech at some point will be offensive to at least one person.
-- Right.
I'm sure this podcast has offended more than one person.
And luckily we live in countries where we can say nearly anything
we want and not worry about getting in trouble for it.
But,
I mean, we've talked before about the fact that, like,
I'm not going to Russia. Right.
Just,
we've said enough crap about Russia on this podcast that there is no
way I'm going to even try to go to that country now.
Right. No, no. Russia's on my not to do list.
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
And, and in fact I was talking about this with a friend the other night.
He was, he's ex-military and after,
you know, just all the leaks that have been happening lately, he's like,
I can't even imagine traveling to some of these countries now just because,
you know, being ex-military you're unquestionably on a list.
And, and, I mean, that's, that's one of the things that always gets me here.
And the thing that I keep coming back to is
who is in charge of telling people what is and isn't acceptable comments.
And I will tell
you now,
I do not trust Google as far as I can throw them because they have
proven time and time again that they put their self interest above everything else.
Well, but that's what people in organizations have to do otherwise they wouldn't
exist.
And part of the problem too is it's not even so much who is deciding what it's?
Is there any transparency? Number one
and number two, is there any process to deal with the false positives or the messes?
And it could be, you know, an appeals process or it could be something as simple as,
um like with, you know, the ad filters,
they have various lists that they subscribe to and you can
choose which ones you do and do not subscribe to,
subscribe to all of them.
I mean, but I, you know, I, I'm starting now that I, I, and again,
not to talk about windows too much, but now that I have a Windows machine,
I need to start looking at some parental control software
and this is the same problem here.
You know, I for example, think that it's ok if my kids want to look up breast cancer,
I'm ok with that.
You know, um,
there are other,
-- well, there's software that will block that because
-- breasts,
uh, my kids found that they were talking about their,
their schools have filtering software and it was
II,
I feel like it might have been breast cancer that they were talking about.
And obviously, yeah, they,
they couldn't look up anything on Wikipedia about that topic,
-- which is, which is wild. But
-- on the flip side having glanced at for
Chan and other sites,
yeah,
that's all I have to say about that.
And I get why they exist.
And I definitely, you know, you,
and I'm guessing you as well were on B BS S before the internet.
Uh, for those of you
who
don't know,
that's a bulletin board system and you would dial in with your phone modem
and then it was a computer that you could leave messages on
or read messages on or play what were called door games.
So they were like little text based games.
Um, and I used to
use a feature in one of those games horrendously
to win it every time because the game would
run for about two weeks and I would win every time I was a bit of a,
not a good person that way.
There
you go.
But, um,
there you go. Yeah. So,
yeah, I don't know. I,
this, and this is something where I think is going to become even more of a
concern because I'm thinking about augmented reality.
And one thing I really would love to have for augmented reality.
My, my two biggest,
my personal use cases are I want to look at you
and know who you are because I'm terrible at remembering names,
you know, and a little bit of context, like, do I owe you money?
Do I owe you a drink?
Whatever? Right.
And number two, I would like to sort of filter out ads like
I was reading the other day, Hawaii
doesn't allow billboards,
which is cool. That sounds amazing
because I live in a town where we have a lot of really ugly advertising,
like just physically
ugly every
everywhere.
And
I would be quite happy to get an extension
that overlays exhibits from the moma or the Louver
-- over those.
-- That would be awesome.
That would be so cool until of course, then you'll have companies saying, oh,
you can't, you can't come in my store because you have your ad blocker on your
A R headset.
So,
yeah, I think those two big things are, is that that transparency of, you know,
what decisions are being made, how are they being made
and then having some process to deal with whoopsies?
That isn't completely insane.
You know, like D MC A takedown systems that most providers now are,
are completely broken.
Right. It's, it's terrible
and, and they always side with the corporations.
You have to, you look at like,
have you ever read any of the stories about
the youtube copyright strikes and just madness around that.
It's crazy
having silence taken down rainfall, taken down people who,
you know,
are the band that produced that song and then somebody used it in
a commercial and had the band's music taken down and that's the best.
Yeah.
And well,
and it's going to be a million times
worse with that insane European copyright directive.
If that thing goes through, man, it's gonna be,
I,
I have a suspicion, what you're going to see is
people just won't care.
It'll be one of those situations where youtube says, screw you.
-- You
-- have to, you'll get fined
-- and,
-- and they can find them.
And
I, I don't know,
I,
we will see, I guess I, I feel like this is going to be,
-- it's
-- about two weeks away at this point
and then you have 24 months to
correct
like GDPR.
If it passes, we'll ignore it for two years and then, oh my God, we'll all panic
and have
whatever the content equivalent of those cookie warnings is.
No, I, I suspect it will pass.
And then two years from now we're going to have an absolute gong show of a mess. Yeah.
That's probably fair.
I don't know. I don't know. Anyway, anyway, back to the topic of content filtering
and I think from the perspective of security
there is
the idea. Sounds like it makes sense.
-- Well,
-- and especially subjective content filtering.
It is subjective.
That's a very good point.
But I, I think it's one of those ideas that sounds like it makes sense.
But I think it's, it's like it's like electronic voting
in theory, it doesn't sound that bad, but in practice,
-- it is a bag of snakes and there is no way you're going to do it
-- right.
Filtering toxic comments.
I can give you a 12th elevator pitch which is
now you don't have to see some of the really,
really horrendous stuff on the internet
and maybe like youtube actually pay people to look at videos who then
end up with ptsd because the stuff they're seeing is so horrific.
So there is actually a valid but like there is a real benefit
to automating this and that is we don't break all these poor moderators
who are either doing this for free or getting paid
and like
they're seeing stuff that is just so horribly bad
-- that it defies explanation. They
-- are.
But if, if we can't fix those sort of things, how is this going to be better?
Well, I think this would be part of that, right?
And you know, it's, it's this technology just won't be used on its own.
For example, you,
you start filtering toxic comments that may be
linked to videos and you start saying,
oh, you know,
we're seeing a high correlation of toxic comments linking to videos that are toxic.
-- No,
-- you know, OK. So here's what I'm going to pick on though about that is
so
well, It's a, it's a bad example, but
it is a terrible example because I,
have you ever clicked on a couple of youtube videos that,
that maybe are we'll say questionable content in some ways.
And I remember,
do you mean the Elsa Gate stuff?
Right. Like any of that?
And I mean,
I remember at one point it was clear that youtube was starting to think
I'm like a white supremacist because I watched the video and I'm like,
holy crap.
No, like quit showing me this garbage. I don't want any and there's no way
to really fix it other than just I started watching like,
things that were the opposite to be like youtube.
Quit, stop this.
I've, I've had that problem occur with uh Amazon and it's suggestions of what to buy.
And I'm like, no, II, I was just browsing that I actually don't want to buy that
and do I need to like, go buy some normal safe items now to like, reset my.
-- Right. Right.
-- My filters serious. Because I was just,
that's what I hate about these A I systems.
-- They, they get out of control
-- and there's no recourse.
It's not like I can appeal to Amazon and be like, can you please?
Like, I mean, I just was curious if you sold powdered aluminum and iron,
I didn't actually want to make thermal.
I just wanted to see if it was available.
You know, please stop trying to,
no,
tell
me
I'm on a watch list now for, you know,
making explosives probably.
Yep. Yep. Exactly.
And like that's the, that's one of the things that just scares me to death is that if
either by accident or even on purpose groups
abuse this and you end up
just, it, it, it could easily go off the rails and again,
we end up in a position where humans are starting to look at it.
And now these poor humans, like you said,
are getting ptsd because of the just horrific things they have to watch or read.
And
it's,
uh, man, they, they, again, in theory, I think it's a great idea,
but I think in practice it is impossible.
Well, here's a question though, even if it's impossible,
is it better than doing nothing?
And I
be,
the answer is a strong, maybe. I, I don't know,
I
don't know if maybe is good enough, but it is definitely a maybe. And,
and it's,
I, I always say this and I, I especially pick on security people of, we love to be, say,
you know, if it's not perfect, it's not worth doing.
And that's usually not true.
And I don't think that's true. In this case.
I think the question becomes,
where do we draw our lines and what do we define as acceptable?
Because
it's, this is like new territory as humans.
We don't have any sort of anything to draw on, to educate us on this.
-- And
-- it's, oh, yeah, we've never had anything remotely.
I mean, the, the
right, like, the only thing we're really good at is seeing lions in the grass,
all of this other stuff.
We have no idea.
No, I would agree 100%.
So, I, I don't know. I, I have no idea. And it, it's
my guess is it's going to take a couple
of generations to figure some of this out just because
you and I did not grow up with the internet. So
that,
like our internal wiring in our brains can't just can't deal with a lot of this stuff.
Well, and, but part of the challenge is we don't have generations to deal with this.
But
I mean, this technology, I look at how far technology has moved in the last 20 years.
You know,
the computers I'm buying and the devices I'm buying literally
look nothing like what I had 20 years ago.
-- Uh
-- That is correct. But I think that is the new, the new mindset.
The youth are acquiring is just the constant change.
Like, in our case, when we were growing up,
I mean,
let's face it from probably the 19 fifties ish
to probably what the mid to late nineties,
the technology wasn't drastically different.
Like, yeah, you got a computer in your house. Isn't that neat?
Look, it can play these crappy games. But as soon as the internet came, just Kapa,
-- everything went off the rails.
-- Well, a simple example,
Felix,
we have to plug a keyboard into the computer because
you can't just tell a computer what to do.
Oh, wait, no, actually
that analogy doesn't work anymore.
What kind of piece of crap computer is this?
Yeah, exactly. I was like, no, wait, it's windows.
It has, uh, I want to say Cortana, Cortana.
So I was like,
but I was like, yeah, wait a minute. I, that's a bad analogy, you know.
Yeah. Whoops.
Yeah. Exactly. Exactly.
Yep. Yep. I hear you, man. It's like that. The Star Trek, what is it? Star Trek four.
When Scotty was talking about
computer,
the
computer. Right.
No, you, you know, you have to, you have to push,
push the buttons and then of course he goes crazy.
Like, he, he a typing speed of, you know, like, 300 words a minute. Yeah.
He, like, cracks his knuckles and,
yeah.
Right. Right.
And he, he, he gives us with transparent aluminum which if, if,
for those of you listening you've never seen Star Trek Four.
It's fantastic. Go watch it. There are whales in it. Right.
Which,
which ironically were, it was a concern.
They were going to go extinct back then and then it wasn't. And now it might be again.
So
hooray always relevant
anyway, I think we should, we should start wrapping this one up, I guess. Yeah,
I,
I hope what Google wants to do succeeds.
But I think I'm equally terrified.
It
-- is going to go wrong in a
-- terrible way. Well, and my concern too is even if
let's just spherical cows for a moment, let's say they build an A I
that objectively just filters the really, really horrible, horrific stuff.
Part of my concern is,
is that then we ignore those people and they end up in
their own crazy echo chamber and like that guy in Toronto,
they end up renting a van and driving down
the sidewalk trying to run over women or something equally
-- bonkers.
-- It, it, it is. And you and I,
so
Kurt and I talk about this all the time and he has
a pretty firm position if we have to try and I have
a pretty firm position of like these people are too far gone
to save and I don't think we'll ever agree on this topic,
but I, I, we also
will say polite enough to one another that we agree to disagree
and
that is how debate in society should work.
Well, actually, I, I would say I partly agree with you.
Right. II, I hold, I hold mutually opposing viewpoints on this topic
and I'm just not sure
-- that's
-- fair.
But yeah, I'm just not sure.
-- I don't know, man, may
-- maybe we need A I trolls to infect these toxic communities and,
and brainwash them back.
Like, speaking of Brexit, I'm pretty sure that's how we got there.
I don't, those weren't A I trolls. Those were Russian trolls. It's fine.
Well, yeah, you don't even, you don't even have to try that hard
-- anyway.
-- All right, I'm, I'm calling it
before we get ourselves on a list.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, use the Pound O as podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.