Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 160 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime Josh Pressers.
So I always love these two part episode things we do
because we just finished the other episode like minutes ago.
And I have no idea how long it's been in real
life because I might publish them at the same time,
I might publish them.
I don't know, a week apart, we'll see like only time will tell.
So, hello, listener from some point in the past, I guess.
But anyway, right. Cool.
So disclosure is our topic and we kind of talked about,
we had a bit of a grab bag in the last episode.
We talked about a whole bunch of crazy disclosure,
ideas and concepts and we really wanted to focus on open source this
time and I'm going to frame this in the context of Web men,
which has a wild story
around it at the,
at this time that is still developing and I'm sure isn't near complete
and
is amazing.
-- So
-- honestly, I'm kind of shocked that Web Men is still a thing.
Nothing ever dies. Kurt you should know. So web
is that web-based admin panel thing for your server, right?
Where you can like set up virtual host format, the hard drive,
fiddle with your email and it's basically you can,
that's
management, whatever.
So anyway, there was a talk at defcon
in
the
AEC village. I believe it was if I'm remembering correctly
where a researcher discovered a backdoor in Wedman
-- and he talked about it.
-- OK? Like an intentional backdoor,
an intentional backdoor, bad person added a backdoor, right? And
he didn't tell the web men people that he found it.
I
found out after his talk about this. And
if I was disclosing an issue,
-- I
-- would say there's actually a difference between
a security vulnerability and an intentional backdoor.
No, the web and people didn't put it there.
-- Kurt, somebody hacked them, added a back door and this guy found
-- it.
Like, how long was it in there for
a
couple of versions? And in fact,
they,
it didn't, it wasn't on by default, you had to set a setting. And then I guess, uh
they try due to a series of bizarre events, they, they,
somebody submitted a pull request,
maybe the same guy to like basically enable this
setting by default and it broke too much stuff.
So they undid it.
So there was a small window where all of
the web men instances were vulnerable to this.
But
the ignoring all of that,
if you are a researcher
and you show up at a conference with, with a talk like this and you've never,
you haven't told the open source project what's going on.
-- Don't do that.
-- Well, especially like I'm just looking at web men's thing.
They have a security page with security alerts,
lots of
them.
But the point is they, they do fix security flaws and I,
I don't know how they are about it but I assume they're not complete jerks.
-- You know,
-- my understanding is they are acceptable.
I don't, I wouldn't say they're amazing. I wouldn't say they're bad.
I would say they are,
they're good at what they do. Exactly. And that's a huge part of this is,
this is where framing open source differently
is enormously important because
as a researcher,
-- you're talking to a guy who might,
-- I would say it's complicated
because there's open source like Red Hat where like
you and I literally were paid to deal with.
-- Well, these people,
-- no matter what open source, I would,
I would put that in the vendor bucket when I say open source,
I'm talking about a project.
Oh, ok. Ok. You're talking about the, the upstream, right? Got it
-- upstream. Exactly. Exactly.
-- Ok.
What about an upstream, like openshift that's owned by Red Hat
vendor. That's clearly a vendor, right? There's,
and that one, that one's too easy. I mean, we could
open SSL.
It gets a little more dicey because Open SSL is a foundation and is that a vendor,
is it not a vendor?
I don't know what's going on anymore.
And
that one's more complicated.
But even them, I would,
I would dump in the vendor bucket and not think twice about it just because it,
it makes life easier and like they have a dedicated security team
and they're competent and they know what they're doing.
I mean,
one of the challenges you get is if you're a researcher and you go to
say an open source project that may have never released a security update before.
In fact, this just happened to me about a year ago where
I went to a project and I basically said,
look like we found the security issue in your stuff and they said,
I don't know what that means. Right.
And, and then I looked at their website, they never released a security update.
Well, not intentionally,
but they know we fixed security flaws they don't know about.
But,
yeah.
Ok. That's fair. I will agree with that 100%.
And so, like, they didn't know what to do.
Well, see. And this is what drives me is fundamentally what do you do?
Well, fix the code and ship an update
and, and maybe ideally label it as a security update.
-- Yeah. But
-- that's easy for us to do.
I mean, and in our case, like I got him a CV ID,
like we did it upright just because they were,
but at the same time it was one of those situations where
it's like if you have a heart attack in front of the doctor's house. Right. Oh, good.
You're fine. But, you know, that doesn't usually happen.
So it's, it's obviously
dier for a lot of people. Yeah.
And I mean, if you're a researcher and you go to an open source project and say, hey,
I found the security issue and they come back and say, I don't know what that is.
-- What do you do now?
-- Honestly, I would say
I would have, I would try to help them understand the vulnerability or the flaw,
you know, and, but more in the context of a classic vulnerability
or flaw, not like a security vulnerability or security flaw
and get them to fix it hopefully properly and ship an update
and ideally label that update as a security update so that people know
that, you know,
this update maybe matters more than those other updates and ideally get a CV for it.
But, you know, honestly,
the main thing is get the code fixed and get it out there.
I, I agree with you,
but I would not be shocked at all if researchers who say don't have free
time and maybe this is something they do for fun in the side or whatever,
they might send that mail, they get back.
I don't know what this is
and they may never reply again.
-- You
-- know, these people are doing this for free. Then that's kind of a best effort.
And my one comment there is you could, for example,
then as a security researcher choose to just
simply publish it to the full disclosure list,
kind of not the nicest thing to do. But I disagree.
Well, no, no, no, no, no, I didn't say it's not the right thing to do.
I said it's not the nicest thing to do
that's different.
And for example, you could, you could send it to Cert
-- and have them deal with it. Cert
-- doesn't care. Cert's already too busy.
In fact, I'll never forget I had, I called CT once.
This was years and years and years ago where there was,
we, we, I, I was in the middle of an incident and
in fact,
I was at Red Hat at the time and I just started working with them and like we needed,
we needed ct's help to make some contacts
and I called him and this was like, on a Saturday morning, I think it was.
And they're like, we, we're not gonna help you.
We don't, we, we're not gonna do anything
and they hung up
and it was like, what now, what just happened?
I'm surprised they actually answered the phone on a Saturday.
Yeah, I found a number but I don't know if I was supposed to, but like, they didn't care
and I think that's the problem is, Cert is
-- grossly overwhelmed.
-- Well, no, no, no, no.
See, you are just making the attribution again.
You say they don't care, they may not have understood.
Didn't you just finish saying that when you try to report a security flaw?
Maybe, you know, except that the remote end might not caught on to it as fast.
-- You'd like
-- this one was pretty obvious, Kurt,
like they knew, they knew what was going on and they,
they legitimately said we don't care like this was, this was very cut and dry, right?
This wasn't a oh I can overwrite one null byte of memory in
this obscure location that's in the middle of a data structure like it.
I think it's exploitable. Like no, no, this was like,
yeah,
there's a guy holding a gun to my head and he's going to shoot me if you don't help.
Oh, you don't care. Thank what? By
that. That's what we were talking about here, right? This was,
it was very obvious. Yeah, but anyways
isn't going to care and I think publishing it to the world is not
irresponsible necessarily because at least somebody who
might care can do something about it.
Then
now I will also say as a caveat to this github
is starting to do security advisories for projects on github.
And basically at this point, everyone's on github.
I think. So I'm comfortable just saying that like
that might be a game changer, but it obviously it's going to take some time.
So we're not there yet.
But at the same time, if you're an open
source project and you're listening to this or you have friends or whatever,
uh, look at the github
security advisories.
Well, the other thing to remember too is, I mean, you don't have to make github
your source of truth. You can just clone it into github to take advantage of this.
Right.
And that's something I think a lot of people forget
is that you don't have to like move to github,
just make a copy of the stuff in github
with all the depths and everything and
-- you'll start getting those notifications.
-- Sure. Right. Right.
Yeah. And that's fair. That's fair. So let's, let's keep going.
We have a situation where a person
may have reported a security issue to an open source project
and let's say they understand it is a problem
and they're willing to fix it.
Ok?
What happens next is where things can get dicey as well,
where
I've seen open source projects get security reports and they might just fix it
immediately and say nothing like they might just add a commit to their source
source co management
people.
Yeah. Right. Right. And they might not release a security advisory.
They might not say anything.
And you might say, hey, why don't you guys release a security advisory?
And they might say we don't care, we don't need one. This is fine.
Just everyone runs our current version. It's ok and you're like maybe not. Um
And I think that's one of those instances where again,
like publish it to full disclosure or something.
Well, see, here's the problem is you get some really fundamental,
fundamentally different business models and software cultures,
but they have very different realities.
And one thing I wanted to mention is, well, so like, where do we,
where do we put the line of?
So you release a piece of software, how responsible are you for it
once you release it? Because,
you know,
I literally know people who've released a piece of
software that they kind of scratch their own itch
and it ended up getting like 10 million downloads
because it apparently was a really good scratcher.
Well, are they all of a sudden beholden to these 10 million people to keep them safe?
You know, because I'm pretty sure every software license ever says, you know,
we disclaim any and all everything to do with anything going wrong.
-- So
-- actually, I have a great story for you about that. The, the, the guys who did zip
the
Vor
and
the other, I forget they've got the VP A is VP eight there. I forget.
Anyway, they've got,
they have all these audio and video formats they created, right?
And uh Chris Montgomery is the guy who
is kind of the brains behind it all.
And I remember working with him at one point where there was a security issue in like,
so in Ag
Vor library he was publishing
and his comment was, oh well, this is just like, you know,
this is proof of concept code.
No one should be running this in production.
And I remember
Chris the freaking world like this code is in everything today.
Like this is probably one of the most U I it's in
the top 20 of most used pieces of code on the planet.
Like no, this is not a proof of concept.
We have to fix this and,
and that happens sometimes.
And now at the same time,
I think the popularity of a project is something
to take into account because let's face it.
If you are fixing an issue that is in 20% of everything ever built on the planet.
I think it is a very different universe than if
it's a project that let's say has 25 installs.
-- I
-- could flip it on its head and say, you know,
if you're doing something for free that 20% of the planet uses,
shouldn't that 20% of the planet
maybe be kicking back some resources to help you,
right? I mean, because that's the problem we have in
like in the CV world, for example, you know,
there's a lot of, you know, when I shut down the DW, I remember everybody's like, oh,
I would have helped and it's like, no, no, I know you wouldn't have helped.
And I have the proof that you wouldn't have helped because you didn't help.
And I asked
people and I obviously, I, you know,
I didn't have a big marketing campaign to ask for help.
So I would say fundamentally if you are kind enough
to write some software and give it away for free.
Awesome. Thank you.
That's all you have to do now,
if you want to do more and especially if you
want to do security and do it really nicely.
Awesome. Thank you. That's amazing.
But fundamentally if you don't, I I'm not going to be angry at you.
Uh So here's where I would turn this on, on its head and I agree with you.
I think just like just publishing source code for the world to use is an enormous
benefit to society. And that's, that's all you owe. You don't even know what's that.
But thank you. Here's why I want to turn it on its head though is, let's say
you have a, in order,
I'll pick on Red Hat because we have that know them from experience.
So let's say
Red Hat shipping your stuff and you have a security issue in your stuff.
There's no shame in saying redhead, I need help
or in fact, and if, if, if someone is shipping your stuff and you say, hey,
I've got a security issue here I could use some help with and they say, no,
screw those guys.
-- That's not. Ok.
-- Well, and it's the classic free rider problem.
And to me when I say free rider problem, I need it in the sense of like how to identify
the situation not to pass judgment on it.
Because fundamentally one of the fundamental pieces of open source is that,
yeah, you can take well depending on the license,
but you can take my open source and go make a
pile of money with it and give me nothing in return.
Not even a bug report
or a thank you.
And quite fundamentally,
is it moral or ethical? Don't know.
But that's what the license typically allows and even encourages in many cases.
Right. Right.
Now, should these morally and ethically, should they kick back or help?
Yeah, probably.
Especially if they, you know,
don't want to get surprised the next time there's a security
and it's like,
-- why didn't you tell us? And
-- that's exactly it.
That's exactly the right way to look at this is, I mean, when we were at Red Hat,
if a project came to us and said we need help like we were on it.
Right.
That was, that was part of the job, was,
was kind of that community help in that respect.
And
I mean, even today, look,
if you're a project listening and you need help and you email me,
I'm going to help you.
I don't care if I've never heard of your project before.
I don't care if I don't even know what the language is like,
you will get help because it's just, it's one of those, like, morally,
right things to do for society because this is,
and even just from a utility point of view, like,
if you and I help will take five minutes and we'll save them five hours.
Well, right, because we also have done this for 20 years.
That, that's another part of the, the
here, I guess too. Right.
Is, is if you're a new project,
if you're a new researcher and you've never done this before,
it's the used car salesman thing, man.
Right. When you go to buy a car, that guy, you think you're going to finagle him?
No, he, he, like he or she does this like three times a day,
-- you do it once every three years
-- right before
you've stepped all the way through the door,
they know what's going on.
Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. Right. Exactly. Right. And anyway, uh, so, right.
So you're a researcher, you report something
and
it, it, it can be a challenge.
Now, at the same time, I will say there is nothing wrong with
not, not doing this all in secret.
And this is a trap I think we fell into as an industry a long time ago. And we were,
I, I will blame myself as being obscenely guilty of this in the past of where
every security issue needs to be secret.
-- Like we, we have to keep a secret, we can't talk about it
-- and by security,
you mean embargoed.
-- Yeah,
-- embargoed would be the term that was used in for, you know, in our space.
And we talked about this stuff and I will tell you now,
an embargoed security issue is insanely expensive.
And I don't mean that in terms of money, I mean,
it's mentally exhausting.
You generally need special setups internally to run your tests and test, you know,
do you check in your code, all this kind of stuff?
And it is an
enormous amount of work and sometimes that's ok. Right.
-- You look at some of these, well,
-- sometimes it's needed.
Right.
-- For a really bad security issue. It's ok,
-- but very rarely. Right.
Exactly.
And I think in 99.9% of the time you don't need to have an embargo issue
and just dumping this stuff in a public issue on github
-- is the right way to do it
-- well, and in fairness, github
has made this easier now. So kudos to them.
Yes.
Yes, they have,
you can at least have private issues and stuff because there are
some really good arguments for the embargo thing which is like,
for example,
you don't end up with press about it
and then people harassing you constantly because that's,
that's the thing.
Like, I remember some security issues in certain pieces of software
would get the press going and
then you have to deal with that.
And I mean,
there's been cases where these poor open source projects have gotten really grumpy
because it's like we got bad press about X because of this.
You know, why couldn't you report this privately or whatever? Right.
-- Right.
-- You called my baby ugly. Basically.
Sometimes it's just an ugly baby Kurt.
But please don't, please don't send me hopefully they
just
want
sure that's it. Uh,
but anyway, anyway,
this is one of those situations where I think when
I would say if you're a researcher contacting a vendor,
you kind of hold all the cards and you can make them dance for their dinner.
I think if you're a researcher and you're working with a small open source project,
like you need to cut these guys a little bit of slack
and this is totally the right way to look at it.
And,
and additionally, if you don't want to work with a little project,
find a vendor shipping their stuff,
like go to a Red Hat or somebody and report to
them because I know when we were at Red Hat,
if you wanted to report an issue,
Debian and ubuntu,
-- basically everything,
-- go to one of those guys and,
and talk to them and interact with them and that can sometimes work, work very,
very well.
So, you know, at the same time, I want to say,
let's say you're an open source project and somebody comes to you with a
security issue.
What, what do you do? Right?
-- What now,
-- I mean, uh depending on your maturity model basically, I would say try to,
you know, fix it, ship it and again, label it as a security issue so that
the people know it's kind of a special one,
ideally maybe get a CV E identifier as well because that
makes it easier to identify and talk about.
But also gets it into the CV database, which, you know,
again is a great notification tool because to put it bluntly, you know,
unless you're paying for a vulnerability feed
CV is kind of the only free vulnerability feed out there.
It, it is true. Now, let's, let's back this all the way up.
If someone sends you a security report, it's a bug at the very least, right?
How would you fix any bug?
You're just going to do a release, you might have a change log entry.
I don't know, it depends on the project, how you're going to deal with it.
So I would say at the absolute minimum, if someone sends you something
patch it,
-- right. Get a, get a patch shoved in your repo
-- well, or at least document it.
In some cases,
security flaws are really hard to fix because of architectural design choices,
at least documented the behavior and let people know about it.
Right? Because
then I can make at least some decision as to what
to do with this and,
and that decision could be to stop using
the software because it's just broken and unfixable
or I could change the behavior or I could use it in a safe way.
I mean,
you know, there,
there was a lot of cases at Red Hat where there
was a flaw in some software and it was like,
ok, well, we don't use it in that way, haa,
you know, we'll, we'll eventually patch it and ship an update for it, but
we're not vulnerable in, you know,
and we use it in a very constrained manner in this product, for example.
-- So we're,
-- we're good.
So that's actually becoming a lot harder now
because of all these automated security scanners,
I get scan reports on a regular basis now where people will say
uh here's the 7000 CV I DS. My scanner says you're vulnerable to
and I will say uh 6995 of these are
false positives and these five don't affect us because
we're not using that functionality in that library. And they say
we don't care, the scan has to come back, clean, fix it.
And then it's like, I don't think,
-- you know what you just asked?
-- Well, and the thing is that's not really
a
problem for open source projects because, well,
you're not paying me so good luck with that scan report.
Exactly. Exactly.
If you're an open source project and someone ever send you a scan report like that,
like just send them back a picture of someone holding up the middle finger and that,
that there's a nice picture of Linus.
Right. That's exactly the right thing to do there
because they owe,
you owe them nothing you've already given them more than they deserve.
And so that's,
that's really important to always remember
now
at the same time.
Uh Yeah, if you're, if you're a consumer of this stuff, like, don't,
don't be asking projects for that, that's,
you're in a hole if you do that. Right. Like go help.
These people don't ask them for help. Right. So,
this is a bizarre mishmash of advice and problems again
because this is super hard to do and especially in open source.
I think it's even dicier
-- than it's ever been before without question.
-- Well, it also matters more. I mean,
it used to be computer software around on a computer, did something but now
I have computer software in my house that controls a bunch of light bulbs, you know,
-- a ring doorbell, but
-- not only that, it's all open source.
Yeah.
But at the more extreme end, like, there's Tesla, like that vehicle.
If somebody hacked it and made it drive,
like they can make it drive into a crowd of people.
Security bugs are, you know, you can blow up generators.
Like every,
every piece of industrial equipment is now attached
to the internet and you can probably,
most of them, you know, run it in some way.
Well, and again, it, it's, it's all open source.
I mean, that's the, that's the most important thing to think of here is,
and, and again,
this is where
I feel like if you're an open source project and you don't have the ability to handle,
dealing with security
reports.
Right.
Essentially,
if you lack the ability to kind of disclose
things to the public about what's going on,
you need to ask for help
and the people who are running your stuff
can either help or they can get screwed over because you're
not doing what they think you should do for them.
And there's no shame in that either.
And I think that is such an important point is
these so many organizations are treating open source as this,
just set it and forget it, thing.
Well, they're strip mining it. Right.
-- And they,
-- right, they, they take whatever they want and they never update it.
And this is actually a place where these automated scanners.
Well, I know that a lot of them are terrible right now.
I think this is where we're going to end up where these
automated scanners are going to be able to look at what you have
and say
you have software from 12 years ago and it has these 7000 security issues in it.
You need to fix it.
Well, the thing I keep telling a lot of devs is,
is it's not so much about fixing the security flaws, but it's,
if you can't keep the software up to date,
then essentially you're diverging from reality,
you're diverging from what everybody else has,
which means at some point when you do have to fix it. Well,
good luck with that.
It's probably not even going to work, you know,
and it also speaks to just your general ability to ship an update or fix
your software because again, if you can't do that, you can't do that.
Now, for whatever reason, be it a bug or a security flaw versus,
you know, if you keep up to date on security updates, that kind of forces you to,
to have better process, you know, C I and CD,
you know, I've seen a lot of organizations that don't have C inc D.
So shipping a, you know, a software release is a major
Multiweek or even multi
month marathon in some cases and it's, you know, not easily reproducible
again, not talking about a security reproducibility thing.
I mean,
actually just talking in the sense of like we shipped an update and it didn't blow up,
you know.
No, I know, I know exactly what you mean.
And
so I,
I guess the thing I keep coming back to in my mind as
we talk about this in the context of open source is very much.
If you're a project,
you owe us nothing.
You've already given more than you,
you need to because the amount you need to give is zero and you've surpassed that.
Now, I think you could, there,
there will be people who will make the argument that it is morally wrong
to release software to the world and then never take care of it.
And
if you believe that just don't use open source, which
you can't
is kind of where that
is,
-- but I feel like
-- never buy anything ever again.
That's right. Seriously.
I,
I think the, the place we're going to have to end up with all of this is
if you are an organization consuming or repackaging open source,
which is basically every organization at this point.
I think the last holdout might have been Microsoft and
they gave up on this a long time ago.
They didn't give up, they embraced the heck out of it.
It's nice actually because
I, I have a, I kind of hate to say this but I have a slightly better Linux experience
on Windows 10 now than I do actually on native Linux.
Oh, my goodness. We wanna talk about that.
But here's the thing
with all of this put together
with a pretty bow on top
is
the organizations, the vendors making money off of the open source.
It is up to them
to somehow
make sure these problems are dealt with and there's a multitude of
-- ways
-- or to make the choice of not dealing with it.
No, that's not, that's not gonna be an option.
I think the, the automated scanners
-- are going to fix that
-- the light bulbs I bought.
I know they're running out of date software and
will never be updated properly and have security flaws.
Like, for example, if you end map, scan the base unit,
it dies like you have to hard power it.
That's a, that's a feature. See you can't, you can't hack it if it crashes.
Right.
And, but I, I went in knowing this,
that like there is no good light bulbs available that will
get software updates for at least say five or 10 years,
like the lifetime of the light bulb.
And so I made a choice to buy basically the cheapest, most garbage ones because.
Right. Right.
Same thing.
And,
and we've talked about this at length in the past is like
crappy and working is going to defeat secure and working every time.
I mean, unquestionably. But however I'm talking about, I'm a company
shipping software
that's full of open source.
And
what I'm seeing now is customers
are starting to scan this software using tools.
Like, I mean, we talked to aqua security not long ago. Right.
Or, or SNCC is another one.
-- Well,
-- yeah, in that case,
if you want to keep those customers and not make them angry then, yeah,
you better start fixing this stuff and keeping, well, not fixing it,
keeping it up to date.
Yes. I mean, just, just blindly updating it would suffice.
But I, I have a feeling
right. I mean, that's right now, but I have a suspicion in the future.
Blindly updating.
Won't be enough because these,
these scanners are gonna get better and better and better
and we're gonna reach a point where
the actual security of the stuff you're including is going to matter. And that means
if you want to use it
now, we're going to have to start caring more. And like today,
you basically have three options.
Option one is, I don't care, I'm not doing anything,
which is basically what most people do.
Option two is getting involved with the upstream and in some cases
you'll see that in a lot you won't because if you're shipping,
let's say 500 open source libraries in your product,
you're not going to get involved.
Well,
Mercedes remember that I looked at their list of all
the open source in a Mercedes car and it's over 1000
-- projects.
-- Yeah. Right. Exactly. You're not gonna get involved in all 1000 right?
Maybe some, maybe the most important ones you could conceivably get involved in.
And the third
I think is going to be
I I envision a sort of universe
where there are kind of like companies helping Shepard around the open source.
And like today, Red Hat is an example of that.
I mean,
the way they work is diverging from kind
of the the rest of mainstream development now,
but
it went back when Red Hat was founded like that, that was mainstream open source,
unquestionably, right?
Like they were the only game in town for the most part,
I see there's companies like Tide Lift, for example,
that have the ability to kind of sponsor open source. I see some of the efforts
SNCC are doing where they're getting heavily
involved in some of these security issues
and they're really shepherding them along and
they're doing research to find new ones.
Like that's really cool.
And I think that is
unquestionably where all of disclosure is going to end up at some point, but I don't
and it's probably 20 years away.
Well, I think part of it is the industrialization of it,
right?
It's that centralization, that economy of scale, that specialization, you know,
the fact is like when you have a security team with
like five full time people that just do this and really
CV and stuff,
you know, they can churn through a lot of vulnerability
really
fast and, you know,
you can handle a lot of
vulnerabilities and upstream notifications and assisting them
with a pretty small team.
But basically, but they have to basically be, that's all they do.
-- Yep,
-- that's fair.
In fact, that's funny because I just II I released an advisory today and I,
I only do this a couple times a month now, only a couple of times a month and it,
it takes a while to remember.
Well, it's not like it used to be, I mean, you know,
that elastic currently doesn't have, we do pretty good while I'll say.
And so I don't,
I don't release a ton of advisories and every time I do it now I've got to, you know,
pull up my process document and,
and check it out and make sure I'm doing things right.
And
it's funny because I remember when I did this, you know, twice a day, every day.
It's like, I don't, I don't even need to look at the process document, you know, II,
I am the process document.
It's fine.
So it's just, it's different,
it's different and I get this and if you do it once or twice a year, it's even harder,
you know.
So,
all right. So we are approaching the end
and I guess let's
I, I will give my parting thought and I will let you give the last note.
So here's my parting thought,
ask for help. There are a lot of people who can help you.
I will help you. Kurt will help you.
-- You can probably just say on Twitter, hey, I need help with this
-- in fairness.
Kurt's pretty busy. So Kurt may point you at somebody else to help.
-- I'm just saying like, well, no, and
-- that's just it, right?
Like I'm, I'm not going to help anyone and hold their hand.
I'm going to say here's what you need to read, here's what you need to look at, right?
And that, that's what, that's what I mean by help.
-- We're gonna do the work
-- because I've had people try and fob off their, their job on me,
like vendors who are like, I want you to help me
and, yeah, don't do that. And I, I will not do your job for you.
And if you're a vendor, like,
I'm not working for you for free either. So I don't think that's an invitation.
That's the thing. Right. Just, just ask for help.
There's a lot of good security people out there
that can help you out
and
find them
and work with them.
And
I, I guess at the same time, like that also comes in into line with there,
there's a lot of talking heads if you ask someone for help and they don't help you.
I would be my,
be wary of their advice because it's quite likely they actually
don't know what they're doing and they just like they're,
they're a gas bag.
But anyway. All right.
-- So Kurt, your turn and
-- try to be a little bit kinder and more understanding
to each other,
you know, especially in the open source world.
Like I,
there's literally projects running on all the computers where it's one
person who works on it part time on the weekend.
Yep. Yep. That's true.
You know,
thanks to people like those,
not everybody gets to actually work for a vendor that
pays them to work on the thing full time.
And that, that's fair. Be nice. Be nice to open source.
And I guess if you're open source, uh, try to be nice
to the people you have to work with also.
But let's all just be everyone. Be nice to each other. Right?
That seems like good advice.
Yeah. All right, sweet. So, I guess thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, you see Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.