Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurtz Fried and my partner in biological firmware updates.
-- Josh Bresser. What's
-- a biological firmware update
of vaccine?
Oh, those right. Yes,
that's right.
Well, I, you didn't use those words.
I'm not real quick, man.
Well, it's funny because I was actually talking with my son about what is firmware.
And I was like, well, back in the day it was like, you,
you took an E prom and like physically burned it in,
it was like this magical hardware stuff that you could like reprogram.
It was kind of both the memory and the execution and magic.
And I'm like, and now firmware is just everything.
It's just software.
Like there's those shoes that had software. My, all my light bulbs have software.
This sort of leads into our topic for today, which is
what happens when you get things that are so large and complex. Can you secure them?
No.
No, you can't.
Right. And, and that's kind of,
yeah, basically, I mean, you can make it less
like the financial system amazes me like there's all these financial shenanigans.
We try to minimize their impact sometimes we win,
sometimes we have Bernie Madoff and we lose hard.
I feel like we've just mixed a lot of weird things into the pot.
-- Yeah.
-- But basically, so this is in the context of five G.
Well,
there's so there's a couple of things that
I think we should frame this conversation,
five G
part of it.
And we'll, we'll, we'll talk about that in a moment.
There's this code
COV
issue which is we,
we'll talk about that a little bit and then there's just more solar winds news,
which is the story that will never die.
I suspect.
So let's start at and,
and I guess we're going to wrap this all up into the box of third party
stuff. Ok?
And
sometimes it can work really well and sometimes it can absolutely not work.
I think it always works well. But let's start with five G. This one is your story.
I will let you explain it.
I love five G because it has the potential to be so amazing, right?
We're talking super low latency, super high speed.
You know, I,
I know what it's like now to have gigabit fiber at home and it is fantastic.
Like I'm so happy, for example,
spacelink is now available for people out in the sticks
because they have terrible internet, sorry,
sorry,
whatever.
And so
five G, you know, I look at what the internet enabled whole new industries
and I look at what smartphones and apps have enabled whole new industries,
right?
Not just new companies,
but just entirely new things that we couldn't even conceive of before.
You could not run the modern economy on dial up.
Just you couldn't, you have to have high speed.
And so five G is fascinating because I was, I,
I was running a thought experiment with myself which is given a
five G network that I own and operate and fully control.
Can I actually
know for sure that it's not
aggressing data that I want to stay in my network?
So like billing or customer data or it's like secretly mirroring all the
phone calls of all the government officials to a server in Russia.
And the answer is because five G is so big
and complicated and there's so many ingress and egress points,
like it's connected to the internet, it's connected to millions of cell phones,
it's connected to millions of computers.
You can't lock it down.
There's even more to it than that.
And I'll put this story in the show notes is from the European angle.
The providers of all of this gear for five G is the United States or China.
-- If you're Europe, do you trust either of those entities?
-- Well, and it gets better.
It's not just the, they're providing you the equipment
in a lot of cases, they're operating it for you. Right. Right.
And that's the thing like there.
If I buy the equipment and operate it there's, at least
-- maybe the possibility I can sort of secure it.
-- No, there isn't. Well, not anymore.
-- Well, no.
-- And then, yeah, now with it being as complicated as is there is no chance.
But if I'm not even operating it, if that's outsourced, then there's no hope.
You literally
the security.
It,
it's basically bank security and that I give my money to the bank and
I trust and hope that they do the right thing and don't lose it.
Right? And from the aspect of Europe, like,
do you, do you trust the United States government not to do shenanigans?
And the answer is no, they don't.
Do you trust the Chinese government not to do shenanigans?
-- Yeah,
-- look, I'm just thinking, you know,
given 30 days of cell phone and phone records
for a country that's the entire social graph.
Who knows who, what their relationships are probably.
And I was thinking about this, like, how do you securely,
how do you securely communicate with somebody else nowadays? I mean,
and you know,
so uh you're gonna need like end to end encryption so nobody can watch it.
But then the second problem is who cares? Because meta data is usually enough.
But just the fact that a talk to be at three in the morning for 20 minutes,
the only answer is you have to go to the park and sit on opposite park benches and
right, just like in the movies, I'm sure that's fine.
Yeah, that was my favorite thing with the Burn after reading was all these people.
Like,
I've been to DC
and
there's, like, in all these movies, there's just tons of people in suits,
sitting on park benches,
like eating an apple and reading the paper or just sitting there staring,
not at you. And I'm like, that doesn't happen in real life.
Some of the parks might have. I mean, so here's the thing. Everyone in DC wears a suit.
-- Yeah. But, and they're all camped out on their phones.
-- I mean, now they are, but
you know, these old movies, it was different,
right where you didn't have a phone so you might have to read the paper or something.
Stare at the squirrels, maybe. I mean, you figure if I've got an hour of free time
gonna go sit outside and, and do nothing, you know,
the, the other thing is,
is you can't not deploy five G if you want to have a modern economy, you, you,
you can't opt out of this.
-- So what do you do?
-- Well, and, and so this kind of leads itself now into this code
COV
discussion as well where the, the,
so the story that happened here is there's this company, I'm probably,
I'm probably pronouncing it wrong, but I call it code COV
in my head.
And the idea is this is a company that provides a tool that when you run your tests,
it will tell you how much code coverage, your test hit.
And obviously in any application, ideally,
you want your testing to hit 100% of the code you have written.
And of course, that's never the case.
There's always some amount that never gets hit in testing.
-- Well, unless
-- you're Google,
you have
-- shenanigans.
-- Right.
Right.
And so what happens though is the way this
works is you basically inside of your like Jenkins scripts
you
call
out, it's the, you know, curl
pipe to sh sort of command
where you call,
that's literally the documentation is bash space less than bracket.
E
hyphen
S blah, blah, blah, blah blah bracket.
And so what happens is you're downloading the script from their
server and then basically just running it in your environment,
-- run your tests, magic and then you get a
-- report.
My favorite part of this is
you're not just downloading it once and keeping a copy of it, but you're doing it
repeatedly potentially.
That's right. Every time you run it, it's a
new
for bad things to happen.
And, and that's basically what happened is it
-- an evildoer got into their stuff.
-- We don't know that they were evil,
whatever
of an entity
of unknown origin and intent, basically added code to this script
that then
we, we don't exactly know. And this is one of those stories.
No, it exported all the, all the, the g environment variables.
That's what we know today and here's my concern with that is the story.
It's evolving over time.
Like Joseph Men just wrote a story this morning at the time of recording that,
that kind of shed some more light on this.
There's a lot more going on here. We don't know. And my suspicion is the ko
-- people don't know either.
-- Well, the thing is we can't know,
we know for sure one instance of the script did this one bad thing.
But I mean,
there could have been scripts flying out of there that formatted
the hard drive or inserted malicious code or a malware or,
or they could have done anything.
And I mean, here's where it gets complicated is so
generally speaking,
in most C I environments
you,
you aren't, you,
you want to build your code and not necessarily release what
you're testing in that way and it's complicated and weird.
But I think in many instances,
the potential for backdoor here is probably pretty low,
but it's definitely not zero because obviously everyone kind
of has their own Homebrew C I infrastructure,
which is one of the unique challenges to this problem.
-- But anyway, anyway, there
-- are,
you don't have to be that sophisticated to place
a back door because you can go buy them,
you can rent them. Now.
That's
like the ransomware stuff. It's
true.
And I'm kind of shocked that nobody shoved a ransomware into one of these things.
-- But anyway,
-- so this is I, I want to tie this now to the five G story,
which is kind of that.
How do you trust what you're getting from
your five G vendor? How do you trust what you're getting from your software vendor?
And like this totally plays itself now into solar winds, which is like,
it's the same freaking story of some company gave you a thing. Now. What?
Well,
and it's not even just that they gave you a
thing but they've had problems in the past where,
oh, that thing was weirdly modified, whatever.
Just smash that override button and jam it in like straight up.
That's, you know what they were telling customers like, oh,
the digital signature failed.
Cool. Y just
force it.
And I'm like,
why even bother having digital signatures if you ignore them
-- when they fail? Which
-- everyone does. I mean,
you know, there's a couple of apps on my Mac where, you know, Apple is like, oh boy,
like it's not from the store and it's not signed and I'm like, just,
just install the same thing.
Shut up.
I need to work.
-- Uh
-- I can't help but feel like somebody installing
solar winds should be a little more careful than,
you know, me installing some random whatever on my Mac
one would think.
This reminds me of the whole BP Deepwater horizons disaster in that.
A company makes some relatively bad mistakes.
It gets exploited and it has an outside
effect. So
the code C
thing is great because it affects about 29,000
-- customers,
-- open source and companies and like the number is astronomical.
Well, and, and it's not one thing per company customer either, right?
A lot of them have multiple things.
So the amount of code affected by this, it's over 9000.
The thing I'm thinking about here is,
is how do you even begin to do incident response when incident response is like,
all right,
free company in the world has to go audit their code base for bad stuff.
Well, if they could do that,
they'd be doing that and they wouldn't
-- have as many security vulnerabilities you
-- can't because
for example, a bunch of open source has been affected by this.
You can't audit that, you don't know
-- what's in it half the time as it is. And so it's one of those unique problems
-- where,
well, and it spanned like three or four months. It was from January to April of 2021.
-- Like,
-- yeah, it's a long time
that that's what really offends me.
Not only that it was there for three or four months,
but that a customer had to notify them.
I mean, the company didn't keep an eye on this script.
Well, I'm sure they thought they were
but
-- they clearly weren't
-- because they specifically said as
one of their steps for fixing this,
that they are now downloading that script once in a while to you know,
sort of keep an eye on it.
And I'm like, well, that's, that's nice, but
there's so many ways to still
-- shenanigans.
-- Right. Right. Right.
So, ok. Ok.
-- So here's, I've, I've done a bunch of thinking about this one because this
-- is,
there's
literally no way to securely do this is to hand out a bash script and hope for the best.
It doesn't matter how secure it is because it's easy. So it's going to win. Ok.
So let's ignore that part of the problem, right?
Because that's, and here's the thing, even if it wasn't a bash script,
even if they had
something you downloaded from their website and inserted into your project,
it doesn't really matter because it's just going to end
up downloading a bunch of crap from them anyway.
That's probably unchecked.
That's the other thing that gets me right is by definition,
anything that has an update mechanism
-- is potential, arbitrary code execution.
-- That's right.
I mean, look at what was the not pet you right where it was,
it was literally an update from accounting software that was full of malware.
Here's the thinking on this because I've done a nontrivial amount of,
of writing and thinking on this topic because it matters.
So here's the deal is from the perspective of trust,
you just have to kind of draw a line and say I trust this open
source project.
I trust this vendor, whatever because there's just nothing you can do, right.
You might
think you can. But the reality is you actually can't.
If you have 300 dependencies from N PM in your project,
you're not auditing that code, right.
So you've got all this stuff, you're running it in your infrastructure
and let's say you think some of it might be bad.
So, what are you gonna do? Are you going to stop using it? Are you going to contact
the 9000 open source vendors you're using? There's just,
there isn't a good solution.
And even if you contact your corporation, you're going to say, hey,
give us a statement on this, we're going to be like, everything's fine.
We did our analysis like did you,
well,
you don't know.
So here's the thing,
the only solution to this problem is to have the ability to move quickly.
So when, when not, if,
when a report comes out that something was
we'll say maliciously modified or has questionable origin,
you have to be able to fix that in less than a day. That is the solution.
-- The
-- problem is what does fixing that mean?
Because if you are now looking at some, it means different things.
Well, and the problem is for this, for example, you're now saying
there may have been some malicious code added to your thing at
some point in the last three or four months.
I think what this really speaks to is having, you know,
sort of this Netflix style of infrastructure where it's,
it's constantly renewing itself.
Because I think one of the biggest things now
is we have to accept that the Attackers will win and get in.
So we have to make it really difficult
ideally for them to pivot and gain additional access
and number two to get persistence,
right?
And so, for example, one thing I loved at Red Hat was in theory,
the build system basically took a, you know,
an RP A source R PM package and built it in a quote unquote air quotes offline system,
right?
And the reason I like that is because mostly I didn't care about security,
I cared about the fact that we could actually build this thing.
Like if some remote website was down or not working,
we're not up the creek, right?
The challenge with that is, of course, it takes discipline and maturity to do that.
But I think it's, it's worth it.
And I think just that alone,
having your BUILD system essentially run in sort of an offline mode
would benefit people in so many ways, right? Like left
disappears and everything doesn't just immediately break.
-- That's part of it I think is
-- so caching and being able to do it offline, I get that,
that's tough because, you know, there's a lot of Mavin and Gradel and all these,
you know,
build systems that essentially anticipate being online and
grabbing stuff on the fly as needed,
right?
And so now you need to build this big thing in
front of it that kind of pre populates all that.
-- But,
-- and even those have had problems,
there's some hilarious problems you get where, for example,
there was a security researcher, I'll try to dig up the report.
But basically if you were running behind, I think it was Maven or J Frog,
you could basically
set it up. So internally
you might be querying some like package at
available in your J Frog except it checks like N PM first.
Yeah, it checks the public ones first.
-- So
-- if someone creates a public thing with the same name as your internal thing,
it's going to pull in the public one before it pulls in your internal one,
which obviously is like, hold on there.
Yeah, I remember we, I think we talked about that on our previous podcast maybe.
-- Anyway,
-- probably we talk about a lot of stuff.
That's the thing, right?
These, these build systems have made a lot of assumptions
that may or may not be what you're expecting
and they're definitely not expecting to be offline.
So getting them to work sort of offline is not, it's going to be nontrivial.
The other thing that gets me about this is the complexity.
I have sort of set up build C I CD pipelines. They are super nontrivial.
There's a reason
that there are so many commercial services that do this.
Yeah, it's super hard, you know,
you know what it reminds me of actually is to kind of put my geezer hat on for a minute.
Is
I remember creating build systems back in the make days, like when you had auto
-- comp and you had auto make and whatever
-- dot slash gunfire
space make space, make, install or no make test.
When you would do that, I remember you would, you would write like your auto
comp script
and it would be say 300 lines and it would create like 200,000 lines of output
in terms of checking lots of stuff and building your make files and doing this.
And I remember thinking I have no way to vet any of this stuff. It just created.
-- I'm going to assume it is correct.
-- I just played whack a mole like, OK, it failed. OK,
just try to fix OK. It's missing a hitter file or whatever.
Just, and just keep whacking what those moles until the thing.
I
mean, that was once the build system existed though is what you're talking about.
I'm talking about actually creating the build systems.
It was bananas,
how much output you got because these were all these
wacky macros that did all this stuff and it was,
it was a site.
I mean, it was amazing to behold when it worked, but at the same time, it was,
I recognized even back then, I have no idea what is in this.
It's just too big
how many people really don't understand how their house works
-- or their car. I, I, I'm not even going to pretend to understand how my car
-- works.
You don't have to either. Right.
No. No. Well, unless something breaks and then it's,
somebody has to understand how it works to fix it.
-- Well,
-- somebody, you an expert, you bring it to.
Right. And
that's
in the tech world.
It's weird that it doesn't seem to work out very well When we do that,
experts, Kurt,
I'll do anything. It's fine. I'll just do it myself. It's easy.
But uh what, what always gets me is this like this code
C thing? I don't know that it can be done securely because
the script itself is basically designed.
It's written in Bash because it's basically the lowest
common denominator of this will work almost everywhere.
OK. Let me, let me ask you a different question.
So how do you, so let's say we're going to say code
-- COV can't be secured.
-- Well, the alternative is for code
COV to actually build a whole pile of different, you know,
installation specific things.
Why does
-- matter what is the
-- difference that could be signed or could be better integrated?
But you can't prove that's any safer if you have people
downloading your new artifacts every time they do a build,
why, why is it any different?
You could have code signing?
And in theory, like for example, it could be an executable that's code signed,
right?
Bash
doesn't have
a,
-- that, that's just not a thing with bat. But
-- here's the thing.
If the attacker had the ability to covertly modify a batch script,
they could have totally changed whatever
Kov was distributing, say an N PM. Like I'm just saying, there's,
there's no solution to this problem.
There is no complete solution to this problem, but you can begin to
walk off things that the attacker can do. So you can go,
for example, instead of keeping the signing key on the server,
you can have the signing key in an HSM with good logging.
And now you can say, oh, the attacker used the key seven times on these dates
instead of,
well, the attacker has the key in. Uh we, we have like this is a perfect example.
The attacker,
we definitely know that they modified the script for about 3 to 4 months.
That's all they can say. What does that mean? We don't know what they did.
We don't know how often they might.
I'm guessing Ockham's Razor is that they only
modified it the once and just were like,
ha ha this works awesome and moved on with life.
I mean, like, so we have an example of this is
there is a red hat security advisory that exists because an attacker broke in
and signed a version of open
SSH. Red hat had an HSM, the key wasn't leaked
and because of logging, they knew exactly which version
was signed So obviously there's an update that says
we'll install this update because this has a
larger version number than this other version of open
SSH
that we don't know what's in it, but we know it's probably bad.
We'll never completely solve this, but we can definitely raise the bar.
Oh, no, no, no, we're not done yet. We're not done yet.
So, ok, so let's say code cove signs their stuff, who's checking the signatures,
right.
Well, it, ironically they,
they are sort of trying to do so they released a little script that
essentially curls the bash script down and then curls sha 256 sum down from github
user content and compares it.
So you'd have to break into their github and
-- you know, their web server.
-- This is new now, I've not seen this.
It's on their code
cov bash uploader web page, I assume they add,
let's just say recently.
Yeah, I mean, it, it's, it's
a
step. It's obviously you're never going to be perfect.
But I mean,
that's the big challenge is there's lots of things that sign
something and then it never gets checked which defeats the purpose.
The problem is you don't have to be perfect.
The problem is companies are making mistakes like solar winds, 123,
that was the interns fault.
It's fine.
Yeah. So, I mean, that's,
yeah, that,
that's kind of what I'm getting at if these companies were
making sophisticated mistakes that let me put it this way.
Airlines, typically when they have a problem, it's a, it's a chain of events.
It's, you know, my famous, my,
my favorite one being air transat where they installed the wrong size fuel pump,
the um, or backwards. I forget which I think it was backwards.
Anyways, the, the, the line rubbed it split,
it started spraying fuel so the one side is leaking.
So what does the captain of the plane do? Oh, you know, uh my left side is
running out of fuel. I'm gonna pump fuel from the right side to the left side
and he manages
hail Mary to dead stick landing in the uh like in the
Azure or basically somewhere in the middle of nowhere and you know,
nobody dies.
Yay.
But
like it's a comedy of errors,
right? It's, it's just these like you did what?
Now these technology things like solar winds are comically
terrible.
These are the airline equivalent of, oh, we forgot to put any fuel in the plane or?
Oh, you wanted like all four engines installed for the flight? What? Oh, yeah.
No, we thought two was good and you know,
-- we'll get the next two on Wednesday
-- to be fine.
-- Yeah, you know,
-- it's sort of look, I think that's an unfair comparison because
I feel like so in the airline industry, most of these problems are well understood.
-- Dude. Come
-- on solar winds 123
but Kurt that was irrelevant to the actual problem. I recognize that, that
that is an issue for its own reasons.
But I think obsessing over that terrible password distracts from the bigger issue.
Well, but it,
-- it shows a systemic and endemic failure at solar winds and
-- I'll agree with that.
And that's part of, that's part of the story.
But I think obsessing over one terrible
password distracts us from the actual problems.
Sorry, to me that that
was a symptom of like, to me it's like this is so much worse than you. It
appears at first glance.
I mean, it might be, but it's not just solar winds, it's almost everyone.
And I'm saying that so I see a couple of issues here,
the vast majority of developers want to do the right thing.
I know security.
People love to bash developers and be like, oh, those idiots are just trying to,
you know, they just want to make it work,
don't care about security.
Like I think most of them do and I think in
many instances it's sometimes hard to do the right thing.
-- Well,
-- it's also what is the right thing? Yeah,
we don't always know exactly.
I mean, like signing software,
building software supply chains are a great example of it's, this is hard stuff.
Like I'll give you a great, I'll give you a great example is
I was reading a report from a very well known security company
and they basically said oh, you should do reproducible builds. And I said how
they're like, what do you mean? I'm like, you tell me how to do this.
I know this problem and I know what the solution looks like. I want you to explain it.
They're like, well, I'm like, yeah,
you can't tell people to do this
and then not tell them how to do it.
-- Like that is a problem or
-- even have some really solid actionable advice and
it's not,
it's all squishy fluffy.
Oh, you should do these things. Like buy a unicorn. It's like, where do I buy them?
Well,
it's what you should do is eat healthy and exercise
more and drink lots of water and get good sleep.
Well, yes, we all know that, but none of us do it. You know
-- what
-- I'm saying is that's not actionable advice. No,
I agree.
It feels like it could be.
-- But it's not
-- like, and I, you know, I feel like a jerk for this but to quit smoking,
you just quit smoking.
But then the second part and this is the tricky bit is you never do it again. Right.
-- Right.
-- And that's the second part that a lot of people have trouble with.
-- This
-- is what annoys me to no end is the fact that
there are countless people who want to do the right thing,
but we don't know sometimes what it is.
But even when we do know what it is,
I think we're not making it easy to do. No, we're not.
And even if you know what to do, sometimes it is impossible to do it. Right.
And like my favorite example here is like third party dependencies, right?
Be it hardware, you're buying, be it software, you're downloading, be it software,
you're buying be it Windows from Microsoft.
Right.
Like we obsess over this and it's becoming a huge topic because
of every thing going on around supply chains and it should be.
But I've yet to see anything even remotely resembling
good actionable advice here.
-- It's all just hand wavy nonsense that's meant to shift blame.
-- Well, I part of it is
I'm not sure we even have defined the terms properly because
we were having this discussion yesterday on the github issues.
Remember where we're talking about sort of what counts as inclusion and embedding,
right? Like this is a subtle thing.
So for example, there's a big difference between a hypothetical example,
I update open as a cell to fix a security problem. Cool.
Then I, so I update the system open as a cell
and for example, uh Apache the web server.
Well, once it's restarted, makes use of that open SSL,
like I don't actually have to kind of
necessarily maybe do anything to Apache,
right? If it's using the system open SSL as it versus
a piece of software where open SS cell is embedded.
OK. So open SSL updates.
Well,
that doesn't do that piece of software any
good until that piece of software updates,
its dependency pulls in a new version of open SSL gets recompiled, blah, blah, blah,
blah blah.
Right. And we're talking about sort of where is that line?
And that line can be very subtle, you know. Well, system libraries are,
at least it's just a restart. Like you don't need to get new software and do
too much strangeness. Typically it's just
install the update, restart the system.
And for example, hope that the fix wasn't to remove something you need
it
because that
thing, those are fun and then for kind of embedding and recompiling.
Oh, yeah, I remember when I started at red hat that XML hashed off stuff.
And so I was looking for who includes like XML.
It's like everybody, they all embed it and I'm like, what the heck.
So it works on Windows. I'm like, oh
yeah, that makes sense. Same thing for Gzip,
Gzip.
There are so many wacky copies of zip and G zip included in so many things because,
-- well, how else are we going to get it to work on Windows? Yep.
-- Exactly.
I have a great, I have a great example actually. So
node Js
includes their own copy of open SSL when you get the binary from them.
And if you're doing any sort of node development, there's this,
this script called NVM, node version manager
that everyone uses because if you don't like it's a nightmare.
And basically so think of it this way though.
So open SSL updates, node Js then has to update Node Js and release a new version.
Then like the containers you're using,
you have to update the version of node Js and no and oh and by the way,
there's a bunch of other dependencies that you can update as long as you're here.
You know what I mean? And it gets out of hand really fast.
-- Well,
-- it's like why I love and I hate home on
my Mac because every time I run home brew to insult something, it's like, oh,
you got to run an update.
And I'm like, ah, I just need this to work now.
-- So,
-- actually, Python and Home Brew is why I quit running a Mac.
I ran one for a couple of years
and, like, every time you run Brew update, Python is busted and I was like,
you know what this is?
I, I'm done, I can't do this anymore because I use Python too much. Just I'm gonna get,
I'm gonna get a Linux machine and it's been perfect ever since.
Famous last words, I'm sure it will break later today. Now.
-- I
-- mean,
at least people are starting to use build systems in
C I CD pipelines so that if something is broken,
we have a place to fix it and not, oh, you know, teach Bob to do it properly.
No, no,
-- just change the config get better software
-- unless your C I system is back doored.
Yeah.
Well, but at least, I mean, if your C I system is back doored, you can
get an un back doored one from the vendor at some point.
-- Theoretically,
-- unless the script you're running is downloaded the back door.
I mean,
like,
again, again,
this is how I'm going to wrap this all up is there's all these considerations,
there's all these dependencies and I'm not saying you should
be like f it and throw caution to the wind.
I do think there's a certain amount of due diligence.
All of us are responsible for doing, of just saying
at least know what you have, right?
-- Know if someone says, yeah, but
-- that
-- is
-- a lot harder than you
think it is. I agree.
And that's,
that's a, that's an elephant, right? You don't eat it in one bite.
But the point is
the most important aspect of all this.
And the lesson we should all have here is that rather than
obsessing over our third party stuff, it is vastly more important.
We know what we're shipping and we can move
quickly because when it is time to move quickly,
it is imperative, you can do it like 90 days is not going to cut it.
-- And
-- that speaks to automation,
automation is fast
reproducible and you can fix it
and humans are bad at this stuff.
-- So don't, don't let them
-- humans are unreliable, right?
Like that, that installer script I wrote for Hyper Ledger fabric. I mean, it is,
there's actually quite a few steps and if they happen out of order it breaks
and there's quite a bit of subtlety going on to make it all work.
And there's no way as a human being,
I can remember to do all those steps consistently every time.
So I scripted it with
also has the benefit of now anybody with Ubuntu 20.04 can just
run the script and bam it works.
That's right. Yeah, I agree. Ok, I'm going to call this one. So thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to up at our
security podcast.com. Hit up or
not. It's use
a Poo
Ss podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.