Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Christmas Spectacular with myself and Josh Bresser,
who is myself? Oh, sorry, Kurt
Siefried. No, I have not been replaced yet
by a robot. Well, in fairness you do the sound auditing so I can't replace you.
Uh That's true. And I, I'm, you don't have the logins to the
various websites we use for publishing either.
So we should probably fix that at some point, but not.
No.
Well, this is a great example of Bus Factor where it doesn't matter because
the podcast is two people and the whole thing is kind of
the two of us bouncing off each other. And it's like,
I,
I'll be blunt, there's a bunch of Starcraft podcast,
uh
Starcraft game casters. Some of them are great on their own.
Yeah, like,
and some of them I'm not going to name names.
Some of them are absolutely terrible on their own, but with the right co
presenter, they're amazing.
Right. No, I agree. I think if either one of us exited this show, it would cease to be.
Definitely.
Yep. Yep. Absolutely.
Alright. Alright. I wrote a Christmas poem. I printed it out this is the paper.
And so we're actually going to talk, why did you print it out?
But it's the poem I wrote,
I printed it because poetry should be read from paper versus a screen.
And I feel like it makes it easier to read and
it's going to be a dramatic reading. So I obviously need the ability to gesture.
We'll say wildly, turn your camera on then.
No, I'm not turning my camera on.
It makes a web browser crash.
Anyway. Anyway. Uh
So for anyone who's still listening,
we're, we're actually going to spend some time on log for Jay.
But I do have a marvelous poem. I spent more time than I want to admit
reading. So
here we go. Here we go
was the night before Christmas would all through the stack.
Not a scanner was scanning, not even a rack.
The S bombs were uploaded to the portal with care
in hopes that next year would be boring and bare.
The interns were nestled all snug in their beds
while visions of dashboards danced in their heads,
the ciso in their kerchief and I in my cap
had just slept our laptops for a long winter's nap.
When all of a sudden the pager went
ak AK I sprang to my laptop with worries of attack away to the browser.
I flew like a flash tore open the window and cleared out the cache.
The red of the dashboard, the glow of the screen gave a luster of disaster.
My eyes rarely seen
when what to my wondering eyes did appear
but a new advisory,
innate vulnerabilities to fear like a little old hacker all ready to play.
I knew in a moment it must be log for j
more rapid than Gigabit its courses.
They came and it whistled and shouted and called them by name. Now. Log for Shell.
Now, CV E now a SF and NVD
on Sisa on Luna
on
GSI, the dog to the top of hacker news to the top of the wall.
Now hack away, hack away, hack away all nice. I like it.
I'm not done yet.
Like the bits that before the wild CDN flew by when they meet with a firewall,
they mount to the sky.
So up to the cloud like bastards, they flew with tweets full of bones and log for J two.
And then in a twinkling, I read in the slack,
the wailing and screaming of each analyst called back as I drew in my head
and was turning around down the network log for J came with a bound.
It was dressed in a hoodie black and zip tight.
The clothes were all swagged from a conference one night.
A bundle of bones that had checked in its git
and it looked like a peddler just being a twit. The change log.
How it twinkled, it features how merry its versions were like roses,
its logo like a cherry,
its draw little mouth was drawn up like an at and
the beard on its chin made it look stupid and fat.
The stump of a diff
tight in its teeth and the bits they encircled the repo like a wreath.
It had a flashy,
read me an annoying little fad that shook when
it downloaded like a disk drive gone bad.
It was chubby and plump,
an annoying old package and I laughed when I saw it in spite of the hack, a
wink of its bits and a twist of its head soon gave me to know I had everything to dread.
It spoke not a word but went straight to its
work and pointed all the servers then turned with a jerk
and laying its patches the side of its nose.
It gave a nod and up the network, it rose,
it sprang to its packet to its team gave them more in a way.
They all fled leaving behind a back door.
But I heard it exclaim or it drove out of sight.
Merry Christmas, you nerds log for J one tonight.
That was,
that was actually awesome in the traditional sense of the
word and the fact that most of it rhymed,
I'm impressed, you know how hard that is to do.
I know
that. So I don't write poetry.
It was,
it took me many hours to put this terrible poem together.
But I was very proud of myself and I'm like, I need to read this on the podcast, dude.
No, that was not a, that was a great poem.
I also love how just inherently like ageist your references are.
Yeah, probably like pagers and hard drives.
Well, I had to come up with something, I mean,
I tried putting other things in and it just wasn't easy.
I mean, part of the,
part of the thing with this actually was there the night before
Christmas poem has a very certain flow that rolls off the tongue.
And while I know I didn't replicate that as well,
it was definitely something I had in mind.
And so a lot of the words that are weird or don't make sense.
It was like I need to make this sound right.
But anyway, anyway,
now I want to say I want to put a little disclaimer in
like I pick on log for J and that log for J developers.
You guys are awesome.
I'm not picking on you.
It's just a silly poem. Open source owes you nothing.
That's right. It's just a silly poem that I had fun doing.
All right.
That was,
that was really good. I like it. And you're posting it right?
Like you're not gonna make people transcribe it.
Yeah, I'll put it in the show notes. It'll be in the show notes.
Um
Yes.
Yes. Even though even though I read it from paper, I wrote it on a screen.
Yeah.
Can you even read your own handwriting anymore.
I
can
actually, my problem isn't reading it.
My hand gets really tired now when I write because I do it so rarely.
Yeah.
So when I try, I can write like, three or four sentences and then, like,
my hand starts getting sore and I have to just stop.
Well, it's funny because, like, I've literally with my one son, you know,
um,
he
basically, I just,
I'm not worried about him actually ever learning to
write with a pen or pencil because the question,
will he have a compute device?
He can type into
the answer is yes.
Yeah.
And if you
have one, somebody else will,
it amuses me when I hear old people like, oh, kids don't learn cursive today.
And it's like,
no, we don't
care.
And,
and the funny thing is I actually explained why cursive was a thing to my other son.
And it's because you used to have to be able to write fast to take dictation.
Right. Right. Exactly.
Yeah,
because black lettering is slow. Yeah. Well, I'm trying to explain to him that,
you know, like the whole dictated but not read,
right. That used to be at the bottom of letters.
And
so for those of you in the, uh,
listening to the show that are under the age of like 30 dictated but not read,
literally means that somebody dictated a letter to their secretary,
the secretary typed it out and sent it without the person reviewing it.
So like literally you speak out loud, somebody types in your,
well let's say email because make it a little more current
and and fires it off and there may be errors in it.
And so that that dictated but not read was sort of a disclaimer of like
here's what we think we heard the person say
but you know it might not be entirely correct,
of course. Now the answer is just send your own damn email
I mean. Yeah, exactly. Exactly. Alright. Alright let's
let's talk about love for Jason Mo because why not?
That's the topic of the day.
Well,
and I love that again every like a bad vulnerability to log for Jay and
it's kind of like yeah and do you think this is the last one?
Like and by last one I don't mean ever I mean like this week.
Well ok there's there's two pieces I wanted to discuss
and and I'll start with this what I thought would
be the second one but so we're talking about log
for Jay a lot and it's getting all the attention
but something I I did is I've pulled down
uh the Docker Hub api I can they they I get like 100 and 35 containers when I ask them
give me the top containers in Docker Hub, right?
And for whatever reason it stops at 100 and 35.
I don't know why I don't care, whatever, it doesn't matter,
it's good enough.
But anyway, I took them and I started looking and saying, what are the packages
in all? Like, what are the most used packages in this?
And I think
that's one of the things we need to think about is
log for J is obviously in the top 10 because every Java thing uses it.
So the other like one of my questions now is
like, what, what's the thing every node package has?
So let me guess, let me guess. I'm guessing engine X might be real popular.
A web server. Uh
No, no. Remember these are, these are the containers, these
I, I don't have it off the top of my head.
The basically the top probably 20 or 25 I think it was
are almost all N PM packages because almost everything is N PM.
How do you build a web thing?
Yeah. Right.
Log for j's in there and like no seriously because I, I there's as far as I know,
there's literally no sane way to build a web thing.
No. Yeah.
Right. Right.
And so I, I mean, I'm working on it,
I'll put some data together and talk about it at some point.
But you get the idea, right?
Like there's way more than just log for J that is everywhere. And so
I, well as defenders, we're starting to ask these questions.
I have no doubt the Attackers have already done this
work and they know what they should be looking for.
I actually will disagree with you because I've been thinking about this a lot.
Attackers have finite resources just like defenders and why they don't,
generally speaking,
most Attackers don't need to use zero days unless they're like some fancy nso group,
you know, selling to states,
the majority of Attackers are using well known zero days.
Not,
well, when I say well known zero days, like things that are either exploitable
and haven't been patched yet or, or straight up,
they were like a zero day or not even a zero day, but like they've been patched forever
and they might as well be a zero day for how many people are still vulnerable.
Yeah.
You know.
Yeah, that's fair. But anyway, anyway, it's just something to think about is
there are packages
in everything, there's going to be a certain subset.
And those are some of the things like we
always talk about all this critical path like,
oh open SSL and
the Linux kernel and Debian or whatever. And the reality is
log for Jay wasn't something on anyone's list and it turned out to be
the most important discovery potentially of the last decade.
Well, and that's something I uh so two of my questions that I'm,
I'm looking at in my third blog entry are it's
this inability to know how widely a library is used.
Now,
you can say like N PM will tell you like, oh, this thing's been downloaded, like
10-K jillion times. Cool. But that doesn't mean anything. Exactly.
Like, is that,
like Google is one download and then they use it internally everywhere.
Well, actually the real problem,
so I've got kind of two funny little anecdotes about that is
any time, like ac I job runs it often will just redownload all the node modules.
So, like, if you have AC I job running, you know, 1000 times a day,
that's 1000 downloads.
And so the the company you work for now,
Acor, we like ingest and scan containers and infrastructure, right?
So if you're using a certain container,
it will,
you basically say like I'm,
these are the containers I'm using like pay attention to them
and
the the
Encor Enterprise product will ask Docker Hub periodically like, hey,
are there any updates to this container image?
And apparently every time you do that, it bumps the container count up one.
And so there were a handful of containers that
we know we're hitting a lot
and their count keeps going up and people are getting excited and we're like,
we think that might be us like we don't,
I don't think people are using that many of these
but like, you know what I mean?
This is, that's why just like counting the number of hits or downloads or,
or whatever the the popularity contest statistics
aren't valid in this context.
You need to actually look at like, what are people using
and then what is in it?
Well, and then at least the second question is ok. So
how sort of widely used is this thing? Like,
just because it's downloaded doesn't mean it's actually kind of being used.
And, and the thing is like, we have no idea
until sort of,
we boil the ocean and everybody takes a look and
the only way to get that to happen is yeah,
to have something to log for J with a, a
massive, you know vulnerability.
Well, now,
now here I want to introduce the second thing and this is totally related is so
if you would have told me a year ago,
there is going to be a critical vulnerability in log for J,
I would have been like whatever nerd, it's log for J log stuff, right?
And so let's say we had
given log for J specifically log for J
infinite resources and we had
tens of people working on it full time. We had people doing security audits.
Would they have found this? I suspect not. Here's the thing, even if they found it.
The problem is
because of how the culture of building software is, it was originally
much worse of a problem than it needed to
be because it was enabled by default even though
almost nobody used it. And
I mean, their response after what two weeks was to say,
look after dealing with CV E you know, 2021 44 228 or whatever,
this J and D I stuff is just really dangerous. So, we're disabling it by default.
Right. Right. Like, if they'd done that from day one, this would have been fine.
And the question is, how many other features did they add that are just on by default?
And this is true of countless libraries. Yes, there are.
I, I think it's really easy to turn things on
and then there's always this attitude of we're going to break
backwards compatibility or we're going to break someone something or other.
And so there's always a reluctance to turn features off and
it's, it's a delicate dance.
Well,
and this is fascinating to me because we have sort of
the known quantity of if we disable this future by default,
X number of people are gonna have to turn it on and complain
versus the somewhat unknown quantity of by having this feature on by default.
If it has a vulnerability in future,
everybody's gonna have to deal with it and everybody's gonna have to turn it off.
And what is the cost and hassle of that?
And what's interesting to me is
again as it turns out like I, I
don't think very many people are actually
using the JND I lookups.
I would be shocked if it's used by more than 0.1%.
Well, it seems like a real enterprise feature of like, oh,
we want to have this request come in and then do like an out
lab look up so that in the logs, we can, you know, assign a cost center to the request
and that's a valid use case and actually quite a useful one,
but it's so insanely complex.
Like there's no way normal people are going to be doing that.
I, I think these days the way most logging systems work is you do the enrichment
when the logs are brought into the logging system,
not as the logs are written to disk.
So I think that's a feature from
a a
again, it goes kind of back to that cultural thing of I own the logging system.
I have to add this feature. Ok. I can add it here
and you know, shoehorn it in
and,
and that's the reality of like large software enterprise stuff
is trying to get another group to do something.
Good luck.
That's true. That's true. So it can be hard.
So anyway, anyway, I, I feel like this is, this is the question though,
like if we had tons of resources, would this have been found?
Well, would they have even, would they have documented it
because, well, they did eventually, after two years,
literally two years later, they actually added it to the documentation.
I mean, but anyway, so anyway, here's,
here's where I want this conversation to go into is so
there is all these features in all these libraries used across the entire industry.
And some subset of the features just by their very
nature are dangerous like this J and D I thing.
It was literally doing exactly what it was supposed to do.
Well, you know what, it's not just that they're dangerous,
but they're,
I'm going to use the word they're exposed by default,
right?
So a good example of this Python has a silly
ridiculous dangerous feature called Pickle where you basically take a object
and turn it into text.
So you can shove it over the network or
shove it locally over something and then you unpick
it
and it, it can be code, it can be config it can be data, it can be whatever. And like
like as I keep saying,
the Python Pickle page has this giant
red warning saying Python pickle is dangerous.
Don't unpick all untrusted data.
But the thing is you have to go out of
your way to make something that does that nobody accident.
Like nobody has pickle enabled on their data by default.
It's you have to like you have to use Pickle. Now, here's how I would
discuss that is
why doesn't Python just yank it or add an option that says Pickle will only be
enabled if I run Python with dash dash
enable Pickle because I'm doing something stupid.
You know what I mean?
Because you effectively already have to do that by writing code that uses Pickle.
Whereas log for J you didn't have to write code that
uses the, the stuff.
It's just if you pulled log for J and at all and used it at all, it just,
the data was coursing through log for J and vulnerable.
I mean,
yes,
you have to explicitly take a piece of data and unpick it.
But II, I think your argument is weak.
I think any time there's a dangerous feature, no matter what,
it should just not be there.
And I think if it's something that's critical to certain organizations,
then you can make some bizarre way to enable it,
that is
you have to live. I mean, saying pickle, you have to go to your way to use Pickle.
I don't buy that because you can just import Pickle, you can run Python,
you can type import pickles, import
that happens. You still have to write code that takes untrusted data. And
I understand that. I understand that, but I think you're splitting hairs.
I think the fact that a danger like why leave a dangerous feature in place,
why leave it there at all?
Well, that's a
part of it would be,
you can check how many people are using it and quite a few people use it.
The thing I think about log for J is that
you could have written the world's most secure, most safe java code.
But the moment you import log
for J
Poof,
you, you're affected by the vulnerability.
Well, I mean, this is true of lots of libraries where as soon as you use them,
you gain the superpower of the library but potentially any of the drawbacks.
But here it wasn't a potential.
It was if you import log for J and it touches any data,
you're affected whether you like it or not.
And this whole like people are like,
oh you sanitize your inputs and it's like you can't with this like,
like
what I love is people,
you know, tweeted out the first exploit and it's like, oh OK,
here's a filter for that.
And then they're like, OK, well, here's, you know, here's my anti anti filters,
you know, evasion
and it gets to the point where somebody posted a grip
statement for that supposedly catches all the log for J stuff.
And it's like, you know, it's like half a page long.
It's enormous and, and I'm sure there's ways to evade. Oh, absolutely.
So which OK, so that,
that's actually I was just discussing this with someone this
morning before I talk to you actually is the fact that
we have this like obsession with detecting and preventing sometimes
and in this case,
you have to patch it. You don't have a choice and, and like that's it. I, I appreciate
that people are doing this work, but at the end of the day, like
there's no escape
unless you're the size and technical ability of a place
like cloud flare where you are literally touching double digits,
percentage of all the internet traffic.
And you have some of the smartest craziest people
that have been working on filters for years.
You don't have a chance.
It's a waste of time.
It's like writing your own crypto or writing your own authentication system.
No, you just,
you, you use the one from this massive
and, and when I say massive,
I don't mean like numerically massive but just massive in terms
of like technical ability like cloud flare or Amazon or Microsoft.
And you don't do it yourself.
Like the hot patch, you don't write your own Java hot patch.
You download one of the popular ones, you know that Amazon Blessed.
That's right. That's right. And, and, and that's part of it is like, it's, it's,
you know,
it's the difference between a model T Ford where you can fix
it with a rock and a screwdriver and a modern car where,
you know, oh, for example, you know,
my check engine light goes on one day and I'm like, oh crap.
So I, you know,
drive around because it's not flashing, whatever, no funny noise, no funny smell.
And
uh I,
I go home park have dinner and then I go over
to a friend's house who has an O DB two whatever reader
and check the code and the light goes off by the way. So I'm like, oh great.
And the, the check code basically boils down to, it's like one of three things.
It's either
the, uh,
the
engine oil or in the camshaft is not like the right, uh,
fluidity.
Which makes sense because it was parked out overnight and it was really cold
or like, my camshaft is about to destroy itself or fall out.
And I'm like, well, it's probably option number one because the car was cold.
It's,
and
are you going to do if it's option number two, there's nothing you can do.
Well, I take it to the dealership and I pay some guy, you know,
thousands of dollars to fix it
because I can't, I like short of going and getting, uh, I
don't know, do car mechanics get degrees or? Well, they get certifications.
Spending four years educating myself. I can't fix the camshaft in my car. Yeah.
That's right. That's right. Like
that.
As I understand those things are like in the middle of my, I have,
I have an even better example for you.
So I own an electric car now. Right.
Have you seen the tools you have to use to work on an electric car
are 480 volts. If you touch that, you're dead.
So all the tools are like coated in thick rubber because I worked for, uh,
chemical electrical for six months.
I was their network admin and they do industrial electrical contracting.
So I'm actually very like I sat next to the safety officer
and the stuff that they bought like
$2000 for a pair of gloves.
Yeah. Yeah. But you need it, you know.
Right. Right. But, but again,
this is
like this whole dog for j thing in many
instances trying to do the runtime protection feels like
here's a pair of, of, of surgical gloves.
Now, go work on that high voltage line over there. It's like, wait a minute, what?
You're gonna want a chicken switch?
That's right.
Now, I'll just keep moving us along into strange tangents because I can,
uh there was also a worm
at the beginning of the week which thankfully at the time
of recording didn't go anywhere because the worm was broken.
But yeah, that, that's scary.
I'm mortified that like on Christmas Eve,
which this will actually come out the day after Christmas is when I will hit publish.
But I'm like, mortified Christmas Eve is going to be, oh, hey,
there's a log for J worm, everyone.
Merry Christmas. Well, and I think it might
be even more applicable than it was. I'm going to say two things. Number one,
if you have not updated your log for J yet, well, then
it's
good luck like whatever, whatever environment you work in is clearly so broken you,
you're up the creek no matter what.
And number two,
if you haven't
changed your systems or started changing your systems so
that you can update and patch them faster,
like you basically have,
it's not just enough to do an emergency patch.
You also have to learn how to fight fires better.
I mean, I think it's more nuanced than that.
Well, the thing is what I'm saying is if this event hasn't been the wake up call,
that your leadership needs to mature your security process,
you're, you're doomed.
I,
I agree and I think this is an example of
vendors need to have pressure to upgrade quickly if they,
I mean, if you have a vendor that hasn't upgraded their Java yet, like, come on,
if you're a, what is it? A federal civilian agency you have until the 24th,
they say that they always say stuff like that you can get waivers. And
I mean, there's, there's ways around that,
but
no, absolutely.
I think now there's, now here's a terrifying statistic at,
at this time of us recording.
This is Wednesday. The what the 22nd
there you can go to. Uh Sonatype has a, a website for Ma
they run Maven Central, which is where like everyone downloads all the Java stuff.
Only 40%
of the log for J Jars being downloaded at this time are the, are the new ones?
60% are the old ones still
the
Google,
the Google Security Blog from uh December 16th.
Um I'm just going to read it as of December 16th, 2021.
We found that 35,863 of the available Java artifacts from Maven Central.
Depend on the affected log for J code.
This means that more than 8% of all packages on Maven Central have at least one
and I love this have at least one version that is impacted by its vulnerability.
I
love Java.
These numbers do not encompass all Java
packages such as directly distributed binaries.
But Maven Central is a strong proxy for the state of the ecosystem.
And now here's the terrifying sentence
as far as ecosystem impact goes, 8% is enormous.
The average ecosystem impact of advisories affecting Maven Central
is 2% with a median less than 0.1%.
And that gets us in the birthday paradox territory of
essentially, if you download a random package from Maven,
like
over the whole thing, it's an 8% chance you're gonna get one with log for J
now more realistically because of the long tail and everything. It's, it's like
almost guaranteed.
You're going to get something with log for J,
especially if you're downloading more than a handful of packages.
And
like you said, if only 40% are fixed and 60% are vulnerable, then there's a really,
really good chance that there's a
good amount of stuff slipping out the back door.
So, absolutely.
And, and that's a good point.
That's something I hadn't even thought of in the context of that statistic.
But if you have a Java application, you're depending on
some library and that library specifically asks for an
old version of log for J and I mean,
this comes back to that whole, oh,
everyone pin your dependencies or an old version of that handy thing that, you know,
takes a bunch of data and hands it over to the
server.
Right?
And, and I guess in this context, pinned dependencies are actually a bad thing.
So, yeah,
well, pin dependencies are
terrible for security because it's that much more effort to try and update them.
It,
man, I'm not going to get into this way.
I've heard arguments both ways and I think everyone's wrong
in
dependencies.
I think the problem is everybody assumes that these libraries are well maintained
and actively maintained.
See, that's the thing, you can have a well maintained library.
But the I like literally,
I'm not going to name names but when we did the XML hash off thing,
there was one library
where literally the developer like cool,
I have a free weekend in like a month and a half that I can work on fixing this.
And of course Red Hat was like we, we, how about we just do it for you like now
because we can't wait a month. But now
that's why you pay Red Hat
because they have people who will literally do whatever it takes
to solve these kind of problems.
Well,
and that's the thing is we don't have in the olden days if it took you
a week or a month or hell a year to fix the security vulnerability that was known
that was kind of ok. But nowadays,
no, it's that we can't do that anymore.
And I think we had an entire show on this, you know, where we talk about this and
you just don't have time anymore.
Like
this log for J thing
became public on Thursday
was publicly, you know, fixed and done on a Friday. And then like sort of
people basically, if you hadn't fixed this by Monday,
if
a, if an attacker wanted to target you, they would have.
And it looks like uh what was it?
The Belgian Defense Ministry I think got popped by this.
And
that's what it sounds like. I don't think I've seen like AAA verified
agreement to that, but that's the rumor
looks like our story on Copyright and Apple.
Maybe we should go verify some sources first. That's
right.
Who knew those journalists were onto something?
Yeah.
Anyway,
to be professionals, we're definitely not professionals. We have poetry now.
So that's great.
We're open
source security, poetry slam, dude. NFT that poem.
I know I will not be nft it. I'm too lazy. I just don't care.
I'll tell
you you can nft it. OK?
You have
my permission.
Speaking of verbal contracts from Christmas episodes,
you still owe me a box of wheat grits from three years ago.
I owe you a box of white wheat grits.
Just listen to the 2018 show.
There's one where you agreed to send me a box of wheat grits because I was,
I agree to that. Yeah, I was complaining about how hard they are to find in Canada.
You just need to ask. I'm happy to do it.
Well, although now it will take seven years
back to the
thing,
infinite security spent would have still resulted in them adding this
dangerous feature and it being enabled by default most likely probably.
And
what they have see the problem is there's,
there's things like buffer overflows where it's like, oh, you know,
you take a piece of data,
you should figure out how long it is because it's longer than that,
then everything falls apart.
But
the problem with JD I is, oh, we're gonna, you know, support this data thing
and it's like JND, I is, I don't even want to know how big the spec is.
I'm guessing it's between 500
1000 pages. It's probably huge. Yeah.
And, but here's the thing like, well, right.
It was working literally the way it was supposed to be. Well, and that's the thing.
It's you, it's like supporting J big two or, you know,
um A sn where these standards are over 1000 pages
and
yeah, like
it, it's not.
How do I put this nicely? I don't care how careful you are
when you're building a space shuttle.
Probably the first few are gonna blow up on the pad.
Now. The problem here is we
ship rocket man from spacex. I mean,
they had some spectacular whoopsies.
Now, I will say,
I think from a marketing perspective it was brilliant what they did
because
I watched almost every launch while they were
blowing up and I haven't watched any launches since
it's boring. Now, the rocket went up in the air. It's like watching a Costco truck.
I, I also need to give a plug since we hit on space.
The James Webb Space telescope is supposed to launch on Christmas Day. I,
I cannot wait.
It's gonna be I, I, no, no, it's gonna be great. It's gonna be, I can't wait.
It's gonna be an amazing telescope.
But
uh
I just,
the thing is when you, when you support something like L
dap, I mean, remember L LDA with their anonymous binds,
right?
Or,
and yeah, exactly.
Like go look that up people because if you're using
LDA and you don't know what an honest blinds are,
you probably have one.
I don't think there's any way it's reasonably safe
to pull in something like J and D or LDA
and not have security vulnerabilities
unless
you spend some crazy amount of time and
effort and engineering trying to make it safe,
which
you just can't realistically do.
It's like writing a secure PDF parcel. Adobe invented the format
and there's over 1000
like, I think there's over 1000 CV s for Adobe reader.
Probably PDF is very, very complicated.
Well, PDF is multiple standards and it's basically a container
that's the dirty secret PDF is just a container format that's fair
but embeds everything.
It's probably turning complete.
Oh, no, that
I wrote an article. It's, it's turning
the actual like config parsing part of it is turning complete,
let alone the content.
I believe that.
I mean,
because you can essentially reassemble content within a PDF using PDF commands.
I, I don't, does, does PDF encapsulate all of the postscript
language, do you know
it encapsulates basically everything?
OK.
That wouldn't surprise me because I only bring it up
because I remember in my younger days at university,
all the printers were postscript printers
and
there was a postscript file, you could send it the printer.
I think I talked about this once before on the show,
but it would calculate pie and then,
and so it would, it would clog the printer up for, for a very long time.
That's why I had to buy
a new printer is I had an HP Laser Jet Four,
which I loved beautiful printer
and the CPU is just too slow on it.
Like I would send it print jobs and it just could not render them
in a reasonable amount of time because you know, it's an HP Laser Jet four,
it's older than most of our listeners.
So I upgraded to uh Lexmark, whatever, 250 something.
And again, it was fine until the CPU was too slow to render, um, the form PDF S.
I could not do
that.
And so then I had to upgrade again. I got an HP now,
you know, and it's like,
it's,
but the funny thing is the HP.
I think it has, like, it's a four or 500 megahertz quad core CPU in there.
Like, it's basically better than my computer from 10 years ago
and it's my printer
but it has to be, to, to handle these PDF S.
Yeah. Yeah.
Right. Right. All right. All right. Anyway, so
I think fundamentally there's, there's, the good news is a Attackers are lazy.
They, the majority of Attackers
are not going to go find some amazing zero day that's widespread. They're going to go
and find a vulnerability for which exploit code exists
and they're gonna go use it because people don't patch quickly.
And the thing is, especially in the rents and,
and attacks have changed from targeted to, I'm gonna ransomware spam 100 people,
10 will get infected.
One will pay and I've made my rent for the month. Sure. Sure.
Ok. I mean, yeah. All right. Whatever.
II, I,
you're not wrong but I still think we need to
pay attention to some of these most used packages.
Oh, absolutely. Oh, no, no,
I'm not saying we don't pay attention to them.
I,
I think those are the highest risk we have at the moment and I
bet the vast majority of them are a couple of volunteers which is,
if
we're lucky,
it, it,
I,
I truly appreciate the work people do on open source
and it annoys me to no end when someone's like,
oh, it's just volunteers.
It's like, yeah, they go volunteer jerk. Like, don't complain. Help.
That's the point.
But anyway, all right. It's Christmas.
It is the day after Christmas.
It is time to go.
I want to say Merry Christmas, KT Merry Christmas. Everyone listening.
Thank you so much. It's been a heck of a couple weeks for sure.
Yeah, I'm just sorry,
I was just looking at one of the most popular N PM packages
and it's the last commit was like a month ago on github which,
which package chalk?
It does like text formatting.
I don't, I don't know if that was on my, I don't know where that falls on my list.
I'll have to go look at it.
Well, it's one of those classic things where my in my brain, I'm like,
even if it has a vulnerability, it shouldn't be that exploitable.
But then I'm like, no, Kurt, I would have said that right.
Log for Jay proves you can't say that. I mean,
here
it is. I used to buy
used by 76,000 package as of
26. That great.
So
I hope there's no flaws in chalk.
Go get it. Security researchers. All right. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to
Security podcast.com to get the text for that amazing poem.
Use a
Pound
O
podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt
Merry Christmas,
Merry Christmas and a happy holidays to everyone and a happy new year to everyone.
Indeed. Let's hope 2022 is much less exciting than 2021.
Boring. Would be nice. I would love a boring year. All right. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye
the