Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in paying extremely large bonuses to ourselves.
Josh. Press
-- what? You get
-- a bonus.
-- I decided I get a bonus.
-- Do
you for our
huge budget of negative $40 a month?
-- Anyway,
-- it's funny because you, you wanna talk about insider threat, right?
Yes.
-- Well, it was your idea
-- and, well,
and I'm assuming you're thinking more on the technical side, right?
Like, don't click that link because if you click that link,
it'll bring down the whole company.
-- Right? No,
-- I'm just thinking there's many types of insider threats.
I mean, you can have financial insiders doing dodgy things. You can have
rogue employees, you can have everything. I mean, every department,
there is someone in that department that has
some ability to functionally take down your,
well,
I shouldn't say take down your but can definitely cause problems for your business.
Well, and here's my one thought is because this is timely is uh
Netflix shareholders voted on Thursday to reject
multimillion dollar pay packages for the company's top executives,
including the CO CEO S.
What is with these companies that have CO C Os like Blackberry and Netflix.
-- That's insane. It
-- seems to be the hip thing.
I don't know. I don't get it either.
-- Is it
-- like a spare tire situation where they take turns? They take team?
It's probably ridiculous. Internal politics is my suspicion.
But
the thing that gets me is
uh,
number one,
anybody essentially below a sea level
person
should have oversight.
Like they literally should have a manager.
Every, the sea level people should have oversight. Everyone should have oversight
to prevent them. Like at a very lowest, low level,
you know, a person making food.
Maybe somebody else checks that the hot dogs are at the right temperature. Right.
That's one thing I love about Costco is you'll
see them like every 10 or 20 minutes opening
up the hot dog thing and sticking thermometers and
making sure the hot dogs are at a temperature.
Do they? I've never,
I see it all the time at Costco, but I'm also, I believe you conscious
of
it.
Right. So you'll see them stick a thermometer and a hot dog
and then they write a number down on a clipboard.
So I don't think I've ever eaten a Costco hot dog. Do you know that?
Oh, you're in for a treat. My friend.
They just use their hot dogs out of the right. I've eaten those hot dogs,
but it's different.
I agree. It's different because they steam the buns. I agree. They steam the buns.
So my, my example of this is when you buy a hot dog at a ballpark,
baseball in the United States,
like it is magic and it's sold by a man carrying around a
box around his neck and it should be disgusting by all accounts,
-- but it is, it is magical and I can't explain it
-- and I love it.
It's the steaming of the buns,
maybe it's the moisture.
So
anyway, so basically like at, at lower levels,
like if somebody can click a link and that's gonna destroy
your company and result in like a giant ransomware incident that
whatever, then, well, then your it and your infosec and your, your,
your process is bad.
I mean, right, you have incompetent it at that point.
If you have
one bad employee to mcdonald's
that should not result in everybody getting food poisoning and dying
in
the whole
world.
Yeah.
Well, and, and, and uh there's a study, I'll have to find,
I don't know if I can find it in time,
but like a vast majority of food poisoning related outbreaks as it turns
out are related to sick employees coming to work who could have guessed.
I mean, I believe that. Now, now here's something I found interesting. So Cisa has
a,
a page dedicated to like the definition of insider threats
and there's a link in the notes for the show.
Kurt has access to it. I will put a link in the show notes.
So I, I assume Kurt hasn't pulled this up yet. Given the typing I just heard.
But
here's what I love the most about this particular pages it
has is they break down insider threats
into unintentional threats and intentional threats.
And then there's also an other, but I mean,
this is something
and, and this is where I have,
I have a plan for this episode that Kurt doesn't know about.
But
so there is
the unintentional aspect that I think we don't often consider.
There's also a quote here. I want, I want to read this Toot from Leslie Carr
Hacks for Pancakes because it's so good
and it will help frame some of the this discussion.
I run into a lot of orgs these days that are too uncomfortable considering
intentional insiders as a threat vector in their security drills and planning
because it might offend a higher up or ruffle feathers.
Meanwhile,
the cost of living is almost the highest it's
ever been compared to pay banks are failing.
People are being forced back to offices,
homes and cars are almost unaffordable for most people dot dot dot
And I think we can all understand exactly what's,
what's meant by that and that's completely valid, right?
100% valid.
Well, I mean, you look at any security vetting process and they look at things like,
do you have debts
that are maybe not like to
a drink but to like Guido.
Are you like blackmail,
like, for example,
uh well, back in the olden days, if you were uh you know, outside of any social norms,
privately, well, then that's potentially blackmail.
Whereas if you're outside of the social norms
publicly, then, well, you can't be blackmailed for that.
And
yeah, and one of those big things is like, I,
I always love when these people it turns out like they have this lavish lifestyle and
they're working a job that's like 50 grand a year and it's kind of like,
well, hang on a minute, right?
Like, obviously something shenanigans was going on.
Yeah, like,
especially now with the,
the whole organizations cutting off 5 10% of their employees.
Well, if there's a good chance you're gonna get fired or laid off anyways, right?
Like, why not sell access to your email account to some Russian website that'll pay
100 bucks for it and be like, oops, it must have leaked
for sure. Now, now here is where I think the conversation gets truly interesting.
So
when we define who an insider is, right? And, and Sisa, I'm gonna go up to the top and
I'm going to read
one particular aspect
of who an insider is, right?
They say a person to whom the organization has supplied a computer and,
or network access, right?
Which makes sense.
There's a person, the organization trusts, including employees,
whatever and given sensitive information and access.
And then they talk about a person
who develops the organization's products and services.
This group includes those who know the secrets of the
products at p whatever don't care about that part.
So here is the ultimate question I think. Are the open source
developers whose code you pull into your product?
-- Are they insiders in your organization?
-- Yes, they are trusted.
I agree.
And, and for any organization that is like, no,
we review all the code before we use it.
No, you don't, you don't,
you can't, I'll give you a hint because you're running Linux.
No, I'm dead serious. Like if you run Linux
and even remotely pretend like you audited that code before deploying it, nobody,
nobody can understand it.
It's too big and complicated.
This is,
this actually brings up AAA friend of mine sent me a link to a story over the weekend
but I did, of course I did.
It was
a,
it wasn't you.
But uh anyway,
yeah,
that's
right.
I, I trust this other person.
Unlike
links, Kurt.
Kurt sends me,
but it basically said anyone who claimed you shouldn't trust anyone
who claims to know C++ and it was a playoff.
There's an old programming
article that's like you shouldn't trust anyone who
doesn't know C++ or something like that.
Basically, right?
And the angle being this was back when like scripting languages
were becoming a thing and it was seen as like lesser programming
-- and
-- same
thing with A I and programming.
-- Now, same thing with PHP
-- program, it'll never change, it never changes.
But the point now is just saying that like C++ has become so enormous and complicated
that
-- nobody can claim to know. Like
-- C plus people making the standards,
-- they
-- don't know either.
They
don't pretend by definition if there's a bug in the standard or in the thing
and clearly somebody didn't understand it fully.
That's it. Like, that's all I got.
Like, like TCP/IP, we,
you're old enough to know what we tried to do
to fix TCP/IP congestion and network congestion 25 years ago.
And it's like all of that
on paper seemed like a, not a bad idea
and in practice, it was completely worse than useless,
right? Like literally every bit of TCP congestion and flow control from 25 years ago
is actively harmful in a real world scenario
for sure, for sure. So all of this put together, right?
Like this is nice definition of insider threats,
-- hacks or pancakes, insider threat
-- question.
So I, because I've never really thought about the unintentional insider threat,
but that makes sense because people make mistakes and
ideally you have processes in place to catch that.
Like somebody, oh, for example, somebody fat fingers a quote and you know,
drops or adds a zero to a quote and a customer is either very happy or very upset.
Right?
And one thing I've always like, one thing I wanted to actually get into CWE as a,
as a vulnerability was essentially ridiculous price movements.
So
for example, you're,
you're using a crypto wallet and you want to sell or buy
some crypto and you offer or give a price that is like,
well outside the norm,
it should
like all the wallets should be like, whoa, like, uh, even better example is, uh,
the gas fee,
the gas fee should be a small percent of
the transaction and people have swapped those numbers and
lost all their money.
And again, I think the wallet should be like, hey, you know,
if the gas fee is more than like,
5% we should probably throw up a big red warning and like,
just not allow the transaction.
-- So
-- actually I had to move some Bitcoin, uh, maybe a year or two ago now.
It was basically when Coinbase was like, oh, any of the Bitcoin in our system is like,
it is, what, what is it like, uh, uh, debtors can, can go after it.
I was like, yeah, we're taking this out of there.
-- Yeah,
-- that's how corporate debt works.
What did you think Coinbase was a bank or something?
-- That's,
-- no, I'm serious because
like, well,
they're being sued right now by the sec about exactly that.
-- No, no, no,
-- they're being sued for, uh, unlicensed securities.
-- But here's the thing like the, uh, the FTC.
-- Here's a point. Here's the point though.
Ok,
so I put in a much higher transaction fee than normal because I
wanted the coins to move because obviously you can put in like the,
the whatever Bitcoin suggests, but it takes like two days.
And I'm like, I want this money out now
and I made it pretty high and the client was like, hey,
your transaction fee is really high.
Are you sure you want to do this?
And I was like, absolutely, I do like, get that coin out of Coinbase right now.
And so, yeah, like, but that, that's a technical thing,
-- wallets can do well
-- or any software where it should be
like, for example, stock, like if stocks start bouncing up and down too much,
you know, they'll shut down trading on the stock because
even if
is technically wrong,
like we need to maybe take a pause, you know, the circuit breaker idea, right?
-- Where it's maybe less harmful to stall
-- it
out.
But now, I mean, from the context of insider threats,
how many organizations have circuit breaker
type things in place for unintentional
insider activity?
-- Probably not many, a lot
-- of them do,
but it's under the guise of quality control and Six Sigma and not a security thing.
So,
for
example.
Right.
So for example, with the restaurants, uh, they, uh,
good restaurants have a lot of backstops to prevent food
from hurting people or going out bad or whatever.
Sure.
You know, there's a lot of companies that invest a lot of, oh, I was just watching, um,
uh, Der
Bauer and he uh goes to NVIDIA and sees how not NVIDIA,
he goes to a video card manufacturer and how they make video cards.
And for example, you know how they get like all the components on those tape reels,
like say capacitors or little resistors or whatever.
Well, so for example,
if they get a reel with like they have these QC charts and it was like,
if you get a reel with like it's like 1000 or was it like 10,000 of these,
you have to take 200 out and test them
and if one fails out of that 200 you're ok.
If two or more fail, then you have to test a whole bunch more. Sure.
And so they literally buy all these things,
these products like reels of parts and they test
hundreds of them to make sure that they're correct.
Right.
They don't trust the people they're buying from
to not ship them some shoddy product because
if you think about it, right,
if you buy a reel of 10,000 capacitors and they're all off by a few percent,
that's a heck of a lot of broken video cards,
right. You know,
and so,
so that's the thing, like they have every single thing that comes in,
they basically test some statistically relevant sample
of them and if they fail enough,
they test more, they chuck it out or whatever.
So there are companies that do this,
but it's almost never really done as a security thing.
Like banks are a good example. Right?
Every time you go to the bank and you want to do a transaction,
say of over three or $4000 the teller has to go get an override.
-- Ok, so that the tellers can't like do a bunch of shenanigans quickly.
-- That's right.
I guess, I don't know if I've ever done.
-- I, I don't know, I can't think of an instance where go
-- to the bank and,
and ask for $5000 in cash and they're gonna make a manager, like,
look at you and look at your ID and be like, ok, or if you want to transfer like,
some large sum of money between accounts or, or get a cashier's check or whatever.
Right. They're gonna basically get a second set of eyes on it
because there's just too much potential
for shenanigans
and, and also for errors again, back to the unintentional thing. Right.
How many, how many people have, you know, uh, every time I make a bill payment online,
I make sure that I don't, like,
add a zero to it because if I do the company would be like, thank you,
you're paid for the next 10 months.
Right. Right. Exactly. Everything you've said is correct.
And I, I think it seems like it, it makes sense but I,
I still, like, I,
I keep having in my head this idea that all of your open source
is functionally an insider threat that you
have basically little to no mitigation against.
And there's very little you can do about.
Part of the challenge is I think it's the scale we're back to scale and logistics of.
If I give you 10 lines of PHP, you can absolutely code review that.
If I give you the Linux kernel, you, you basically say uh huh
and
no one
-- can review that correctly and couldn't even
-- try.
Like the literally about the only thing you can do with Linux is like,
are we gonna run up to date or like a long term?
That's basically your two options and you pick one and go with it
and, and that's fine. And so
you can outsource that also.
And, and I think there is a big thing is we can,
but you can outsource the risk of the insider threat by, for example,
paying red hat for the kernel instead of just grabbing the random open source one.
-- But,
-- but the kernel is irrelevant in this conversation, Kurt, because
the kernel is
one piece
of all of the software you run.
You're taught,
you're probably my guess is the kernel accounts
for 10% of the code in your infrastructure,
-- maybe less
-- actually by code by line by numbers,
especially because we're mostly serverless.
It's actually
probably a lot.
But,
but here's the thing, right. Here's the thing
and no one's serverless.
The number of companies that are actually serverless is hilariously.
We're not serverless yet, but we're going.
-- But
-- the point is
so we traditionally think of a supplier relationship where we're buying,
say software from Microsoft, we're buying nuts from some company where,
and bolts from this company.
And generally, I think we've stuck our head in the sand and said like, oh,
this isn't an insider threat because
we have a contract in place
and they're going to give us what we asked for and we, we, like,
totally ignore that sort of behavior.
Right.
-- Well,
-- except for the companies that, like, test every, uh,
-- 200 out of every 10,000 capacitors coming in and,
-- and no, no,
that's quality control.
Right? Quality control, I think is a different problem. It's similar.
I won't disagree
but
any time you're building a thing you have to do quality control. I mean,
I remember
you,
anyone creating a quality product is doing quality control. That's the reality.
I know you don't have to.
I know there's plenty of products that don't,
but we're gonna just pretend people do, right?
Because it makes the conversation easier.
Now, when we have open source, we often,
and I shouldn't even just bucket open source into this.
Right. We're gonna, we're gonna take any vendor,
you're using windows, you're using Mac Os, you're using. Linux
doesn't matter.
We don't really do quality control over a lot of this stuff. Right.
We just kind of take it and use it and we say everything is fine.
-- Next,
-- I think there's two challenges here.
One, it's really hard to do quality control
and, and so, and a lot of places I'm actually gonna disagree with you.
A lot of places do, do quality control.
So for example, Microsoft patch, Tuesday,
people don't just blindly apply the updates across the board,
they selectively test them and then decide which patches they're actually
gonna deploy and they put a lot of work into this.
And number two,
here's the ugly truth. You don't have a choice, right?
See, for example, if you're buying capacitors,
you, you have choices,
you probably have more than two or three
vendors that make a functionally equivalent identical capacitor because
they have standards. If you wanna run a Windows app,
you have
realistically one choice which is to run windows.
Now, I know that there's things like wine and
that other stuff, but
realistically,
if you're gonna run Windows in production or run a Windows App in production
and you suggest anything other than running windows,
you're probably gonna get fired.
And, but so,
and I think this is part of the problem is you're trying
to do quality control on something that is at the same time,
both hideously complex
and potentially closed source.
I mean, sure. But, but
I
don't, I
don't wanna go down the closer
path.
No, no, no, no, no,
but I'm just trying to point out when you do quality control on something.
If I gave you a sealed up box that has like an input and an output.
You can check that input and output,
but you're not gonna know that one of the resistors inside is
gonna fail after 10,000 cycles unless you actually cycle it 10,000 times.
Ok? No, this is OK. This is exact. This is a good point.
I think this lends itself nicely into
where I wanted to steer this plane by the end of this conversation. And that is
so
let's say all of open source is an insider threat you have to deal with. Right.
-- Well, it's trusted. So
-- sure
when we think about things like insider threats, we,
and if you read like there's all this guidance that
it has a mitigating insider threats guide somewhere, I'll,
I'll find it and put a link in the show notes.
But basically they talk about like creating all these programs
and putting all this stuff in place to like,
identify threats and watch for bad behavior and, and things like that.
Right? When we talk about things like software,
I think we love to talk about prevention
which doesn't work.
We all know that in the world of software prevention doesn't work.
I'm, I'm not,
you can make arguments.
Oh, but it does in this obscure situation, but fundamentally it doesn't.
So we're running all this software that's
functionally an insider threat to our organization.
We have little to no control over the software
and instead of saying, OK,
let's build our mitigation strategy around this reality.
We obsess over things like, oh, we'll just control all the open source we use
like reproducible.
-- No,
-- you won't, you won't do any of these things. You're going to spend
a gazillion hours talking about how you're going to fix open source.
Instead of saying, let's construct
a
insider threat program. Let's construct security policy. Let's create
our internal security program around these realities.
And it blows my mind sometimes how we have this
session with changing open source instead of changing ourselves.
Well, I mean, I'm, I'm lucky working at the CS A.
I was, we're able to do that because I'm like, hey devs,
you sh you update the website twice a week.
Ok. Keep doing that. That's our security
and that's,
-- that's
-- it. And, and yes, that works for you. And that's lovely.
Yeah.
And I, but I get also a lot of places, you know, if you're making banking software,
you can't just ship an update twice a week.
Like that's just not gonna fly.
Right.
The more I think about this,
I
think this is one of the reasons cloud one is
that it allowed you to outsource this in a way
that you really could strongly ignore it because it was so hidden.
It's like you just get a nice API or a nice website with cornflower blue.
No, I'm completely serious because you
magic
it away
it, yes, the,
you know, it's like going to a gas station and not thinking about, like,
the last 20 years of the war on terror.
That's right. Or the first Gulf War and all the,
it's totally just like a nice facade
and it could be
the most ridiculous crack den behind it.
But as long as it looks nice from the outside, it's fine.
I like the idea of the unintentional threat as well
because I hadn't really ever given that that much thought.
And especially with open source, there's a lot of, well, like people
accidentally introduce bugs or they try and add a new feature.
And I mean, my favorite all time example is the open SSH.
People who are like, hey,
this vendor wants kind of the support for roaming sessions.
Hey, that sounds cool.
You know,
your IP address changes and your connection doesn't poop itself
and you don't have to log back in again.
Cool.
We sort of implemented that server side but the client never got built
and then we had this dead code and we kind of left it there
and then it turns out to be, you know, a key disclosure vulnerability. Oops,
I remember that like
these are the people that are supposedly, you know,
holding themselves to the highest standard and doing one of the
most security critical pieces of code that used to be available.
Like now, honestly open SSH is not as important as it used to be because
we have orchestration management software.
-- And it's still pretty important.
-- I'm not saying it's not important.
I'm saying it's less important, right?
Because it used to be, we used to manage servers by logging in via open as sh because
what else would you do if there was
no
Anzel or Puppet or
an
uses open SS A?
Yeah.
But anyways back to this, but basically even they made
like,
like if you were looking at this and you were paranoid, you'd be like, oh,
that's an insider threat that introduced this bug that allows key disclosure.
Well, no, it's just people being people and not removing dead code. That's bad.
-- I mean.
-- Right. Right. But
you are correct that we often don't think about those things in the same context.
And I think we often
actually, you know, I think in a lot of ways we deal with bugs more correctly
because how many times are, well, there are efforts to ferret out bugs before
the, before it's deployed and most of those don't work very well and we all know that.
And so we've developed these
oftentimes comprehensive and impressive response capabilities to bugs. Right.
And when you,
I think bucket malicious insider threats to unintentional insider threats,
that sort of like quick response is very similar.
Now, I will say though, I think in many instances,
the number of malicious insider threats is very, very low.
The number of unintentional insider threats is much, much higher.
Well, I mean, technically any bug that causes a, a serious detriment is an insider,
-- unintentional insider threat.
-- It, it kind of is, I wouldn't disagree with that.
And I think, but this is where reaction and response are our
behavior in that context. Whereas when we think of malicious insiders,
we try to ferret them out and stop them.
So we focus on prevention, which is often not effective.
I wonder if it kind of goes back to that problem of the intention,
argument around security versus regular bugs where essentially, well, see,
and this works for the military in the sense of, ok, we have a threat
and a threat by definition has an actor.
So if we deal with the actor,
then we take care of the threat.
And
in computer software, we, well, we can't get rid of all the bad actors because
it's a global
world and they can all connect to us via internet.
Whereas, you know,
like my house physical security, for example,
I don't have to worry about people on the internet so much as I have to worry about,
uh, somebody, you know, going through the neighborhood testing,
seeing if all the doors are open or whatever.
Right?
And for example, like,
so
I think maybe that's part of it because the idea and I, you know,
this speaks to a lot of the threat intelligence where, you know,
where they're tracking all these advanced
uh acting groups.
You know,
there was that recent news of the
Chinese one that's going after infrastructure stuff.
And
I think part of the challenge there is a lot of people feel like
and I suspect they're right that we can't boil the ocean and fix,
like we can't fix all our infrastructure providers and get them to be secure.
That is correct.
So for example, maybe if we
and I don't know how exactly, but maybe if we
get all the bad actors to stop being bad actors,
have we tried asking nicely?
I'm not really clear on how we do that,
especially when they're in a foreign jurisdiction
with a government that's ok with it.
But ignoring all that,
you know. Yeah, it's an attractive
and it, it's sort of sexy and it's sort of cool, like, oh, yeah. Well,
you know, we, we found, uh, what was it? Fancy bear and, you know, they're in Russia,
like, cool. Like, what are you gonna like?
The Russian government is quite happy with them.
-- Well, but that's,
-- I mean, that is technically an insider threat,
but I think it's generally not seen as it where
we think of insider threats most commonly as actual employees,
right?
Versus Attackers on the outside.
-- Yeah.
-- Who are buying access? Who are, I
mean, some of them do for sure, for sure.
Not all but, and I, oh man, I guess that's part of the challenge as well, right?
Because if you have an insider threat being coerced by, say a foreign government,
social engineering,
social engineering, somebody who falls for social engineering,
that's
the unintentional insider threat right there because,
right, the external attacker wants insider access and hey, Bob, you know,
uh my laptop's dead and I need you to like, read off, you know, like
whatever. Right?
So,
yeah.
No, I, I like that idea of unintentional insider threat because it explains,
for example,
I think a lot of these efforts that like, oh, well,
we'll train everybody not to click on fishing links.
Well,
except, hey, it's my job to click on links in email. And b
again, I'll be blunt if somebody,
even the CEO clicks the link in an email and
that causes your company to have a really bad day,
then
I mean,
somebody's gonna accidentally click that link at some point or,
or, or, or delete a file they shouldn't have or whatever
100 percent.
And
so,
and here's just a fascinating slight tangent,
but
you're saying that companies don't really have
a way of dealing with insider threats.
So they kind of don't acknowledge it.
And yet every time they like fire a person, they immediately like,
lock them out and then treat them like they're going to be evil right away.
And my thinking on this was always like,
but if that's the kind of person they were, you know,
and you truly think they're gonna be evil, like,
might they not have done something sooner?
-- I
-- mean, I wouldn't think of it in that context. I think
once you fire someone, even if they are a good person,
good people can get angry and do silly things.
And I think it is a way of
hedging your bets
against a good
honest person being extremely upset because it's a,
it's a very emotionally difficult time if you're fired or laid off.
And so I understand from the risk perspective, removing access to
-- infrastructure. And
-- it's funny because the last three places I've left,
they didn't
immediately lock me out.
And it actually really annoyed me because number one, I wanted to be done.
And number two though, is it left me at risk?
If something goes wrong, they might blame me.
Uh Maybe, and I wanted to be locked out and just be like we're done here. That's fair.
Right.
Because I mean,
if something goes wrong and Kurt potentially had access to that system,
-- well, let's blame Kurt. That seems like the easy way out.
-- It would be an easy way out.
Yes. So, anyway, anyway. Ok. Ok.
I want to end this one on the idea of your open source developers are insider threats.
Now,
there are going to be people who immediately think we need
to vet open source developers because obviously they're insider threats.
They're in our organization. That's obviously ridiculous. Right.
-- Completely ridiculous. It's,
-- that's assuming it's even legal,
-- right? Because there's Pir no, I'm serious.
-- Right. Like,
-- probably.
I mean, you can't like, what are you gonna go to github
and demand the identity of
github.com?
I bet that happens to them multiple times a day,
probably hundreds of times a day honestly. But regardless, regardless,
I think
if nothing else, this is an interesting thought experiment
because you have an insider in your organization,
you don't know,
they do not work for you.
You have no control over the software they write,
but it is critical for the running of your company.
What do you do in that situation?
I think number one
looking at it as,
and I've again, I'm, I'm annoyed,
I've never heard of this unintentional insider threat thing.
So I think number one,
you look at them through the lens of the unintentional insider threat
in the sense of they probably don't even know you're running their software
unless they're like curl in which case the assumption is
or the len external, right? No, like really,
I mean, it's safe to assume if you wrote Curl or the lens kernel that
yes.
Um So, so first of all,
I think moving it from the lens of
insider threat to very specifically unintentional insider threat
will help you be more in line with reality.
And then the question becomes
what,
what is possible, what can you do?
And so for example, you might be able to
get involved in the upstream project
and
provide
help
upstream projects and, and well,
that's where I was just about to go with this
but that does not scale.
No, not at all.
You could maybe do it for a few critical things.
And in theory, and this is what we've always hoped is that like, you know,
if 1000 companies each get involved in one open source project boom, now,
1000 open source projects are much healthier
and everybody benefits.
And that
does happen
unintentionally and
unofficially because a lot of companies are paying people who do work on
open source like and not in the red hat way where it's intentional.
But,
but, but I,
I don't think this is a practical solution
because you're running thousands and thousands of packages.
Well, and it also basically depends on the com, it's like the tr the,
the common good and all that.
So
I think the biggest question would be is to figure out what's even possible.
And I hate to say,
I don't think
I, I don't think there's anything possible at scale.
That's it full stop.
And even if something is possible at scale,
you have to get by in like you even if you, oh perfect example,
you build the world's most amazing magical A I that just fixes security
bugs like it looks at a bunch of code and goes boom,
security bug.
Here's a patch.
Not all the upstream are going to accept them or not,
all of the upstream are even alive enough to accept them.
-- Uh
-- Sure. Sure. And that, that's like a different problem for sure.
Well,
no, not in the unintentional insider threat world.
That's, that's part of that unintentional insider threat bucket.
I mean, but we don't know what to do. I, I think that's how we have to end.
This is just the fact that
when we think about
insider threats,
we don't usually think of things like open source as part of that, but it kind of is,
and it makes an a very unique thought experiment
that we don't have answers to
but is definitely probably something we need to think about.
So moving forward,
I have thought about this a lot and my response and my
policy is
I accept it. It's fine.
Like I don't worry about
-- it and
-- that, that is acceptable also. Yes.
And I just use it because
it's, it's like driving on the road. I just sort of hope that that yellow line
magically works
from the other side of the road and I don't get hit in the head on collision or,
you know, like I keep telling my kids the light turned green,
we check that it's safe to proceed. Then we go because
like
right where I live there's like four red light cameras in
a few blocks on a couple of the busier roads.
And like
one guy tried to argue that he got a bunch of speeding tickets from these three
light light cameras that are in a row that it was a single speeding event.
So you should only pay one speeding ticket on three speeding tickets, right?
Because he's speeding the whole time.
But that's the thing, right?
Like we accept these kinds of risks all the time because,
like,
my favorite thing is every time the
Edmonton police service do a commercial vehicle inspection
on, like the hand a so it's like our major ring road freeway thing,
you know,
some massive percentage of all the commercial vehicles have in
some cases horrifically terrible flaws and like they have tow trucks
there that are like taking some of these trucks away
because they are so unsafe that they can't even late,
like, legally let them drive
and
they only do this, like, once or twice a year.
It's not like those trucks all wait for the Oh. Right. Right.
Like this is just every day.
And so there's a lot of this where we accept these risks and threats and
the,
the thing that gets me is from the open source world. I keep coming back to
the value that open source provides me
vastly outweighs
any downside or risk full stop.
I, I think that's exactly how we end the show because I agree.
I agree. That's it good.
Like, even if open source came to my house and burned it down,
we would still use open
source. I would still use open source because
-- what's my alternative
-- Kurt? You had it, you had such a nice ending and then you'd
open
it
up and down my house.
No, I'm leaving this in. This is totally staying in. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Head of the genre.
Use the
Found Os S podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Let us know if open source burns your house down. Kurt.
-- Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.
Like you had such a good ending
then you.