Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 159 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
-- What's
-- new man?
Well, I guess in the interest of full disclosure,
we should let everybody know what we're talking about
be.
That was great. That was the, the worst set up ever.
So, yes, for those of you wondering what's going on,
we decided to have an episode about disclosure and I know we've kind
of talked about this in the past probably more than once it's been.
I mean, we're in a big number now of episodes. I, I don't remember, but recently
just the concept of disclosing security issues has become,
I guess relevant as a current event for a variety
of reasons. And so we thought it would be fun to talk about it today.
-- Why don't
-- we define the problem a little bit first?
Because I was actually thinking about this when you mentioned the topic.
Yeah, that's a great idea.
So I guess my first question would be is, um,
-- what's being disclosed
-- whatever you want? Like
-- actually that is part of the problem.
-- So we're going to talk about this in the general
topic of
-- information, security.
-- Right. Yeah, I, I think
security
bugs
specifically or, or I
guess
even
security
flaws
on
you could
find
a,
like, did you see the most recent one with the master lock thing where you can, like,
see the gates?
-- So he's like, you can just,
-- does he pay you to be in this channel?
Because
I honestly though he does a lot, like, who, let me ask you this,
who else is out there actually doing good security ratings
work that places like consumer reports or like the standards,
you know, like underwriter laboratories should be doing.
No, II, I agree.
And lock picking is one of those unique skills because doesn't my,
my favorite is when he, in fact, I, I watch his channel also,
but I love it when he gets out.
He says like, oh consumer reports gave this, you know,
the highest rating and then he picks the lock in 15 seconds.
Well, I mean, I, I still love this master lock thing where the,
the it's a combination little box lock thing to put your like
phone in and lock it up at the pool or whatever.
So it's a cool idea and I like it like he says he likes it too and it, it is a cool concept.
But
the thing is so sloppily made
that you can actually, when you turn the dials,
you can see where the gate is so you can, like,
you just turn it until you see the shiny part.
That's it. Like, that's how you pick this lock. You just look at it while you
open it. Cool.
You know, it reminds me that cable lock where they're like, it's Teflon and Krypton
and, you know, um, like Kevlar and Titanium and God knows what else.
And he, like, cuts through it with a pair of tin snips in like, four seconds,
right? But so yeah, first thing is what are we disclosing? Ok.
So we're going to talk about
information security, computer information security specifically.
Ok. Second question. Who are we disclosing to
the vendor, the public at large? A select group of industry experts?
I mean, that's part of the discussion, I think because
the term so
to, to back this up even a little more maybe is when we talk about disclosure,
you'll hear terms like responsible disclosure
or co-ordinated disclosure or whatever,
there's, you know, pick an adjective and put it in front of the word disclosure.
And for the most part, those are all loaded terms.
They're worse than loaded terms in that.
They don't actually have like an official meaning.
-- All
-- right.
Well, no, no, they,
they have an official meeting for the people using the word to generally shame.
-- Yeah,
-- but everybody uses them differently. Some,
they do.
I know that's part of the crazy because like responsible disclosure was a
term Microsoft basically ended up inventing because
people would report bugs to them,
they do nothing and then people would report bugs
to the world on the full disclosure mailing list.
And now Microsoft is like, oh, you didn't disclose this responsibly.
It's like, no, well, they did,
you just didn't responsibly deal with the disclosure.
So
your fault, not theirs.
And I mean, also part of it is then, you know,
how much or what all is being disclosed because, I mean,
there can be I I've had people like disclose to me,
it's like there's a flaw in the loans kernel.
Well, yeah, there probably is. Yeah, we know.
Yeah.
And then I've also had people like, you know, very specifically
there's a blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, here's the diesels, blah,
blah blah versus also that plus like exploit code,
right? And
that's exactly it.
You,
you get this a lot in the open source world where
someone might try to write an advisory for something they fix
that is lacking on details.
And it's like guys, you know, like the patches right here,
you check to test and then actually exploit this.
What are you doing here? You know,
I
mean, and that's the problem is these are all dimensions that can you,
you can slide them up and down as it were,
you know, and even within this whole like a group of industry experts.
Well, is that like the Linux kernel mailing list?
Wait, that's publicly bad example. Oh what was that list? That solar runs? Linux
distro list? Yeah. Linux distro, man. I mean, I used to be on it.
I should have remembered this.
Well, yeah, there was vendor
se before that and I think, does a Zarda
-- list still exist even? Like, I don't
-- remember,
I don't remember.
And like, so I know there's the districts list and you know, there's like the,
the quote unquote secret stuff goes there.
So people have time to deal with it.
And actually, and when I say deal with it, I don't mean like bury it and ignore it.
But I mean,
like some of these things are complicated to patch and fix like they are nontrivial,
you know, after the whole shell shock thing where that, that was a bit of a mess.
But then there's other industry groups, there's industry specific verticals,
you know, where it's like all the banks share stuff or power industry.
Uh What is it? NANR A something starts with an N
I think it's N
Yeah.
And so even within that, you know, I know there's various cloud groups,
there's various vendor groups,
there's no doubt there's just lists that are like literally AC C that's
been going on for six months or 10 years in some cases,
you know, I know people have their sort of,
I don't want to call it a list because it's literally
just somebody started an email thread and it just never died.
Right. Right. And with open source, this gets even crazier because now
we'll pick on the Linux kernel,
you have vendor shipping kernels.
You know, you've got people like Debian and Red Hat and Su
and whoever you have people consuming kernels like Google and Amazon are two
phenomenal examples there.
So
how does the
-- IOT space T together? Right.
-- Exactly.
Well, I mean, my favorite is always open SSL. Right?
Because everybody uses open SSL. Every TV on the planet uses Open SSL.
And I remember they were, you know, some of these TV manufacturers are like,
we want advanced notice of open SSL phones and the Open SSL group was like, no,
like you, you're not,
you think you're special enough but you're not. And more to the point
the risk,
how do I put this nicely? A lot of these big vendors aren't
great at security
and I don't mean just like patching stuff but, like keeping stuff secret.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, exactly. I mean, there have been more than one leaks.
I know of where
it was an attempt to do some sort of co ordination
and somebody accidentally did something they weren't supposed to do.
And it's like, well,
the cat's out of the bag. Everybody. Here we go.
Yeah, I mean, yeah, I, yeah, I just, I don't know what to say.
We need to say that this is a hugely complex topic
and it's one of those things that people love to say,
oh,
if you only have a bug bounty or you only have a
disclosure policy on your website or you only do this one thing.
It's never one thing
ever.
Things definitely help though.
Well, it certainly does, but I want,
I want to add one other really important point here
around disclosure in general. And that is that
the world of today is not the world of even five years ago.
And there's a nontrivial amount of content I read about disclosure
that are from people who have old knowledge and it's,
it's not useful and that's also something that muddies the waters here.
Is
it,
you know. Yeah, you worked at Microsoft five years.
But like, it's all open source now.
It's not even that it's old knowledge so much that there's new knowledge. Yeah.
Yeah, that's fair because old knowledge is not inherently bad.
Like, for example, starting a fire with two sticks like a fire bow.
-- That's old knowledge.
-- Have you ever tried to do that?
-- Like, it's terrible.
-- No, this is why I always bring two lighters with me. Right.
I bring two lighters, not one lighter but two lighters because, yeah, I've tried.
Yeah.
No, it's, we're going to be doing this at scouts this year, you know,
the fire starting stuff and,
you know, ranging from like, hairspray and a lighter to, yeah, two sticks,
good luck kid.
And, and that's kind of a good example here is,
it's not that the old knowledge is necessarily
bad or wrong. It's just,
there's way better ways to do this now, like a butane lighter,
you know,
and same thing with disclosure, like, for example, having a disclosure policy,
well,
that signals to the people trying to disclose to
me that at least I know what disclosure is
and I've thought about it a little bit and I care enough to maybe have an email address
all the way up to a bug bounty where it's like, no, you know,
and depending on how much your bug bounty is, it like not to name.
Well,
you know, that vendor that just came out with, you know, we're,
we're upping our bug bounty to a million dollars.
Well,
it's pretty clear they,
they care about disclosure and they want to hear about it
first if they're putting a million bucks on the line,
even,
even that gets funny because there's people complaining about
paying bug bounty hunters is dumb and you should be
using that money to hire better security people and it's
like we can't agree on anything and it's beautiful.
Well, here's the thing I always get with the whole hiring argument is like, cool.
You want to hire people? Great.
Please tell me how you're doing that so I can copy you because man,
like finding competent people who are just like looking for work.
Oh, my goodness. I know. I know. It's,
in fact, at work we, we, we're opening up some security wrecks and
I, I see my future
and it's six months of pain.
That's what it is trying to find people because you're going to talk to a ton of people
and it's going to be like, why am I even talking to this person? What is going on here?
Oh,
my goodness.
Anyway, anyway, but by the way, if anyone's looking for a job, like hook, hit me up,
like just saying.
All right. So anyway, disclosure.
So here's,
here's the one thing I will tell everyone listening to us right
now is that everything you're going to hear about is fundamentally opinions.
Kurt and I have been doing this for a long time, but there are no facts in this space.
There are none, anyone who tells you they have facts is lying.
No, there's a couple of good facts like everything's messed up and broken.
-- OK.
-- That could be a fact.
The other fact that's really, really bad is
all of these things mean different things to different people,
not just because
like they use language differently, but because, well, here's a great example.
You talked about a kernel consumer. What, what like is an IOT
guy who just ships a vanilla Debian, a kernel consumer.
He's shipping a kernel or,
versus somebody who takes a kernel maybe modifies it a bit and ships it versus,
you know,
somebody who's actually actively involved in maintaining a subsystem or,
you know, 5% of the Linux kernel code.
Right. Right. Right.
These are all and, and then it also depends on what you're using it for, for example,
Google.
Well, a better example, Amazon
is a huge consumer of, I want to say Zen, right,
the the hypervisor stuff for their cloud,
but they don't
like ship it
per se
in the traditional sense of the word. Like
my understanding is like with Amazon Outpost, you can actually get hardware,
running it on premises, but it's not like you get to log in there and, like,
run your update on it.
You know, my understanding is it's,
it's a piece of Amazon's cloud that just
happens to physically reside on your premises.
Exactly. You know,
so, like, is Amazon shipping, Zen,
they're probably running more copies of it than anyone on the planet.
Right. Right. Exactly.
And, and, well, in fact, even to make it more crazy is I,
I remember reading this was a while ago.
I,
I looked into it at all but Amazon announced they
were going to start moving to KBM for certain things.
So now it's even crazier
and they also have silicon on dye doing stuff. So it's like
it
-- knows what they're doing at
-- this
-- point.
-- Bonkers, everything going on. So anyway,
like this is,
I think one of the fundamental problems were disclosure we, we're putting on our,
our security researcher hat is you find a security problem.
What, who do you tell? How do you report this to anybody
-- is question one who owns
-- this thing is not always clear,
you know, uh, like something like open SSL or Apache. Ok.
There's like the Open SSL Foundation and the Apache Foundation or, you know,
you find a flaw in a Microsoft product.
There's
microsoft.com, like, ok, good.
But you don't know who to talk to yet, but you know,
which general direction to point your email.
Sure. Versus like Lib Jasper,
you know, I hate to pick on Lib Jasper but, you know,
it was written as a thesis project and the guy wrote it and
it's who maintains Luke Jasper.
-- Uh
-- maybe nobody in some cases it could be a guy, it could be a github
repo.
-- I
-- think Google for a while was doing kind
of keeping caring and feeding it a little bit.
But,
yeah, I mean, it's just, some of the stuff is like, it's just abandoned or whatever.
It's not clear, kind of who owns it. Like it's in uh
XML XML hash dogs, right?
There's a piece of code that's been copied everywhere or like the zip, you know,
zip is copied into all the songs
software. So it will compile on Windows natively without a whole bunch of hassle,
right? Who owns that zip code?
Well, you embedded it and it's diverged from, I guess where you copied it from.
Yeah, but ignoring the ownership, I'm a security researcher.
Where do I go?
Do I, I mean, you look at like, in the case of the SNCC guys,
when we talk to them about Zip Slip,
they actually spent effort reaching out to like literally
hundreds of projects that had embedded the source code.
-- And if I'm just a guy who, who did this,
-- that's an amazing amount of effort. Yeah.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. I mean, if you're just a researcher
there, you can't do that. There's no way.
Well, I remember those, the guys that found Http Poxy came and I was like,
do you want me to handle this?
Like the notification piece? And they're like, oh Lord, yes, like, thank you.
You know,
because that was literally my job and it was
literally like these were software guys from New Zealand.
Like they don't,
they're not a security vendor, you know, they just found this horrible flaw.
Oh my goodness. We're like, we're like halfway through this episode and we
are still on the very beginning of the very
-- and
-- I think that's,
that's fundamentally the problem here that I there you go in a nutshell folks.
That's disclosure.
It's a giant mess.
It, it, it's, it is,
it's so hard to do and there's so many
opinions and everyone thinks you should do it differently and
-- it's just, it's so hard.
-- Well, and then this ignores the fact.
Like, remember when a couple of the automakers came out a few years ago saying
we will not sue you if you try to disclose flaws to us.
And you know what that was actually progress.
It was huge. Progress
seems insane when you think about it.
But that was a problem where researchers would report an
issue to a company and the company would sue them,
-- which is, or threaten
-- to sue them.
Right.
-- You know, to stifle them.
-- Exactly.
It is, it is something else.
It's a thing. All right.
Right. Right.
So, anyway, anyway, back to the horrible topic we've decided to talk about.
We've got the issue of, let's say I'm a researcher
and I somehow figure out who to contact, let's say I contact Microsoft because
they're big
and they,
it's well known how to contact them. They even have a bug bounty in some cases.
Well, even beyond a bug bounty, what I love is not only do they have a bug bounty and,
you know,
work well with the researchers now.
But, um, I don't know if you remember, but at RS A or at black hat rather well.
And Rs A they had that wall of like,
our most valuable bug bounty participants and like,
they're celebrating them and like, yay.
But one issue too, that is more of a complicated problem in the open source space.
Not so much in the commercial space.
In the commercial space,
you typically know which vendor sold you this thing and that's the only
or whatever, who did this software
and they're the only ones that did that software.
Whereas in the open source world stuff gets embedded and copied around a lot.
Or vendors distribute it.
You know,
there's only one entity really distributing Microsoft Word that's Microsoft.
But for like openness,
well,
those are different problems.
And let's,
let's just pick on Microsoft here because I
think the story is easier to tell because there's
-- corner cases
-- they went from terrible to OK.
Compared to everyone else, they're pretty good. I'm not going to lie to you.
So here's the thing.
You're a researcher, you find a full on a Microsoft product,
you report it to Microsoft.
Ideally Microsoft will say, wow, thanks, good job.
You know, here's the money we're going to credit you whatever.
They're, they're good about that and then they release an update,
people install the update, everyone, rejoices.
We're all done. Right.
Well, except for the case, you know, where somebody's like,
we have a 90 day disclosure policy and Microsoft, like,
I think it was one case they wanted like 92 days and it was like, well, nope, 90 days
-- and that's
-- fine.
I seem to remember. It made them pretty grumpy.
Probably.
I know there was something recently that,
that project Zero reported to them that went over and
they were, they were cool about it. They, they did, right.
But anyway, so, right, you can have issues with you could,
you could as a researcher reporting something you could
say you have 90 days or I'm going public.
You can,
you can say I expect
that you will wear a chicken suit when you announce this right, you can make like,
any crazy demand you want on the person you report.
It doesn't mean they're going to listen. But that's one thing to keep in mind is
sometimes when you report something,
some of these vendors are going to try to push you around and here's the deal,
you don't have to take it.
-- Well,
-- unless they threaten to sue you
and you. Well, yes, there is that
this is not legal advice, but if somebody threatens to sue you,
probably go talk to a lawyer.
Yeah.
Call the eff or somebody in that case, if you're,
if you're doing good working with the open source.
But, but anyway, here's the thing.
Now you could build Microsoft and they might say we don't think this is a security
issue or they might say this isn't serious and we're going to fix it in next year
or whatever. Right. It could be some who knows.
And as a researcher that's where things start to get dicey.
So let's say Microsoft says, I don't think this is a security issue and let's face it.
Like with, with that problem,
Tavis just found with whatever I forget the name of the,
the technology and Windows that's been there forever.
It would not shock me if he'd found it not done enough research,
went to Microsoft and they'd be like
this is unexploited. No.
Right.
And then what,
-- what, what now
-- Well,
see,
and my thought always there was if the vendor says it's not a vulnerability, cool,
then I am, I'll just publish it publicly because it's not a vulnerability, right?
And that is exactly the right way to look at it is if the vendor says not an issue,
then you can take it to the court of public opinion and say,
look what I found and sometimes you might be wrong.
Sometimes, you know, the world might look at it and just say you're an idiot.
You know, this is, this is nothing
and that happens sometimes like it totally does. I, I agree with you.
If a vendor says, not a problem, we're not fixing that or something.
I think there should be no, no question
that bringing it public is totally the way to go.
But now at the same time,
you can be a vendor and you get a report and it
could be a ridiculous requirement where someone could say in seven days,
-- I'm going to publish this
-- well, or I want a million dollars in a monster truck,
which is a fair request.
But right. Exactly. You could end up with some sort of
response like that.
And now at the same time, if you're a vendor working with a difficult researcher,
there's also nothing wrong with basically saying, you know, thanks for doing this.
You do. You, we're going to fix this our way
-- and, and cutting, cutting ties. Oh Yeah.
-- No.
I've definitely had to deal with people trying to number one report
things that are not vulnerabilities to like the cloud security lines,
you know, saying things like you don't have D
Mark set up and it's like, well,
80% of the top websites don't because they don't, you know, we have SPF and DC
MD
Mark doesn't
help
and things like that and, and, you know, and also they were wanting money and
stuff for us to pay them and it's like we,
I don't know that we can legally do that without so much
paperwork and I don't even know where to begin with that,
you know.
W eight Ben and all that.
Yeah.
Bug bunnies are great for that because they actually do all the vetting and all the,
the background nonsense.
Who knew doing your accounting legally was hard. So
you're willing to break the law. It's no big deal. But, yeah,
to me it's, it's a continuum of, sort of maturity and capability. Right.
Because there's a lot of places that are
wanting to do the right thing,
but they physically cannot because they don't have the talent or the,
the resources and there's a lot of places well,
that have neither the will nor the strength of technology to do the right thing.
And there is that yes.
And then there are places that kind of technically should have the ability
to, you know, do things better, like all the skate vendors,
the large ones should be able to do security.
They definitely have the money. You know, these companies are posting profits
but they generally don't have much of a security team if any.
And, and part of that too boils down to like who you're going to hire
it
cost money.
Like
it's not even that it costs money. It's ok. So
you have, let's say you have the ability to do computer security and skater work.
Are you going to ever be
looking for work?
No, there's going to be people coming to you trying to hire you constantly.
-- Right. There's just not enough people to do this,
-- even if you don't do SK to work.
Right.
If you're a security person, it's, it's a good time to be employed.
Yeah. If you're remotely competent, you're fine.
Even if you're not,
-- you're fine. Yeah.
-- No, that's
actually, yeah, that's sadly true.
Right. Right. Because if they ever, if confidence mattered I'd be homeless. So,
it's right. Right.
Like, II, I just keep thinking in my head what we're talking about here and this,
this is all so complicated and so difficult. And I guess that is
the thing I keep coming back to all the time is
when you're reporting to an organization,
I think it's easy
to assume ill intent right away.
And in fact,
-- I've seen this more than once for someone to report something basically say,
-- well,
the fundamental attribution error.
Right. That guy cut me off. In traffic. He was plotting to do this all month.
The reality is the majority of these vendors that are bad at security are just, well,
they're enterprise vendors that are kind of slow and big and not,
they're just not great at, like responding quickly.
-- A
-- lot of them don't actually know what to do. And in fact,
there have been so many times I've tried to contact
a company and it's like you put on Twitter,
hey, I'm looking for a security contact at this company.
Does somebody know anyone? Because it's like I can't even find where to put this.
My son went to a summer camp
and they sent out a survey. How was your summer camp? Would you come again?
What would you improve stuff like that? Right.
The usual except they cc everybody who registered like,
so there was like over 100 people on this CC list
number two and I was like, whatever archive, ignore it.
Hope to God, there's no reply all storm,
but then some of the emails out a virus to it. And so I replied to the original sender
and their hr and a bunch of others pointing out that like, yeah,
really messed up here.
You need to train your employees.
This is, you know AAA privacy violation and a GDPR violation.
And you know,
there's also now this virus running around and it's a liability issue
and like hr you need to like address this because it's,
it's a liability issue for you now.
And, uh, it's, you know, it's been a couple of hours. No reply.
Probably not that important.
-- Probably
-- not. They, they,
they, you know what they did, they click the, uh,
this is a crazy person button on you and now you'll never get to talk to them again.
Yeah.
But, uh, it just, you know, and I,
it's funny because I actually know people of this organization who I
could talk to and they would understand and probably be like,
oh, God, we did what?
-- But if I, like, try to go in through the front door. Yeah.
-- Right. It's, it's hard
and I guess at the same time that you can make the argument,
this is part of the value that comes
with hiring good security people because you'll probably
be able to find somebody at the organization.
-- But that, that's, that's not
-- right.
Well,
the problem is not only do you have to hire good security people but you have to
let them do their job and a lot of places you sort of can't because for example,
again,
I remember it's like we want to make a
public statement explaining what happened and they're like,
well, the lawyers have to approve it first.
-- Uh, yes. Right.
-- Because I mean, an admission of liability,
that's
a
-- little bit scary
-- sometimes.
So, so anyway, anyway,
disclosure, we're nearly out of time. So we'll,
maybe we'll do a two parter because there's
a lot of open source disclosure things that
I think we need to talk about also here because those are super interesting and,
and super important as well.
So here's the one thing I guess I always think about when
we talk about disclosure is if you are reporting to someone,
be polite and assume the person on the other end
either doesn't understand you
or doesn't know what's going on if they're not talking to you in the way you expect.
Or in some cases,
it could be a matter of like English as a second language for some people.
Well, even more simply put as a security researcher,
it's kind of like being a car salesman.
You sell a lot of cars, people don't buy a lot of cars.
Most projects handle a literal handful of security vulnerabilities every year.
So they're not really gonna get good at it because they don't, you know,
if you only do something once a quarter.
Right. Right.
Yeah, it's, it's new every time you do it versus you do something once a day,
hopefully a little better of
it,
you know,
have checklists and stuff
and, you know, and,
and that to me is fundamentally one of the problems is a company like Microsoft can
have hundreds of products that each only have one or two security flaws a year.
But because they can centralize those resources, they can have the MS RC,
the Microsoft Security something.
Center
response center Thank you.
Yeah, research response remediation,
whatever those MS RC people can be good at this.
Like it's literally their full time job. But you know, you find like some,
some random open source project, they probably don't have a security
-- team
-- and, and we will, we will get to that, we will get to that in the next episode.
And now on the other side though,
I want to say if you are a vendor receiving a report from a researcher and
you feel like they are hostile or you don't like
their tone or you don't like what they're doing.
It becomes a situation of these people could be grumpy because they
just got told off by somebody or they're working with a difficult other
person or company or whatever.
And so again, it comes down to one of those, you know,
be patient and be respectful and be mindful and that can go a long way.
Now, sometimes you can just be working with the jerk and that goes both ways,
be researcher or vendor, right?
And, and sometimes you just have to agree to disagree on some of these issues.
And that, that can be just the way it is, but it is,
again,
it kind of comes down to just be polite and ask a lot of questions
and communicate constantly when a researcher comes to you as a vendor and says,
-- I found something,
-- oh man, when they go radio silent for a week.
-- Or two at a time.
-- It's terrible.
-- So,
-- even, just, even an email saying we're still working on it.
Yep. Exactly.
Exactly. It is up to the vendor in effect. Like I even think of this.
I mean, I'm guilty of this where I,
I try to reach out once a week to the people who report things to us but
it doesn't always happen and sometimes I forget and then of course,
I apologize profusely because it's like I know what this is like.
It sucks. I I'm sorry, but it is
when you are the vendor, it is your job to initiate and hold communication.
It is not their job to ask you questions and come to you.
They already gave you a gift, you need to do something with it.
And now I will also say though there is the added,
I guess complexity of bug bounties that goes on top of this
and bug bunnies are special because they give the vendor the ability
to coerce the reporter into behaving in the way they want.
Well, not even coerce but to signal.
I mean, it's one thing to have a disclosure policy that's good,
but to have a disclosure policy and say, and we pay cash,
I'm comfortable calling it coercion.
Well, if some do it as coercion for sure, like, you know, well,
to pick on like Apple again,
Apple really is, you know, they're all about brand and brand marketing protection,
right?
Like and I get it. That's, that's kind of apple shtick. Right.
They're a marketing brand company
that makes technology and they're very good at
it. Yeah, they, they don't want anybody pooping on their brand.
Right. Right. You can get into situations where
I bag
bni might say,
here's your money now.
Never talk about this to anyone ever again under any circumstances.
And it's like,
what?
Well, that's how a lot of, like, you know,
you read the old stories about the finance industry, that's basically how,
you know, they were infamous for trying to sweep stuff under the rug constantly.
Sure.
-- And there's a lots of industries like that,
-- like, and in fact, right,
that's where a lot of the laws came into play that now say you have to talk about this,
you can't just pretend everything's fine.
Well, and you still see them discussing like if it's what,
what exactly does breach mean?
You know, like,
-- you know,
-- exactly.
-- That depends what the definition of is, is
-- like Equifax with there,
there was no data breached except for the following list
and then they listed out like a million Canadians.
That's right.
Oh, I love it. All right. Anyway, let's cut this one
and we will continue on with open source because I
am ecstatic to talk about it just because there was,
there's an insane story about Web Men
that we need to cover in the next episode. So. All right, cool.
Thank you for listening. Thank you, Kurt.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show, not, it's U Pound Os S podcast hashtag
to hit us up on social media.
-- And yeah, I guess Kurt, I will see you in the next
-- episode. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.