Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Seyfried
and my partner in discussing what Poly Phil dot Io has to do with NFTS and A I,
Josh Pressers.
Oh my goodness. What I don't even want to know.
So, OK. Well, first let's set the sage. So what is Poly Phil?
Do you want to take it or shall I?
I'll, I'll explain it as best as I can.
So mind you, this all kind of happened yesterday at the time we're recording.
So I assume I'm hopeful more information will emerge.
But what is Poly Phil and to be clear? Poly fill, not poly fill dot IO.
-- So let's start with the software,
-- right? Poly fill the concept, right?
So, and I'm,
I'm gonna explain this in the context of the
web browser because I think that kind of makes sense
when you're using a web browser,
new web browser versions will have new features, right?
Where it could maybe show an image on a screen in a certain way or, or maybe, you know,
rotate something or whatever, there's millions of things web browsers do.
Now, it's ridiculous. And so
the idea being
some of your users will be on older browsers that don't have those features.
And so Polypill is this like concept in,
I don't know if it's specific to computer science or programming necessarily.
But the idea being we're going to add this functionality in.
-- Well, it's monkey patching, basically,
-- it's not monkey patching.
You're just adding the function
like via a library
versus being included in the browser.
Yeah.
And it's, but what I mean is it's a similar concept to you don't have this capability.
I want you to have this capability so that my software runs.
Because fundamentally as a web
application developer, I don't want to write 4000 versions of my software, right?
I want to write one version of my software that
will show the dancing monkey and rotate it or whatever.
And oh your web browser, I wanted to work on browsers that are like
years old.
-- I mean,
-- I think I would video games are probably a great example of this, right? Where
if you have the latest and greatest graphics card, you might have,
you know what, what is the thing? Ray Tracing is the big hot topic right now,
I think they gave it a weird name.
But anyway,
you know where there's functionality in newer
cards that aren't available in older cards.
And so now when you're a game developer, you either just don't use the functionality
where you're like, you don't get shadows, right or whatever
or
you write a software function that will do the thing you need to do.
Just not as well as the hardware, for example, might do it.
Same idea.
Yeah.
And so, and to be clear,
this is classic web stuff where it's a bunch of javascript that
is included in the web page loaded. And that leads to a problem.
What happens if you include
hundreds of kilobytes or
tens of javascript files on a web page? Well, it loads slowly.
Well, they all include like bazillions of things now.
-- But yes, I understand what you're saying,
-- but the more you include,
the more slow it is.
And so, and this is where Poly
dot io comes in, which is, it's actually quite close.
So what Poly
dot io does, which I think is quite gorgeous
is
it serves the Poly
Fill javascript
but
depending on what user agent and headers,
it serves different things.
So it basically says, oh, you're like, really up to date,
you only need this one more recent thing.
It only serves what you need
exactly. And
you're 34 years out of date, OK? You're getting like half a megabyte of javascript.
Good luck. And
because it's poly fill dot IO because it's served off of
a central CD N if I use Poly Fill dot io.
And the first time you come to my website is slow,
but then the next time you go say in a week
to somebody else's website that uses poly fill dot IO,
it loads
instantly basically
because you've already cashed it
because we're, you, we're both using Poly Phil dot Io.
And that's one of the reasons why people
because II I always see this like,
why are web devs so insane of like including third party stuff.
Well, for example, Google fonts,
we include Google fonts because you've already got them loaded
and so they just load instantly and like
our web page doesn't load slow while you wait for half a megabyte of fonts.
There's a very important thing
that poly fill that IO
does
or rather there's an important security feature.
Poly fill that IO can't use when you're loading remote javascript.
For example, a lot of people might load
what's a, what's a javascript library like
the Google fonts or, or let's let's call it, let's say Bootstrap, Twitter,
Bootstrap, right?
That's a better example where I'm gonna say go to
this CD N download this javascript and run it.
And so as a security minded developer,
I'm nervous about this because I don't want to just download
whatever random crap the CD N is going to serve me.
So there's this ability in the go load this javascript. I forget the name of it.
It's SR I and it's not just javascript, it's
-- oh S
-- R I, that's it,
it's any, it can be pictures, it can be images, it can be audio,
right? Yeah. Any, any remote content.
So you can say here's the, here's the check,
some of the javascript I'm expecting to download and use if the checks don't match,
it doesn't load it obviously because you don't want to download random crap.
However, because of the way poly fill works, poly fill dot IO specifically,
you don't know exactly what you're going to get.
So you can't use that SR I tag on poly fill
content.
Also, a lot of people don't use SR I because for example,
you point at the latest like you point at the
bootstrap dot Js, not a specific version of it.
-- And so it will at some point update and then have a different hand break
-- everything.
Exactly. So a lot of people don't use
subo integrity sr because
fundamentally it forces you to pin your versions which you should
and there's a, you know, there's a chance like for the sake of argument,
let's say they start,
it's serving it regular and then they start serving it min
well, different hash and it was
-- which is it should though you want it to break.
-- Yeah. Yeah. No, I agree.
But the problem is if you give a developer a security
capability that requires
extra work and often results in potential breakage,
they're not going to use it
and, and regardless Polly Fill that IO just can't.
So this
in
this context,
dynamic
generated content.
Yeah, you can't do it
-- right
-- now.
Something special happened to Polly Fill dot IO that we found out about yesterday,
but it looks like it happened at the beginning of 2024.
Yeah,
-- it got sold to a Chinese company and
-- now they're serving what appears to be
-- malware
-- selectively once in a while serving
malware and you found that supposed payload,
-- which
-- is a link off of a github
-- issue that was closed. And now you have to look at archive.org to find.
-- Now
for
-- archive.org, the whole
-- thing is super sketchy.
-- Basically,
-- it's, it's pretty much exactly what I was expecting, which was,
it's not a payload itself.
It's a loader. That kind of looks at what you are,
what you're, you know,
what kind of are you on Baidu or Tencent or some like a couple of Chinese websites,
what are you doing?
And if you meet certain criteria, then you get to,
you get told to load this other very suss looking domain something something Js
which is now gone. It's 400.
This is very common
in the malware world. Is
you, you do some work to understand?
Am I like running on my legitimate target system
or am I being inspected by a malware researcher,
for example?
And
like a favorite is
malware will look at your CPU and if it detects it's running in a VM,
it just won't do anything because it's like I'm probably being researched by.
-- So I'm going to make their lives miserable.
-- And these tricks
generally work like they,
-- they're surprisingly effective and
-- not only that when I looked at some of the de
obfuscated code,
it looks like it was just basically doing like a math,
not rand and only running a small percentage of the time,
which is also very clever because now you go from malware that I'm noticing
something weird is happening on this website to, oh, the website's acting weird.
I'll just reload it.
It's back to our bicycle theft problem.
-- Right.
-- Like, if you stole every bicycle in Edmonton, the cops might care.
No, like they might actually care. But you steal 1% of the bicycles in Edmonton
and their response is make sure it's registered on bike index.org.
And if we recover it, we'll check and give it back to you.
I wonder if 1% of the bicycles in Edmonton legitimately get stolen.
I bet it's higher than that,
but it's,
I don't know, 1%. It's pro let me go this way. It's probably less than 10% I hope.
And it's probably more than 0.1 of a percent. Ok.
But now here's,
I think what makes this whole story kind of wild and
I think the topic we actually need to talk about.
So it sounds like the
github repo
was changed to some other entity.
Probably the people running the new Poly Fill that IO site,
the Poly Fill,
that IO domain which was apparently not owned by the original developer.
-- I don't understand that. So
-- basically the poly
fill
as a
piece of software
was totally
separate from Poly Fill dot Io.
They, they,
the only thing they had in common is that Poly Fill dot Io was this
really cool service that was of all places run by the Financial Times originally.
So I'm assuming the Financial Times was using it
and was just like somebody internally managed to sheer
their way into like, let's host it, pay for it.
And, you know, it probably was not that actually expensive. And so
the Financial Times actually owned Poly Phil dot Io apparently.
And then, yeah, sold it or got rid of it or whatever.
And so there's the software itself which is fine, it's good.
But there's this CD N serving
it most of the time. And once in a while, a little extra special sauce,
a
little spicy,
you know, you get a little chili pepper in there
that you're not expecting.
That's the thing is,
uh what's really funny is back in February Cloud Flare actually started serving.
Yes, Pauly fill dot IO.
Like they basically, if you go to like it's like Cloudflare CD, n.com/and,
-- then they basically like
-- cloud flare serves a ton of this kind of
stuff like Bootstrap is in there and a whole bunch of other things
-- like that's not unusual for them at all.
-- The problem is they don't,
they serve the content like statically, like as one traditionally does,
they don't serve it in the way that Poly Phil dot IO dynamically generated it.
And that is,
and, and so that's the thing that Poly Phil dot Io with that dynamic generation,
it reduces load times because you know, if it's,
if a recent browser comes and is getting it for the first time,
it's only gonna have to get tens or
maybe 100 kilobytes of javascript, you know, versus the whole thing.
And so
using poly fill dot io basically means you don't have to do anything clever,
like determining what the client can and cannot
do and then serving them the files selectively.
Basically, the three options are serve if you want to work, serve them all the files.
That's slow, simple, but work
but slow, you determine what they need and serve them that stuff,
which means you need to do some clever stuff or you just point out what polyfit
I own kind of like,
-- it mostly just works
-- well in that very web.
Now,
that's just kind of how the web works is you just
point at a CD N for whatever weird library or javascript
you're using and you use it because the CD Ns are
-- fast and I don't have to carry the crap around
-- it
-- and they're hosting it for free. They're not charging you. So it's like magic.
-- OK?
I think the, the more interesting discussion is the,
you had a trusted open source project and service
that has been taken over.
Let's make sure that they're very like they are very separate things.
-- They
-- were at the beginning. Are they now though? It sounds like the Poly filled
github Repo has been taken over by a
-- nefarious individual
-- and that's where things get complicated.
It sounds like, yeah, a Chinese entity has taken over essentially both of them.
I don't know if they're maybe going to try and sell people
a service or if they are straight up militia just malware like,
hey,
let's grab this service that, you know,
the reality is hundreds of thousands probably of websites or more depend on this
and the tweet, you know, update all your poly
fill io things to fix this.
Like less than 1% of poly fill io users are going to see
that and of that 1% maybe 1% will actually make the change.
Sure. This is like this is like, for example, Calgary had a water main break.
They asked people to use less water.
No,
there was the quote yesterday where I think it was,
they, their, their target goal is to uh the, the threshold is 480 million L a day.
And
they said we're approaching that limit yesterday. They used 476 million L.
Like that's a 1% buffer basically
like,
yeah, exactly. So it's like we can't even get people to stop flushing their toilets
and you expect something as complicated as changing a whole bunch of software,
right?
That's just very few
at
the high end single digit percentages of people using polyu
dot IO will, will actually fix this.
And what's really interesting is so, um, ad blockers,
some of the ad blockers have started adding that domain as
-- malware.
-- I can't go to it now where you block origin is hitting it.
I don't know if Polly filled that Iowa.
Actually, I could curl it to see if it's still up at least.
Oh, yeah, it's still there. I mean, they paid good money for it.
Why would they take it down
the registrar or other
in between?
But they haven't kind of been,
it's one of those things where, like, I don't like this sort of cowboy, like, oh,
you know, the, the registrar just takes it down because they feel like it,
like there needs to be some due process here because one could argue for example,
what if they got hacked and were serving that malware once in a while?
Like, that's enough to nuke your entire thing
because that happens with Google where people, you know,
come on hacker news and they're like,
Google blocked my domain because I serve some malware and now I fixed it,
but they don't believe me.
And it's like,
yeah,
-- that's how that works because Holly Phil
-- is still
serving what looks like a legitimate web page.
I'm just looking at HTML. Ok. Ok. Anyway, there's the angle of, ok.
So we have a project
that has been co opted by an organization with nefarious intent.
Let's say I'm comfortable with that statement.
OK. And what about the service? Same for the service.
I'm going to group them together because both of them
have something strange going on.
And I think it makes more sense to treat them
as a single entity for the purpose of this,
this discussion.
Because the question is,
as we're seeing, we'll say more and more.
I, I hesitate, I guess it's a supply chain attack.
We'll call it a supply chain attack.
It is a supply chain. What else is it? It's part of the,
it's a supply chain for that.
Let me put it this way.
It's one thing if it's somebody's personal blog using poly fill.
But what if it's your bank?
-- Uh Well,
-- yeah, like for all I know my bank is using Poly Phil.
-- Who
-- knows? I'm
right. Anyway. OK.
So
you have an open
source project. It has been co opted. We don't know the details.
I don't care if it was stolen or expired or someone paid someone.
The details are unimportant. The point is
that you have something that used to be,
we'll say open and moderately trusted that is now
kind of open and not trusted at all.
Well, it's clearly malicious stuff going on in this
instance.
Sorry, I have to say this. I just opened up td.com.
Click on login, opened up the easy web
login page,
script source equals poly fill dash blah, blah blah, blah, blah.
So they are hosting it themselves.
But like my bank uses poly
fill. So it's pretty clear at this point.
Although there is something coming off of nigh.com, I assume it's an insight thing
and there's B CD n.tv.com.
So I assume that's, I assume, I hope that's their own content delivery network.
But like my bank is using poly fill. And if I had to guess I would say
a good chunk of banks are using poly,
I would not be surprised at all if an enormous part of the web is using this.
But regardless
that's not important for this particular topic, the topic is
well, but the point is this poly
actually matters because
-- it's in use. This isn't a theoretical.
-- No. Exactly. Exactly.
Like I think all of these sort of attacks matter and,
and they might not matter to a huge swath of people, but it,
it's gonna matter to someone.
Right.
So it doesn't matter if it's a hugely popular important open
source project or it's a project used by 10 people.
Like when you have something happen like this, it is kind of terrifying and,
and kind of bizarre.
But the question is,
so I'm existing in the modern world, I'm using open source software.
How can I possibly keep track of something like this and have a clue
of whether my UPS streams are marginally
trustworthy or if it's completely gone off the rails,
especially with the web stuff it's really hard because unless you happen to
go to the web page and you happen to get a malicious polypill
and you happen to notice it's malicious
and you do a bunch of investigation,
you're not going to notice.
But this is the beauty of these webs
attacks is if I, if I modify code and github,
everybody can see it.
But if I modify code that's served via a web page,
only that person
sees it and like, unless they notice,
well, they don't.
Right.
And like Paully Phil was doing this for weeks or months.
Who knows?
Ok. I, I think there's two sides to this though.
There's the
angle of it has been co opted, right? Which is one that's its own discussion.
But then there's the piece of the security universe seems
to be doing a reasonable job of detecting this stuff.
But you have to be paying attention and you have to know,
you have to be following the right people, right, so to speak.
-- Yeah.
-- And that's not sustainable.
It is definitely not sustainable and normal
people would never even know about this.
Right.
If only there was some database of vulnerabilities and incidents and problems.
-- Oh, I know.
-- Right.
With maybe some sort of, you know, common
product enumeration
naming scheme.
No, but, ok. But like this is one of my complaints is
CV, will never cover this issue. That's the best part.
-- No, which is nuts because it's a
-- service.
Well, not even because it's a service, it's malware. They don't cover malware.
It's an intentional backdoor.
So if somebody had accidentally put in a back door, like a password or something,
they would know.
But because it's intentional, they'll never cover it. Like,
fantastic.
So
yeah, but
that's, I like the more I look at this,
the more this is clearly the future
because these little projects have grown not into
trees but into giant forest ecosystems that are like literally used by my bank.
I check my other bank. My other bank doesn't seem to be loading it.
I'm going to check. Uh
you know, but the point is like at least one major Canadian Bank is using it.
And by major, I mean, one of the top five.
Right. Well, we have five banks in Canada.
That's how we roll, you know, two airlines, five banks.
It's, it's a country of three corporations in a trench coat masquerading.
The thing is like the cost to hijack poly fill like the cost to straight up,
just buy it.
It's probably in the low tens of thousands of dollars
because
here's the thing, the person running poly Phil dot IO,
like running an operational service for free for the internet is a pain in the
word I can't say
like that's just it,
it's a pain and there's no way to monetize it or make money off of it.
There's, you know, you're not gonna offer consulting or premium
to
access or whatever. And so, like, if somebody that looks somewhat legitimate,
said, you know, I'll, I'll just give you 50 grand for this and like,
it's not your hassle anymore.
I mean, that's 50 grand and you don't have the hassle of it anymore.
That's a compelling story. That's compelling argument.
And, you know, same thing with running open source projects, like, as we,
as most people are starting to notice
that's not a very thankful job. Like, you know, you look at like
the emails or the issues, the stuff they have to, you know, the,
the vitriol and hatred they put up with.
Yeah, like somebody comes along and says,
I'll take this off your hands and I'll pay you for it.
Like,
yeah,
maybe
because the other thing is like, if you worked on Poly Phil, like, yeah,
your resume is good.
You're, you're hirable, like, you're clearly competent and good at stuff,
you know, you're not doing this as a portfolio project anymore.
And,
well, I mean,
one of the devs at the CS A is in charge of a Rails library because, well,
we needed to use it and it was not properly maintained.
So this poor guy ended up maintaining it and now he's, you know, like a baby goose.
It's his, he's stuck with it.
And I mean, if somebody,
if he came to me and said somebody offered me five grand for this
Rails app, I'd be like a sell it get the five grand. I want 10% and B
we need to stop using it immediately
for sure.
And, you know,
like you think use of open source and just fire and forget devs using open source was
quote unquote, air quotes bad.
Like as far as I know there are no s bomb products for the web.
No, no. And this is something we're going to talk about at some point
because there's a concept called the Sass bomb that
C has been like pushing on. But it's definitely,
I don't,
the, the, the,
the purpose of it today would probably not have caught this because a Sass
bomb is more about, I'm going to just scan my, like, local infrastructure,
not necessarily like all the services I'm using,
but the services you're using is definitely something that
needs to come into scope at some point.
And there's well, and,
and it's a subtle difference but it's more think
of it as the services your clients are using.
You're not
like I as TD, I'm not directly using poly fill,
it's being sent to the client who then renders it
right. Yes, exactly. And so there's a subtle distinction from like, like from
a, it's kind of like control ownership argument in the sense of like, yes,
TD is air quotes using it,
but it's running and being actually called by the client side
and with the web as we know,
like most devs are pretty lazy and just want to include stuff.
So it works and I don't blame them because,
you know, if your choices are figure out how to use poly fill or
just literally as per their main website, you know,
what is it? Script
poly
dot io slash V three slash polyfit
min dot Js.
And it just works.
-- That's what I'm putting in my code 100%. I mean,
-- yeah. Right. Anyway, OK.
So the question though, I think,
I think the thing to think about and the thing to
try to answer is we have all this open source everywhere.
Some of it is going to be co opted we've seen now, this is like the second in what,
like two months we know of, we get X
for now. You've got this, they were completely different ways to co opt a project.
But it fundamentally same idea,
like
I have a suspicion,
there's a lot more of this happening we don't know about
and the question becomes what can we do? You know what I mean?
And I don't, I don't have a good answer for it right now.
So this would be where the classic, like the security companies that like
have some sort of incentive to scan for malware because for example,
they scan for malware because they make a malware antivirus product,
right? Or like the companies I worked out where we kind of worked on,
on, on malicious code and stuff because so we could alert companies to it and say,
like, look how clever we are.
We saved you from this horrible thing. That
doesn't,
I'm gonna use the term and forgive me for this.
That doesn't work at web scale because the problem with web scale is even if you have,
OK, let's thought experiment.
Let's say you have a perfect database.
You have a system that catches all of this malware in minutes
and publishes it clearly and concisely and
in really well machine readable language.
-- What percentage of websites would use it? Less than 1%
-- probably.
Yeah, I don't think it would be huge.
Like my bank might Walmart might but like, you know.
Yeah. Right. Right. It's
like, and what could happen? Cloud flare, for example.
Well, cloud flare can at least see like, OK,
I'm serving a web page with Paully Fill involved.
Right. Then what's cloud floor going to do?
Like, just start blocking it and break 30% of the web?
That's not going to be a good time for anybody
-- is breaking all of the web better than serving malware.
-- Yes. Yes.
Breaking all of the web is better than serving malware to a,
a minor percentage of people.
Absolutely. It is worse. Yeah.
You know, the thing is too, like,
just because you got served malware doesn't mean something bad happened, right.
These are attacks, not successful outcomes, right?
And we don't even know what the payload was like.
For example, you know, was this targeting crypto wallet users by, you know,
like exchange
loins, right? We don't, we have no idea what was being served.
Nobody's shown the payload,
-- not the loader but the actual payload.
-- I know that's the thing.
I've been trying to figure that out and there's
been less attention than I'm happy with about that.
But I'm also not like in that malware universe
so there could be a ton of stuff happening.
I'm just not even aware of.
-- Somebody definitely has a copy of it because
-- like, I just, well,
I'm sure a crowd flare has several copies
probably.
Yeah, like, I mean, and for all we know Clouder, for example,
is running a service where when they see a new javascript include that's popular and
1000 times more, you know, I would assume that they,
one of their people had a pet project that maybe is in production
now that grabs that stuff and archives it for this exact eventuality.
But the trick is unless Cloud Flare grabs it air quotes properly,
they might be served the neutered version of it.
Like, unless they're using
a
-- headless browser with the correct user agents and behavior.
-- I would
hope they downloaded it from like the github
site.
Well, no, no, no.
-- What I mean is the payload being sent by the malicious Poly Phil dot Io. Right.
-- Right.
Well, that's coming from somewhere else anyway. Ok.
We keep dancing around the question I asked and we,
we don't have an answer and I get it.
-- No, we, we don't even have the beginning of an answer.
-- I mean,
I don't, I don't think we know what problem is yet either.
I think you're right. I think you're absolutely right. Because
you're gonna hear
in the next days and weeks and months all about, oh,
use an S bomb and use a malware scanner
and use antivirus and endpoint detection and blah,
blah, blah, blah blah.
It's like I went to my,
for the sake of argument.
There's, there's got to be some exchange out there using poly
loaded dynamically from the
dot IO site.
-- Like it's just statistically, it's, there's at least
-- one I'm sure there are,
I'm sure there's Bitcoin exchanges all over the place
doing it.
And so they in theory could do something which is like use a static copy or whatever.
But me as a user,
there's nothing I can do. Like I'm going,
you have no choice
the best I can do honestly and that you can generally do
for your web security as an end user is run an ad blocker
like running reputable ad locker because the vast majority
of these attacks are done using drive by downloads
often over ad networks because to quote Jesse James or whatever, you know,
why do I rob banks?
That's where the money is. Well, why would I serve malware from an ad network?
Because, well, that's,
that's who serves content to everybody on the planet.
And so I think honestly right now for end users, ad blockers
and for sites.
Well, I mean, don't,
don't use convenient things and do it yourself the hard way that's not gonna fly.
I
mean, like, my bank will do it. But,
-- you know. Oh, I wonder if the CS A uses it.
-- I already checked an cars websites.
Like, that's the first thing I did. I was, like, holy crap. I hope this isn't there.
But I couldn't find it. That's the thing that terrifies me though.
So I couldn't find it in any of the websites I looked at,
but it also doesn't mean there can't be
like some crazy freaking third party service.
That's all of a sudden gonna do something weird because goodness knows every
website on the planet has a bunch of stuff plugged into it.
-- Well,
-- yeah, like we serve,
we pull something off of this third party site and I bet our devs aren't
even totally aware of it because it's probably
pulled in by something they pulled in,
you know, and that's part of it is, um,
like a lot of these things are being pulled in by frameworks and dependencies.
-- Like they're not, you know, the DEV is not typing in, grab
-- this.
I started a thing a while back
when we started talking and it just finished. So I want to, I want to discuss it.
I ran open SSF scorecard against the
github
Repo in question.
Did it do? Well, they did very well.
There is, if I ran, if I looked at the scorecard,
there is nothing in here that would cause concern to me.
The, my favorite part is the contributor. Section score has a perfect score.
Well done.
Perfect 10 of 10.
There's 43 contributors
where
it, it, it looks at the, the contributors for
weird.
I, I don't even know exactly
what it's looking for but it looks for like shady looking contributors and,
and they all, there's 43 of them.
It's 10 of 10. Like they all checked out.
It has, it has dependency, updating tools like, yep. Good job.
The license. Great. It has a security dot markdown or whatever they call it.
The that thing,
-- the
-- security policy,
10 dependencies, good job folks. 10 of 10.
And that's like, realistically given a budget of,
let's say for this government $100,000 you could easily,
like, that's easily a couple of months of a competent person's time
and 10 or $50,000 in cash to go.
But like, that's the thing why, like, yeah,
like hijacking XC by being kind of mean to them.
And also nice, like, good cop, bad
cop, basically, thousands of dollars of work basically spread over a long time.
-- So some patients and
-- even if you had a full time employee
and you were paying them hundreds of thousands of dollars a year,
the potential outcome of that attack is worth millions.
Yeah.
And like in this case, buying, you know, it's like you can literally ask Google,
like what is the most popular framework to fix
my javascript to make things run better and good?
And how do I make it work automatically?
And you're going to get solutions like Paully Filled Off
show. And there's, there's more, this isn't the only one
-- and,
-- and look, the reality is if you have an overworked,
underappreciated maintainer and someone shows up with a bag of money,
everyone has
a
and it's easy to say, oh, I would never do such a thing like that.
Why on earth wouldn't you? No?
Seriously, why on earth wouldn't you sell that headache?
Well, because you're a decent human being who doesn't want to, you know,
basically doom the world.
But maybe this company is saying, look, this is really important to us.
-- We want to make sure
-- that's true. That's true. We don't know any details.
It could have been totally that they might have lied,
right? And that,
that could totally happen. You could,
yeah, I mean, you could be an open source developer and they could show up and be like,
hey,
I, I wanna fund your development. I want to take over this project.
You know, I, we, we, we want it for this reason. You're right.
OK, perfect.
Now I showed up to Liber Chat and I'm like, hey,
there's no information on backing this up and no scripts.
I'm gonna do that.
And this is a case where the scripts and stuff are
simple enough that it's like literally a Mongo dump of a,
a URL, right?
So there's, but, but in theory
I could, oh perfect example,
I could build something really sophisticated and fancy with a IU I
and hide some code in there that like sneaks the backups off to some other URL.
Anyway,
I want to get us back on track so we can end
this episode at some point because I think we just keep it,
we keep driving off the road because we don't, there, there's no road,
like there's no map that's
to
do. We're wandering aimlessly around in a field.
Well,
this is where open source was 10 years ago where it's like all of
-- a sudden people started to realize
-- this is where open source is now.
Yeah, there's no,
so this is like open source 10 years ago where it had one pe you know,
it wasn't official.
Like we have didn't have the paper saying like
86% or whatever of software is open source.
But in this case, on the web,
all of these goofy nifty free services run by literally who knows are
-- like used
-- widely.
The web is irrelevant in this context because every open source project,
no, what are potentially the same.
But what I'm saying is I'm focusing on this sort
of website delivery where I don't have to compromise github.
I don't have to, essentially, I don't have to do anything that is very noticeable.
I can just buy a free content delivery network or a multi user one or whatever, or
hijack it by being mean and nice to them or pay for it.
And
now I have control over what is served from
hundreds of thousands or even millions of websites for
tens of thousands of dollars.
Like, that's a cost to hack each website of pen
and what are we going to do about it? No one knows.
Well,
we're certainly not going to serve the content ourselves because that's way too.
No, I'm serious. It is. It slows the page down.
It makes things complicated and hard.
It would be a worse user experience for everybody.
-- You know? I mean,
-- again,
I don't even care about the website problem.
I know, I know you like it, but I don't think it matters because the reality is
this problem exists everywhere.
It is literally being we, we, I won't say it's just now being exploited,
but we're at least starting to find out about it
where XZ now poly fills something else is gonna show up soon.
And
the thing baking my brain
is we literally don't know what to do about this.
And you, you, there's,
there's gonna be a ton of people with solutions coming out of the woodwork and like,
look at scorecard,
that's of no value in this instance. Like uh it what do we do?
Well, the problem is like a thought experiment time, let's say,
for the sake of argument of going really crazy somehow.
A North Korean company, let's ignore sanctions.
A North Korean company buys cloud flare.
Yeah.
Yeah,
we don't have a way to deal with that.
It would be like a world ending of it.
So, so funny enough, the solution there actually is the US government would block
the sale of cloud flare to anyone,
someone like Microsoft or Google or Oracle or someone like that, right?
That is an example of cloud flare being critical infrastructure
and the government is going to care. But now let's say curl, right? Which is a guy,
let's say Daniel one day is like,
I'm going to sell Curl for $10 million to this
-- shady Chinese company that doesn't
-- even have to be shady.
-- Yeah, whatever.
-- It could be totally legit looking. But
-- you
-- know what
I mean?
And they be like they promised me they won't do anything bad
and like
what, what then
you know,
well, or a better example would be brew, right?
Like how do you install brew on Mac Os curl, blah, blah,
-- blah pipe sh
-- which is how everything is installed on everything.
So if somebody bought brew,
they would literally now be able to compromise every Mac developer on the planet.
I mean, yeah, and there's there's I I bet if we put together a list of like critical,
we'll we'll call it critical open source infrastructure,
things like curl and brew and all that.
I bet you we could make a list of 300 things easily
and that's already more than 10 is un trackable.
And so now we're back to the, we don't, we have no idea what to do.
And this is, I mean, this is something like Toma De Pierre, right.
That I, I am not a supplier
of a blog post author.
He and I talk about this on a fairly regular basis, is all of this,
like just infrastructure
that doesn't get attention, it doesn't get funding
and in many instances, like it's very critical path.
OK. Here's two thoughts.
I have number one even just identifying it,
like what are the things that everybody installs on their thing?
You know, home brew VLC blah, blah, blah.
What if like because there's been talk of, you know,
ad blockers being sold to malicious.
Well, there have been instances of, of browser extensions at that
and this is happening with like not a theory,
-- actual
-- real.
And so I would say the first thing would be even
just identifying it and we're not even close to that yet.
But then the second thing would be is sort of who's in charge or control of it.
Like where does it come from? Who can?
And again, we can't do that because some people would like privacy, you know,
they're a, they're a pseudonym or an anonymous user on github or they don't
have their real name and pictures and for all we know, you know,
let's pretend that's not even an issue.
Should it be Sisa? Should it be the eu, should it be the United Nations?
Like, no matter what group you pick, half the people are going to hate it and be like,
morally opposed to it.
Here's my comment on that.
For example,
every country has the generally speaking their own food safety standards.
-- And so for example, fruit loops are pale in comparison to American fruit
-- loops.
They're not radioactive.
Well, because there's certain dyes that America
likes and they,
they do pop like they make the food look amazing
and they're illegal in Canada and the e in Europe,
you know, and so I think part of this is this is part of digital sovereignty, you know,
which Simon Wardley and Wardley Mapping talks
a lot about digital sovereignty of us,
America if I
like they have no control over poly fill or how people use it or even insight into it.
So, in the US context, yeah, CIA needs to do something.
I don't know what that something is, but
I would say this falls under like it sounds like a problem that they need
to go deal with or make sure
somebody's dealing with because under digital sovereignty,
-- like you're handing it off to this Chinese company
-- except there are
9 million
open
source projects.
Well,
and there's like 9 million vendors on
Amazon selling stuff that sometimes catches fire.
And we've generally tried, like, I won't buy food on Amazon,
like, just
the chance of fakes and stuff.
-- Like,
-- just, no, luckily no one started selling fake cheesies yet.
So I can still buy those off Amazon.
Right.
I mean, this is, this is part of that maturity curve of, is this a pain in the butt?
Yeah. Well, this is, this is the kind of thing where government is necessary.
This is not a private solution space.
Yeah, you're probably right.
Like I,
I don't think the answer to this is not going to
be open ssf scorecard or S bombs or anything like that.
Like yes, those things can help and I'm not saying you shouldn't use them
to try to keep your own infrastructure in order.
But this is so much bigger than that and I want to end the
show because I know we could keep rambling on for hours about this.
But I don't know how long this kind of stuff has been happening,
but I think we're going to see more and more of it because
because the more people look,
the more they will find like at the moment we're stuck at the point of the
drunk looking under the streetlight for his car
keys because this is where the light is
and I think
-- it's gonna get crazy
-- and I think it's gonna get
worse in the sense of look at the pandemic.
What did we learn from the pandemic?
Nothing.
No, like nobody. Very few people are masking
the adoption of the latest COVID shot in Canada is like 20%
like, and I suspect this is part of the problem
here is that this problem is so big and so convoluted and complex. There
cannot and won't be a solution
that works for everybody.
Will there be like private solutions where like, oh, well, you know,
find these malicious guys and help you block them and you know,
s bomb your supply chain of web stuff.
Yeah, that there's already a market for that,
but this isn't going to solve it at scale and make it better for everybody and, and,
-- but life will just kind of lurch along like, you know, I mean,
-- we'll, we'll,
we'll survive.
Some people will get ripped off and like a few people will log into their exchange and
their waltz will be empty one day and that's gonna suck for them.
It's ironic, it's too big to fix.
Like,
so we'll just ignore it.
Too big to fix.
-- No, I like that. Too big to fix.
-- That's, that'll be the podcast episode.
I'm calling this one before we keep going. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you ever listening. Go to our security podcast.com. Hit up the show.
Not UZ Podos
says, podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.