Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 91 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers
and a special guest today.
Hello, everyone. My name is Felix
or you call me Kurt's son.
That, that's awesome. Not quite our typical guest, huh?
Yeah.
So, so tell me Kurt, why do we have Felix on the podcast today?
Because I suspect at this point most people are wondering, like,
has it gone so low that Kurt is chilling out his Children now for ratings?
So we are having Felix on the podcast today
because he is an expert on minecraft Security.
Minecraft Security. A
Yeah,
I've been playing Minecraft for a really long time basically. So I know it
and I've been watching Minecraft so I know really better.
Yeah, I play and watch Minecraft. So I'm good at security then.
Yeah.
And, and what, what is I, I guess what, why do we need to secure things in Minecraft?
I'm let, let's, let's pretend I don't know anything about Minecraft and why,
why do we need security there
because somebody might
get, steal your
stuff that might be felt you
like your first ever diamond you found.
So, maybe you could put, somehow make a laser gate that would,
if they walk through it they could
melt.
But it is a laser gate a thing.
Oh, you have trip wires, right? And you can hook them up to Redstone devices. Yeah.
Maybe you could put the Spencers that shoot our arrows and that shoot.
And that love it comes out of,
-- yeah, I love a dispenser and
-- maybe they would spawn zombies or Skeels.
-- That'd
-- be good.
That's, that's a lot to unpack I think.
And so
why don't we back up a little bit
and start at?
So Minecraft is a game if you don't know what Minecraft is, I guess, shame on you.
Now, explain to me how you play Felix.
Are you playing by yourself or are you playing with other people?
And that's where you need your protection, your security.
Uh He plays local only. We haven't played multiplayer yet.
Yeah,
you don't play local
-- multiplayer,
-- play local multiplayer, but
we have
learned not to grief each other,
right? Felix?
Because Felix, what happens when you grief people,
they don't wanna play.
So, so what is griefing?
It's feel
or other things? Like is it like shoving them into lava again and again and again,
like
when they respond, you do together
again,
-- they might never play ever
-- again or like locking
them in an iron room but they can't escape.
Yeah. Maybe a
bedrock room which you can't break bedrock only and create bunch
rock.
-- Nothing can
-- break and Felix. Have you ever grieved somebody?
Like,
maybe,
maybe.
But did, did this per, do you think this person deserved it?
Maybe
what? They killed me? What they give me?
Maybe they should, maybe I could tell him if,
but what they're ignoring me when I'm talking to them.
It's a good point. Maybe you could do it. So they know what, so they know what it,
what's like in case they don't
twist it,
-- they don't listen to you
-- like, you know,
if you're talking to the person griefing you and they don't listen,
then maybe you just grief them back.
-- Is that what you mean? Felix?
-- Yeah.
Wait, maybe you could put a water bath soak deep up.
It takes them a while to get back up and they build round.
Yeah.
So it's funny cause I remember when minecraft came on, I'm like, oh,
it's such a nice game with no violence.
Then a couple years later it had violent
and they made Minecraft hunger games. Yeah.
What, what is, what is Minecraft hunger games?
-- Is it like the
-- movies? No,
it's where you get weapons in our men try and kill people and
be the last man standing kind of remind me of game called for
fortnight and they made New Mo called 50 for 650
and to be clear, I don't let him play these games.
He just, he watches this on kids, youtube,
-- which I try to prevent but obviously not very well but
-- whatever man,
Fortnite is pretty cool.
Ok. So, so that's interesting. So
II I want to unpack this and see if we can get to
the root of, of security
because I, I feel like we have, we have a guest
who isn't adulterated by social norms
or, or expectations. Right. So,
so Felix, let me ask you this,
you have things in Minecraft, you have your items, you have your base.
How do, how do you protect this? I guess.
What is, what is the thing you think is the best way to keep your,
your Minecraft stuff safe?
Is it to hide it? Is it to build traps? Is it, I, I guess
I'm, I'm trying to understand
the motivation.
Maybe you could do that. Both. They could hide it under and they
-- may have to dig under and then get through a lot of traps,
-- Felix.
Which do you think is better the traps or
hiding your base and you're hiding your stuff?
I think,
I think it might be
i your base
because maybe it's somewhere where they never ever looked and they can't go
and they can't find that area because it's really far away and
it might take them a real, uh,
a couple of minutes to find and they might die
when they, and before they get there.
Interesting. So we have a vote for security through obscurity.
Right.
And
No, no, that
somewhat. Yeah.
Do you like traps or higher base?
I personally like a bit of both. So
I like to have sort of a hidden chest with all
my good stuff and then like a bait chest with,
you know, sort of normal stuff.
Yeah.
Wait,
maybe you could ride the chest with all your goodies in and
then have a chest with pretty common stuff that's common and,
and you find a lot of it in the game.
So, p
do you think
traps will work to keep you
out of your stuff or do you think they'll figure out
-- how the traps work
-- and figure out how the traps work?
Because a
lot of Minecraft player, a lot of Minecraft players are really good at Red Stone.
So they might figure out it and they might have
break the walls and then break the red stone.
So how your base might be better people
if you did both,
that would be really good because they could barely get in your base probably
unless they somehow knew Red Stone and,
and how they could in and
where your base was hidden.
Yeah,
that would be bad.
Ok. So, I, I feel like we've hit on something important here,
hiding your base
doesn't always work
and traps don't always work.
And
this is a good analogy. I'm gonna, I'm gonna step back from maybe speaking to Felix
because
we're going to go a little weird.
But, but this is interesting actually because
it parallels
the, the security universe we exist in today of nothing is 100%.
And so I guess, let me, let me go back to you, Felix and ask you this question is
if, if you can't hide your base forever
and you can't rely on traps to keep all the people out.
What, what does that mean? I guess. What is, what do we do next?
You've got your, you've hid in your base, you've got your traps.
Now, someone has made it past all of that. What do we do then?
Wait, here's a good solution.
Maybe you will have all your goods in your inventory and then you quit the game.
Then they could never ever steal your stuff. Unless if you,
yeah, they can never ever steal your stuff unless
if they take your,
what you were playing on and then
play what they were.
So, basically Felix, what you're saying is you take your good inventory,
like out of the game by
putting it on your personal character and then quitting the game.
So he's exploiting the game a bit.
Literally take your ball and go home.
Well, I know some games, you know, when you quit the game, your,
your corpse or your body is sitting there with all your stuff on it.
Right? And you still,
you have to guard it somehow.
Uh, maybe, I mean, that's, that's well within the, the rules of, of normalcy.
I, I don't know if I'd call that an exploit
except the people that grief, people, only people that got stole
that got robbed, the law would never ever play the game. I think.
Interesting. That's
probably a fair observation is
if people get burned too many times, they're, they're definitely not going back.
What amuses me though is Felix is basically discovered. Air gapping.
Well, no, it doesn't really work awesomely great.
But this is actually kind of a cheap, easy way of doing it.
Air
ging doesn't work
like a cold wallet.
Yeah, I mean, it, it is.
But, but I guess the downside is
you can't play
right? Which, which the intention here is to play the game
because that's where the enjoyment is meant to be.
Uh, so, so let me ask this,
if, if people grief you too much, you said you would stop playing?
Why would you stop playing if people grieve you too much?
Hm. Well, it would be really annoying though. What
it cost $109.99
to play it. What, what you spend all your money on that for worthless junk app?
That's a good question actually.
Who would ever do that? It
sounds like the security industry.
Ok. So, so
let's, let's do this. Let's, let's change the conversation a little bit. So,
I, I think we spent some time talking about Minecraft and
minecraft is a wonderful game and there's a lot of opportunity. But I think
we, we've hit on an interesting point of
you can't really stop a motivated attacker being the griefer here in this case,
right?
And so your options become very limited, which is not unlike the real world.
So, Felix, let me, let me ask you this.
-- Do you know what a password
-- is?
-- Don't
-- say your password?
I got, I got 20 bucks that says I'm going to be editing a password out of this podcast.
-- Remember, Felix? Your password has to be secret. Remember?
-- Yeah.
My password might be easy to figure out or it might not be if you just,
if you don't have one,
what if you're a hacker? The gay?
And?
Yeah.
Ok. So, so let me ask this, uh, your, your password is supposed to be secret, right?
And
you're not supposed to tell other people. But, but why should it be a secret?
Do you understand why it's a secret? Can you tell me that?
So the people can do whatever they want on your electronic?
-- That's a good answer.
-- Which is a really good plan.
Yeah.
Wait, if you're a hacker, maybe you could hack.
So your goods look like a worthless junk.
And then tell you, tell everybody that's robbing you and to you, it's your good,
that's actually a good way. But
they might ban you from the app. So I would not probably do that.
So, so tell me about hacking. What, what is hacking?
It's where you put in the code and you do whatever you want to and,
and you can't do that in the game. Well,
hacking basically is putting in the code and then you, whatever that code does,
it happens.
Knackers actually might go to jail like
John Doe who hacked the law of camps in roadblock on March
18th.
Oh, basically, I think he's in jail or on March 13.
That's strangely specific.
Ok.
-- So, so are hackers? Good guys or bad guys?
-- Bad guy?
-- Interesting. That's gonna,
-- he hacks people on March once for, I think 14th.
I don't know why he does that but he just does it.
Ok?
-- I, I have no idea what that means, but
-- so Roblox is like a Minecraft clone but heavily,
heavily into micro transactions.
Ok.
Roblox is a game where you call people names
and swear and they might not actually exit out.
That doesn't sound very nice.
Yeah, that's it. It, it has built in chat functionality.
You can't turn off or filters. So I, yeah,
what
kind of annoying.
Fair enough.
So
-- do a lot of people do grieving through the chat stuff in
-- Roblox.
Yes.
Think you have to be
in that 18 years old to play Roblox Minecraft.
I don't know, basically, probably
54. I don't know.
Somewhere between four and 18,
Felix. Why do you think somebody should have to be 18 to play Roblox?
Is it because of all the swearing and stuff
because of all
the swearing and griefing.
Ah,
so, hey, Felix, getting back to passwords,
do you know how to pick a good password?
You pick one that's long and that you pick a long password
and you pick some
numbers that people never ever use, I think
really long password in numbers nobody ever used.
So it take a really long time to figure out the pass.
S
so folks,
when you have somebody like an adult complaining about password requirements,
just playing this recording from a seven year old
Billy, pick a long password. And the one that has a lot of good,
like pick a really, really long password.
So it would, maybe the criminal would never ever find that.
Maybe the criminal just give up on finding out the password
or maybe it won't.
Who knows?
And, and how many, how many passwords can you remember? Do you think
I can remember my old one?
I can remember my mom's ipod password.
Wolfie's ipod password at my mom's house.
That's probably not. And my,
all
my ipod here
password and the computer password.
That's a lot of passwords I can remember. I wonder,
here's a question. I'm gonna ask how much passwords can you remember? And
that, you
know,
and also that you just,
maybe you'll figure out one,
maybe you,
I have about five main passwords
and one of them is to a password manager.
So the,
the problem is I can't remember all my passwords because there's hundreds of them.
That's a lot.
Yeah.
Do you think it's too many?
Maybe you,
I think you should have 10 or less passwords.
Ok. I'll buy that.
That seems like good advice.
10 or less passwords is not a lot to remember. And it's easy.
So, don't pick 1112,
don't pick a lot of pass if you have a lot of password to remember there,
maybe you will forget a lot. Maybe I have to do two at the same time.
Hey, Felix. Do you think we should use the computer to help us remember? Passwords?
Maybe.
Yeah. Maybe you could
use computer to help us remember your password. But
here's the point.
Maybe somebody would find out what your password is.
-- Um, and then get all the passwords.
-- Yes. So, I think it's not a good idea.
Ah, that's, that's a good risk assessment. Felix.
So, I think if you type out somebody's password, it won't show up because
it would be, if it showed up it would be, that would be really bad.
Felix. What you mean is when we type in a password, it should,
like, it should show stars and not the actual password.
Yeah.
And why should we do that?
So we can't get through. So, nothing happens to our beloved computer.
Hey, Felix, what do you think you should do
if you know a hacker knows your password,
then you should change it.
Ah,
that's the easiest thing.
Wait, or maybe you should just break the hacker's computer.
One of these will work, I guess.
Maybe you could just break all his electronics that says house on fire.
You're gonna be in the news, Kurt
Felix. That might be a bit extreme.
I take things serious sometimes.
So it would seem,
or you shouldn't do what I did.
And if life gives you lemons, give life back the lemons. That's
-- right.
-- Burn life's house down. Right?
Portal two. That line is from like,
-- all right, cool. I,
-- I think we're good,
-- Felix. That was awesome. That,
-- that was fun. All right. All right, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna, I'm gonna end it here. So I'm gonna say thank you, Kurt. Thank you, Felix.
Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source Security podcast.com to get
I don't think we have any show notes really?
Well, I'll put a couple of links to some of the things talked about in there.
But yeah, otherwise I guess
everyone have a, have a great day and curtain Felix. Uh talk to you guys later.
Thank you so much. Bye bye.
Goodbye.