Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefried
and my partner in trying to avoid privilege. Josh Pressers.
-- Do I try to avoid
-- privilege?
Remember back in the day where everybody wanted
pseudo access on the server so they could,
oh, that kind of privilege.
OK.
That was not the privilege I had in my brain when you said that.
Uh And then now I'm like, I don't want access to that system.
And unfortunately,
I have access to all the systems because I'm also like that means, hey, Kurt,
it's broken, you can go fix it.
So it's funny that came up because at
work,
we're switching a bunch of our security stuff over to
use the elastic sack because it does multiple things.
It's like just tool consolidation, right? And one thing we need is I need a machine
running the elastic agent
so I can like send it job
still like query remote logs and other weird kind of stuff like that, right?
And it just, it's a VM somewhere. I don't care where it is.
And I told her it people, I'm like, hey, I need this.
They were like, do you want the log in.
I'm like, no,
I sure don't like you install this agent and everything is fine after that.
-- This machine is not my problem. I do not want to log into it ever.
-- I
know, I don't want to have to patch it.
-- I don't have to configure it. I don't have to.
-- Exactly. Right. It's not my problem.
And it is funny you say so we're going to talk about, well,
we always pretend like it's a secret we're gonna talk
about even though like the freaking show title is,
is based in pseudo and
insisting this was funny this came up.
Uh, so Conan o'brien has a podcast which also, by the way,
if anyone listening hasn't watched Conan o'brien on hot ones, you have to go.
It's, it's, it's art, it's absolutely art. Anyway.
He, he, at the beginning of his podcast they always do like little bits about, oh,
who's on and stuff.
And one day Conan's like,
like everyone knows it's in the fing title.
It's like, yep, it sure is. But, but anyway,
anyway, yeah, I,
I do remember back in the old days when we
logged into computers and did things because we had like,
four computers
and,
yeah, having Pseudo access was a big deal. That was like, oh, I'm special.
-- I, I can do Pseudo thing. Well,
-- or that even just thought you had a login.
Uh Yeah,
that's true
because I sure as heck wasn't letting people have logins
on the mail server unless they really needed it.
I remember when I worked at a little ISP, everyone got a,
we had a shell server so people could
fell in.
And it was always funny because we look at the logs and there
were so many people who would try running pseudo all the time.
It's like,
ah, ha ha
-- you knew.
-- Well, part of it is also muscle memory.
Like I literally caught myself, I ssh into some, one of my local V MS or machines.
And I literally just typed in like
pseudo space su space dash out of muscle memory because
I was like going to do something administrative on it.
And I'm like, no, wait, no, I don't need to do that.
This is stuff like people trying to change the root password.
These were obviously people reading like a how to help
guy or something.
They were, they were not,
we'll say accidental pseudo executions.
And then of course, we'd send them an email and be like, if you do it again,
we're canceling your shell access.
And they were usually like, oh, I'm sorry about that. It wasn't me like, ok, sure.
Anyway,
-- so your accounts been compromised, we should turn
-- it
-- off.
-- Don't do it again.
I don't care what your excuse is.
-- But anyway, ok,
-- so, well, let's just do a brief history of pseudo. Why?
Here's a good question. Why does PSEUDO exist
or what is pseudo for start.
That's true. There's probably people unfamiliar with this whole universe.
There might be people who haven't been living in a command line for 25 years.
-- I hope there are.
-- So back in the early days, you had the SU command, right?
Which is switch user, I believe it stands for, but
just basically
SU dash
and type in the root password and then your root and you could ruin everything.
-- And
-- so the trick with SU was is you could become another user
but you had to know their password.
And so it was, for example, like when you're troubleshooting some users thing,
you'd su
Bob
get Bob's password on the phone because back in those days, that's how we did this.
And then you know, you'd poke around Bob's account and be like,
oh you like messed up your profile or you
changed the setting in your mail? Oh
This is back when people logged into a shell server to read their email.
So we're talking like the the dark stone ages of computing.
It was for sure. And, and I mean,
the problem being so
another aspect of this is like back in those days, if you were route,
you could do anything you wanted. There were no se Linux policies
capabilities. There was like root was
the super user like that was it, you could do anything.
So obviously you didn't want to give everyone like
unfettered root access because that would be very bad.
And an example of this
when I worked at the ISP, we had like support people, which is where I started out in,
in the way back in the day answering phones and,
and people would come into the office to sign up for the internet, which is weird,
whatever.
-- But anyway,
-- and pay by check
that
yes, that happened a lot.
I don't know if we could even take credit cards at the beginning.
It was like a chunk machine if we did. I'm sure.
But anyway, so what would happen
is we needed support people to be able to create new accounts,
right? And so we need a way for these people. And this is also by the way,
the shell server
was the like the main identity system.
So
if you were going to log in to the ISP,
you needed an account on the shell server with a
password that was probably MD five way back then.
-- It was probably
-- crypt. I don't know. II I think it was MD five.
I think we're in the MD five era when I was doing this.
But anyway,
so obviously we want to support people to be able
to run a command to create a new user for.
And of course,
we asked them what their password was and we'd write it down
on a sheet of paper and then they would type it in.
But
that is something we had to do.
And obviously we don't want all of the support people to have unfettered root
because people like me, for example,
would have definitely broken something if I had that.
So we could type pseudo like, I don't know,
create user dot pl because it was a pearl script, I'm sure.
And, and do his thing, right? And that was the idea.
And so OK,
well, and this is a normal one.
Most unixes have had set U ID for a very long time.
And set U ID allows you to have a file, let's say,
for the sake of argument owned by root or owned by Bob or owned by Kurt.
And you can set U ID or set group idea
and thus
when it executes, it will execute us that user.
And why do we not use that? And instead use something like pseudo.
And the answer is simple because it's terrible
and it's prone to error.
-- It's hard to track and fun fact, you can't do with shell scripts.
-- You
can,
-- you can't set your ID or set group id, shell scripts.
-- Not anymore.
You used to be able to,
you can't anymore.
Bash doesn't let you do that because Bash will yell at
you if you try to execute like shell scripts as root
in
a UD
insecure that we actually banned it.
That's do you know how bad something has to be for the people? No,
-- that's true.
-- How bad it has to be from a security point of view.
-- For it to actually get disabled by default.
-- There's more to the story than just this.
So the thing is pseudo compared to just running a set U ID application,
it cleans up the environment,
it takes care of like some weird tt Y type stuff and makes sure you're,
you're only executing certain things like it does a bunch of
weird operations because the issue being if you just have a set
id binary, let's say that creates users, you can do things like, you know,
change where it's looking for configuration files.
You can depending upon the system,
you can set like the LD library path and that doesn't work any,
it shouldn't work anymore.
But,
but, and,
and so obviously a tool like pseudo is designed to clean up some
of the mess before and after executing a set U ID application essentially,
right?
But that doesn't mean it does a perfect job. There's like tens, well,
more than tens of pseudo vulnerabilities every year
and they range everything from like stupid little
denial of service type things to full on en route now because pseudo has a bug
and, and the attack surface of pseudo is very large.
It is grown
from a simple tool into a bit of a behemoth.
Well,
I remember when the the configuration file was essentially who gets to run pseudo.
And now it's quite a lot more
-- complicated
-- because you can set environment variables.
You can talk about like loading libraries. It does like all this
stuff. It, it's, I mean, it's almost impressive in a way.
But the, the problem with it and the reason
that system D is, is kind of creating their, they're not pseudo, run zero,
which we'll talk about momentarily
is fundamentally pseudo has to cross the boundary from a
regular user to the set user route in this instance.
And anyone who's ever written a
binary that's supposed to change the user id correctly.
-- It is very difficult to do and it is fraught with errors.
-- I'm gonna say it's basically
-- impossible. It's
-- not impossible. It's just really
hard.
It's, I would say it's basically impossible for anything of complexity,
which by definition is probably what you're doing and needing something to
do something as root or whatever now
is because it's complicated.
-- If it was simple, you probably wouldn't even need to do this.
-- Yeah. OK. Sure. Why not?
I mean,
this is there have been lots of vulnerabilities related to things like
this in the past where the issue being when you start changing
like from,
from a user to root or route to a user or whatever you're trying to do if there are
strains imposed on that us.
Like one of my favorite examples is there was a bug some years ago and on Linux,
you tried to switch from root to another user
and this was, I forget what the primary app that even found this was anymore.
It's been so long.
But anyway, if that user was out of some sort of resource,
be it like file descriptors or memory or whatever processes,
and it's not hard to fill up the number of processes you're allowed or
fill up your file descriptors or whatever the set U ID would just fail.
So you, the app, the application was still running his route.
So if you didn't like, check all of these error conditions first, you were still root
and now it's like a, I'm root. Everyone. Look at me
and because that, that transition back and forth is really hard to get right.
And I think that is like the primary thing
from reading this like very long toot thread thing. Leonard put on, on Mastodon.
That seems to be the killer app here. And I, I will agree with that.
Well, and there's a lot of, I hate to use the word simple,
but there's a lot of air quotes, simple
things,
but like
software starting up has to do that sort of a little bit privileged because
you don't want the facility that it's using to be open to everybody.
But conversely, you don't want the application to run with a super high privilege.
But for example, oh, perfect example,
you want
Apache to be able to log and depending on how you're doing, logging,
maybe you're logging into the file system so you can just use file permissions,
not a big deal,
but, well, you also want maybe some enhanced logging through, you know,
system D or whatever
and you don't necessarily want Apache to have to run with a extra privilege.
So on start up having that ability to kind
of give it that little extra bit of privilege momentarily
for it to do something that was very common. Right?
That's, that's absolutely what you want. Oh, ok.
You know, even better example, simpler example, when Apache starts,
you want it to be able to read its key files
and when it restarts, you want it to be able to read its key files into memory.
But beyond that,
it actually shouldn't be reading them.
Well,
and not only that you want an application like Apache
to remove as many privileges is possible while it's running
because it's gonna get attacked and compromised.
-- OK.
-- So let's talk about system D now.
So system D which has become an insane behemoth of its own. Right?
Well, it has to because it, it has to,
it has no, it has to do everything. It's like Excel where
-- it does what I need.
-- But I'm not getting into this argument.
It does a lot, maybe too much anyway.
So
there is an idea in it.
It's, I don't know if it's out now, it'll probably be out when this podcast comes out.
But the, in the new version of system D version 256 it is going to have an application
run
zero.
And the idea behind run zero is it's not,
it doesn't work like pseudo where you run a command,
it does a transition in privilege to
route and then maybe transitions to
something else depending upon what's happening.
This is this functionality they're using for run zero.
It already exists in system D, it's called system D run.
And
the idea being
that
instead of transitioning from like a normal user
to root and then maybe somewhere else,
whatever, who knows,
you run this, run zero command
and it basically tells system D I want you to
for
a process as root
and do this stuff.
Which kind of makes sense. There's no like transition.
And then what happens is there's plumbing between the process running,
it sets up a pseudo TT Y it sounds like and,
and just pipes everything to your real TT Y and then things happen as root.
So like your, the, the, the screen in front of you,
the process you're inside of it has no elevated privileges.
It's all happening magically behind system D the,
with the idea being you can't like it.
Let's say there is a bug
and somehow that remote process I could magically become root.
You don't, you wouldn't be able to keep that in theory.
I mean, I'm sure there's gonna be lots of edge cases and bugs.
It makes it a lot more hard in the sense of if I find a
bug in the software, I have to hand it a piece of work
that triggers that bug versus being able to interact with it.
And then also, hopefully, once it's done running, it's done running, which is not
with the traditional process,
right? The other thing is so OK. And, and here's a and
this just to knock this out of the way, why don't we use Se Linux
to give the thing the permission, it needs to do the thing.
-- Se Linux doesn't grant permissions. Se Linux takes them away.
-- Exactly.
And also it's just too damn complicated
-- and it may or may not be available on the system you're dealing with
-- it would, I don't
know enough about Se Linux
to say
you'd have to switch the contact.
-- It would be very complicated anyway, I'm not going to think about this.
-- Exactly. So
honestly, at this point system D is everywhere.
Se Linux is pretty much everywhere too.
But to be brutally honest,
asking people to like write their applications
to use the system D functionality is a
lot more likely to happen and succeed than asking people to do Se Linux policy.
You in theory,
you shouldn't have to change anything about your
application to use something like run zero.
It should just theoretically work and do the right thing.
Well, no, but don't you,
you'd have to change your application to take advantage of it, right?
Like it's not gonna
like when Apache tries to read its key, it's not going to use run zero
-- magically, but
-- that's not its use case either.
This is for users trying to run pseudo this isn't for
applications starting up with elevated privileges and then dropping them.
Oh I thought it was more also aimed at the applications, not just the users, I mean,
the se uh system D already does that basically where it can do some weird stuff,
but this is strictly user interaction
is what I'm talking about.
And then the other thing they're doing that
is freaking brilliant that I don't know why.
And no one has done this before. Is it changes your terminal color to red
while you are running as an elevated user?
-- I love
-- that. I'm well, number one red, green color blindness is a thing,
but also depending on what your terminal settings are, colors may not display.
So, but yes, it's a cute thing to have.
Personally
see what's interesting to me.
I'm always kind of,
there's this sort of thing in Japanese culture where here's a tool,
this tool is very sharp, don't hurt yourself with it.
And you're expected to master the tool and not hurt yourself with it.
But there's also a very good argument to be made for something like the um the s
stop, you know that thing where it detects uh moisture in what you're cutting
and fingers are moist like hot dogs.
And then it basically kicks an aluminum block into the saw blade to stop it
so that you don't have to throw your fingers off.
The downside being is you can't cut pressure treated lumber and a
bunch of like wet wood and stuff without destroying your saw blades
because it'll fall trigger.
But,
but when you look at the numbers of how
much money we spend on health care for people and
table saws,
it would actually be cheaper to just buy everybody.
-- One of these new fancy table saws
-- probably look, here's, here's my take on that.
You can make the argument that you should be
some trained professional who is we're gonna make mistakes,
but we do, we're people.
Well, what I was gonna get to is actually, as I was going to say,
changing the color is not enough, you need to like have it like
a
banner but a big banner that's flashing
-- while the command is running. Like
-- I'm fine with that too.
Like I would certainly not complain if there is a giant flashing banner.
And there's also, here's something I love is
when you make administrative sort of,
I don't want to say abuses because it's not an abuse.
If you make that kind of administrative work
annoying,
there's more of an incentive to fix it.
-- I
-- mean,
-- I maybe
-- sure and to maybe actually architect the things so
that does it properly or to change your workflow or something.
-- Ok.
-- No, no, I think you just made the point, right?
Is generally speaking,
I think most systems now are running in a manner
that we're not having to just like I remember becoming
and just being rude all day to do work
because it was easier than running pseudo 700,000 times,
right?
100%. I would just pseudo su space dash at the beginning of the day
and like be careful.
I think it is more common for systems to be
architected in a way that you have tools like,
you know, Sheffer puppet or answerable or you're using Kubernetes or whatever
and you're not living as root.
I think when you need to become root now,
it is an uncommon event
and when you're not doing something all the time,
your propensity for failure, I think goes up substantially.
And so I think that's what makes something
like putting big warnings and flashing lights and,
and sort of things that I think is what is really cool about such a feature.
Because the other thing I think when I think
of this is that the systems gotten more reliable,
they just, they, they're better behaved.
They don't need as much like you're not,
you're not running a route to edit your X config file by hand anymore.
Thank goodness
that is stuff I used to have to do all the time,
the good old days.
And then that's one reason I ran Sousa for
a year because Sousa had the X 86 config thing
that just worked and it was
-- magic.
-- I know they, they did a really nice job. Ok.
Now, here's the other side of this coin though. Right.
It's easy to gush over this new tool that
we've never run that we just read about online.
And it sounds like a neat idea. And, yeah, pseudo has its own problems.
There is, I think a couple of pieces of this.
Number one, there is an effort to rewrite pseudo in rust,
but it amuses me because there are vulnerabilities against
it
even though it's rust, which rust fixes memory problems,
it doesn't fix logic problems.
And most of these pseudo bugs are logic errors now, right?
Most of them are not memory problems now. System D is a behemoth
the attack surfaces. System D is gigantic.
I know they're going to compartmentalize this is a whole bunch and all that.
But the fact remains that system D is gigantic. It is bigger than
pseudo has plenty of problems and it has
way more attack surface than it probably should.
-- But I have a suspicion system D has an even larger attack surface. Yeah.
-- Absolutely.
And it does a lot more like it's, it's, well, it's running in the background from
it's basically in it now,
right? Like it's
Yeah,
and, and look le
or hated system D is everywhere. And so we have to deal with it.
Well, and what's interesting to me too is like we talk for example,
but you just mentioned stuff like chef and
Ants, Bull and puppet
and a lot of people don't even know what that is, let alone use it.
Because for example, I have a true scale NAS
Box at home. I'm not going to set up automation to manage it.
I'm just gonna go to the web interface once in a while and click update
and same with the three V MS running on it, like the three V MS running on it.
I'm not going to set up automation.
They're just a bunch of long term support V MS running,
you know, my torrent client,
something to remember is there's a lot of sort of small and medium business or kind
-- of one offs that are not part of a big healthy managed fleet
-- for sure,
for sure.
I mean, I have a bunch of V MS running in my basement that about once a month, I'm like,
I should make answerable work with these and then I start doing and I'm like, hey,
I'm too lazy, I'll just ssh in and update them and
-- then I run pseudo or
-- sue like in cloud terms.
I do this all the time where I back up a lot of our
cloud services and some of them are fully automated because it was really easy.
Like our cloud clerk,
I just have a script that
hits the API gets all the domain names,
then gets all like just grinds through and gets
everything took like an hour to write the script.
So worth it.
I have other systems where
to automate it would take 10 or 20 hours of learning how to use the
API and getting it to work and then I'd still have to monitor it.
So I might as well just do it manually once every two weeks for five minutes.
And so that's the other thing is to keep in mind is,
is asking people to do things air quotes
correctly and automate it and make it robust.
There's that famous X
uh what is it XK,
I'm spacing out XK CD
chart.
You know where it shows like if you do this like 10
times a day and you say five minutes by automating it,
you, you can spend this much time automating it, it breaks even or whatever, right?
And a lot of people forget about, but a lot of this stuff is actually quite shock.
Like it's easy to automate in the sense of it'll probably run
most of the time
but to actually automate something such that it is like five or six nines reliable
for sure is expensive.
Yeah. And sometimes it's easier just to log in and run pseudo
-- app to update or app, get update.
-- I have an amusing anecdote exactly about this. So I
query the ecosystems data now daily,
which I was doing a lot of work by hand and it was running
every now and again and it would take a long time
and the scripts would fail constantly.
And it took me, I bet more than 10 hours to, like,
I basically just rewrote everything because it was, it wasn't worth trying to save.
Yeah, that's,
that's something I've noticed.
If you get an automation solution that's like 80 or 90% of the way there,
it's actually usually faster just to rebuild it from scratch than to try and fix it.
Yeah. And I made it a little more, we'll say
it looks like a real programmer wrote it now as opposed to what it used to be.
But anyway, the point is like, take making it will say I'll, I'll say 90% robust.
There's still some issues I run into now and again.
But like it was an enormous amount of work and
it's definitely one of those situations where it's like,
OK, this is failing every other day.
It's taking up, you know,
10 plus minutes of my time and I had to clean up a mess because I usually
ended up with a process that I didn't die because one of the threads got stuck.
And so I had all this stuff eating up all my memory
and I actually figured it all out when I was like,
where did all my ra m go?
Like
this machine's out of memory and it shouldn't be.
It's like, oh, I have 30 processes running in the background each eating, you know,
20% of the memory that's what happened here.
And so anyway, you get the idea though. Right.
It is easy to talk about automation and is magic and easy. But it's not, it's hard.
-- I get it.
-- Well, and it's funny because
this is the, the, the flip coin of, of security where
in security you have to write it so it's secure but you don't get to
find out what the attacker does until they do it and then they often do something new.
Now there's another piece of this and this is kind of where I want to end.
I want to land this plane on this last idea.
So
we have known for a long time what the drawbacks and difficulties pseudo has
it.
It's just it, it's in the security universe like we get it, it,
cleaning up environment variables, cleaning up library paths,
keeping track of this kind of stuff.
What is going on? Maybe we want to let certain environment variables through.
How do we configure those? It's a lot of,
it's a pain in the butt now.
It is also likely that we can never fix pseudo
because of the just legacy it carries with it.
Well, it has to maintain compa like you can't break pseudo.
-- If you break pseudo,
-- it doesn't have to,
they just don't want to, I want to make that clear.
This comes up all the time where it's like, oh,
we can't break backwards compatibility,
you can do whatever you want, you decided not to break backwards compatibility.
But that now creates future risk based on past decisions.
The challenge though is this is, I always kind of come back the Hippocratic Oath of,
there's a lot of systems running pseudo that do kind of get updates.
But if you break pseudo for them, they won't get pseudo updates anymore.
Maybe, I mean, that's a plausible argument
and, and part of me is kind of like, well,
maybe too bad in those companies need to stump up some money
to manage and maintain a fork of pseudo that they like.
-- But we all know that they're not going to,
-- here's the thing.
System D is an opportunity to just change the way we think about
and do all of this stuff,
right? I think that Greenfield attitude
can be valuable at certain times. Not always.
I'm not saying we should rewrite everything all the time.
And this is,
I think an example of where like pseudo Rust will probably not catch on
because it's trying to mimic an already flawed system versus a new paradigm.
That means we can make new rules.
Well, the challenge always is how do you make something that is
essentially identical in operation and functionality to the existing thing and
yet somehow better enough that people want to switch to it.
You can't,
you have to create a new thing.
The other advantage system D has is it's basically been shoved on all our throats.
So we don't have a decision like we're going to get this, whether we want it or not.
And I love, like, part of me wants to make somebody go get like an old,
an old enough version of Linux that has in it scripts and like, make them do something
no difficult. And it's like, see this is why system D exists.
System five and knit was terrible.
Well, like, I hate the binary logging in system D in the queering,
but it's so much like trying to get your in it scripts to log
properly. Like, no, they failed. They stopped logging.
That's what I and I can't figure it out because the in it script itself failed.
And now no one knows why,
you know
-- magic.
-- I got like, I literally would sit there rebooting the computer watching it
-- and like putting print statements in my in its to like, see,
-- that's right.
-- This is not the world you want to live in people.
-- It is.
That's one of the things that amuses me is
it is very easy for some of us to look back at the past and be like, oh,
it was so much easier back then
and certain things were easier,
but most things were terrible.
Well, but it was easier in the sense of like, oh, I just make a fire,
-- which was
-- a shell script.
But no, like microwaves are way better than fire.
-- I
-- mean,
-- it depends what we're making for
-- purposes of
-- safety and getting your food
-- hot heating water.
Well, I, my electric kettle is the best, but that's another story
anyway.
So I think,
I think what's most interesting to me is there's a
vocal minority that cares very much about this stuff.
But I feel like the vast majority of people really and by vast majority of people,
I don't even mean the vast majority of like regular people.
I mean, the vast majority of like
sins
really don't care as long as it kind of works
and isn't too much of a steep learning curve.
They'll use it just like they switch to system D
not by choice.
Now,
here's the other piece of this that Leonard talks about in his thread is he
wants a world with no set U ID applications on a system ever again.
Yeah, I'm cool with that. I'm, I'm fine with that. I mean, I remember
when I was at elastic, there was some bug in like pseudo
and we took it off all of our, our like container images running in the cloud
and then we were like, wait a minute, what about all this other set U ID stuff?
Do we need any of that? We looked at it and we're like,
no, we don't.
Let's let's get rid of them as long as we're in
-- here
-- back in 98 in the Linux Administrative Security guide.
That's one of the things I talked about was auditing your system for set U ID binaries
and removing them and like mounting temp with no set U ID.
And you know, all these others like mounting slash home with no set U ID.
-- So here's
-- the thing without a system to
execute things in an elevated manner.
What do you, I guess you could ssh to local host and log in his root.
But that creates other problems, I think.
Well,
there were a lot of set U ID binaries people could live without because there was,
there used to be a lot of set U ID binaries,
lots
of weird stuff.
But most people, like when I, when I started auditing for it, I was like,
what is this stuff like?
I don't even know but it comes installed by default.
You know what my favorite that always just like annoyed me
to death was I don't know if they still do it,
but
Debian used to install other games with the set G ID for games so it
could write like high score files and stuff and it like it was just,
it graded on my mind.
-- Like there's got to be a better way to do this
-- shared high score files.
-- Perfect example.
-- Yep. Yep. I remember.
Well, I suppose you don't want people to edit them by hand. So anyway.
-- Well, no, because then they cheat and get the high score.
-- Obviously,
you know what I love is just like the dumb stuff where it's
like what I want to change the system time and I get that,
that's a sensitive thing, potentially,
but it's my workstation and I have physical control of it.
So why are you asking me for my root password?
Like even Lenis Torvalds, you know, fetched about this,
like 10 or 20 years ago where, remember he was like,
trying to set the time on his kid's computer and he's like,
why do I need the root password to reset the clock?
And I just, I feel like one thing I always wanted was like,
I want like a workstation mode where it's like, just
let's like,
like if I'm locally logged in and I'm the user just
let me do whatever the heck I want because let's stop pretending
they work pretty well like that.
Now, I think if you use a modern Linux distribution,
it's nothing like it used to be in the old days.
It's
not
as bad. There's some issues.
But I would say for the most part, it's pretty good because I run,
I run Linux quite a bit and I've not,
I can't think of very many instances where I've had to do something as root.
The, the worst it usually gets is it will be like,
please type in your password to do this thing
you're trying to do.
-- Yeah. No,
-- a lot of that's gone.
But it's still,
I think part of the problem is we keep trying to apply the
same security model to everything from workstations to light bulbs to servers.
We do that often. Yes.
I mean, this goes back to like Greg Khs,
comment about like Linux kernel vulnerabilities.
You know, the thing runs on spaceships and milking machines. It's not,
it's very different paradigms that we're dealing with here.
So.
All right, I'm, I'm honestly, I'm kind of excited to give this one a go.
I'll probably run, run zero a bunch of times, mess around with it.
Enjoy my blinky red background
and then I'll hopefully never have to run it again.
That's my dream.
I,
I would be so ok with not constantly needing to
elevate privilege just to get my daily job done.
I have not needed that in a long time.
I think the biggest thing I do right now is II, I log into my Flex machine to run Pseudo
app
to get
update and APT get
dis
upgrade.
And that's like that's probably one of the few times I run pseudo. So I'm ok with that.
I'll change it to run zero at some point. We'll see.
-- Anyway, I'll give you the final word on this one.
-- Man.
-- I just change is scary, but sometimes it's good. Uh
-- It's
-- usually
-- good but it is scary.
I agree. I agree. I'm gonna call it then. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you very much for listening. Go to for social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show, not, it's Uy
Pound
Dos
podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon.
Thank you, Kurt. Have a marvelous. Rest of your day. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.