Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in connecting the dots.
-- Josh Pressers
-- connecting the dots.
I suppose we're kind of doing that today.
I always remember those when, when the activity books, when we were kids,
they had those dot connecting things.
And
if you just like obviously being the the rigid engineering mind, I am
the shortest distance between two points is a line.
So I of course,
always drew the straight line whereas you obviously had to give some curve and
form to them to actually look like the thing you were trying to do.
So anyway.
-- Well,
-- so, so there's a really fascinating article in wired about stolen bicycles
and how
like there's a lot of stolen bicycles to the point where like
even in my local police force is saying use bike index.org,
like straight up there
advice on bicycle theft is register your bike with bike
index.org
and like that's it, there's no part to it.
It's like trying to like good luck getting it, not stolen.
-- Like, I mean,
-- you're never going to get it back.
Well, no, actually quite a few people do get their bikes back.
Well, not quite a few, some people get their bikes back now because, you know,
the police, well be because the police, you know, for example,
when they're pulling people over who are on bicycles,
-- but maybe they don't own and then they check the index number and
-- voila,
the police check it
or when they recover stolen property. Right.
Like they, you know, they're like, find a garage with, you know,
whatever a shed with a bunch of bicycles in it.
Like that crazy story where that guy,
they found something like several million dollars and stolen,
used tools in a storage locker.
Yeah, that, over like a decade this person was just stealing tools and
-- doing nothing with them apparently. Yeah,
-- that was weird. Right.
Anyways, but back to this.
So,
so somebody actually decided to do
some investigation and basically long story short
there's like
a bike ring theft being run by a guy in Mexico who gets bikes stolen in the US, shipped
all over the place
and then, you know, sold because I guess bikes,
high end bikes kind of keep their resale value pretty good.
You know, like a lot of things when you steal them and try to pawn them, you're gonna,
you're gonna get pennies on the dollar.
-- I
-- mean, you're still getting like,
50 cents on the dollar or less when you read the article.
Yeah.
But still that's a lot more than five cents on the dollar, like, for a power tool.
I mean, that's fair. But, and also
there's a lot,
a lot of people who would be happy to buy a $5000 bicycle at
half price and not carefully check the serial number that it's stolen or not.
Well, in bikes are weird like that. Like, I have a bike.
It's, it's not super awesome, but I, I ride it a lot, like 1000 miles a year,
give or take and
it is strained.
Like every now and then I will look at you the used bike market and it varies widely.
Like sometimes there's bikes that are selling for a couple 100 bucks.
It's like, that should definitely be way more than that.
And there's other times it's like
that's the new
price. Why would anyone buy your used bike for the same price? It's very strange.
-- It's a weird market.
-- Well, same thing with the PC market, right?
L TT has done this where they go through some
of the online PC sales and it's kind of like,
you know,
it's like twice what it would cost just to buy the parts and build it yourself.
-- Like,
-- what the hell? That's fair. That's fair. Ok. Anyway,
but back to this. So
I know what was most interesting to me is that
I don't want to say this is the perfect crime, but it's very close,
I think in some ways because it's like the Superman crime, you know, we we,
we steal a fraction of a penny from every transaction and nobody notices.
And that's the thing with bike theft. Like
when you go to report a bike theft, you know, it's like the big Lebowski.
It's like, oh, yeah.
You know, we'll have detectives working on that triple shifts,
like around the clock.
No, like,
has a bike theft ever been properly investigated?
Well, in this case, it was because they actually,
once the guy brought the evidence to the cops, it was kind of,
I think it's one of those cases where it's so shameful that they kind of have
to investigate because the next step is going to the news and then of course,
the news is going to be like, you know,
so and so found a bike theft.
The cops don't care,
they don't.
Ok. But this, I think ties in with some other more security oriented topics
where
it feels like everyone is getting breached right now,
which I think is the opposite of the bike story
because they are. Well, no, no, it's not just that they are.
It's that this is, this is, this is the,
I think the other side of the coin to the
bike theft story where like there's always been bike thefts.
It's always been,
we'll say
small scale theft
that you go to the police and they just don't care.
It's like everyone has always been breached, but now they have to talk about it.
Thanks. To the SEC and other federal rules.
Actually, one quick point, it's not that the cops don't care so much.
But for example, one time my license plate got spray painted,
right.
And I'm like, why would they spray paint my license plate?
And then my neighbor was complaining that they did as well.
And I'm like, hey, I'm glad they didn't spray paint my car.
They just spray painted the license plate. Why?
That was literally my question.
So I took a picture, went to the cop shop because it's close to where I used to live,
to report it.
Right.
And it's funny because the cops like he's like, you want to report this, I'm like,
yeah, I just want to report this like I know you're not gonna do anything.
He's like, oh, ok. And he gets the form and hands it to me,
right?
And because I'm like, yeah, if I don't report it,
you guys don't know about it and like, nothing's gonna happen.
Like there, there's no possibility of change.
But at least, you know, because if 1000 if this happens once in a while, yeah,
whatever, who cares?
But if it's happening consistently, the cops will be like, yeah,
maybe we'll have a patrol drive through your alley way once in a while or something.
Funding of police work is driven by data.
So if they don't have any data showing any crime, they're gonna be like, cool.
Like, why would we send officers over there.
We have enough, like, we have so much real crime to deal with
and that's kind of the nature of security work too.
It's like, like I have a bunch of backup projects to do at the CS A, like,
I've backed up our core stuff,
but there's a bunch of stuff we should really back up better and more regularly.
But, like,
and, you know, it hasn't caught fire, it's pretty reliable.
I've got all this other,
honestly, more high value work to do.
So I'm going to go do that.
You know what I mean? Like,
and I think that's a big part of this is this.
I, I love the idea of this,
not just mandatory reporting but mandatory reporting
to a centralized source that then collates
it and sees patterns because we've had this happen in Canada with car fires,
car fires are not, like, really reported. And so
sure there was the Mercedes.
Was it Mercedes smart cars or it was, I think it was some brand of Mercedes was like,
just catching fire.
And at first they're like, oh, yeah, that's fine. It's your fault, whatever.
But then it turns out like 40 or 50 of these cars have caught fire and they're like,
-- oh, yeah, I guess we have to do a recall.
-- Yep.
-- I remember that you told me about that a while back.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
And this is, I think the difference is like the train derailments.
In the US, remember, train derailments were so hot last year
and it turns out of all people,
NASA runs the train derailment safety reporting program
that all the train companies promised to join
and didn't.
Well, yeah, I mean, they're never going to unless you make them.
I mean, that's the other part of stories like this, right? Is that
the, the, like, like voluntary reporting and things like that
-- is, it doesn't happen
-- well or they report it but it's like, oh yeah,
we had a minor train
related incident
and you know what they mean is like there's like
400 rail cars on fire and like toxic smoke and like
a small town like that time, a small town burnt down in Quebec, you know,
like because a train derailed
and that's the thing like so
there I think there not only has to be
reporting but sort of structured
reporting like, like
how many people died, how many people were injured, how
they injured?
Somebody has to come up with the standard kind of
like the health reporting standard like bitten by turtle,
bitten by turtle second incident apparently is a thing.
-- Yeah,
-- people laugh at that. So for anyone who doesn't know
in the, I don't, I,
I imagine this is an international standard but there's
all these codes that when you're doing health care,
you have to type in like what,
what happened to the person and
there's like ridiculous things like you know,
bitten by whale or something like that.
And there's an enormous number of possible things you can
claim had happened to a person which you make fun of it because it is funny.
But at the same time, you need this kind of data.
Yeah, but somebody put that code in there because it happened enough times
that they went, we need to actually have a structured code for this.
Uh fun fact, the US uses I CD nine
and Canada uses I CD 10.
So you're just a version behind us, which is interesting.
Well,
we have more centralized healthcare so it's probably easier to deploy updates.
-- Right.
-- That's probably true.
That's probably true and whatever,
it's, it's interesting. Ok. Now
we hear about the bike story,
we hear about everyone getting hacked which they are and I'm not,
we're not going to recount all of them because it's,
you know, like Ticketmaster and Snowflake and A MD and everyone's on the list.
You know, it's bananas.
Technically, I think snowflakes still denying it a bit.
-- Even though it's pretty clearly them,
-- they're busy trying to blame someone else.
I think
it's,
it may be someone else's fault. We don't know it doesn't matter.
And in fairness if it is credential stuffing,
ok? But they really should have forced two fa or M fa and that's another show.
But we gotta, I think we gotta start talking about what are basic table steaks
and like things like two fa and M fa and single sign on are no longer a nice to have.
They are
-- like tying your shoelaces in the morning.
-- Ok.
We will talk about this soon because here's my comment about that.
It is easy to say that multi factor authentication is a table
stake and it's definitely something that absolutely everyone should be doing,
but it's still too hard to do.
-- Like,
-- yes, that's the problem. And HTTP S used to be too hard to do and we fixed it.
It was yes,
between Cloud
and Lutz and Crypt. It worked. Now.
That's right.
I'm not saying m fa can't be done.
-- I'm just saying some investment is needed to make it more possible
-- tangentially.
There was a recent past Keys event this week and it was
fascinating because it was a security event from the past key five
to alliance blah, blah, blah.
And it was pretty much everything was focused on usability.
It has to be, yeah, I know. Right.
But to me there's actually that hope now of like usability first and then hopefully
we can get some security out of it versus the old style of like security,
security, security
f the users. And of course they don't want to do it. So we don't get the security. But
back to this, the other fascinating thing is,
is like without that centralized reporting, you know, it's just kind of like, yeah,
I hear a bunch of bikes are getting stolen but is it really that bad?
Is it 5 55,000?
Like, those are very different numbers.
Like, if, if the city of Edmonton had five bike thefts a year,
I mean, wow, that would be awesome.
You know, for a million people in the metro area,
I'm assuming it's more than five.
But is it like 555,000? I have no idea of even like what logarithmic scale to use
little in the number.
Well, and this is the same thing with breaches,
right?
And, and this is funny because
the, the cybersecurity insurance industry
-- is starting to tease this kind of stuff out
-- because they don't want to pay out.
-- They're getting tired of it.
-- Exactly.
And so they're like, the insurance industry is notorious for having
tons of data for anything they're doing.
And obviously they're going to be able to recognize and what I love though too,
like the insurance industry, like anytime you're talking about statistics,
there's a whole, you know, correlation is not causation.
The insurance industry doesn't care
if they found correlation.
They're, they're going with it. You know,
if red cars get in more accidents, they're charging more for red cars,
-- they don't care why
-- causation doesn't
matter as much as people think it does
in the sense of causation really only matters if you're trying to fix it.
And by definition, insurance happens after the event like it's too late.
That's true. That's a good point. Actually. And security
in general happens after the event, I think more often than not.
Yeah, we built it like five years ago and now it's broken.
Oops,
I want to tie in one last thing now to this cornucopia of stories we're talking about.
And this is a blog post from Trevor Dunlop who we know from GSD things.
He was a student at North Carolina State University doing
a bunch of research around vulnerability statistics and information.
He's at uh Chain Guard now. He wrote a blog post
link to it on the chamber blog.
And he basically has he titled Vulnerability Fixes in plain sight.
How your scanners are missing hundreds of vulnerabilities.
And basically what this is
is Trevor has done the research
to and, and I, I'll,
I'll explain the research and I'll explain what Kurt and I told
Trevor when he came to us like years ago with this,
but he did this research and he basically found that
if you look at change logs and open source software,
you can find boatloads of a fixed security vulnerability
that either they fix them,
not knowing they were security vulnerabilities
or they knew they were vulnerabilities and
just never bothered to get like a CV ID for this stuff,
right? Because it's a pain in the butt. That's why.
So I remember Trevor came to us with this research a long time ago and he was like,
look at what I found and he was a student at the time and it was like,
if you give this to people, they're going to hate you
because
people can't handle the amount of work they have today.
And if you show up with like, an enormous amount of new work, they aren't going to
take it.
Well, and I think I've talked to,
I bet four or five people who've done similar work to this and the response is
always the same word is like universal disdain of we're going to kill the messenger.
Yeah,
-- absolutely.
-- Which is sad
dude.
Same thing happened to the guy who wanted doctors to
wash their hands after handling dead bodies before they,
you know, help pregnant women deliver their babies.
Yeah. They, what they, the doctors made so much fun of him. They drove him insane.
They had him declared insane,
right? Same guy,
the guy that won a Nobel Prize for, you know,
proving most stomach ulcers are just take a course of
antibiotics for 10 days and you're good to go,
right?
Like,
and he infected himself and then cured himself and ended up getting a Nobel Prize.
But like straight up there was a huge industry of like, oh, you're stressed.
That's why you have a stomach ulcer,
take this pill every day for the rest of your life.
Yada yada yada.
And it's kind of almost worse than shoot
the messenger because like a perfect example,
like pick literally any the open source project that
is big and not a CV numbering authority,
which is basically the default because there's only 400 CNAs globally.
And half, more than half of them are companies.
-- Very few open source projects are CN
-- A
S
like a very simple example, you look at Korda, right,
big Blockchain project thing written in Java.
And they have like three CV S3 CV S
from 2019 and like they have a very, actually a well structured change log with like
security issues, labeled us security
updates and issues.
-- Before
-- we go too far, we have to clarify one very,
very important thing about this topic, which is if we talk about bike,
we just talked about bicycles and how it's under reported.
Then we talked about
the federal requirements for reporting breaches.
And now we're talking about open source and
a bunch of hidden vulnerabilities in no way.
Are we suggesting there should be like some sort of federal regulation
man dating open source projects,
report security vulnerabilities because they already are overworked enough.
This is 100% not a job the, the project should have to do.
So I don't want anyone to think we're going to say that.
-- Uh
-- just a thought experiment for a moment.
What if you had a federal requirement that if you sold a product or service
you had to number one do s bomb.
Let's agree on that as stage one,
like you got to know what your shipping kind of thing.
Right. And that's, that's kind of start going to happen.
-- I bet
-- Kurt's going to invent the cr a, let's see if he doesn't
basically.
And then the second question is what if you had to
then report in a structured manner to a centralized source.
And I'm going to say CV, because there's nothing else at this point that can do it.
And CV, as broken as it is, it's all we got
for now.
And you know what if they basically had to then
essentially put the, the incentive, well, not the incentive.
Well, the incentive would be, you know, a paddling
but you put the work on to the vendor
shipping the stuff to like actually look at their open
source change logs and search for the word security and they have to go get the CV S.
-- You almost invented the CR A almost you're
-- close. What is the CR A for those of us?
That's the Eu Cyber Resiliency Act,
the European Union is putting it together. They have some originally,
it was going to cover all open source projects and thank goodness a
bunch of open source foundations like banded together and got them to,
to that silliness, but it does mandate things like, you know,
vulnerability reporting and, and S bombs and,
and things like that and tracking your
dependencies that are included in your products.
Well,
I'm saying not so much vulnerability
reporting but it mandating vulnerability searching,
right? I understand that and it's not there yet.
That could be a logical next step. But yes, you are absolutely correct that
the consumers of open source should bear much
-- more of this responsibility for things like this.
-- Well, they also get the benefit.
Now, of course,
obviously there's all the downsides because like every product would then slow
down their updates and wait for other people to update first,
to report the vulnerabilities first and do the work first.
And I guess that what I'm proposing would absolutely probably be far worse than we,
we have today.
It's not that we can't put this on the open source.
It's that we can't, in the sense of like, it's physically impossible.
Like arguing with a black hole that it does not exist. Can't put this on open source.
There's multi pull angles to this, right.
There are projects that are just too busy because they're one person or whatever,
right?
And they don't care about doing the grunt work of vulnerabilities and that's fine.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Now, at the same time, there's nowhere they can go for help.
There are projects that have security people but they,
they've tried to get CV ES and they can't be bothered to do it.
I love that CV E and CV S scoring has gotten so painful that curl
and Linux Kel
-- became CNAs.
-- Actually, it's probably less
painful now than it used to be.
I mean, it still sucks, but it's, I think it definitely sucks.
-- Less
-- minor fun fact tangent.
So you know how the NVED labels vulnerabilities with their CWE, their root cause.
No, they don't. They use the simplified view of CWE.
So I actually asked them to correct ac we in, in an item
to, for it to be correct. And they said, yeah, we don't support that.
CWE, we'll use the parent of it, which is more
in general and because they use a simplified view of CWE,
which I did not even know this.
And I've been doing this, I'm on the board of CWE and I didn't know this.
I used to be on the board of CV E and I did not know
that the NVD uses a simplified view of CV. We, so their data is wrong.
It's not as fine grained as it should be.
-- It's
-- not wrong, it is wrong. It isn't as good as it could be.
Well,
they're using, it's like using CWE 20 input validation.
-- It's, it's a meaningless, it's useless
-- there. Some of them are, I agree.
So in this case, they use CWE uh
the parent which is way less fine grained
and doesn't narrow down what's actually the problem.
Ok. I have two comments for you.
Number one,
the fact that you can mail NVD right now
is impressive because it's basically been dead for months.
Congratulations there.
But more importantly is if you look at actually the Cwes
and their CBS S scores and all the things they do,
the volume of vulnerabilities they handle is enormous
and
it's,
the
data quality is bad.
They,
well, yes, you could say that the community help except they don't
because they're paying a contractor and,
and the community helping with federal projects is some weird thing that,
that kind of can't happen.
But, yes, I mean, fundamentally
the issue is that they used all of CWE,
it would slow them down even more than they already are slowed down.
And my guess is they would screw it up even worse
than they do now because if you look at the Cwes,
they get a lot of them wrong a
lot.
Well,
and also people parsing the data would have to like
all of a sudden handle like twice as many Cwes.
-- That's
-- irrelevant. The people processing this stuff are doing it all automated.
They don't care if it's right or wrong or anything. They're just,
they're just showing people whatever it says we don't care.
-- But
-- back to this, like the thing that gets me is this is, it's a,
it's a scale problem of, it's essentially, I don't want to say it's intractable,
but it's almost intractable in the sense of
there's not enough money
to pay a, like there's not enough
to have a single centralized source, do it quote unquote properly. Right.
It would require so much money to get it done. Right.
And I think what
I would say is is ideally we want to make like a best effort,
kind of a reasonable commercial approach.
Like, you know, it's not reasonable to spend 1000 hours on a single CV, E, like
-- half an hour or an hour
-- unless it's log for shell. Yeah.
Well, and, and that's a, yeah.
And, well,
and that's interesting because that's more of the detection side of things.
I,
I think conceptually we have to split the
vulnerability kind of reporting from the vulnerability mapping
because
it doesn't matter how much I know about the world,
there will always be something I don't know about that uses this.
-- So
-- here's how Trevor kind of ends his, his piece.
It does turn into a shameless plug for chain guards product, which I guess, I mean,
corporate blogs, whatever.
But
the idea is, I mean, yeah, that's fair.
That's kind of the point of corporate blogs like is to bring people in
and show your product and show the value which in some cases like this,
-- there is actual value. Thank goodness. So
-- here's the thing, the the intent
is he says we should instead of focusing on vulnerabilities which
is upgrade all of our stuff as fast as possible.
And I've been thinking about that for longer than I should have.
And I don't think that is a, I think that is just as ridiculous as expecting
it's a
pipe dream. Every project to acquire CD ES for everything because like
people can't upgrade all of their dependencies as fast as they can. They just can't.
Well, and it creates a lot of friction work.
Like, uh let's say I have a bunch of docker containers using an old version of docker,
but it's on an internal network only and hard to attack.
To me,
part of the problem is what is the value
of actually updating all this stuff on the fly?
And the thing is to get to the point where
you can safely update all the stuff on the flight.
You need a huge level of maturity and testing and everything, right?
Like the outside
bills.
Colonel, most of us just don't and can't
exactly it because you can't run a business like that. Right.
So I want to tie this back now. Well, we'll kind of head head backwards where
if you look at the rules like the SEC
has for filing these reports for breaches and stuff,
there's a bar to reach, you have to be a certain size company.
Well,
you have to be publicly traded and then
even the breach has to follow certain requirements,
right?
And so it, it's very similar like that, like all of these security things that,
you know, going from the bicycles to the sec to open source with all this stuff is
there's these like there's these bars you have to hit
because people say like it can't be every single thing,
right?
If every company had to report every single possible security incident that the
SEC would need to hire 10 times more people than they have.
Right.
Because anyone who's ever worked, like, in a sock at, uh, a large company security
center, you probably have somewhere between 10 and 100 like,
active investigations at any point in time.
Now, granted, 99% of them are nothing but
they exist. Right?
The one thing that gets me is at some point we kind of have to have uh
like, and when I say structure data, I don't mean like super
JSON structured like CV scheme, OS V scheme or whatever.
But I mean, just even like putting in some, taking some keywords like security for co
and
law
in a change lock is immensely helpful. And I do think that
that might be a reasonable thing to ask these projects to say like, look, no,
I don't think it is if you know, or think reasonably
that this is a security related thing,
then please put the word security in your commit message in your change log message
in your whatever message so that at least I have a chance of finding it.
I don't think that's
apply
suggestion.
-- I think,
-- well, I don't think it's plausible in the sense of it'll happen.
I, I don't think it's, it's reasonable at all.
I think open source projects just they're already really busy
and giving, putting even something that sounds as minor as that on top of them.
Is going to create a ton of mental burden because now you have to be like,
is it a security vulnerability?
Is it not a security vulnerability? Should I maybe add the tag just in case?
It's definitely,
it sounds simple but it's not,
it's, it's a very mentally taxing thing.
So it's fixing a bug.
-- Yes.
-- But they want to fix the bugs because they like doing that.
-- They don't like thinking about security.
-- I don't know.
I just let me give you a great example of this. I have a perfect example.
I edit this podcast every week.
I like editing the podcast because I get to make myself sound smart.
And if I want to, I can make Kurt sound dumb
sometimes I do.
But no, I'm kidding.
But I enjoy
the art of audio editing because I've learned a
lot and I learn something every time I do it
when I am done,
I have to think of an episode title
which I'm not very good at
which is fine.
But then
I have to add the keywords, the tags
to the post, to the, the blog post and the podcast.
I hate adding the tags
that feels super minor and compared to literally
spending an hour editing audio and constructing show notes
and coming up with the show title
and editing the graphic that goes with the podcast.
-- I thought those were all dally generated or whatever
-- now. No, I haven't.
No, I quit using A I because all the images were crap that I came
with.
So I just, I go back, I went back to Pix A Bay
and then I usually crop them and make them into what I want.
You get the point.
Like I do all of this, like incredibly,
like I would say detailed work that is not simple at all.
And then when I have to think of like five words to describe the podcast,
I literally hate doing it.
And I, I've,
I've stopped editing
and like gone to bed because I don't want to come up with those stupid tags.
Like for real, why don't
I?
No, because he'll do it wrong. But,
but anyway,
the, the point is asking someone to add a word,
one word to a commit message sounds trivial, but I promise you it is not,
I know it's not trivial.
But at the same time, see, there's what's fascinating to me is
on the one hand, we say you should not have expectations from open source and,
and the license is explicitly say, you know, like there's no guarantee, blah, blah,
blah.
But at the same time, there is sort of this expectation of
you should ship software that's not malicious.
I think we would all agree on that.
Like it's not containing malware or malicious or,
you know, like when left shift or um the he put in that denial of service, you know,
loop in the code.
It
everybody got upset.
There's a general expectation that you should sort of fix things.
So a good example is uh youtube downloader was broken for like a year.
There's like a one line or two line code fix
to handle the new youtube I DS and they hadn't,
they put the code in but not built a new release of it.
People have an expectation of it should be fixed
and kind of fit for purpose to some degree.
But at the same time, like, yeah, obviously, well, it's free and it's,
you didn't pay for it and you don't even know who built it.
So, like,
really can you expect this?
You know, like if you put out a food hamper,
you're expected to put out food that's not going
to kill somebody and have like poison in it.
That's true. That's true. That would be illegal.
Yeah.
And so, like, at some point I'm not saying this is like a legal thing,
but there are sort of societal expectations
that, you know, like when people jaywalk, I'm ok if they jaywalk,
if they look and like, don't run right in front of my car.
Like if they Jaywalk intelligently cool. You do that.
I get it because it's a long walk to go to the corner.
But on the other hand, I see people like, just, you know,
on their ipod with their earphones on, staring at the phone, like,
just blindly stepping up into the middle of traffic and I'm like,
on a practical level,
you're gonna get smushed
at some point.
And
I kind of feel like that's the thing with open source.
Like, on a practical level,
if you don't take some accountability for what and how you're using open source,
you're gonna get smooshed.
Like an attacker is gonna find that you're using a way out of date thing and
be like, cool.
And I go,
I mean, so
this is interesting because I think you drastically changed your
point and maybe accidentally at the very end is you,
you started out talking about the societal like implications.
Well, what I'm saying is it's all levels,
-- it's both the provider and the user,
-- but the right.
So I think this is interesting and I need to think about this because
we generally talk about open source from the the kind of
expectation
and
we generally talk about open source talking
about like the responsibility of the developer,
which then it's easy to say the developer owes us nothing.
Open source owes us nothing.
So we're going to claim the creator
technically has no responsibility.
And the open source license even says they don't,
I think the the responsibility of the consumer is a topic not discussed very much
and we probably should, I think it comes up maybe more and more where there's,
there's a more prevailing attitude of like if you're using open source,
you need to be responsible for it.
It's more just risk management.
Yeah, I mean, it is risk management,
but it's more than that I think because risk
management is obviously just very focused on yourself.
But when we're talking about responsibility of a consumer of
open source that suggests there's some sort of bidirectional channel
and I,
I need to think about this. I think that's profound,
-- but I don't understand what I want to say yet.
-- Yeah, I see.
And this is a bad analogy, but for example, like,
it doesn't matter how bad the jaywalker is, they
have the right of way.
So even if they are breaking the law by walking across a highway and,
and they'll get a ticket for that,
they still have the right of way and you're not allowed to run them over.
-- Yeah,
-- if you hit them, you're in trouble.
I mean,
they will also get a ticket for being on the highway when they shouldn't have been.
But
yeah, you're not allowed to just be like, I ran him over no big deal.
I always love that when like I'll,
I'll cross the street at like there's those blinky lights,
you push the button and the lights going through the crosswalk and all that, right?
And I'll cross that one day, some old man started yelling at me and I was like,
if you hit me, it's your fault, like shut up,
-- like stop yelling at me.
-- It's basically always the car's fault essentially.
You know, it's like rear ending
it's always your fault for rear ending the other person.
-- That's right.
-- Exactly. It does it right. If, if
it doesn't matter what happened,
like it's your fault. Exactly. Anyway, ok,
I want to end this show because I need to think about
-- what you were talking about just now to add a
-- wrinkle to it.
I think there's also an element of how shall I say, of,
sort of practical responsibility.
So, for example,
my Children have the right of way crossing
the street at a crosswalk with blinking lights,
but I have also taught them to look both ways for moving cars.
Yes, I do agree with that.
So there's a sort of realistic element
where I, but I don't want to slip into victim blaming of saying like, oh,
you didn't look both ways before you cross the street and got run over too bad.
Right. Because,
you know,
like an old lady got run over in a marked crosswalk by a city bus and
I'm like a city bus has pretty good visibility except for the one pillar apparently.
And it's a professionally trained driver, you know, blah, blah, blah. Right.
But that's the point, right?
It's not just some like 20 year old or whatever, an 80 year old.
It's, it's a professional driver driving a commercial vehicle with other people,
like he's the captain or she is the captain of like a little ship basically in my mind.
Um So yeah, you can get married on a bus by the bus driver.
Small
-- dude, I
-- don't know it's Canada.
Canada is a weird place. Alright.
Um but,
but so there's like there's I wanna say like there's
that sort of practical real world element of responsibility of like
looking both ways when you cross the street, even if you have the right of way.
This is a lot to think about. So, thank you, Kurt, thank you ever for listening.
Go to open social security podcast.com. You
or for the sea,
not
Pando
says podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt, have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.