Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- And
-- it is our advent calendar holiday extravaganza.
Story number one,
you don't just get one Christmas specialist here. You get a whole,
a whole pile of them.
You're going to get 2424 days of the
open source security podcast in bite size increments.
-- And
-- the bad news is it's not chocolate or beer behind the door.
That's right. It's just pain and suffering
and,
you know, Kurt talked me into this and I am,
I'm quite certain I will regret this decision.
Honestly, if I, if I was the one doing the sound editing,
I probably would not have suggested it.
-- So
-- I actually did some, some I crunched some numbers and
24 5 minute episodes
is two hours of content,
which is exactly how much content
-- we would basically produce in four weeks.
-- Well, yeah, four weeks, right.
But a month is more than four weeks, almost.
Trust me.
We, we might take some time off after this one. So
we'll see, we'll see anyway, 24 episodes.
-- Also, we're not stopping if the bus school. Less than 50. We all die.
-- Ok.
I guess.
Anyway,
Reeves.
No, I get it. It was,
I,
I just don't understand how we speed up or slow down the bus.
-- But,
-- well, I'm saying the bus has to keep moving or we all die.
That was the point of the film, right?
-- Like, that's why they had to run over the stroller full of tin cans.
-- Anyway.
Episode number one.
Well, no, no, no, no, not episode door number one. Ok.
Door number one, door, number one, that's better. Door. Number one.
-- So
-- I was looking into portable X ray machines mostly because
you know those legs, Lego mini figs,
I'm familiar with them.
-- So
-- I just, I wanted to be able to buy,
here's the thing though,
if I say I'm familiar with them, you can't just start talking
-- someone listening. I was
-- about
to say so it's basically,
it's a, it's a plastic bag
with a Lego mini fig inside,
right? With some special, like it's like a special Lego mini fig like
-- a
-- plastic bag you cannot see
through, correct? But you can feel through it.
But they also put a piece of paper in their image,
make difficult but a lot of the Lego mini figs like the Ursula or whatever they
have like really weirdly specific pieces that you can often kind of get a feel for
anyways
and they come in a box, I forget how many Lego it's like 40 or 50 packages to a box.
It's not like a completely even distribution, right?
Some are more common than others.
And also, of course, some of these mini figs, some are more popular than others.
Right? Like llama guy or a corn dog guy or hot, oh, hot dog guy. Hot dog guy was very big.
And so basically I looked into buying a portable X ray machine
so I could basically buy a box of these because normally
the way it works is you buy a box of these,
you rip them all open and then you sell them on
ebay for between like a dollar and like $10 each.
Right? And I was assuming I had the idea that like
if I could guarantee what's in the bag,
it's probably worth more because it's unopened.
-- I mean, maybe
-- why would I believe you,
you know,
because my seller rating on ebay is like five out of five or whatever
or basically I post a picture of the X ray next to the image
-- and
-- that could be kind of neat.
Yeah. Well,
but basically, and then I realized also because uh Playmobil does this too, right?
Playmobil sells individual playmobil people with, you know, accessories, a core
again in a non see through plastic bag,
which annoys me because you have to like before COVID it was fine,
you could sit there and squish the bags, put one down, squish the bag, put it down,
squish the bag.
Oh, that's the one I want, you know, put it to the side and
like, literally, I remember once going to chapters a local bookstore,
I started doing that and the lady's like, oh, don't bother.
I'm like, what? And she's like, oh, somebody already did that.
Somebody had already, you know,
fondled all the bags and gone through them and gotten the good ones.
What's the point of the story?
So the point of the story is you can actually buy a portable X ray machine,
you can get a prescription for it.
Why do you need a prescription for an X ray machine?
-- That's the part
-- I haven't figured out yet.
So if any of our listeners know, please tell us what on earth, like what possible
medical condition would you have
that requires a prescription of a portable, like a small, like an X ray machine?
And what does this have to do with advent or security?
-- Because you want to see what's behind the door? Number one?
-- Oh, I see.
So we're using an X ray machine to look behind door number one.
-- Well, to scan the whole thing, even
-- though we've, we just flung it open
and,
and now,
although no one knows what the rest of our advent calendar looks like.
Oh, it's probably horrific and full of
Kulu and evil.
I
mostly just stupidity and poorly informed decisions.
-- So
-- information security is an industry representative of
an advent calendar or us.
-- Well, the whole stupidity and full of craziness.
-- Maybe.
I think there's a lot of good intentions.
I think there's a lot, dude, like there's
like World War One was full of good intentions.
-- I
-- guess.
-- I, I feel like this is,
-- you know, we'll, we'll take that piece of land,
just ignore the germs with machine guns over there.
-- All right.
-- Maybe we're going to find out, I guess as we embark on this journey.
So, I guess, welcome to Christmas, everyone. We'll see you on December 2nd.