Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 184 with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, what's new man?
I actually phoned in a complaint to the city and they agreed that it was
a correct complaint and that they would check into it in a few days.
I was actually kind of shocked
-- that it was that it
-- doesn't mean anything
just because they agree with you doesn't mean they're
actually going to do anything about your complaint.
True, true. But in this case, so they bladed all the roads yesterday and
that,
which is nice because the roads were a bit flatter now and then they had like a little,
a guy in a gator.
So it's like a little four by four kind of golf cart on steroid thing, you know,
with the little snowplow on the front
to, to clean off in front of the driveways and stuff because, you know,
otherwise you get like that 2 ft pile of rock hard ice
uh, in front of your driveway.
And, um, so he cleared out my driveway, but he made a 4 ft pile of like,
ice rubble on top of
-- the drain for the street.
-- What could possibly go wrong.
Yeah, exactly.
And the thing is last year they spent like,
two days fixing potholes on the street because of that quo, of drainage issues.
So, obviously,
ok, so I need to, I don't, I don't understand what this means.
You said they bladed the road.
So when they plow your roads, they don't plow down to the concrete.
-- No,
-- they plow down to within four inches.
It's, it's more a matter of just making it flat because like the road out here
not so bad, the ruts are maybe 23 inches deep.
But for example, I've been in back alleys a couple of which were, the ruts are so deep.
My car bottoms out,
right.
So you get a 89 inch difference and we're not talking like, oh, fluffy snow, ha ha, ha.
We're talking, you know,
ice.
And when you bought them out on ice, your car makes a bad noise.
It just reminds me of like,
this kind of doing maintenance is really
important and doing maintenance correctly is really important
because it's great that they bladed the road because the idea is like,
there's less wear and tear on our cars and when the stuff melts it'll melt better,
you know, because it won't be all like, it'll be flatter so it'll run off,
but they blocked the place where it needs to run off to.
But it's easy to say this and everyone always says
this about how you need to do the maintenance,
you need to do all this work
and
almost nobody ever does it.
And this is true of government and it's true of private industry.
It is true of our personal lives.
I would generally agree. But I mean, at least it's getting easier.
For example, you can do GPS maps of where all the drains are and just, you know,
have a tablet and the guy can be like, oh, don't pile the snow here.
You know,
like the farmers with their spraying of crops more intelligently based on,
you know, GIS state and, you know,
ah,
but now farmers have
a desire to do that. Right? Because they will make more money.
The word you're looking for is incentive.
-- Right?
-- There's, there's a reason whereas
paying the man driving the plow to not pile
something up in a spot on a tablet. What is his incentive to not do that?
Literally nothing?
Well, somebody phones in a complaint and he gets dinged with a fine, maybe
for doing it wrong.
I mean, there's this great guy, this guy had, uh, I forget what brand of camera but
his poor neighbor comes to him and he's like,
do you know what happened to my car last night?
And his car is just like the back end of it is just
destroyed and it's pushed into a car in front and the guy's like,
yeah, I'll check my camera
and he does and it's a grater, like a big grater and you know how they have, like,
the two big front wheels just ran into a parked car and pushed it into the car in front,
backed up and, like, kept going, which I get, but he didn't like phone it in or,
you know, like, tell a supervisor later on in the shift, like, oh, bye.
The way I clobbered this poor car over here.
The guy just destroyed this car and just drove off and, you know,
without that video footage proving that the greater did,
it would have been basically impossible.
Right.
It's
interesting to me that, to see the, you know,
there is the potential for these technologies used correctly to,
to help us with maintenance, you know,
augmented reality, you know, don't, don't connect that pipe to that output.
That's wrong.
You know,
don't connect that black wire to that white terminal
-- connected to the black one
-- and in some cases,
I think that will work, but
it's,
it just depends on what the incentive structure is
in all of this. And
I have a strong suspicion for the guy driving the plow.
It's going to be hard to have an incentive because let's face it.
His actual job is getting the snow off the road,
right. That's all anyone cares about.
-- Yeah, but
-- like the guy in the gator, for example,
his incentive should be not just to clear the
driveways but to make sure also that the,
-- the drains are not blocked up
-- except you're probably the
only freaking town who's calling and complaining about blocked drains.
-- So,
-- probably,
yeah.
Although she, it didn't sound like this was her first complaint.
No, I'm amazed that that is true.
Now, were the other complaints you calling earlier?
Anyway, let's talk about something even worse than snow.
Yeah. So,
ok.
Are we going to even mention the whole.org dot com price grab, you know,
financial shenanigans, conflict of interest,
possibly illegal stuff going on or are we just gonna leave it at that?
Let's, let's ignore that. That's,
there's other places people can go if you, if you aren't aware.org
org
is sort of maybe up for sale and there's some
-- bizarre political shenanigans going on. Go educate yourself. No,
-- not bizarre.
There's just straight up old tiny, like I
control.org, I'm on the icann Board, for.org and we're selling it to a company that,
huh?
Weird. I also sit on that board.
Right.
Ok. Anyway, we're not getting into it.
And same thing for.com, they just approved a 70 what was it?
A 72% or they want to approve like a 72% price increase
over a period of a couple of years for the registry.
And it's kind of like,
that's a lot more than inflation.
-- I'm
-- not getting into it. Go find someone smarter than, than us
that's talking about it and you might learn.
Let's just talk about the other DNS tire fire,
internal domains.
I God bless internal domains.
Do. I'll let you explain it. It's a Krebs story. It's good.
We'll put a link in the show notes.
So the way computers do a DNS look up is not what you'd expect.
Basically, the long and the short of it is, is you can have like a local search domain,
like say
creed.org.
So that when you look for printer,
you don't look for just printer, you look for printer.creed.org.
And
assuming you have that set up, you find your printer, talk to it. Life goes on.
The problem then becomes also is it, it gets way more complicated than that,
especially with,
say a technology like active directory for Microsoft where you have a
combination of a directory for users and computers and services and systems
that also ties into DNS sort of but not really like,
it ties into DNS in the sense of it does DNS and it provides DNS,
but typically people don't actually tie it into a true DNS name. They
Microsoft literally says set up your Corp name as Corp.
And so then it basically thinks it's corp.com.
Well, no, I think I from my understanding is Microsoft meant to say
set up
corp.cried.org, not corp.com, but I'll let you guess which one everyone did. No.
Microsoft said just set up Corp but they didn't again. Yeah, go deep enough.
I know a bit about ad
stuff. I don't want to know. It's
ad is horrendously complicated and amazing.
Right. Like it's LDA
combined with
a bunch of other stuff on steroids. You know, it makes uh novel night.
We back in the day look simple. So it's actually not as simple as that.
Even if you set up Corp, say.company.com,
you still have problems.
There's a whole pile of corporate networks out
there with internal networks that think they're Corp.
And so when they start looking for stuff, they think they're corp.com and, well,
it turns out that's actually a valid domain name.
And the guy that owns it,
this is my favorite part of the article.
They're like, we basically decided to do a test where we'd actually like
stand up corp.com.
Like it's, it's a domain, it's registered domain, but it's not active.
So we'd actually make it active and we'd, we'd, um,
collect all the traffic sent to it.
Right. Well, ok, before we, before we start on this point, we should clarify.
Corp.com is owned by a person
and they want to sell it now because they don't
want their Children to take on this toxic sludge heap
when they eventually pass on.
And
they've not been using it as like, goodwill to humanity up to this point.
Well, in fairness, they've done sort of the least terrible thing with, with it,
which is to keep it inactive.
Right. Right.
And so now you're saying that basically in this creb story,
people did tests where they turn it on
and holy crap,
-- they
-- turned it on and they had to turn it off after 15 minutes
because it was so horrifying how much traffic was being sent to it.
And we're not talking like, oh,
you know, I want to talk to the printer. We're talking like,
hey, I need to authenticate.
Here's my credentials from like thousands and tens of thousands of systems.
And they ended up like taking a brief glance at the data
and going nope and just deleting all of it because I,
I did something similar back in the day with my ISP.
My ISP back when it was Videotron.
They let you, they had high speed cable internet, 10 megabit uh down one megabit up,
you know, this is like 20 years ago.
So it was pretty fantastic.
And they let you pick a host name, right?
So that's pretty like they gave you a static IP and let you pick a host name.
Oh, I remember this thing. You picked what logo
host was it?
I picked local host.
Yeah.
So again, when, when a computer looks up local host,
it looks up local host dot Whatever its default search domain is and
then that fails and then it looks up just local host and goes.
Oh yeah, that's me. Yeah. So the default search domain.
So local host dot Default search domain,
I had to disable that pretty quick because my, my, my link got flooded.
Um And then I had to go tell Kevin and I'm like, yeah,
I remember that because I was trying all these different domains.
Like I tried www which didn't let me grab. Good.
It, I tried to grab admin which didn't let me grab and
mail, which didn't let me grab and a bunch of others. And I'm like, OK, good.
And then I'm like local host and it's like,
oh,
so, yeah, they, they're like, yeah, we're gonna update the, uh, the,
the blacklist there.
Well done.
But yeah, similar thing.
I mean,
it's just the reality is computer networks by and large
have the potential to leak a lot of data.
They just typically don't because the DNS end point they want,
they want to leak to doesn't actually exist.
But if it ever starts to,
you're kind of up the creek
like there's dot Internal. Right. So many people use dot Internal as a domain name.
And 20 years ago I would have been ok with this, you know, where they say,
like dot Internal will never be a real domain name.
And I would have gone. Yeah, you're probably right.
Except now we have over 1200 top level domains and
there was talk at one point of actually making dot Internal
like a valid top
level domain.
Yeah. Right.
Uh huh. So, yeah, probably not the best idea.
I, I just, I don't know what to say or do here because you know,
this is like a systemic problem with how people
set up their DNS and set up their networks.
I I have an answer but I will, I will start this by saying so my home network,
I used to use uh breast dot home as my home network and then dot Home became a TLD.
I'm like, well time to fix this.
But
so yeah. Yeah. Now I just pretend I'm part of breast.net,
which is my, my my domain. I own. This sounds terrible.
And I will explain myself a bit, but honestly,
I think corp.com should be sold and I think the
more evil the person who buys it the better.
That sounds terrible. I'm sure.
But here's kind of,
here's my reasoning on this is so the owner wants Microsoft to buy it for like 1.7
-- million I think is the asking price I
-- saw
he didn't specifically want Microsoft to buy it.
He's selling it for 1.7 million and he'd offered it to Microsoft and past,
but they'd only offered like 20
and he's like, well, no, because
-- you guys made this mess and it's a bigger mess than 20 grand
-- and that's probably fair.
But my take on this is so if Microsoft wants to pay a reasonable price for it,
I think that's fair and there's nothing wrong with that.
However, if somebody evil buys it, now,
we're back to our discussion about incentives,
people have an incentive to fix this.
Whereas if Microsoft buys it, there's no incentive.
-- They won't. They, some people won't. A lot will.
-- I would argue that
it,
we would, we would generally all be better off economically speaking,
if Microsoft just bought it and deep fixed it because it's going to cost,
I think you will agree a lot more than $1.7 million
to fix all those networks.
-- It will not cost Microsoft $1.7 million to fix all those networks.
-- True.
But I'm thinking, you know, this is, this sounds a lot to me like broken window files.
It's like, oh,
we can make a whole bunch of economic activity by throwing bricks through windows,
you know, by having somebody do something evil with corp.com,
we can generate a whole bunch of activity and people have to secure their networks.
Well,
they're not going to be securing their networks.
They're gonna be scrambling to like, rename them, which, oh man,
technically speaking, renaming your active directory is possible,
but
I
bet it's terrible.
I mean,
it's technically also possible to like change out your cylinder heads
while you're driving down the highway at 100 miles an hour.
-- I don't know if that's possible. I feel like it's not.
-- Yeah.
Well,
and that's kind of my point with these large corporate
global spanning networks with hundreds of thousands of hosts.
-- And
-- look, man, if you are a legitimate organization,
like if you're large and you have resolver trying to hit corp.com.
Holy crap. What is wrong with your security team
in your network team?
Because you should have someone competent enough to figure this out.
The security team probably had no say in this
because this was the best practice from Microsoft
man. I feel like no, that's
-- no, just, no.
-- Well, and it's one of those things like a lot of security flaws.
It doesn't become a security flaw until somebody evil
owns corp.com and starts doing something with it.
Until then it's like a buffer overflow that just sits there lurking
man.
If you are a security team and you've got Resolver trying to hit corp.com,
there's no excuse for that.
There just is none even saying it doesn't go anywhere.
See,
I would argue this is Microsoft's fault because
-- guess when this domain was registered a
-- long,
-- long, long, long time ago,
-- 1990
four.
Right.
It was part of this guy,
whoever owns it brought up a whole bunch of really
juicy domains and sold them off which I mean,
good for him.
That's, I remember back in the day it was, it was hard to buy domains.
-- Oh, poker.com got sold and that that person retired.
-- Right. Right.
I don't know because I would say the
blame here generally lies squarely on Microsoft for
creating this dangerous behavior and kind of recommending people do it.
I'm not sure how much I would blame people if they're following Microsoft guidance,
fully understanding a technological decision,
especially when it's something that interacts with DNS in a weird way.
There's not a lot of people that actually understand this.
-- So
-- you just made me think of something else that's really
important is in the vast majority of compromises of an organization.
Active directory is basically the target because
the odds of it being configured correctly are essentially 0%.
I'm not sure there is a correct configuration.
There probably isn't.
But like this is,
this just feels like another one of those examples where active directory is
-- unnecessarily complex.
-- No, I would disagree.
It is necessarily complex when you look at what it does and what it enables.
I don't think you can say that.
I think if you make a tool that literally can't be configured correctly,
you've created a tool that's unnecessarily complex.
So E Linux,
I would agree.
E Linux is unnecessarily complex and that's why everyone turns it off. I mean,
look, I would be the first person to admit that I'll turn Se Linux off the second.
It gets in my way and I'm a security guy and I know how to fix it,
but I can't be bothered to do it,
expecting normal people to keep that on is ridiculous.
And the fact that basically the Se Linux
developers mitigating strategy for all these years has been yelling at people.
I mean, how did that work out guys?
Like, no, I think se Linux is a perfect poster child for like
this is a fundamentally flawed technology that needs to be fixed.
I wouldn't say it's fundamentally flawed. It's fundamentally difficult to use and
there's just been no impetus to, to simplify it and make it work better.
Well, no, but like for example, cars early on when you were crank starting them,
they could
start up and like break your arm
and well, then we got starter motors,
right.
We made it better.
Yeah.
And I mean, that's what I'm saying. Se Linux,
I remember Se Linux actually had a graphical tool to look at logs and to build policy.
Well, and so this graphical interface was actually pretty decent,
but it sort of just died.
-- I don't
-- remember that and it wouldn't shock me
because there was probably no demand for it because, you know,
it's easier than fixing.
Se Linux is turning it off
-- and this is similar to active
-- directory. Well, you can't turn active directory off.
Well,
no,
not exactly.
But the point is, well,
you kind of can now because I think there's alternative tools that are acceptable.
We'll say
-- it wouldn't be trivial to migrate.
-- No.
Like if you're running a large Microsoft network, you use active directory first.
-- All
-- right.
Well, and that's fair.
If you, if you're big enough, you're not going to migrate to anything else.
But regardless,
I will blame Microsoft for building a terrible tool more than I will blame.
I'm not so sure. It's a terrible tool as it lacks additional tooling
because fundamentally what it does it needs to do.
And I still think
that
claiming it's unfixed bad and corp.com has to go
to Microsoft because there's no other way around.
This
-- is an absurdity.
-- Well, I'm not saying it's unfixable bad.
I'm saying just buying corp.com and deep fixing it is a far cheaper option.
Well, it's not cheaper for them. I mean, don't get me wrong.
They have the cash to do it.
-- So I don't know why they wouldn't necessarily, I
-- mean,
it's cheaper for even a large company to just buy
it and deep fix it rather than fix their network.
That would be hilarious
and ignoring active directory because I'm sick
of talking about that because whatever,
if you read this article,
there was also a lot of email and other crazy things that came into corp.com
and I have a suspicion. There's, there's kind of two sides to this.
There's a Microsoft side of,
they gave bad advice
and then there's the other side of,
I bet a lot of people didn't realize corp.com was a real domain.
They assumed it was similar to example.com
and they were using it as like part of testing and kind of product defaults.
And so now it's a mess.
The thing is there's also people that chose other domains that are active.
Oh. Right. Right. No, it happens all the time. I will still never forget me.
And like my,
I complain about this. I, I haven't complained in a while but when I go to my gym,
the 172.16 network, except they have the route wrong.
So I can't get to anything in the 172 dot X network, right?
The, the slash or is that a slash eight?
And so obviously it's meant to be 172.16 through 0.32
which is what a sla it's a slash I,
I forget what it even is.
It doesn't matter. Like this is my favorite example because I'm actually, I've seen
more than one place now.
This is about the third or fourth,
but people screw this up because people don't understand how
networking works and they get the IP addresses wrong.
Right. It's like this is why I like the 10 dot X
private IP space and the 192.168 private IP space because like,
it's pretty hard to screw those up.
Whereas the 172.16
is really easy to screw up. It's the same thing with these domains. Right?
It's worse. The 172.16 is a slash 12
slash 12. That's it. Ok. Right. Right.
Yeah.
And so that's a weird number that most people
look at and probably think is wrong or something.
Right?
Because people don't know they,
it's almost everyone is used to dealing with
like slash eight slash 16 slash 20 fours.
-- Right.
-- Well, basically 10 dot Star or wanted to do 168 dot Star.
Right. Right.
Exactly.
Like I literally remember finding out about 1 72.16. I'm like, what?
Like I was so confused for a while. Right.
In fact, I'll never forget when this was my first job out of college. It was a,
they, they were a window shop
and
-- the windows admin
-- like windows,
the operating system or windows like making actual physical windows
-- like
-- no, no, like the operating system, they had windows everywhere.
And of course,
they hired me as a UNIX admin and I was like the super
crazy black sheep and I was annoying to be just as I am
and I'll never forget like he had 172 dot
You know, X as a slash eight for the corporate network.
I'm like, that's public IP space. He's like, no, it's not. I said, yeah, it is.
And like he started arguing with me like, all right, fine.
I got the RFC out and I showed it to him.
He was like, 00, well, it probably doesn't matter anyway.
I'm like, oh my goodness, this is ridiculous.
And yeah, like it,
we couldn't get to anything in the 172 dot
X space because it was our private corporate network.
-- It's like just use 1010 is easy. You literally can't
-- screw it up.
Problem becomes when you need to peer or VPN with somebody else using 10.
And then it just all goes to,
-- and
-- I've, I've had that
actually because I had, uh, what was it? I was, oh, my in-laws
were set up to use 10 dot X. And when I would VPN in
two, I think it was at redhead.
Actually, they, they were, they were using the exact same subnets.
I remember having to re
my network when I started.
And so I just, I gave up and I'm like, I'm gonna rub your network and they were like,
what I said, great.
Like,
they don't even know anything changed. Right. But yeah,
it was,
it was painful and, but whatever,
it doesn't matter when you're a corporate network,
you're rarely VPN into someone else's network, right?
-- It's fine. Everything's fine.
-- Uh Not anymore.
This is kind of the whole premise of like cloud gateway and stuff at Amazon.
-- Like, yeah, whatever,
-- who cares?
Like, even Amazon now has split horizon,
like internal and external DNS for your cloud stuff.
Yep. Yep, they do. It's pretty cool.
So, so anyway, anyway,
I guess my point being
and this is something I've been thinking about kind
of all week since I read this story.
And when you said we should talk about this is just the fact that
it is
incredibly difficult for people to not screw this stuff up. And I don't think
I, I feel like holding their hand too much isn't necessarily the right option.
We're like,
and I'm, I'm gonna come back to, if corp.com is bought by an evildoer,
I think that's gonna fix people quick and I know you disagree with me.
Well, it's not that I disagree with you.
It's just the reality is they're not going to fix their network.
They're gonna, like, filter out going DNS traffic to corp.com maybe.
But that, that's something
I,
I don't know.
I keep going back and forth on this one in my head and
I can see instances where people always are going to make silly mistakes,
but I don't think that is acceptable either because I think it's a combination of
if your tools let you, for example, use a, a public subnet in
your private network
that is partially the tool's fault and partially the person's fault.
How's the tool supposed to know if you're actually wanting
to number with 10 dot star or 11 dot star
when you
setting it up in a Windows, internal network,
that's clearly meant to be a private IP space.
-- Come on, the tool should
-- know, I mean,
I would say the tool should probably be aware of
the RFC 1918 or whatever it is space and,
and say like give you a warning if you
are or are not doing that.
But it's called like for example,
my home network here by default is internal 1 92.168 dot whatever space
plus valid, I PV six because my ISP hands me a valid slash.
Was it like a 32 or a 54 or something?
I PV six is different and that doesn't count.
I would argue that most people have about as much expertise
with I PV four as they do with I PV six,
which is to say none.
Yeah, to a degree.
I mean, this is, I think partially where I PV six gets some things, right?
Because they, you have real ips.
You don't have Nat. Nat is
nat is a headache.
Yeah, you have,
-- well,
-- it exists. Please don't use it.
You don't need it. Nat is there because of the whiny complainers from I
PV for
-- land.
-- I personally like
Nat because I have a lot of devices. I don't want to accept incoming connections.
Like I just want them to be dumb clients ideally
like my TV.
So you run Net on your internal I PV six network.
-- Uh
-- No, because it's uh it's complicated but basically I don't,
no,
you don't get to tell me you prefer nat now.
-- Uh
-- Well, I prefer net basically if something is dumb enough not to talk I PV six,
I don't want it on the internet
because by definition, it's not getting any real good security updates,
but at the same time,
like it is up to your, your router not to allow I PV six traffic in, right?
Like
you need tools to do the right thing. Here
anyway,
-- I guess
-- what it boils down to DNS is
still complicated and people are still messing it up.
No, DNS isn't complicated. Active directory sucks. That's the lesson here. Like
the tooling needs to be fixed
like full stop. That's the correct solution.
Microsoft should not spend $1.7 million to buy corp.com
and they should spend $1.7 million to look for people trying to
connect to corp.com and active directory and throw up a warning.
That's like, hey, I see your G
connector,
corp.com.
You know, you can have like clipping, tell you for example,
and he could guide you through fixing your active directory.
That would be a better spend
on that
-- than buying a domain just to deep fix it.
-- I disagree.
Buying it and deep fixing it makes the problem go away for now.
And granted it doesn't make the problem go away for all the
other domains people accidentally chose like say company.com is a real thing.
-- I think
-- probably everything.com is a real thing
now
pretty much.
And actually in all seriousness,
if you've made it through the bizarre ranting of curt and I to this point,
there is a domain called example.com that is
literally created for all this sort of stuff.
-- Well,
-- an example.org and
-- well, they
-- have,
yeah,
like use example.com if you ever do any
sort of development or testing or document writing,
except remember that one time
they actually started accepting email for example.com, that was a mistake.
And also if you go to example.com in your browser, it
you get a web page.
-- Yeah,
-- it goes somewhere but it is literally created for this purpose, right?
But it used to not resolve it used to be safe like
it's still safe. Sort of.
Yeah,
example.org and example.com both serve a valid web
page now which they definitely didn't used to.
I'm OK with him serving it because I think it is, it
is an example of something real happening is probably
going to be easier to detect than an error.
Uh
Well, DNS timeouts, yeah, typically aren't
-- all very,
-- no, they, they take a long time and people often give up.
Well,
often I've discovered a lot of networking equipment doesn't really throw an air.
-- It just sort of times out and kind of looks at you stupidly
-- and,
yeah.
Right.
It's always infuriating to me that, like,
I'll go to a website in my browser and it's thinking that and after like 10 seconds,
I just click the URL and hit, enter.
So it tries again and then it pops up immediately and it's like, it's,
it's after five seconds guys, it is clear the TCP connection has timed out
something happened.
Try again.
It's never coming back.
But anyway, networks are hard.
They work better than they used to though.
Uh
Yeah. Anyone who talks about the good old days with any of this stuff is
they have brain damage and it was so bad. It was so bad.
I actually remember trying to set up multicast at one point.
-- I don't want to talk about it.
-- II,
I read about it because I thought, oh, this sounds neat.
And I was like, nope, I'm not doing this. This is ridiculous. And it was, it was
that insane and yeah, I mean, whatever, whatever.
Well, so why don't we talk about something happy and simple?
So,
crypto A G is this company that was
started in 1952 to provide commercial cryptography,
you know, for companies that wanted to communicate over the globe without,
you know, the competitors reading their messages
and without the, you know,
using one time pads or craziness like code books and all that, which,
-- yeah,
-- this is, this is like the red phone, right?
Well,
sort of, yeah,
anyways. Um
uh so,
and there were rumors for a long time that they were like back doored because I mean,
literally the NSA and C I A's job. Now it turns out the CIA owned the company.
Well, that is technically a lot easier
than back door in the company.
Yeah.
No, it was, uh it was owned by the CIA and the BND, which is the German version of the,
uh their Federal Intelligence service.
That's something
I guess. I mean,
honestly, this doesn't shock me in any way.
It is
anytime you deal with encryption,
I think it is a dicey proposition. To begin with.
Well, especially closed source and commercial crypto.
Right. Right. Exactly. Because who knows what's going on there. Like,
like the enigma machine in World War Two had a very subtle flaw
that allowed the allies to core
it
-- and,
-- and there's,
there's tons of books written on this and
I would highly recommend reading any of them
because I've read a couple and they're all fascinating and I never get sick of it.
-- Yeah.
-- Also they had a lot of operational security flaws
which didn't help.
Right. Right. Read the books and they'll tell
about things like the, the weather station in Africa they never attacked.
-- No,
-- it was in the, it was in the Polish, uh
Polar Circle.
Ok. Ok.
It was a, it was a boat.
Yeah. Right. Like
it reported the same thing every day. So they knew exactly what it was hilarious.
-- Well,
-- he started all his messages the same way.
Right. Right. Anyway, anyway,
so,
uh, I
guess my take on this is number one,
no one should be surprised.
And number two
is this is why all crypto needs to be in the open
and vetted by the public because as soon as you start talking about having, you know,
secret encryption algorithms and you have systems that were built in the dark
and you have like secret backdoors is that only one organization can access? Like
that's all super dicey.
What's fascinating to me though is these devices are electro
mechanical in nature.
So it's not like, I mean,
they didn't have microchips with secure enclaves that you couldn't read.
These were all physically big enough devices that you like. You and me
in our garage could take these things apart and build
a schematic of what it's doing and how it works.
-- Yeah. But good encryption. You can know the algorithm.
-- Oh, yeah.
-- But the key is what matters, right.
-- Essentially the algorithm was spiked a bit.
Part of the challenge too with encryption is having
somebody with the actual expertise to audit it properly.
And there aren't a lot of people who can do that
and a lot of them work for the NSA weirdly.
-- Uh Yes,
-- I, I believe they are still the world's largest employer of mathematicians.
I would be shocked if they're not.
It's, it's one of those things that like
I'm
glad they exist and I'm glad they do the work they do.
But I also don't think we should ever hand them the keys for free
and say, take it out for a spin, you know, lock up when you get home because
it is one of those situations that's very cat and mouse.
And this is true of any organization in any sort of
power structure is if you hand too much power to anyone,
-- they just make a mess of things. Well,
-- there's the temptation to use
it
and they do eventually they do. You see this time and time again.
And you know what I always compare this to is like, when
I started playing Minecraft a long time ago
and I thought, oh, look at all this, like, there's crafting and there's,
you can enchant things and there's all this crazy stuff.
I'm like, I'm never going to do any of that.
I just want to, like, build a house with my kids.
And then you made that automatic chicken maker thing.
Exactly.
I,
I created a thing that automatically cooks chickens
to give me food by the end because
it's, it's like being a drug addict where it's like just one more,
one more I can do this.
And that's totally what it's like when you give an organization power, it's like,
oh, just this one time, just this one time
and it, it's always one more time and one more time. And so
like, is it ok? They did this?
-- No. Well,
-- it normalizes the behavior. Right.
Exactly.
Exactly. So, I mean, it might kind of, the way I would sum it up. Is, is it ok?
They did this?
Not really? Were they caught? Yeah.
Sort of, is anything bad going to happen because of it? I mean, probably not,
but at the end of the day I think we are a better society
when we have secure encryption versus when there is a known flaw
that even if only one organization can use it.
I think it's highly dubious that only one organization has access to it.
-- That's not how flaws work.
-- Right. Exactly.
If, if one person finds something, it's highly likely another,
either did or just by the nature of counterintelligence
that the, uh,
the bad guys were basically someone in a briefcase handed it to him eventually.
Right.
And, I mean, at the same time, like, we won't get into it today.
But, like, this is the whole reason why, when you hear people say, oh,
you need to be able to break into every iphone on the planet.
It's like, well, no, you don't because if we give the NSA the power to do that,
then the UK is going to show up and the Russians are going to
steal whatever we gave the UK and then Australia is going to show up.
Well, and that's already happened with what is it Russia wants
or wants Apple to pre install government software on all the iphones.
-- Yeah. Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
And if Apple does anything other than give them the middle finger,
I will lose what little respect I have left for them.
So,
and I, I, I'm confident they will. The Russian market isn't that big. But
anyway, anyway. All right, man, I feel like any, any last thoughts on this one.
I think it is an interesting
thing, but I don't think there's any kind of dramatic lessons or, or takeaways here.
-- Either
-- I would say basically back to, you know, good DNS security practices,
make sure you can actually see what's going out and log it, you know.
Uh, because honestly, even just malware is making random DNS calls.
-- It's one of the best ways to catch it. Uh, right.
-- Everything uses DNS.
So, having, you know, decent DNS security is
-- not a bad thing.
-- No, I agree. I agree completely.
And exactly, if you see, if you see corp.com in your DNS logs,
go fix that. I like it. All right, sweet. So, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, you pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your
-- day. You too. Thanks
everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.