Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in thought experiments.
Josh Pressers.
Yeah, we're gonna thought experiment this one up today because we don't,
well, there's not if it's real yet. So
we don't have any option. There's no facts.
I mean,
so we're just gonna, we're gonna theory craft. There's a fact. OK.
So I want to,
there's a proposed fact is that a fact?
There is
a
proposed,
it's like
a
theory right now, but whether or not we have the evidence to support it existing,
we'll find out
we're gonna find out. OK.
So there's two things that I think have come together nicely. We had a listener
and, and I forget it was email or a master a message or something but said,
hey, you should talk about Graphene Os,
which is a,
like it's an operating, it's an Android Os you'd install on a pixel phone, right?
Which is not like the official Android.
It's one of those like,
like jazzed up versions and it's got a bunch
of cool security features and stuff in it.
But the, the I think this ties into the other half, which is the FCC
has approved a cybersecurity label for commu consumer devices.
This is think of it like an underwriters label type.
It's meant to be
a way to convey to consumers that this device
has gone through some sort of security approval process.
Right.
Well, ok, first of all, is it going to be external validation or,
or self certification?
Like
we
don't know yet?
No, there's literally no details.
So we're going, this is where the thought experiment comes in. We're gonna pretend
it works perfectly for the context of this conversation. We know it won't.
And we know these things take years and years and years to develop. But
I, I'm interested in discussing this
from a, a very experimental place, we'll say.
So I want to start with rooting Android phones first because I
want to lay some of the groundwork around all of this.
So,
so we're not even gonna pretend about Apple
phones being rooted and modified just Android only.
You can't, you can't look,
I'm not gonna pretend you can root an Apple
phone because that's like to jailbreak an Apple phone.
You are doing horrible things to the device or you can just give that
photo Apple for a million bucks.
I mean,
not Apple for
more.
I think the Android example is good because this is something people.
So OK, you've got a pixel phone, right? It runs Google's operating system.
Like in my case, I had a pixel too.
So pause for a second because this is something I'm not 100% clear on Google.
My understanding is there's Android Os for phones and there is like
real
Google one
that gives you access to the Google store
and then there's like the third party ones and
you can't have access to the Google Store,
but you have to, you can have access to like your carrier, I guess phone store.
We'll get to that.
I'm not
a
person. So I legitimately don't know because I'm an Apple person.
It's like my choices are apple. Pay apple
or hold it correctly and pay Apple. Yeah. Pay, pay Apple. You have no choice.
There's no plan B
and OK, so I'm, I'm gonna put this in the context of my
life experiences in this space, right?
I bought a pi the,
the pixel two phone is what made me buy an iphone because I was so angry.
I bought a pixel two Google end of life
in three years.
Yeah. What do you think
killed by google.com? Sorry. But I
know
well,
but they're claiming now they're going to support their phones for
like seven years or 10 years or something like that.
They've said that about a lot of things that they can, I
know that's the thing like I,
I don't particularly like I OS but it's because it says I OS is very like
you do it our way or you go f yourself like those are your options.
There's,
it's kind of the apple way. It is the Apple way.
Oh, you want a laptop with a touchscreen? Yeah, we don't do that.
Right. Like it's,
it makes me so angry. But anyway, ok. Ok.
So
now that my, my pixel phone is dead, I installed a third
party
android. Well, it's not dead. It's just not supported.
Well, it's not supported by Google. Exactly.
And so I installed at the time because I don't think Graphene existed,
but I installed Lineage Os on it way back in the day.
Right. And to do that though, you have to unlock your boot loader
which like wipes the phone and it makes it very easy to hack essentially,
which is what I'm doing.
You're basically a disabling secure boot.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure.
And then
from that point forward,
I had basically an insecure phone from the like local attack perspective
where there was like no boot protection.
Now, when you install like lineage Os,
you then have to go and find the Google apps if you want to use a Google environment
and install like the play store and Gmail and
all that crap because it's not like supported.
I bought a cheap unlocked Android phone because I was trying to get an old game.
My son likes to work and it was, I found the A PK
and I went through a whole song and dance to get
a pks to work on this phone and then of course,
I did an operating system update and it all broke.
So I honestly I gave up,
it was just so unreliable. It, that's fair.
And the cheap Android devices definitely suffer from this where it's just like
madness all the time because you don't know what you're going to get.
But the pixel phones don't.
So anyway, fast forward many years
and now there's a thing called graphene Os and graph you Os took Android,
they reduced a bunch of attack surface.
They like turned off a bunch of like NFC.
You can turn off, you can switch from like five G to LTE.
In theory, the five G code isn't as tested or something.
I don't totally understand it,
but it's got like loads of security crap built into it.
And the best part though is you have to unlock your boot loader,
you install graph E OS and then you can lock it back up again.
So you, you get like that benefit, which is very, very cool.
And I was really excited when I saw that, but
you still suffer from the,
you have to go and find like the Google A
pks and install them in the weird side load manner.
And there's still things that don't work correctly. Like for example,
there are applications that will only run on like the official Google Android
thing, right? Like banking apps are notorious for this.
There's I think Netflix is on the list and in fairness though, those apps are also,
they like,
I guess the idea would be they don't want to run on a compromised phone because like,
oh, an attacker
took over this phone. So, like, I, I think that's the idea, right?
Is you don't, they don't know the state of the phone.
So, and, and I, I suspect in the case of like video application,
something like Netflix or, or whatever,
they don't want people to capture the video, copyright protection. Right.
That's, that's probably what that is
open
source. HDM I Cable.
No, seriously. Right. That was the whole thing on L TT.
We'll never have an open source HDM I Cable.
And I'm like, well, of course we want like, because copyright protection.
Yeah, that's, that's what they want it for, for sure. It's nuts
anyway. Ok.
So
we kind of set the stage here where you've got a device, it,
it maybe becomes unsupported.
You do another thing with it
and
now you have this, I guess hostile environment.
We'll call it in the traditional absence where things like
the Google Play Store is gonna say, can we trust this, this device?
We don't know, we don't know what this is, we don't know what's going on.
Yeah,
there's, I mean, this happens even with like games and stuff.
Like one of my favorite examples is uh Genshin Impact which is uh a Chinese made game.
It's by Miho
Yu, I think is the name of the company behind it.
But my kids were playing it for a while and they were like, hey,
you should play this with us
and I went to install it on my computer and it installed, like, I'm like, no way,
I'm not putting this on a computer.
This thing is like installing, basically root kits is copyright,
cheap protection.
And again, that's the thing that has to, that,
how else is cheap protection gonna work?
Now, that's a whole another conversation we're not having today.
But anyway, so I'm like, oh,
it runs on Android and I have a little
handheld android like game emulator called the Retro.
I'm like, I'll put it on retro,
I install it on Retro. And the game's like this is an unlocked device.
We will not run here. I'm like, whatever.
I was like, kids are not playing this game with you. I give up. But
anyway, anyway, ok, we put all that together, right?
So
the question
becomes,
let's say you have a device, let's say it's potentially secured
and now I'm a user and I mess with it.
And now the default for a lot of organizations is to say,
like we just don't trust this device, we're not going to play with it.
Ok.
Well, yeah, I mean, we see this all the time in real life where for example, this guy,
I think it was in Newfoundland wanted to build his own house,
which you can do if you get plans and permits and inspections.
But he wanted to use some historical lumber. And what's interesting is
the inspector said I can't certify this because it doesn't have the stamp,
even though you and I both know that this 12 inch beam is like
stronger than anything. Home Depot could even dream of selling you,
but because it's not stamped and it's not like, like an aircraft part,
it doesn't have that paperwork, can't certify, it, can't inspect it and approve it.
And I feel like this is like a lot of things like a lot of people are like,
oh no,
I did the wiring myself and it's better than code or I did this and it's better and,
but you actually inspect it and once in a while it's like,
oh, you made a whoopsie, you didn't bond the ground properly or
you might think you did something to make it better.
Well, maybe you did, maybe you didn't,
maybe, maybe. And that's the question right now.
I want to tie this into another
story which says FCC approved cybersecurity label for
devices.
And there's literally no information on this.
There is a logo which I will link to a Cybertrust mark little shield thing.
I don't think it's a very good logo because I
it's, it's very nondescript. It's like a shield with
little boxes in it.
I realized what it looks like to me,
it looks like when those people are doing
the component level board repair and they accidentally
get some of the solder connecting to things improperly. They bridge two points.
Yeah, it
does look like solder bridges. It looks
like. So
a mistake on a soldering thing.
Yeah. Yeah.
But, but so
so not a good look. In other words,
well, it does say us cyber trust mark on the bottom. I assume the text is not optional.
But anyway. Ok,
so here's, here's how I want to tie all this together. So
let's pretend
there is a perfect universe
where the cyber trust mark is independently verified
and enforced in some way.
So, so something I did learn doing research for this particular show.
So you know, that the UL Mark,
which I know UL doesn't quite mean what it
used to mean because there's all this like self
certification and stuff now. But, but what I did learn
is there are jurisdictions. Well, UL I should say is underwriter laboratories.
The idea being if you make like,
uh certain kinds of devices like plumbing and electrical and, and a power brick,
let's just go with power bricks.
Sure.
We'll say power, you send it off to underwriters labs,
they do whatever testing they do on these things and then
they put a stamp on it and you can say,
you know, underwriter's lab,
I tested my product and verified it's not gonna like, you know,
burn your house down or whatever.
Well, it's just not gonna catch fire randomly like all those E bikes do. Right.
In theory.
Now, what I did learn
is that there are jurisdictions in the US
where you cannot, it's funny
you cannot plug in.
It says it is apparently where it's written,
you can't plug in devices to the wall sockets that aren't UL approved
or not approved, whatever the UL MARK is. That's a classic BS insurance thing.
It's like use this product safely. And if you don't use this
briefly, hey, we're, we're off the hook.
Don't click on suspicious links, everyone.
But, but anyway, so here's, but,
but I also learned that there are retailers that will
not sell electronic devices that don't have the UL Mark.
I'm betting that's a very small number of retailers.
Now, it was probably much bigger at one point in the past.
But given the we'll say influx of surprisingly inexpensive devices,
I see at many retailers, I'm fairly certain
that they're not checking the UL Mark.
Well, and here's a problem.
How do you verify that the Ul Mark is like legit?
I mean, I would expect some other entity to do that for me. Right.
Well, so there is actually a verify.ul.com
and learn about claims, but there is like as far as I know, there's no way to plug in,
you can actually look up devices like so for example,
here just clicking on one at random uh Flow tech co limited
if I typed in apple and it said no results for apple.
Uh
That's funny.
But the point is in theory,
you can like look up a device model and name and validate that it.
Like they didn't just add this mark,
you know what no one's going to do and that's part of what I want to discuss, right?
So let's say we have this, this us cyber mark.
You have the question of kind of people understanding and enforcing because
I, I know how the UL works. I literally have an election
engineering degree. I went to school for,
I have never once checked a product to make sure it
has a UL Mark on it when I purchased it.
And more to the point if you actually do this, there's,
there's not a lot of things you can validate. Like there's just not a lot of data here.
Let's pretend that the, the federal
Cyber mark means perfect security
for the purpose of our thought experiment.
Now,
here's the thing though.
So we know people aren't going to look for it, right.
You could, you could blast it on the front of your product.
And if I'm standing in the store
and there's one light bulb with the Federal Cyber mark on the front of it,
that's $10 more expensive than the light bulb without
it.
I think there's a 90% chance I'm going to buy the cheaper
one because I'm a cheap skate and that's just how I roll.
Well, and there's no knowledge of what that mark means, even if I know what it means,
I think.
But for a
person,
yes, a normal person is going to be like, I have no idea what this means.
If anything, they might look down upon something that says,
what does it say? It says us cyber trust mark.
I might be like that sounds like some government spying crap on that thing.
I'm not buying that
right now. Sorry. Just to pause. You all have a security mark.
I remember they were working on that. I didn't know if they made it or not.
That's cool.
Well, no, this one,
I just clicked around a product and it says it has an IOT security rating.
So the fact that you and I don't know about this,
I mean, and it already exists and you all have been doing it,
dude. I'm sorry, like we just proved your point.
Yeah, I agree. I agree. So, now
we have the
question of
how do they spell IOT? Well, with two, I's
iiot,
what does that mean? Industrial is an industrial iot maybe or something.
I don't know,
maybe. I don't know, whatever, whatever. Who cares? It doesn't matter.
So,
like
this is, this is the only way we
work.
This is what I feel like I feel like
the more I learn, the less I know,
like every day I learn something new and think everything is, is do.
Yeah.
So, ok, one thing to say. This says it is UWP 4.0 security enhanced.
Ok. Ok. Whatever.
Like no one knows what that means. No idea what this means exactly.
And I'm Googling it. Google doesn't know what it means. Here's the point, right?
We've got this Trustmark,
let's say it's put on devices and let's say retailers say we're
only gonna sell devices that have been through this program which,
you know, is ridiculous.
But let's pretend that's the case.
Now a device comes to us, right?
This is where I feel like things get weird with compute devices because let's
say I buy a surge strip that the UL has done their business on
and they claim it's not gonna burn my house down.
The number of things I can do to that third
strip to we'll say modify it in an unsafe manner.
It's not zero, but it's pretty low, right? I'm gonna plug
it
in. I'm gonna plug crap into the third strip. Like that's just what it does right
now. If I have a device though,
you have installing apps on the device. Well, actually puzzle
an interpreter because actually a lot of the stuff
you can do to the search strip to damage it
would in theory, for example, be caught by an arc fault circuit interrupter,
which is now mandated by code for all bedrooms and living areas.
So it's almost as if we've learned from burning houses down that
well, you're not allowed to do that. So here's the thing though.
I wonder about like secure devices. Ok.
So let's say I have a phone, let's say it has a cybertrust mark.
Let's say I install graphing
Os on it.
What does that mean?
I would say that based on what I know of phones and the,
the mix of hardware and software that, yeah, that, that mark no longer applies.
So that's like saying, I took a piece of food,
I took the meat,
the hamburger and I put something totally different in.
Does the nutritional label still apply? Well, I mean, that's fair.
That's a good point.
No,
but I, I think devices are especially unique because
how would, you know, let's say I, I
gra
you know,
on the phone, I give you the phone, let's pick a light bulb, light
bulb, light
bulb, turn off even better
off
talk Zigbee protocol.
You don't know what software is on there. Like you're not going to do a Rom dump.
Here's where I wonder about this also. So, ok, let's pretend I have my phone.
I don't install graphing.
O si keep the Google default
OS
with the secure trust mark, right? Of course,
I install a bunch of apps on it.
Like is it, is it very like can we, what can we say about that? At that point?
I think the intent behind this is going to be I buy a device
and I know the creator of the device has taken reasonable actions
to not release like a security Swiss cheese product. And
I'm going to get reasonable updates on the device.
That is almost certainly what this is going to be about that and that would be useful.
And that a good example here is I look at Apple phones and I look at how many
years of support they get from the day they
are released until like they're sort of last.
It's about 6 to 7 years.
I know that's why I bought it iphone Solid six years, about seven.
Whereas with a, with an Android based phone, everybody's like, oh,
you can buy a proper Google phone and they will
for sure support it for five or six years.
And I'm like, that is a great idea in theory. However, I live in Canada
and I cannot get the thing fixed if it breaks.
Interesting. Well, there's no Google stores here.
Right. That's one of the advantages of Apple.
If there's an Apple store, I can just take my phone there and get it fixed.
So if I'm traveling,
I'm way less stressed out about worrying about my phone
because there's like an Apple store wherever I go because I,
I go in cities. So I think this would be good
in that.
It would give
maybe a simpler way for a consumer to validate that. Oh, yeah.
Like historically, this vendor has given five years of updates or,
or even better this vendor has historically given updates for what would
be perceived to be a reasonable length of use of the product.
So like I'm gonna go with phones, I'm gonna say five years,
good. 10 years. That's,
that's an old phone dishwashers on the other hand,
20 years.
So here's,
here's something in this article from Cyber scoop that I kind of want to read,
right?
It says, and this is just a, like I read the whole paragraph,
it says if your car explodes following a minor accident or if a table saw
comes loose and maims you or your light bulb overheats and causes a fire,
you can take the neglige
manufacture to court and recover your damages,
right? Blah, blah, blah.
But if an attacker hacks your smart home devices, let's say your Alexa
listens in on your private conversations.
You have little to no recourse against the manufacturer.
So that, I mean, that is a quote from, from the commissioner, an FCC commissioner,
right? That whole you can sue and get redress. No,
not realistically in a lot of cases.
Well, if it, if it's written into law, I mean,
it depends how damages are defined in law in the US.
At least that, that's,
that seems plausible, but I'm skeptical they'll probably go there with it for sure.
Yeah, I mean, we,
we have that thing with car fires here in Canada where it turns out the
Mercedes cars where like there was a design defect and they were just catching fire
and it took years
because transport, Canada doesn't like track all the vehicle fires.
And there's no, we've talked about this past on the show but they don't.
There's no, so there's like that lack of correlation,
just like train accidents in the US.
NASA runs a program.
Nobody has joined it.
None of the train
operators have, like they said they would join it a few years ago. But they
NASA like the, the space people,
they
don't
make the
trains or like they,
well, I guess they're experts in transport. I don't know.
Maybe they're good at blowing things up.
Yeah.
So really good at that.
That's the thing is like this, this idea of redress that I will. I'm sorry.
But somebody hacks my Alexa because my Alexa is not secure.
You're saying I have an honest to goodness chance to sue Amazon and get
satisfaction. You probably don't. But let's ignore that part as well.
I just wanted to bring it up because I think it's an interesting point.
It's also a very American viewpoint of suing
because like most of the rest of the world doesn't do that
for
consumer safety laws.
And one thing,
one thing I think that works is what Europe does,
where this device has to be fit for purpose.
And if not, you can return it not to the manufacturer, but to the person who
sold it to you and get a refund.
And now that works.
Obviously if you're buying from like a store that's still there a year later which
most big stores like Circuit City best buy.
I don't know what the German equivalents of these are. Circuit City is gone. Kurt.
Oh, yeah. That's right. Yeah. Sorry. Yeah. Good point.
But I think laws like that because then
it's kind of like the Costco thing.
Costco will basically, like you return anything within a year.
They're like, this is ridiculous, but we'll do it
and if you abuse it, they'll fire you as a member,
which is
ok, we're off in the weeds. We need to pull ourselves back to the point.
But the point is Costco picks reasonably not terrible stuff because they
know they have that one year return window thing to deal with.
And I mean,
that's an instance where a mark like this might be valuable to someone Costco,
right?
Where they might look at that and say, ok, this is a good thing.
We want to make sure we're, we're selling this thing.
I think it's more that lack of it is a bad thing.
Sure. I don't think that the market itself is a good thing.
I think it's like, like if something can't achieve even ac certification ul
Yeah, it's like, come on, what are you even doing
the more I think about this, the weirder it gets
just because
I feel like devices are so strange and I think something like
this mark could apply up to the point it enters a person's premises
and I feel like it's almost like no holds barred after that.
Right. You have to, like, use it as intended and then no. Ok. No, no, no.
But that's the point.
That's the point. Use it as intended with digital devices, isn't it?
It, it's a tree of infinite branches.
I mean, you have to think about how many apps exist in the app store.
It's probably millions.
And what are the combinations of those apps
installed which obviously changes the way things work.
And in theory it shouldn't. But you know what I mean? Like
it's so weird.
Well,
and this also ignores Dieselgate where you could have a
device test to the test when it's in testing mode
and then
do other things to get.
Like I,
I can't think of a specific phone example where you would like exhibit a security
behavior and then not do it later to somehow improve the experience or something.
OK? No, I I do have an example of this. So Graphene Os has has this.
So when I was reading the documentation on how Graphene works, they,
they do a bunch of like additional lockdown like
memory protections and all kinds of crazy stuff.
So that does impact performance. No, no.
The problem is there are apps that don't run with it
and so you can turn it off and they call it like compatibility mode or something.
I forget the name of it,
but it's better than calling it an insecure mode.
No, I'm serious. Right. It's compatibility mode, not insecure mode.
It's like WEP, uh, whatever.
Like, you know, it's, it's incompatible mode for old devices.
Not, it's WEP, which can be cracked on.
I was gonna say a laptop but just run an open A P at that point, at least, you know.
But,
but you know what I mean?
I mean, this is,
this is the thing I keep thinking about is there are
millions of configurations like what happens if we root a device?
What? And, and, and here's where it gets even weirder is
I know there are organizations in Europe that are
saying if a person buys a computing device,
they should have the ability to like build a new Os
and put it on there if the manufacturer isn't using it.
But now if we have people like rooting all
this stuff and doing all this wild modifications,
how can you possibly claim anything is even remotely certified to
anything and making it possible to root introduces security vulnerabilities?
Because like, well, if I can re
uh remotely and by remotely,
like not having like physical switches or jumper after bridge on the device,
which is going to be the case with a phone, you know,
having some sort of way to do it like through USB or whatever.
Well, that means an attacker can also probably do it right?
This introduces the potential for backdoors and
for an attacker to hijack my device.
And so,
yeah, it's, it's, it's a, it's to quote,
however, it's a hard problem to solve, I think what would be,
I'm going to take a step back and kind of
go to where I've been going a lot more recently,
which is,
I'm less concerned about the security side of
it and more concerned about things like,
can they and will they,
can they ship an update that I can install in a prompt manner?
Because none of this else matters because at some point
like Apple's been working on securing their phones forever,
lots of vulnerabilities fixed.
They've got the advanced whatever they call it, the uh locked.
Yeah,
where like basically disables everything.
Like you can't get messages or calls from people on your contact list.
You can't, you can't get multimedia.
What is it M MS stuff? You can't
like it just guts the functionality of the
phone to essentially reduce the attack surface,
which
is fantastic.
But you know,
if you're a journalist or certain types of work in certain areas of the world,
you basically get a dumb phone and, but it's secure and I just,
I keep coming back to like, I, I no longer, it's not that I don't care about security,
but security is like more towards the finish line.
And what I need now is I need the vendor to actually support the product. I mean,
you're probably right when you say that and, and
that's kind of
not what I was thinking about here.
But you're actually right, because I think a lot of,
a lot of compute based devices
is they're, they're just not supported you, like, buy them and they, that's it.
Like, what you get is what you get. They, they're never updated ever.
Yeah, I got some globe light bulbs from Costco.
They got, like, one or two software updates and
they just never worked reliably. So I actually didn't even return them.
I just got rid of them.
And then I went with Phillips Hughe as you know,
which actually do get software updates.
Like my printer,
like I was like my printer.
Remember I checked on that show and I'm like, oh my God,
it's actually got a month old claims, a month old firmware update
or
software update or whatever it's called.
And so that's what I'm buying.
And I mean, and that's one of the advantages of the apple ecosystem, for example,
is they have less stuff
like they have, um,
they have a, a lineup of phones that actually fits on a web screen.
And whereas Android, you've got
thousands. Well, Android is, it's such a different model. I mean,
you've got Google with their stuff,
but then they obviously you've got Samsung phones, you've got LG phones,
you've got one off, no name phones.
Whenever I walk by the cell phone,
kiosk, there's got to be at least 100 Android phones that all look very different.
Yeah, probably. And they're super different.
Four Apple phones.
That's it, like
four Apple phones.
They don't, they,
at least when I go to Best Buy the Apple stuff is like all I have in the,
in the corner in the back, like, away from the normal cell phone stuff.
But I mean,
and to be honest,
so that's why I buy apples now is ironically you pay a lot more upfront
but you get the 567 years of guarantee. Sure. Sure. Sure, sure.
My kids are rocking iphone eights.
I mean, look, the thing to remember though is that like, not every company is Apple.
They can't work like that. Right.
Yeah.
And, and it's definitely,
but there are brands and vendors that are starting to do that.
Like Phillips hue they seem,
be supporting their light bulbs with software updates.
Knock on wood. Yeah, more, it's more money up front.
But it's, I guess it's like, it's like buying a car.
I made the mistake of buying a Kia.
And why do I say it's a mistake is because they are produced in South Korea.
There is no, all the parts are produced in South Korea there.
It's not like buying a Ford or a Dodge or something
in North America where there are other companies making compatible parts.
I did not know that. But yeah, that would be annoying.
But like, so with when it comes to Kia,
I ha I have to get parts from the dealership who gets parts from Korea.
Sure.
There's, it's
really expensive.
Yes, I, there was a part I bought,
it was the wrong part but it was like 25 bucks from Korea.
Plus shipping
and it was 500 bucks locally and it was the wrong one. But I, you know, 25 bucks.
So I'm like, ok, that,
that,
so
it's a solenoid, right?
So it should only be 25 bucks. A $500 solenoid. Jeez,
what your options are,
buy it from us or
get it from Korea. Good luck with that.
I'm actually gonna end up paying the dealership
because the thing is the dealership is also not
gonna take my solenoids even if it's the correct one and like replace the part for me.
They're gonna be like, no, we won't do that.
Well, you could probably find a mechanic anyway.
We're, we're in the weeds, we're in the weeds.
I could find a mechanic that would do it, but not a dealership.
And this speaks to this exact problem with these phones and everything where like I,
with a phone
that's really not an option,
like component level repair of a phone nowadays.
I mean, it exists.
You've got these, uh, uh,
like I fix it type places right where you can bring your phone
into like a shop at the mall and they'll fix your screen.
Yes.
And the last time I looked at that is they wanted $900 to replace the
screen on the ipad Pro and it was $1200 to buy an entirely new one.
That could be for the ipad.
I know my wife had,
she brought her phone to one of those places to replace the screen and it was, I mean,
it was like 100 bucks, which I thought was, was fine.
And maybe that is true for the more common
kind of, more common things. But,
well, I should also, it was just the glass, it wasn't like the,
the display or anything and the ipads could be different.
I don't know.
Well, the other thing is,
I've also had a friend who took their phone to one of those ifixit place whatevers
and
they destroyed her phone and gave her a replacement
that had half as much storage and we're like,
too bad.
I'm not surprised by that actually. And that's the problem is it's a hit or miss.
You might get a really great car mechanic
and you might get a car mechanic and your wheels fall off a block later.
That's always been a problem, right?
Like the, in the history of cars that's always been an issue.
Ideally what this mark is doing is trying to say, like, look, this is a good mechanic.
This is a bad mechanic. This is a good product. This is a bad product.
And
that's,
and I want this, I want more of this. We need to have this kind of maturity.
Like,
I worry that there's not even a hint of what they'd be testing for or looking for,
to assign this mark.
Like, well, that's how we're gonna end this show because we've been talking,
I feel like in circles about
the,
the same thing for, for half an hour.
But you're right. Like
we're pretending
all of the actually hard problems have been answered and we
haven't answered any of those and it's still a ridiculous conversation.
I mean,
we're pretending that we know the answers and we
haven't even figured out what the questions are.
No, no, we haven't. This is gonna be,
this is gonna be wild. I think. I don't,
I don't know what's going to come of this. I guess.
Here's, here's the one thing I'll say, here's how I'm going to end.
This is my final comment on this topic, whatever the FCC does,
it's gonna suck.
We know that,
but that's ok
because you have to start somewhere and it's ok to suck.
It's just as long as they, they make a point to say, we know what,
this sucks and we're gonna work on it like that's the key, right.
The problem is we also, we just stuck with a bad standard for two decades.
I hope not. But it is
possible.
I, I think it will have to change because like, I sent you that link to like,
those water facilities being attacked in the US.
Like IOT that controls skater systems that
controls life critical stuff like water power.
We have to change because like, I, I, my city went through the whole, like, oh,
we might not have water.
Oops, it's a little scary. Like there were a lot of people who were freaked out
because it should be, you literally can't live without water and you can,
it's pretty important.
Like where are we going to truck and clean water for a million people? From
nowhere? For not so much.
I don't care about consumer devices as much as
I do about these kind of back end things.
And I, I think there is where this is going to start impacting because
it's getting bad enough that we can no longer ignore it.
I mean, I agree.
I don't, I don't think this is, I mean,
this FCC thing is specifically for consumer devices.
Let's hope they do something maybe a little more sane for that level.
But yeah, I mean, I don't know, I'm just, I'm, I'm gonna end this one. I,
every freaking time I feel like we try talking about
one of these things we just end up with like
the problem is harder than any of us imagined.
Well, if it wasn't, it would have been solved, I guess
I
bias
why
we, so
this problem yet.
Well, because it's really hard
and, and I guess on the plus side,
at least we're, we're looking at it and talking about it, which is really important.
So, all right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you very much for listening.
Go to open
source
podcast.com. Head up the show, not Suzy Pando says podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.