I feel bad for the archaeologist who like,
listens to all the raw audio to try and suss out what the hell happened in 2020
that's staying in.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Curtsy Fried and my partner in breakfast, Josh Bresser.
All right. I, I don't even want to figure this out. I will start with
vaguely related to breakfast.
There was a solar eclipse this morning where I live. It was not where you live.
I actually looked so I could tell you if it was, but it wasn't.
And I got up at five o'clock in the morning to look at an eclipse
and it was totally worth it. It was only partial, but it was still awesome.
Well, I still,
to this day remember seeing Haley's comet
through a reasonably good telescope at the,
at the science museum when I was a kid.
I remember when I was a child
it was like pizza hut or, or mcdonald's or somewhere like that,
sold a little like cardboard telescope you got
in their like kids' value meal or whatever.
-- They was
-- happy meal. The meals were happy.
Well, the meals were happy only at mcdonald's everywhere else.
It's just, you know, contempt and neglect.
But
yeah, it was like a little telescope to look at Haley's Comet. In hindsight.
I wish I'd kept it because I'm sure that would be a fascinating
piece of, you know, just history. But
yeah, it was, that was, man, I was young. That was a long time ago.
One thing I love is when people show those pictures of
the old mcdonald's Happy Meal toys from 2030 years ago.
-- And they are just so garbagey.
-- Some of, yeah, they were, they were bad.
I've got, for some reason,
I found some at my parents' house when I was cleaning something out about a year ago.
It's like some weird little Mario things and like they're just, they're garbage.
They're so bad. Although the toys today are terrible as well.
-- I won't say they're any
-- better. Kinder surprise eggs have terrible toys in them.
-- Now,
-- don't get me started on kinder surprise eggs.
They are literally illegal in the United States and you
have no idea how annoyed I am because of that.
But I mean, kinder surprise eggs are actually illegal for a very good reason,
which is, you can't have non food stuff in food, which
when they made that law, I think it was in the thirties in the U si.
Mean, that was a real problem. You know, we're,
I, I don't want to be eating food that has industrial shavings in it to, you know,
bulk and
-- to bulk it up or whatever.
-- I mean,
I understand the intent of the law
but it doesn't mean I can't be angry that I am
unable to enjoy a kinder surprise egg in the United States.
Well,
the other thing is that the quality of their chocolate has dropped drastically,
like my son won't even eat them anymore.
He kind of crushes them open and
looks disappointed and kind of looks at me and I'm like, sorry, bro,
I haven't had one in almost two years now because
it was, it was the last time I was in Canada. Every time I go to Canada, I have them
and I did not attempt to smuggle any out this time.
-- And I don't remember why that was, uh,
-- because it's a 2000 $500 fine.
Remember I looked it up because I was going to mail you some
-- and you're like, don't do that. And I'm like, why not? Yeah.
-- Right. Right.
I definitely don't break that law all the time. Uh, but anyway, anyway,
what are, what are we talking about? Something about breakfast?
I don't totally understand this one.
-- So,
-- yeah, breakfast.
Well, it's, it's what's interesting to me is, is people really poo poo breakfast
and it is literally the start of the day. It's how you get going.
It's, you know, it's the,
for the rest of your day.
I mean, not necessarily like,
-- I don't eat breakfast a lot and who cares
-- when you're crouchy,
that's just normal.
Like, it doesn't matter if I eat breakfast or not.
Well,
and what I love though is they've done all these studies
that show essentially people's blood glucose levels are directly correlated to,
you know, decision making, both ability.
And for example, all those studies where they've, you know,
done with parole boards and judges and looked at, you know,
their decisions before and after lunchtime
and it consistently boils down to, you know, if you're having a parole hearing,
you better hope that it's right after the judges.
-- I mean,
-- is it because you eat though,
the story you sent me seems to focus on a break more so than necessarily consuming
-- some sort of energy.
-- Well, it's a combination of both, right?
It's, it's a combination of
either breaks or eating people
with low blood glucose can't think. Right.
I mean, Snickers, you know, you're, you're not you when you're hungry
so eat candy to fix it.
Well, as a short term solution.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean,
I can relate to this because I think there
are countless instances is where when I am hungry,
overly hungry,
it can be very difficult to concentrate. I will not argue with that point.
Well, so for example,
there was that thread on Twitter a week or two
ago talking about incident response and kind of how,
you know,
what kind of warnings or what would you tell companies about and I pointed out like,
well, when you're doing incident response,
are you planning to let your people take breaks and sleep and maybe
eat and exercise because these things can take more than a day?
No one ever does that. And people make terrible mistakes when they're tired.
Remember all the DHS Fusion Centers and stuff? They were building out a long time ago
and same in Canada, they were building out this, you know,
terrorism kind of management center.
And the press got a hold of it and ran with the story like, oh,
look at this opulent terrorism management center.
It has an exercise room and it's like, yeah,
because these people might be like living in this building for two weeks
while dealing with something. So
yeah,
-- like they need to shower, you know, they need to sleep.
-- This is something
I, I can totally relate to this. I mean,
there's, I think a lot of cultural push behind some of this.
I mean, one of my favorite examples is I remember back in the day
when I would work on Firefox and Mozilla at Red Hat,
I had built a little bot that would play a loud noise at my computer when
the build finished because the build took hours
and hours and hours to build these things
because it was very common that I would fall asleep at my desk
while trying to get things to rebuild because there would be the
developers would do what needed to be done to build a package.
And then often they were in Europe and I would take over
and I would basically stay up all night long till they showed back up.
And then I would go to sleep, which of course,
at like three in the morning I'm making awful decisions.
And I, I mean, I remember that but that was
kind of expected and no one thought that was weird.
And in hindsight, it's like this was ridiculous. It's a miracle.
We didn't completely break something.
I remember reading,
looking up some studies because I was working for
a company that wanted to essentially have 24 7 coverage
and was toying with the idea of essentially making us work
like swing shifts and day shifts and switching it around.
And I'm like, no, don't do that
because
you will mess with people's sleep patterns and
it just won't work.
And I found two fascinating studies. One was an Israeli study essentially.
Once you've been awake for about three or four days,
it's the equivalent of being legally drunk,
like you can function and you can do sort of
mechanical things or things that you've been drilled on.
Yeah. If you want to get a creative decision or thought out of this person. No,
I'm skeptical. It even takes a couple of days of being awake. I would bet one day
if you don't sleep one night, I bet your decision making is completely impaired.
And then what was really fascinating is I found a study from the first Gulf War
where they had given the pilots, uh,
various medication that they could optionally use.
And what was interesting is the younger pilots tended to take the
stimulants before missions and the older pilots were tending to take the relaxant
after the mission so that they could get good sleep.
And so it's, it's interesting that, you know, these, these men,
because back then basically combat pilots were all men.
Uh, but the, the, the younger and the older ones had two very,
very different strategies that kind of fit with how
we think of young men and older men.
Right? Older men in theory are a little bit wiser and we value our sleep a bit more.
Well, no, no, I remember being young and, you know,
getting four hours of sleep and being like, oh, I'm gonna eat some bacon and eggs.
I'll be great.
And in hindsight I did,
I mean,
there was a lot of work I probably thought was good at the time.
But in hindsight,
if I had a nap probably would have taken half as long and been twice as good.
Oh,
without question. I remember those days. Well, it's,
-- I always think of the famous quote, youth is wasted on the young.
-- Yeah, absolutely.
And what that jerk did to my knees.
Seriously. What's up with that guy?
I, I understand this and I can also understand where it's coming from.
But I also think
there is,
I, I'm, I'm not saying either group is right or wrong.
I think it's easy to say, oh, the old people took the relaxing drugs.
They're much smarter
but it's, it's different. I mean, I know as, as being
an old, old person now will say
my mind isn't as quick or as sharp as it used to be.
I'm completely familiar with that and I will never say a,
that I possess some knowledge that no one else
does because of my age because you just,
you don't, I mean, I think it's,
it's just different.
-- Well, I think back in the olden days it was, it was simply survivor
-- bias.
-- Everything is survivor bias.
-- Yeah.
You know what? Yeah, I'll take that.
But what it, what it really gets me is because for example,
these recent ransomware incidents where,
you know,
they paid the ransomware but actually recovered the data faster than
they could with the ransomware keys being actually given to them.
Yeah, that was the pipeline, supposedly.
Well, from what I've read, I mean, part of this too is who freaking knows
because
in, in these sort of events
you get so much conflicting information,
it's very difficult to understand what's real and what's fake, you can hardly tell.
-- And I think well, or
-- misinterpreted or misread. Right.
And,
and I'm sure part of this is the people involved are extremely overworked and tired.
And they're doing their best,
but at times they might say the wrong thing or the wrong information might slip out.
You don't want out and then people start making crap up to
fill in the gaps and you end up with a mess.
What really frustrates me about this whole thing is there's
a ton of organizations that
constantly handle emergencies relatively gracefully.
What comes to mind is
the fire department, the police department and, you know, emergency health.
-- The
-- military is another good example
that the military doesn't handle
sort of day to day constant ongoing stuff at home.
Like the fire department does.
No, but, but they're a better example,
I think in the context of security because security is,
you don't know what you're going to be like, I wake up in the morning and think,
what am I going to do today?
-- In most instances, you
-- might encounter a new type of problem,
but fundamentally you're going to triage vulnerabilities and see
if they need to get fixed or not.
I mean, to a degree, but this is, I think closer to military maybe than,
than police and fire.
And the point is all of these organizations heavily rely on training
because when you're scared or when you're tired
or when you don't exactly know what's going on
or when you don't have leadership barking the right thing at you at the right time,
you default back to your training
and it's one of those things.
That's really funny where I think about, like, I, my,
my neighbor is a firefighter and I'll talk to.
He'll, it was really wild.
He was showing me all, like,
their new systems for logging events and everything
and it's like you people have to,
like, log when you go pee.
It's amazing.
But anyway, the point is they train to death and the reason is because
they're going to be in a situation where they're not going to be able
to think and they just start doing whatever the training taught them to do.
And like in, in security and even in it to a degree,
-- we don't do anything like that
-- even worse.
We generally don't have any agreed upon doctrine or training.
We, and even places that do sort of have training or people who take certifications,
which is a form of training, there's no drills.
Right. Well, there's what the yearly tabletop exercise, right.
Which if you're lucky,
-- I've never seen one of those and I've worked at a couple of
-- big, we do them all the time.
They're, they're good, good fun. Actually, I have, I will put a link in the show
to, I, I ran a session at RS A some years back where I called it,
I think dungeons and data.
But it was basically like,
I ran a tabletop.
There were a lot of people in the room, I have a blog post about it, but it was,
it was all like dice and
it got really silly and it was super fun.
But, I mean, part of the problem I think with, like,
tabletop is they generally are extremely boring.
And so no one really cares.
It's well and carving out time. Right.
We could be doing some, you know, quote unquote actual useful work.
Uh, ok.
I don't like that attitude and I think that's
something else that kind of falls in line.
Right. Right. Because you think like, oh, breakfast doesn't matter.
Oh, training doesn't matter.
Right. Right.
And I think, saying things like the tabletop exercise is a waste of time.
It, it might have been the way you did it, but it shouldn't be if it's done. Right.
And I mean, we've all been through training. That was a waste of our time.
I'm not going to, I'm not going to claim
that that all training is valuable. But the point is if you do this stuff, right. It
is not a waste of time.
I have been to training that I've walked out of thinking this is amazing.
And I've been to training that.
I walked up thinking I am never getting that part of my life back.
Well, speaking of training. So, because I remember we were just Kvetching. I,
so I finally sat down
and paid 88 Swiss Francs, which is like $98 for
ISO
IEC
which is one of their two sort of information security standards.
The other 129 to 147 which is now an old version of is freely available.
-- But basically
-- the 2014 version is free. The 2018 version is now.
-- So
-- the although although I want to interject one thing, it was just announced,
I think like two days before we're recording this, that Katie Miso
and I think Art Mannion convinced
is
so to make the 2018 version free.
-- So at some point that should
-- show, I was kind of wondering like, really
anyways, the point is the first one is security techniques,
vulnerability disclosure.
And the second one that I had to pay for is security techniques,
vulnerability handling processes.
And I'm thinking, you know, because I'm paying 100 bucks for this document,
you know, and I asked you, how long do you think it was? Right? And what did you say?
I thought it was a couple of 100 pages.
-- Yeah.
-- No, it's 13.
Vulnerability handling is really hard.
Well, but I mean, well, technically if you go high enough level on anything, it's,
you know, like when World War two there, I said it
and that,
that was my thinking. But yes, you said it's 15 pages long
or 13 pages long.
So you paid approximately what, like eight bucks a page.
But here's the reality is actually like
99% of the stuff you and I know cold, but we've been doing it for 20 years.
And honestly,
there's some stuff in here with how they portray it and how they say it out loud.
It's like,
oh, yeah, you really want to make sure you do that.
So even
I, I, I'm beginning to realize that,
you know, there, there's been training and documentation that I think, oh,
it's terrible because I already know some of it or I've already experienced it.
But that, that's kind of not who the training is for.
Right. The training is for the new people.
And that's, you know, we're constantly kvetching about how, oh, infosec, you know,
it has millions of job postings that we can't hire for and blah, blah, blah, why not?
It's like,
well, I mean, I, I suspect one of the big factors is because we don't train people and,
and bring them in and teach them how to do this. It's like some, I
mean, we have the classic, you know,
I want to hire an intern with 20 years experience,
you know, I, I've literally gotten jobs because, and I quote,
we don't have to train you, Kurt, you can just start working like on day one, you know,
and, well, that's not really sustainable or, or a long term solution
-- to having a pipeline for bringing people in.
-- Right. Oh, absolutely. Absolutely.
And so I, I think,
you know, with respect to breakfast, it speaks to that whole,
you got to feed people at the beginning of the day, you gotta,
you gotta make sure they're taken care of.
They're trained, they're, it's the whole thing.
Not just, oh,
we're gonna try and magically hire people who just step in and start working.
-- Right.
-- And
yes,
it, it, well, there's also, oh, man, there's so much,
there's so much to impact in this.
It's,
I, I do think the,
I guess sensibleness and quality of life is a huge aspect of this,
that people often they, they don't take it into account.
And I think it's just kind of human nature to be like here's a pile of money.
I'm going to work you to death. It's like there's so much wrong with that attitude.
I mean, this is one of the reasons I,
I chose a lifestyle a long time ago so that I could have time with my kids and
I absolutely
will not work myself to death anymore. Like I would have when I was in my twenties.
I, I remember those days.
I mean, I thought that it was the, the more you worked, the, the,
the more it would pay off and the more it would be
respected and, and right, I mean,
I, I'm not, look,
I,
look, your laugh is completely justified because in hindsight, like
it's all a waste of time. I got nothing for it.
I, I look at this whole,
every time it comes up on Twitter or on the Web or something where somebody's like,
oh, my God, there's all these open source projects that the world relies upon
and they make zero money.
I mean, that guy, he,
he did the can has IP which just echoes back like your public IP address super useful
and
you know, he's like, it serves like a billion requests a day on blah, blah, blah.
And in total, he got something like 70 odd dollars in donations.
I mean, so there's a couple sides to this topic and this is something,
maybe we could talk about more in depth at some point.
But, like,
there are people who do open source who would love to get paid to work on it.
There's people who do it and don't want to get paid because they,
they like doing it and it's a hobby and it's fun.
And, I mean, I, I'm, I'm gonna tell you now, there's always the people who are like,
oh, do what you love and you won't work a day in your life.
Like, no, that is a lie. That is a complete lie.
Once you get paid to do something,
it completely changes everything
and it's quite often that something that was fun for you
becomes not fun now that you're getting paid to do it
well, and I find usually with that stuff, it's not so much the actual activity, it's
all the stuff wrapped around it.
So I enjoy open source and I enjoy doing open source security,
but I don't think I'll ever kind of want to deal with the,
some of the process and some of the political stuff that I've had
to deal with in the past because that made it very not fun.
Of course. Right.
And, and to a degree that can just be any company you work at, like, obviously,
do you have to do that annual bribery training because you're American?
Yeah. Yeah, I still take that it's not as bad as it used to be way back in the day.
The stuff I take now is slightly more palatable. But, yeah. Yeah,
it was,
you need to be American and a publicly traded company
and then there's all these really boring,
horrible training things you need to take and
they're like the freaking same every year.
Well, it's, well, it's not like it changed.
Yeah.
You'd think you'd spice it up a little bit or something, you know. But,
or you just recycle the same content and charge for it.
Uh, that's probably what it is.
I guess my thought is companies should make sure that.
And I'm speaking more metaphorically than actually, you know,
ensuring your employees have breakfast.
Although,
like, I've,
I've worked at places where there's no food on site and we're
talking like hundreds of people on site and there's a vending machine.
That's terrible. You know what my standard is?
I will not work anywhere that doesn't have free coffee.
You know, I'll never forget the first job I had out of college.
It was a small company that was part of IBM.
And then the original owner bought it back from IBM after like a decade.
And
they'd,
they'd been their own company for like six months at
this point and they were obviously hiring some new folks.
And
I remember I was talking to, I think he was a vice president of,
of software development
and he's like,
and he wouldn't shut up about the free coffee.
And I'm like, why do you keep talking about free coffee?
He said they made us pay for coffee at IBM. I was like, what?
And he's like, yeah, seriously, you had to pay for coffee there.
And as soon as we became our own company, again,
the first thing we did was bought a bunch of coffee machines.
I remember at
the start of the pandemic,
Alberta Health Services apparently was making people bring their own Kleenex
and stuff in and it's kind of like what's next?
Like toilet paper?
No, seriously. Right.
Because at some point, the office just needs to supply stuff,
whether it's toilet paper or coffee or pencils or post it notes
and those are shockingly expensive, but I digress.
-- Um Well, ok,
-- look,
but I think part of that discussion and this can kind of fold into the,
the bigger it picture is
there are kind of certain basic needs you need as a human and if those aren't met,
you end up with that like hierarchy of needs kicking in.
And if you're worried about getting toilet paper and, and coffee
you're not worried about whatever the thing is,
they're actually paying you to worry about.
Right. And same thing in, in, in, like, computers and it, and security is
if you've got people worried about not clicking fishing links,
then they're not worrying about the thing you're paying them to worry about.
I think that's all that needs to be said.
I mean,
it, but here's,
here's what's funny is it seems so obvious when you say something like that
yet.
If you look across the planet, there are an uncountable number of instances where
the basic needs aren't being met.
And so people are doing their, their performance suffers because of it
and yet
-- no one sees what should be an obvious fix. A perfect
-- example. My partner
is rather excited because last week her laptop
is slated for replacement.
And isn't that thing from like 2005 or something?
-- You said once
-- it's like eight years old,
I actually bought her a new battery because her
battery would hold like a 2030 minute charge.
That's madness. And did you get to expense that on your taxes?
The battery was like $30.
Laptop batteries are not expensive.
Like, like it's not a brand name, laptop battery, but who cares? Right.
It's a $30 battery probably won't catch fire.
It's probably fine.
But um, like literally, it's just and I'm thinking about this and
to me it's, if you spend $1000 on a laptop every three years, right. Typical
amortization is three years in the business world.
Right.
That's a dollar a day.
That's it. That's it. That's all I'm gonna say.
It's a dollar a day to give a person $1000 laptop every three years.
You know, and,
and let's go whole hog and get a really nice laptop
with a really good service plan on site support and everything.
That's $2000 a day. That's $2 a day.
And it kills me.
How many companies nickel and dime and just
are insane about hardware for technical people even.
Right.
Like, sure the sales people kind of get maybe not the greatest laptop but, you know,
when you're talking to developer
or
up like some sort of technical use of it, you know,
I upgraded the CPU on my desktop computer here from uh I originally had a really,
you know,
terrible Ryzen 2 3400 G because it was basically the
cheapest CPU that would get my computer running acceptably fast.
And I plan to buy a new CPU and then
that plan kind of went out the window and took an extra eight months. But man
spending the money on the R 3 5600 X.
Whoa, like my computer is about three times as fast as it was.
And I'm, I'm actually getting a lot more work done a lot faster.
-- But
-- I mean, this is that like total cost of ownership discussion.
And I mean, this comes up constantly in every industry where someone will say, oh,
we're cheaper than so and so
and so and so will say yes, but look at the total cost of ownership and of course,
when you're dealing with marketing materials,
you can't trust any of it because it's marketing materials.
Well, but this is like return on investment. I mean, no offense.
But how much of a return on investment do you need to justify? $2 a day on somebody?
$2 a day is a laptop. $2 a day is toilet paper. Really nice. Toilet paper.
$2 a day would be coffee.
I think there's a lot of organizations that don't look at it in that perspective,
they look at the upfront cost of something, not necessarily what it's going to mean.
I mean,
one of my favorite examples of this
is when you look at
like security stuff, right? Where people will look at.
Ok, we need a, a SIM we need endpoint protection, we need whatever fill it in
and
it is not uncommon at all for them to under scope everything they do.
And then your people end up in a position where, ok,
we can only store two days of log files.
But if we throw away all of the windows, event logs, then we can store four days of of,
of
logs and, you know,
like these are ridiculous decisions that at the end
of the day is gonna probably end up costing
magnitudes more than it would to just buy the
freaking extra disk to put in the machine.
But I, I don't know, I guess maybe, I don't know what to say.
Like I just, because the reality is on the one hand, you have $2 a day for coffee,
toilet paper and a new laptop.
On the other hand, you have companies that just, it would,
you might as well try and pull somebody's teeth out.
I, I don't know what to say. Maybe
-- if I have people found strategies that work to get this stuff. I don't know.
-- I mean,
my favorite example is to just say, don't work at those companies
because I think the reality is when you see a
company or an organization nickel and diming to this point,
that's not a sign of a healthy organization, right?
That, that's a company that's in trouble
again. Talking about some studies.
But there's been a lot of studies in the
last few years that have shown that being poor,
shortens your life.
It stresses you out. It's, you know, people are constantly worrying. Yeah.
It literally changes your DNA.
You know, people are worried, like, do I pay the electric bill or do I buy food?
You know, and depending on where you live,
that's a hard choice because you either freeze to death or starve to death
-- and,
-- and, and
I'm sure this affects management when you're at a
company that will say is on the downward slope
to some of these companies aren't even on downward slopes. They're just
ridiculous.
But
I,
I don't think it's, you can't just say it's only bad companies that do this.
There are quote unquote good companies that do this.
There are governments that do this. You know,
there's
governments are weird for their own reason.
They, they, they fall into their own special category
that I would not compare to a company.
Part of it is to maybe be more aware of this because
again,
this is one of the reasons I left the last company I work for is
just that there were a lot of little stressors that were adding up to be
really big stressors.
So I left,
I
get it because I've met a lot of people in the it industry who are really stressed out
and I don't think they need to be,
-- that's all the people in the it industry,
-- I guess,
I guess my advice maybe is take a personal sort of stress inventory and maybe, I mean,
money's nice but not being super stressed out all the time and being able to
-- sleep is I suspect it's nicer than having more money
-- probably to a degree.
-- I mean, that's easy to say obviously, but well
-- above what is that magic,
the number they found like above,
I think it's $80,000 us and pretty much the western world above that, the,
the return on happiness is minimal.
That's, that's my understanding.
So, and again, we're pretty privileged to be like, 0 $80,000
easy, you know, I get it.
It's, that's a, that is definitely I'm coming from a place of privilege to say that.
Yep. Yep. Absolutely.
-- So,
-- yeah, I don't know.
I, I feel like this one, we started on breakfast and we wandered around, but I,
I guess fundamentally
the purpose of all of this strange conversation is just that
I think there's this aspect of self care
that
we don't do a very good job of and it's easy to say, oh, take better care of yourself
and no one is really going to do it
-- well, or
-- sometimes they're not allowed to
how many places are like, oh, we want you to, you know,
take care of yourself. So take breaks if you need to.
But also if you don't get your work done, we're going to smack you one.
Yeah. Right. Right. Exactly.
Exactly. And, and that's
what percentage of people can ask their boss to
take a one hour nap right now in this moment
and
get a yes
man. A one hour nap sounds good. Getting up at 5 a.m. is right
when you're over 40 when you're,
that's true.
Although I would have been going to bed at 5 a.m. in the younger days. But,
-- and uh anyway, anyway,
-- but also I think with the self care,
there's also the piece of maybe if you are management or a boss allow, like,
encourage it and actually
do something to make their life a little bit better.
-- Maybe let them take a half hour break.
-- If you are a people manager
and you talk about self care,
you have to live the example because if you talk about self care,
but you're running yourself into the ground.
Your people look at that and think
I need to work like they do.
-- Yeah, the whole Japanese boss thing. Exactly.
-- Exactly. All right.
So I think we should call it here. This is a lovely place to stop.
So thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up for
not UZ
Pound do says podcast.
Hashtag You hit us up on social media and Kurt, you have a phenomenal rest of your day.
The