Hello and welcome to episode 93 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
Right. I'm just gonna call 2018 as the year that keeps on giving
because if, if I would have told you even say six months ago
that there's going to be a privilege escalation flaw in the beep program.
You would have laughed at me and told me I'm an idiot
and, and
like, I don't even know, like, beep.
Just,
well, that's what I don't even know. This is what I hate about.
All these old UNIX utilities is
so many of these old UNIX utilities require
some degree of privileged access,
especially when they interact with hardware because there was, like,
no sound subsystem.
Like I, you know,
you and I probably both owned our first several computers didn't have, like, sound,
it had the, the built in.
Is it even
a
speaker elect?
It,
it didn't make tones, it just, it beeped or it
didn't beep.
Right.
And it, it seemed to work back in the day and apparently now beep needs to be set U ID
to beep.
Yeah, because it's talking of hardware.
I mean,
unless there's like, well,
yeah,
just, yes, I mean, because here's the thing, like, what are we better off with,
like a kernel interface for beep
or?
Yeah, exactly.
Well, remember that's how I used to play audio files. Right.
Cap the A U file into DEV audio.
I remember that.
And, you know,
I'll never forget there was way back in the day
I was working on an open source project and,
and we thought, wouldn't it be a neat Easter egg
if you caned the binary to DEV audio
and it, it like, played something,
right?
Because it would be like a hidden audio file
in the binary because I remember that too.
That'd always be the joke you do
is you don't log into their computer,
you know, V SSH and then just like, start catting random garbage into
audio and it would,
it would scare them half to death. It was, it was lovely.
I remember and this terminal escape sequence is control G,
right?
And you, if you were chatting with somebody on like IRC,
you could fire off a line of control GS at them in their computer would just be like,
ah, yes, those are the good old days.
And, and that does still work, but, well, not in Irc maybe.
Well, and it's also come up again with, uh people have discovered, of course,
people cut and paste stuff from web pages into their command line.
Like all of those new age Softwares that are like to install this, you know,
type in curl hyphen blah, blah, blah pipe sh.
And it's like, oh, that's a little scary.
But then it's like, oh, wait, you can like hide
characters in there either using um
unicode
or like a really small font or like
a white font on a white background
and people will just cut and paste,
slam it into the command line and you could even embed like a new line so
that they don't even really get a chance to like view it before it like executes,
you know, put a new line in the middle of the command.
Oh Man, that happens to me all the time where if you, if you drag too far,
you end up with a new line.
So when you paste it, it hits enter.
Yeah,
I know.
Go beep and I don't,
I don't think there's much else to say.
Yeah. Well, and, but here's the best part about the beep thing
is remember they provided sort of a
joke patch for it,
right?
And
the patch for
beep, OK? This is going to get a little confusing.
You apply patches in UNIX called the utility called patch.
So when you use patch to apply the patch to beep, the patch exploits patch
and then you end up with patch running arbitrary code as these are running the patch,
right?
Because of a 30 year old feature
I,
right. And that, that's the second half to this story. It's just
old code keeps giving.
This is more than I can handle. It's, it's, I don't even know if, is it old code even is
like, 30 years old. Yeah,
it is.
When I started
I looked in the last release was, I think in 2012.
Yeah, it's not maintained anymore because it's
right.
It feels like one of those things that probably doesn't need a lot of attention.
Let's face it.
If, if we let people keep developing it, it's gonna just turn into emacs someday
and we don't, we don't need that. We have one. We don't need to.
So, yeah. So what happened in patch is there?
So patch basically applies a patch file to a set of other files and,
or it can generate a patch file by comparing two sets of files.
Right. So the idea
doesn't create patch files. Diff creates patch files. Oh, sorry. Yeah.
Just patches.
I thought I had a copy of patch that would actually create the patch file.
Please say, I hope that doesn't exist because that would be terrible if it did.
Oh, ok. Right. Yeah. Sorry. You're right. Yeah, it's different.
It's, it's been a long time since I've had to do this because quite honestly,
everything just happens and get now magically.
It's true. It's true. It's, it's much easier than it used to be. Thank God.
All this stuff is being abstracted from people.
But so yeah, long story short, sorry.
Um
patch
applies a patch
to
uh file or files,
creates new files. Uh can delete files, can modify what's in the files.
Uh The format's
conceptually simple. You
have a file name and then plus space content or minus.
Yeah, I'm getting to that. I'm getting to that.
So, and, and conceptually what the a patch file typically looks like is
here's the file we're going to interact with.
Here's the list of interactions and
it can also have stuff like the line number.
So it, you know, knows where to go in the file and it's got, you know,
um essentially a plus or minus, either
delete this, delete this line or add this line and then when you're modifying a line,
you'll have like the delete the line and then the, you know, plus this new line.
Cool. Right. Conceptually simple. Effective.
Oh,
wouldn't it be awesome if you could have a patch file that could like
cause your uh text editor to fire off so that you could like interact with
the file while you're patching it like that. Actually,
honestly, 20 years ago seems kind of useful.
So of course, they add this
and of course it,
well, here's the thing you need to a text editor on a UNIX system.
Well, what do we have that everybody has?
Ed Ed is the only editor that's everywhere. Yes.
Right. Viv
No V I and
VR,
well VM came after V I so V I didn't even exist back in those days.
But V I, like, I remember being on systems that didn't have V Mas or yeah,
didn't even have V I like so UNIX.
Right. And, and that's so, that's important.
But, you know, putting on the Geezer hat for a minute, you had a couple of scenarios,
one
was,
the system was underpowered and so the
admin either wouldn't install or would disable V
space
or, or memory was usually the issue, right? Ed
used very little memory and, and you could do the work you needed to do.
You'd also have admins like an admin would hate V I and they would disable it.
So you can only use emacs if you logged into the system.
Like what's the matter with you? You monster?
Right. Or alternatively,
um
I remember I worked with an admin once who
hated emacs and claimed it used too much memory.
I'm like, that's, that's a line, you know it, but whatever. So he uninstalled it
you had to
use
or more to the point.
I've dealt with systems where it was installed as a turnkey,
like accounting system and too bad.
There's no editor.
Sure. Right. Right. Well, except Ed or Cisco routers, man. I, I remember I learned Ed
because of Cisco routers because on every Cisco router there was Ed.
And so if you had to edit a configuration file, you could just you know,
open it up and Ed do what you needed to do and then keep going,
see. And here's what really blows me away is like
Mac O West has Ed, like the most recent version of Mac Os has Ed.
Why wouldn't
it,
Ed?
So the beauty is this patch file has its way to
essentially you can have a line
and it passes that line to Ed and Ed processes that line.
Now, Ed being a text editor, of course on a UNIX system,
you're inside of your text editor
and you want to run a command.
And again, this is before the days of fancy tools like screen or you know,
having a graphical user interface or you know, you're on basically 300 bod dial up.
So that means like 300 characters per second.
So
pretty much all the text editors had some facility internally to run commands,
right?
Sure.
I think basically they all still do pretty much eviv
I Yeah.
Anyway, so Ed had this
and so the beauty is in patch,
you can add a line of text to a patch file that will then be passed to Ed
and that text line will trigger Ed to then execute an arbitrary
shell command or commands as much as you want. Basically.
So you can basically create patch files that when applied will
cause command and code execution as whoever's applying the patch file,
right?
And the beauty is Ed, I guess kind of like a lot of people, you know,
is also like, well, this could be dangerous.
So if you run Ed hyphen R, it's Ed in restricted mode and it doesn't allow,
for example, command execution
seems like a good idea
except it's not the default. Whoops. Right.
So what free Bs D did is free BS D created a,
there's now a slash bin slash
Ed and a slash bin slash red.
So there's like a copy of that runs in restricted mode by default.
And they then also changed,
um I believe they changed the patch source code to then point at
that red editor so that they wouldn't have command execution as a possibility.
So, you know, of course, this got caught in 2015 by free BS D. And of course,
I'll be honest, most of us UNIX guys, we, we tend to stay in our own UNIX worlds
really.
You know,
like I, I have no idea what Solaris
or so
Os is doing anymore.
I,
I agree, I've really only run Linux
for probably the last five or six years. And I mean, I run Mac O
now, which is a form of UNIX, but quite honestly, I don't dig around it all that much.
I just,
and,
and more to the point there's no reason to because like either
I get my patches from Apple and install them or I don't,
that's it. Those are my options as far as security on a Mac go.
So, yeah, I mean, it's just,
I was, I was poking around, I mean, there is a ton of old,
uh like if you look at it on a Linux system is the GNU Core
Ils is the package you want to take a poke
at like that's kind of like the oldest craftiest stuff.
Um And I don't mean Cruft necessarily and like it's bad, bad code.
It's just, it's crufty in that.
It's like, literally a lot of this code is older than the people now using it.
It's a really good point. It is really old, isn't it?
Yeah.
And I don't mean just like my kids who are seven, but I mean,
like administrators running these systems,
you know,
it doesn't matter how old the code is sometimes, I mean,
well, because
it's from a different era,
it comes from a different era where, for example, back in this era,
how did you get a patch file?
He downloaded it off the B BS, right?
Or off an MTP server.
And it was essentially a relatively trusted way because
like,
for example, doing a man in the middle attack that was like Black magic 20 years ago.
Like, I remember when tools
unheard of came out to do art poisoning and we're like, oh my God, my local subnet
because we didn't have switches, we all had hubs.
Yes. You know,
and then like, art poisoning came along and we're like, oh God,
we have to get smart switches and we have to configure the switches not to be dumb.
And that was like, really expensive.
We're talking hundreds of dollars per port and now it's, you know,
these things are like 20 bucks,
you know, and they just do this all by default.
Um,
so that's the thing, right? Like if somebody emailed me a patch file, like
that was because I was on, like, the Linux
mailing list or whatever. And they're like, oh here's this bug boom. The deve,
you know, the DEV just mailed me a patch.
I applied it and hey, my system stopped crashing. But part of it too, a lot of projects
didn't use source code control
because I mean, the Linux kernel used FTP
for managing the source code.
I mean, I remember like CV S was terrible but it's all we had.
And that's the other thing is, is when you look at the ecosystem back then, yeah,
you had like CV S, you had patch, you had diff
you had like some very basic text editors
and, and, and devs made these things work together in ways that
assumed
a completely trusted environment of a DEV on his workstation
working with other devs who he like literally
has, you know, known for since college or whatever, right?
Highly trusted groups of people,
you know, like II, I guess it would be like um
the pope and the cardinals, right?
All these cardinals know each other for like, 50 years.
Right.
So, when they elect a Pope,
it's a pretty high trust exercise because it's like everybody in
the room voting has known each other for like 50 years.
You know, it'd be hard to get an imposter.
Uh,
yeah, that's, that's probably fair.
There
was,
there was no concept of a pull request or anything like that.
I mean, it was, it was like an email list and if you were a nobody,
they were going to be like, who's this guy go with? And then they would thrash you
and your code
and then you lick your wounds and come back.
And after about the 10 or 20th time that happened, they might,
they might start talking to you and accept you into the,
the barrier to entry was really high, wasn't it?
The barrier to entry was very mean.
It was, it was and that's,
you know, we laugh but in all seriousness
that
it turned tech into what it is today with all of its
significant structural, I think we can probably use the word
misogyny without being
too out there.
Sadly,
yeah, I mean, you're right, you're right. It's not funny.
No, it's uh so anyways um yeah, I mean, that's the thing, right?
We come from this environment where it's everything is extremely high trust,
like literally
like I remember doing using Open BS D and like I would talk to the developers on IRC,
you know, Yeah, totally.
But the thing is like, the only people that kind of knew,
like you had to be in the in crowd to know about that and the
only way to be in the in crowd and know about that was to,
like,
jump through the flaming hoops and spiked pits
and, or like
the way I got into, Linux is a friend of mine was like,
you know, he introduced me to Os Two,
which was a heck of a lot better than Windows 3.11
I could now run two programs at the same time.
It was pretty fantastic.
And then he introduced me to Linux and I'm like, wow, this gooey stuff is amazing.
And then I saw the N CS, a mosaic web browser
and I basically just about lost my mind because I was like, oh my God,
that is the because I, you know, that's the most amazing thing I've ever seen.
I've only used Telnet and FTP up to that point
and
the web browser uh
didn't really use gopher because like, what's the point of that?
Well, there is some stuff but no,
but nothing fun or interesting,
not like web pages, man.
And so, you know, like this era is
completely different,
like literally everybody knew everybody.
So you,
you,
you've got me thinking and this isn't really where
I expected this conversation to go in any way.
Nor was this something I was really thinking about. But
you have a very reasonable point in pointing out that a lot of our
tools and a lot of our processes we use are from 20 plus years ago
and that's not the world we live in today at all. And, and I think it's,
it would be
time to seriously think about a lot of what we do in that context.
And I can see this in security man.
I mean, how much stuff like passwords are my favorite, you know,
uh whipping whipping boy here of
like
how long did we tell people you have to change your passwords every 90 days?
And there are still people
that I hear that are saying, oh no, you have to do that and,
and you should do it because uh people reuse passwords on site or,
or people and there's all these excuses and I'm like,
none of this makes sense.
Yeah, exactly one.
And what I love there is the guy that actually
started that recommendation has officially apologized for it and said,
please, please don't.
Um
And part of it too is I, you know, like I look at some of these things like
some of it, we just can't do like, for example, you know,
typically when you join a company,
they do at least some minimal level of background check to like
make sure that your name is correct for like tax purposes,
right? Like you are who you are, you have the right
tax identification number, SSN si whatever it is,
you know, because so the tax office doesn't spank them
and,
you know, or like,
I remember when I was working for a company that got bought by a larger
company and they all the larger company
required a seven year background check through.
Um, what was it, choice point was
one of those, you know,
consumer
information holding bureaus, like aqui fact, but
more stuff
and, you know, but like, do open source projects, do that or any
software projects? Really? No, of course not.
Well, well, should they, I mean, I don't think they should.
I, I don't, I don't like the idea.
I would generally agree.
Um, you know, but that's the point is like,
what security kind of controls can or should a
software project put on the people
adding code to it?
That, that, that's a fair question
and, and I would back it up even more and say,
what can they do because
funnily enough, you know, that whole GDPR thing coming along in uh what, two months,
like one month, dude, from the time we're recording.
It's, that's
true.
Like it's May 25th, I believe,
which is
very
soon.
Yeah, that's coming up,
you
know,
on that.
Like, I mean, can I even legally require, like, oh,
I don't want to deal with that. So,
yeah, I mean, how do we,
I mean, the good news is as far as I can tell
in the open source world.
As far as I know and readers, if I am wrong,
please please please let us know because I would love to know about this.
We,
we don't have readers or listeners, sorry.
But as far as I know, there has never been like a truly sort of organized malicious
actor or actors
who have like joined a project to get hostile code in
that we know of that we know of.
Yeah, I was going to say the second thing being some code, the quality like, hm,
well, so here's the thing, I actually,
I've been thinking about this lately for some other reasons,
but this is a problem that exists in any organization.
It's not just open.
I mean,
well,
it's far worse and close source because they're
the only people that might ever know.
Well, now,
now here's something to cook your noodle if you look at an organization with,
say 100,000 employees and there are many of them in the world.
I, I would guess they have more than 100
insiders that are there specifically with malicious intent, be it.
They, they entered the organization willfully to deceive or
they're disgruntled and someone approached them with some sort of opportunity.
There's a million things it could be right.
But anyway,
you know, there's insiders and
it's a similar problem in open source. It is conceivable.
Somebody could join a project as an insider
and in an attempt to subvert the project in some way.
And alternatively,
there are people who just suck at programming
that are there too
and there's people who just make legitimate mistakes. There's right.
And that's the third thing,
like everyone makes mistakes.
Like the open SSH, like the thing I always point to is open SSH, has security bugs.
If those guys can't get, they're literally the best in the world. Right?
If they can't get it. Right. And they even have some
trivial security bugs and like, remember that code that was unused and
was all like,
should have been removed and they just didn't remove a bunch of dead code and
it happens. But anyway, so here's my point is that
we're approaching a place now in technology where
we don't have full control over what's going on and we, we maybe never did.
We
did,
we
it was a, it was OK. That's fair. We'll say it wasn't a problem before.
And so this is where really
it's coming down to things like mitigating technologies are what's
more important than necessarily focusing on correctness of the,
the end product,
right?
Where, where this is, where putting things, you know, you've got your product,
you might or project whatever you wanna call it, you've got your, your application
and
maybe, you know, you did some sort of analysis, you've got your static analysis,
it's been fuzzed to death by different people, whatever.
There's all kinds of stuff that's happened
and then you go another layer.
And now let's say you're running it in a container, right?
And you've got various things where the container is restricting it.
And then you've got your host Os and the host Os
is doing things and you've got something monitoring the application,
you got something monitoring the container,
you got something monitoring the host OS
and
individually, these things aren't necessarily useful, nor are they 100%.
But when you start putting them together,
you start approaching
100% you'll never get there. But it becomes much, much, much more difficult.
And every time you add a layer,
the burden on an attacker goes up
substantially
well. But this also leads to the second point of
having all that is no good if you don't have response, right?
Because if an attacker can just sit there and wail
away on it all day long with no response,
right?
And that's the second thing is you need detection and then some sort of action to,
you know, ideally correct the system or harden it or whatever.
And that's one thing where I love open source, right?
Because open source,
like the majority of security flaws in the open source world are fixed super quick,
like pretty much as fast as the devs can
do it.
Yes, they are.
But I mean, well, in this was, I mean,
this is a topic talking to Rami last time was the fact that even though these projects
are fixing things quickly.
The people actually consuming it often. I don't even know what's happened. Right.
That's, that's a very big known problem.
And that's, you know, one of the reasons why I keep trying to get CV,
data to be more accessible and easy to get because then you can at
least label these problems and give people a chance to know about these problems.
Um
And yeah, I mean, consuming, this is hard, especially now,
like how well trick question, but how much software do you have on your workstation
or on a server? And the answer is like a lot,
that's not a trick question. The answer is infinity.
It might as well be infinity because I can't possibly keep track of it. All right.
Yeah. So
no, I, I do worry about some of these old timey tools and um
cause there's a lot of tools that
people interact with constantly without really thinking about
it.
Yeah. Again, had you told me that that patch has a security issue?
I'd be like you're an idiot, but that's not even possible.
What are you talking about?
And it turns out it does.
So,
and, and now, now here's the thing is the answer to get rid of patch.
I,
we, we do need
it.
Uh
Yes.
And
it, it, but here's the thing too and this is one of the things that gets me.
It's basically unmaintained. It hasn't been updated since 2012.
I, I know, there's a team that, that's dealing with this now. But like
you could argue this is critical infrastructure
and
it's abandon wear. Like what is up with that?
Well, it, it from a functional perspective, it's essentially complete,
right? It does what it does.
Yes,
it's like LS
from a functional perspective. LS is largely complete,
you know, and it, it, these util the thing to remember,
like especially with the UNIX velocity of have a tool that does one thing does it well
and you know, learn to love pipe and smash things together.
A lot of these tools like I'm just looking at core
ILS bin
and I mean,
there's a lot of stuff in here that
could very easily have code execution flaws uh base 32 base 64
base name. Oh God
C imagine if cat had some
thing.
Uh But you know, there's things like, for example,
unique and sort they do some relatively
useful things that also involve holding some very large
data. Imagine
that
unquestionably there are security flaws in that code
right
there. They're without, without a doubt.
Now, it could be extremely esoteric, but it doesn't matter because there, there's
like unique and sort literally 10 times a day,
I guess. Here's my point though is we know we can't fix all that source code.
We know that's out of the question.
And so this is where I think you need
to start using uh your layering your defenses right.
Uh Actually something I started working on at one point was trying to
figure out can I literally run every shell command in a container,
right, where I type unique and it executes in a container.
And then I pipe that and actually what I found out is uh for whatever reason, the,
the pipes would fail if IP too many things together.
It, it did some
wings and that's something I need to figure out. But then we get the point is
this is really what we need to be thinking about is having the ability to like
sandbox everything to death and having the ability
to log and know what's going on and,
and,
and understand, like, let me give you an example,
let's say you run unique 100 times a day, right?
And
every time you run it,
it never writes a file to disk,
right?
Or
I would love to have, you know,
if I could basically define a profile for a lot
of these commands where it's like all you get to
kind of do is return stuff to standard out.
Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And, and not just not saying this is all you can do,
but I think also having the ability to do some
profiling is part of the story here as well because
if
restricting something and saying, all right, you can't write to shell,
but all of a sudden every time you run unique, it's trying to write
uh you know, or execute a shell, I say,
OK, that's bad. But if all you're doing is restricting,
do you have a way to have something?
Tell you, hey, uh, unique is trying to execute a shell, maybe,
maybe something's going on here, right?
We actually could build this policy through Se Linux
right
today.
Oh,
no, totally.
And then that means I now have a E Linux policy file or logs, you know, with problems.
And
I, I, you know, the thing is I run Fedora and I like, I,
I still occasionally get those like Se Linux
policy violation pops up in the thing. And I'm just kind of like,
man,
go away, I don't care,
right?
And that, that's one of the problems with Se Linux is Se Linux creates alert video
in users,
right? Like, well, not
alert fatigue, but what the heck does this alert mean? Why did it happen?
I would have to really dig into it.
And I, I literally
consciously, I don't have time for that. Like I'm just,
I really don't.
No, I, I agree completely. And and this is where
we need to start investigating kind of the
next level because our error messages are terrible.
We don't have the ability to necessarily correlate events
because let's face it too. Like you could have what appears benign.
But when you look at it in the context of the last three events that got logged.
Oh, wait, that's not benign. Like that's a really big deal.
Look at what's actually going on here.
And this is, I feel like maybe the next stage, but alternatively,
are we gonna end up with this in everyone's desktop? The answer is no. Right.
I mean, let's face it, it's legitimately no.
And so this kind of becomes a question of now, what, what's the next stage here?
Because I think in a corporate environment
you've got j well, you should have a substantial logging infrastructure,
right? That, that can look for these things.
You know what I've done, which is I have my base operating system
sy,
like I have my hardware running an operating system,
but I do all my work inside of a VM.
That's a great step, I think. And I, I do the same for many, many tasks.
And in fact,
what I found is also exciting is then obviously you
can just connect to the VM from like other consoles,
for example, and, and do fun things.
But,
uh, like, like R SAS,
the, the, well, this episode will be out after RSA, I imagine.
But, uh, at
RS A, I'm bringing my chromebook, right?
I'm not bringing a real computer because let's face it.
Like the odds of hacking a chromebook are pretty low
and even if it does get totally whacked and I know there's something wrong with it,
you know, I'm gonna do it,
I'm gonna throw it in the garbage and I go buy a new one for two.
And here's the beauty of something like having a chromebook at hacked.
A large company cares very deeply about that problem.
If you go to Google and you say I have a chromebook hack
Google is going to a pay you a lot of money and b fix it really quick,
right? And that's what I love about.
A lot of these cloud providers is like
a great example being like Amazon web services,
Microsoft,
Azure, Google, you know, cloud engine,
if I were to say to them, hey, uh cool story,
I found a way to use resources for free or I found a way to do XY or Z
they would like basically poop themselves a bit and
then fix it as fast as they could because,
you know, their brand reputation really does matter.
Yeah.
Well, not just brand reputation, it's real money, like if you can use it for free
and
yeah, and now with GDPR, you know, those fines are pretty hefty.
So, I mean, and
that's part of it is, you know, using these services and hardware
where somebody kind of really does care about their brand.
Um because I'll be blunt it clearly nobody actually.
Well, you know,
there was that study of um do security events actually impact stock price at all.
And the answer is no,
no, they do not. Like look at Equifax, there was a bounce
or a little dip or whatever it's called
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, let's all delete our Facebook profiles. Sure. Any day now.
So, yeah, I mean, it's, it's,
it's a, it's
a part of the problem is this change has happened gradually over the years,
but it's now 20 or 30 years later.
Like, I,
I have more bandwidth to my house than like North American backbone internet had
while I was on the internet.
You know what I mean? I remember
a T three was 45 megabits per second. That was the big bad boy.
Right. Like,
you know, some people had T threes.
I never got to touch one or log into a system attached to one, but
I heard about them.
Uh, you know, and that was like, what, 45 megabits per second now,
I have 175 bidirectionally,
you know,
that's
like,
so, you know, my computer now is literally over 1000 times faster than it was
1015 years ago.
You know, and
more to the point,
the access to the software we have, like, look at what's on github
now. It's mind blowing.
Right. 20 years ago, we thought the C
A thing with a couple of 1000 modules was like, actually pretty awesome. And it was,
and now you have, you know, your standard Ruby Gems or N PM or whatever has, you know,
50 to 100,000 libraries.
Yeah, it's madness. I agree.
So,
no, I think, but the problem is we've dragged all this old code along with us.
I mean, I look at things like open SSH or Apache. Open SSH is just what?
In their last release, they finally dropped
support for protocol, whatever by I
think it was.
That is, man, that's one of my pet peeves is letting
backwards compatibility. I, I feel like
get rid of it and if someone really needs old functionality,
let them run the old code, like, you know,
and, and don't make it too easy though because honestly,
it might be worth making them, like, go well, you know,
maybe we should just either engineer around it or stop doing that.
But yeah, a great example.
Yeah,
here drop compatibility support for some
very old SSH implementations including ssh.com.
Oh yeah, for those of you that don't know,
you
SSH was originally open source and then the guy tried to
essentially commercialize it and he did commercialize it and it's,
it's a decent product.
Um So you had ssh.com, you know, when they do like versions for mainframes and stuff.
But yeah,
so ssh.com less than are equal to version two point whatever and
open SSH less than are equal to version three point whatever.
Ah that is old. That's,
that's really
old.
Anyway,
these versions were, yeah, these versions were all released in or before 2001
and predate the final SSH R CS.
The support and question isn't necessary for RFC compliant. Yeah, I mean, it's just
again, yeah, this code is now
this, this code can now vote,
right?
And, and here's,
here's how, I guess let's wrap this up, let's bring it home.
But here's, here's my thought on this is
I understand
the necessity of backwards compatibility
in the context of the past
because things did move more slowly.
And I think expecting someone to be on something modern
was not necessarily a reasonable expectation.
And
you could also see instances where people would just,
they they would lack the ability to upgrade because there was an open source, right?
If you were on say an old sun machine and
the new version of Slays didn't work like too bad,
not my problem, right? And so there was,
there was something to be said about that backwards compatibility.
But the the era we live in today
that is much less important and let's face it like, well,
I'm gonna have to disagree because internet of things,
we're recreating this entire problem.
And at a vastly larger scale
in what context
in the context, I have a device that I can't update
because either I can't update it or there's no update.
I was getting to that
right.
There are unable devices and IOT is going to be the greatest sinner in this game.
But by allowing backwards compatibility,
we encourage people to keep these things.
Whereas if we throw away backwards compatibility and we,
we march progress forward in this regard,
we create a disincentive to keep old gear because let's face it. Old gear.
Today is dangerous. Old gear back in the day wasn't
what's going to happen with people who are economically unable to do that.
I mean,
there are schools that can't afford to buy pencils and you're going to
be telling them they need to update their computers and their networks.
Yes,
it is. I, I, you do. You have to do it, man. There's no other way.
Well, and then the problem is there's, that creates a secondary effect.
Ok, I have to get rid of all my old gear. I better monetize getting rid of it.
Which means there's gonna be a huge secondary market for all this
old stuff and somebody will buy it even if it's garbage.
If it doesn't work though,
they will make it work because they'll just buy enough
old gear that it can all talk to itself.
Maybe. I mean,
you, you could be right. I'm not gonna, I'm not gonna say you're not.
I, I, in principle, I would love to see,
you know, if your code is old enough to vote, we take it all back and shoot it.
I would love to see that as like a rule,
but realistically it's not going to happen because there's just,
there's too many systems and people that can't upgrade
for any number of variety of reasons like,
ok, nuclear launch systems, right?
They were talking about how they, they have to source, what is it?
Those eight inch floppy disks. Right. And they do. Right.
Like, that's not a reason to keep using eight inch floppy disks.
Like, if, if one particular organization has a need,
they can solve it with money.
Right.
That's the reality of it.
And
this is a touchy subject and I won't disagree at all.
And I'm, I'm certain I'll get some hate mail
from
my opinion.
I think one of the things is to, you know,
we're seeing more frameworks and more sort of what I'm hoping to see more of is,
you know, so the device manufacturers,
their value add is sort of simpler in the sense
of rather than providing you with a whole system.
It's like here's Linux with Busy Box and you can keep updating
that we just do the web app on top of it,
right. And reduce the cost for these IOT guys so that they do,
they're less incentivized to not support it because it'll be well,
make it cheaper to support and there's a better chance they will.
I mean, maybe I'm,
I guess we don't know what the future will hold, but I'll tell you this,
the future can't be old devices that can't be updated, right?
Like that is, that is not a future we can afford.
Well, the Marai
Botnet, I mean, it'll be that times 1000 million.
Maybe it'll become self aware and start fixing itself, right?
That hope
and that's, that's how we shall end it.
I think I for one welcome, our robot overlords.
Alright, sweet. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you audience.
If you want any of the links to the, the very silly things we talked about today,
you can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit us up on social media with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag And yeah, I guess Kurt, you have a great rest of your day, man.
You too. Thanks.
Thanks everybody. Bye bye.