Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 63
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Bresser.
Holy cow.
Kurt. I feel like the whole world has lit on fire all at once.
I've not been offline for a week, but I, I moved.
So I've,
I've been somewhat unaware of it apart from the continued flaming train wreck.
That is Equifax.
That will,
we've got,
I
bet we have a couple more months
to make,
to make some, some hay with that one. It's not going to go away anytime soon.
No,
it's like, well, you know, it's like a hurricane, right?
It's just such a big massive event.
Even when it's over, you still have to clean up and deal with all the,
unless there's another hurricane right after it.
And then that's all anyone talks about.
And we're on like the third or fourth hurricane at this point. So,
uh yeah, no one even remembers the name of the first one, right?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
And, and that's kind of what I feel like is, is starting to happen here and,
and, and so here's the question for you and this is something we,
we briefly talked about before we hit record was, is,
is this the new normal? I feel like everything has lit on fire and it's just
more fire. You know, it's not going out.
-- I actually
-- think it's probably not that much worse than it was in past,
but part of it is there's much better coverage of it.
Uh, I suspect there was, I mean, because I know in the past a lot of these incidents,
the response was it was like hoof and mouth disease, right.
Shoot shovel and burry.
So ho and melt disease is a disease that, you know, it, it affects cattle.
And essentially the response is you shoot the cattle, dig a trench, dump them in,
cover it up.
So
that how you deal with
-- me.
-- It's funny you use that as the example because,
uh, I live in, in the north almost as north as you.
And we have. Right. Right.
We have that in the wild white tailed deer population here.
It's called chronic wasting disease.
And I think your analogy is interesting because in the cattle perspective,
you can sort of control it.
But when it is a wild animal, especially a herding wild animal,
you have no control over what's going on and, and they do like all this testing,
the new thing they're doing here, you know, God bless these people is
they decided that not enough people were getting their animals tested.
So they did away with the free testing.
And so now they're like, yeah,
if you think your animal has chronic wasting disease you shot.
Uh,
yeah, good luck. Right
here, there's a whole bunch of, um,
hunting zones.
So in Alberta, the province is split up into a variety of hunting zones, you know,
based on which animals and how many animals are present and stuff like that.
And
there's a big pile of zones in the south where, you know,
chronic wasting disease is an issue.
And yeah, if you shoot animals there, you're heavily encouraged to get them tested,
but it's not mandatory.
Doesn't this sound like compliance? Like we encourage you to do it? Right.
But if you don't? Oh, well, and, you know, you might die. We don't know. Good luck.
Yeah.
Well, it's also for, you know, if,
in theory, if we get testing, then you have a good sample size and,
you know how bad things are.
Right.
Yeah, that too, because part of the problem is, you know,
if you have 10 people bring in 10 dead deer and they all test positive is that,
-- you know what I mean? Like, what, what's the, how bad is this actually?
-- Right.
Right. Right.
And I think these data breaches are kind of like that and that
part of it too is the scale of them is such that you can't hide it anymore. Right. When,
you know, when like 10,000 people have their details leaked.
They're not gonna, like,
put it together and figure out that they got popped by necessarily.
Right.
But when it's millions and millions of people,
uh, you know, like the, the Home Depot thing, right.
You can just correlate, like, oh,
look 100% of these people all shopped at Home Depot.
Right.
-- You know,
-- we can't prove
and, and
what's, what I find most interesting is, I mean,
epidemiology learned a lot of hard lessons starting. What about 200 years ago?
I think that's kind of when it started
the guy with the uh water pump in London. Jeez, what was that?
The statistician who figured out, you know, it was the water pump
that had the collar and he took the handle off the water pump and
problem
solving.
Interesting,
interesting.
But at the same time,
the cholera was caused maybe by the water pump.
But in reality, the issue was people were throwing their waste out the window,
right?
Like it's, it's
correlation isn't necessarily causing,
he knew it was coming from this water pump.
So we knew where the problem was originating. At least I got you, got you.
Um
But uh and, and that's
the problem is, you know,
we so that if you look at the the public health system in most developed countries,
right?
We have a huge system set up to report
disease and so we can do correlating like locally,
for example, there was a, there's a food festival.
Uh I think it was a taste of Edmonton.
So basically a whole bunch of vendors, you know, with food carts that kind of stuff
set up in the park, people eat their food
and the one I guess was giving out free salmonella with their food,
you know, and so like 2030 people got really sick
and, you know, and they're so, you know,
they correlated which one it was and they're warning,
you know, if you ate at this one and while you feel sick,
go to the hospital because it's not just like a little sick,
like you could be very sick.
Um
Yeah, I mean, it's,
I feel like in computing the problem is we don't have
good data because a lot of people hide their data,
right? They don't want the world to know that they got popped
and there's no central authority to really, there's no who there's no, you know,
CDC.
Uh
Yes. And, and OK,
so I, I like where you're taking this because I, I don't think you're wrong.
And I also think the work that the CDC type of organizations do is amazing.
It amazes me
that
five people can get food poisoning and they asked them a whole
bunch of questions and then they can say something like it was,
it was lettuce from this grocery store.
And I think that's amazing that, that you're able to do that, right? But,
but I guess more importantly is
they know what they're looking for and they understand the problem.
We don't have either of those things in security today.
I,
I agree
there's a lot of new
attacks and stuff,
but there's a lot of simple stuff like where somebody
hacked a whole pile of accounts or personal data.
It doesn't really matter how they hacked it. The fact is it happened.
Ok. I understand what you're saying.
And that's kind of what the have I been pawned sort of
set, right. Yeah.
But part of it, and this is my real frustration is we can live without disease.
We can't live without personal data and we have to share personal data otherwise.
No, no, you're, you're,
I think you're making a bad analogy because saying we can live without disease
is
that's not the problem.
The problem is we are a society and if, if humans are interacting,
there is disease just like existing on the internet means sharing personal data,
meaning your data will leak.
What I mean in the sense is
our
modern economy is based on
a high degree of transparency and efficiency.
So for example, if I'm going to uh sell you a car
and I make you pay upfront for it, I'm going to sell about two cars a year
if you're lucky,
you know.
So I have to be able to do credit.
Well, if I'm going to do credit,
I have to be able to figure out whether or not you're gonna pay me back.
And, well, first of all, I have to figure out whether or not you can pay me back
and assuming you can pay me back. Are you actually going to?
Right. Right.
And that, you know, what am I going to do?
Get personal references, you know, talk to your boss
again, that's going to cost me tens of hours, you know, it's,
and hugely inefficient and, and it's not going to be very good or accurate.
Hence, we get things like Equifax where Equifax, you know,
stores data on everybody and on their
credit history and on their payment history and
literally assigns you a score that basically indicates how likely
you are to pay back money lent to you.
Yes.
You,
that
I,
-- I,
-- I, I don't have enough money to buy a house.
II, I doubt I ever will like most people in my generation, you know, we're not gonna
-- somehow save up, you know, four years of salary and
-- buy
a house. I'm
an old man. Don't pretend you're a millennial.
No, but even my generation, I, you know, very, it's, it's owning a house is pretty,
uh, it's,
it's expensive. Our parents generation all owned houses. No big deal.
Yes. But they, they still took out loans.
Yeah, exactly.
I mean, even, even in the land of milk and honey,
they weren't writing checks for houses.
Right.
Yeah, exactly.
And of course, it was purely, it was just hard work. That got them there.
So, and so the problem is like,
what, what I was saying is we can, you know,
we can live without disease in the sense of if we all don't have Ebola, that,
that's ok.
But we can't live without sharing personal information because,
you know,
uh my son's school, like they need my phone number,
they need to be able to contact me in
case, you know, he's puking or throwing chairs or whatever. Right. Um,
there's all these situations where we really
do have to share personal information,
you know, you get in a car accident with somebody.
Ok. But although I guess what, you're,
yes, I, I'm trying to, my brain is processing this now and
there are various levels of personal information.
Like my phone number is basically public knowledge. It's not even hard to find.
And so
that's one level, but at the same time there's things like, uh, today
in, in the US, at least you have your social security number,
which is supposed to be private.
But thanks to
basically every hack in the last 10 years,
it's like I know mine isn't private anymore.
It's, it's, I've never actually looked for it,
but my suspicion is it's not hard to find.
So I moved houses and I, um, I changed DS L providers.
Uh,
I changed to tell us because they're running fiber
here and I want to upgrade to the fiber.
And, um, well, actually know the crews are right out.
-- They're three blocks away right now, pulling the, uh, the fibers to the house,
-- some
donuts and be like, do me next.
Yeah.
But so anyways I phoned tell us and I haven't been a customer of,
tell us in like 15 years.
Right? Because I had shaw
and I had tech savvy and so
the guy, you know, he's like, ok, well, we basically have no idea who you are.
So like, what's your name? What's your address?
You know, and,
and obviously I'm gonna give them my real
address because that's where I want the service,
right? I can't, you know what I mean?
Like they tell us obviously is going to get my real
address because they're going to send a guy out to like
-- around my wife.
-- It's kind of an important point,
right? Yeah, exactly. So, so
they're like, I'm like, he's like I need, uh, you know,
I need to know um your driver's license ID number.
I'm like, I'm not real keen about giving that out, but ok, you know, it's this,
it's one blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, whatever it is.
He's like, ok, now I need your social
or your social insurance number and I'm like, no,
he's like, I'm sorry, but we need two forms of government ID
like, and please note this is over the phone.
This isn't like I was in a store showing him the thing.
Um
I also discovered now they don't give you a social insurance number card anymore.
In Canada. They used to,
I, I have like a plastic card that's embossed with the number,
like an old timey credit card.
And then they went, I think,
to a paper slip and now they just don't even bother because, like, you know what,
you're going to show it to get into a bar.
Have you ever seen a US social security number?
That the,
it's like
a,
it's flimsy paper designed specifically. So if you lose it it falls apart and like
that, that could be
like,
-- yeah, they're super weak. I mean, it's
-- definitely
in your lifetime.
Yeah.
So, uh,
but anyway, so he's like, we need two forms of government ID.
And I'm like, thinking first of all, ok,
what, what's the liability here?
Number one, there's going to be a piece of, tell us equipment at my end
that's worth about like 100 bucks, right? A DS L modem.
-- These things aren't expensive,
-- you know,
they're buying those things for probably like three bucks.
Right. Yeah.
Uh, secondly, there's the call out of the technician to, you know,
basically poke the wires.
Ok. That's, that's like 50 to 100 bucks cost, right? You know, that's fair.
But beyond that, there's like,
just a minimal marginal cost for them to add me to their network.
So at most they're looking at, you know, 100 maybe $200
that they can kind of lose on me
and,
but because of, you know, the way businesses work now, right.
They want to minimize their liability, they want to minimize
the amount of loss that they eat.
So they require two forms of government ID.
And, you know, so I gave them my health care number which again, really annoyed the
government health care. What's that?
Yeah. Anyways. But, um,
you know, it, it's really frustrating because I, I just want DS L,
I'm paying 50 bucks a month.
It's not like I'm paying, you know, it's,
this isn't like some business line at like five grand
a month or 50 grand a month or something.
This is like a $50 a month home DS L line,
you know,
and the hoops I had to jump through to get it,
you know, with giving away my personal information is I think a bit ridiculous.
-- But what choice do I have? Right.
-- Ok. But let's, let's think of it this way,
my guess.
And this is just a guess,
but my guess is when they started requiring two forms of government ID,
the number of delinquencies that they were seeing
in new customers dropped by a significant margin.
Well, and more to the point when, if,
if I try and get service again from them in the future,
it would be very difficult because I could, for example, use my same name,
but I would have to give different,
you know,
forms of government ID that they would then be able
to tie back to the other ones most likely,
you know, and they could refuse me service effectively. Right.
And that's,
you know, that's my frustration is that, yeah, I get that.
It saves them money and it saves them hassle.
They don't really pass the savings on to me.
But, uh, regardless, but my worry is, you know, the,
the cost if they do manage to lose or leak my information to me is it's a lot of hassle.
You know, we talked, you talked about this,
how one of the biggest problems with identity theft is,
how do I show actual personal loss versus like, oh,
I spent like 100 hours on the phone dealing with these people.
Right. You know,
right. In, in, in all seriousness.
My, I, my, my social security number has been stolen every which way you can imagine
and I have yet to see any fraud against myself.
Now, granted, I keep saying that and I'm sure I'm, I'm in for a doozy now
and tempting fate.
Well, I was reading on hacker news and, you know,
these and on Reddit and these people are talking about
identity theft and what they've had to deal with and,
you know, sending certified letters to Bank of America to point out that no,
I did not do XY and Z or,
you know, with Verizon. No, I didn't buy 10 phones,
you know, like, just,
you know,
the best part is the guy,
like they bought 10 phones and had them shipped to my address.
And so I had to phone Verizon security and
that one was actually easy because it's like,
hi, I have a box full of 10 phones.
I didn't order. Would you like them back?
You know.
So
crazy, man.
So actually one thing that,
that just sprang to mind when you're talking about Verizon is
I am a T mobile subscriber.
And if you have
a like proper T mobile, it's not really a contract, but it's sort of a contract,
whatever they call it.
Now,
you have to give them.
I did not, my wife did.
But uh well,
we used to have a real contract with them and
then they like did away with contracts and stuff,
but they still have a concept of prepaid and postpaid.
And,
and so actually I have a, my
fi I use when I travel and my, my
fi is prepaid
and the reason it's prepaid for the month in advance, right?
And it's prepaid because I can only put it on postpaid
if I give them my social security number, which I said no.
And I could jump through a bunch of hoops and like add it to my existing account.
But then I would,
we have like some ancient rate locked in for dirt freaking cheap for,
for unlimited data.
So I'm
I'm not touching that ever right? Until they make me. So anyway, anyway,
Uh, right.
If you, if you're unwilling to work with them, they'll still give you an account,
but it's prepaid and obviously if they don't pay the bill,
I just turn it off and whoop.
You do, no one cares.
Which is, which is kind of cool actually.
Yeah. Well, and, you know, I get it because this makes business more efficient.
They're less likely to have losses that they have to eat more to the point,
the losses that they do have to eat are cheaper and easier to deal with.
You know,
like you said, we just turn it off. Ok. That's a, you know, that's a crap account.
Right. And actually, you know, it's really cool. They did too.
And this was really clever is one time I,
I just didn't pay my bill and I was out of town or something.
Right? I forget the details and
I go to use it and I'm thinking it's not working. Right.
So anyway, I called him up and I said, uh, hey, my, my, my, I is broke and they said, oh,
you didn't pay us.
I said, oh, ok. Well, whatever, here's my credit card number, right?
Uh Turn it back up
and they of course only re enable the service to the end of the billing cycle.
Like they didn't add 30 days.
So you figure, right. Which is brilliant, right? If you miss half a month
and you call them now you're basically paying for
the full month of service for a half month.
It's
right on, you know, good for them.
Yeah. No, I mean, this is sharp business.
I mean, this is, you know, businesses that do,
that will have a few million dollars more than the businesses that don't.
I would hope so. And, and, yeah, I dig it
so, but that's the problem. Right is
we can't secure this personal information because by definition,
I have to share it with a ton of people
so that we can have a, a modern economy that's, you know, really efficient and
so like literally, you know, people go out and they buy a car in an afternoon,
takes them an hour.
Yeah, probably, you know.
Right. I mean,
I look at this whole house thing and like it's a few
10,
it's like 10 or 20 hours in total of
paperwork and stuff to like do all the financial stuff
and my, you know, and, and a
lot of banks and mortgage brokers now will just do it entirely online,
you know, that's incredibly amazing and efficient, you know,
when you think about it,
you do.
So
we, yeah, I, I don't think we can go back to
like,
I am going to need five references and I'm going to call them in to have interviews is,
is Josh a good guy, like does he, you know, he, oh, he has a dog?
That's good. That's, you know, plus five points
and uh you know, that's just not gonna happen. So the problem is
we,
we've built these systems that rely on this information being secret.
Like, you know, you phone the gas company, your phone,
whatever company they're like, ok, I need to verify your identity, you know,
like what's your name and your postal code
and your billing number? And it's like, but all that stuff's on the mail that you send
up,
you know?
I know.
I mean, that's, to me, one of the biggest things for electronic billing is now,
-- I don't have to worry about
-- mail
theft or, or, you know what my favorite is I called the cable company one time
and they said,
uh, what's your pin number? And I said, I don't think I have one.
They said, oh, no, you don't, you have to send one. Will you give us a PIN number?
I'm thinking what is wrong with you people? This is ridiculous.
-- Yeah. But for 99 out of 100 cases,
-- it's
more than that. I
-- think
-- I started doing
one in a million man.
I, I set the password or the pin number to like, company name sucks
or something along those lines.
And it's, it's more to just, you know,
to, to vocalize my displeasure with them
than anything else.
And, um, but yeah, it's childish and I get that, but,
you know, it, it's frustrating because I really do wish, for example,
they have logins to their websites.
Why am I logging in with like,
anything but my email address or more ideally my
Google account or a Facebook account or Twitter account.
Because,
you know, like,
again, you got like, they have these terrible password requirements.
It's like my bank. Right. My bank has
still doesn't have two factor authentication.
Who most Canadian banks don't?
I know mine doesn't either. It's ridiculous.
I mean, on the mobile app it's just like, what's your user name and password? Great.
Oh, and your user name is your like account number which is embossed on your card.
-- I don't
-- have that, at least
mine's just,
I won't say what it is.
The dirty secret is that numbers,
you know, if it's a debit card, that's also your like debit visa number. Right.
-- So again, it's really not secret.
-- No,
no, it's not.
Right. You just post a picture of that on Instagram for everyone to see. Right.
Look everyone. I have a debit card.
Yes. Anyway, anyway.
Uh
-- Right.
-- So I think the reality is this is here to stay because all these companies
have to have this information to,
you know, have an efficient business.
Ok.
I,
I would go a step further than just saying it's
here to stay is I don't envision any drastic changes.
Let's look at Equifax and that is probably one of the largest,
most dangerous leaks that has ever happened in the history of humanity.
The reality is, it's probably not going to affect a lot of people
and my guess is it will change nothing in the industry.
I think what we might see is maybe credit freezes become slightly easier to do.
And that's it. But even that, like, oh,
it, it's the Equifax site. Right. You can find out what any
credit freeze number is,
like three
public pieces of information. I mean, it's,
but even then, even then, all right.
So someone's gonna have to target you specifically,
right? It's, it's not going to be like
-- hundreds of millions of people affected by
-- it.
And
if I get enough personal information about you
and your credit rating is high enough,
I can take out a mortgage in your name and that's a lot of money.
-- No,
-- you can't because the bank is going to come and take the house away.
But when they find out it's not me.
Right?
No, but the seller would get the money, right. And
you know,
it's
a James Bond movie plot.
This stuff happens
Google
it.
I, I'm sure it is conceivable but, but I don't envision that being
an overly practical problem.
Uh
No, it happens quite a bit.
I
don't believe you
-- Google
-- it.
I don't want to,
I'm just gonna not believe it.
Here
we go.
Equifax says it has been able to flake nearly $1 billion
of attempted mortgage fraud among its lender clients since 2013.
That's an article from 2015.
Um It's I know, mortgage fraud is a problem in Canada, in the Canadian market.
I don't know about the US market, but it's definitely a problem up
here. Mortgage fraud. Explain this to me. Then
basically, it's where, you know,
I get somebody else's information, personal identification
and I take out a mortgage in their name and then I pay the seller and the seller.
Uh for example, we might pay an over inflated price or something.
And that's how the seller makes a bit of extra money.
You know,
they're typically in on the fraud as well or you
have a property that's not worth much of anything,
right?
And you vastly overpay for it.
Uh or you, if you have multiple people, right?
You would actually buy from, you would buy from a legitimate seller,
pay the legitimate seller
and then immediately turn around and flip it.
So that way, you know, you can siphon off the money,
OK? And
you flip and you sell it to another
entity that is also stolen information,
-- right? And so that that's how you extract those big piles of money.
-- But,
but, but
if the first couple of things, you talk about where you,
you essentially have a seller in
cahoots,
somebody got the money. You can't exist in a civilized country
with stolen money like that
and not be found,
-- right?
-- Well, true.
But that's, you know, you can do multiple layers of sellers and more to the point,
how do you prove the seller was in on this.
-- Uh
-- That could be a problem.
But my suspicion is the bank can still go after them because in,
at least in the United States,
if you have stolen goods, they're not yours.
Even if you paid for them, they, they will come and take them.
-- But he
-- doesn't have stolen goods. He has the money, he was paid.
But here's the thing, man, if, if I'm walking down the street
and a guy stops and says, here's a million dollars,
give me your coat and we're even right.
And I say, wow, that's neat. Thanks.
And then the police show up and say, hey,
that guy just stole a million dollars from the bank.
Uh Give it back to us. I say, oh no, no,
he, he bought my coat.
They couldn't be like no,
give me, give me them. All right.
So on the one hand, you, you, they, they would have to prove that it was their money
because you could also, there's been cases,
there's been cases where people have been flying and they
have a lot of money in the ts a confiscation.
That's different though, right? That's different.
Well,
I'm just
saying that
back
to the original
point.
Ok?
But back to the original point,
there is quite a bit of mortgage fraud with stolen identity.
We add
links in the show notes.
Um
and it's uh you know, and, and some of it too is also
um, people wanting to borrow more than they're allowed to,
you know, by, well, what their credit scores and stuff would indicate. So they may
not necessarily borrow somebody else's identity,
but they may monkey with their own stuff, you know.
So that's not really identity fraud.
That's just more classic, I guess, straight up fraud.
Um,
but there was a good reddit comment pointing out that, you know,
this stuff used to be called bank fraud.
And now they've turned it on its head to be, you know, identity theft. And
essentially they've turned it from being like the bank's problem to being,
you know,
your problem, like your identity got stolen.
Now, you're the one that has to jump through all these hoops
and deal with all this BS. Whereas in the past it was,
yeah, you know,
um, and I think fundamentally, yeah,
that's just not gonna change because obviously, you know,
companies aren't gonna take on liability unless
it's absolutely shoved down their throat.
And, I mean, Equifax was
weeks or even months ago trying to get rid of a whole pile of, you know,
if they get breached, they'll be held accountable for stuff.
Um One of the hacker news threads pointed out simply put here simple idea,
$10 per record.
Uh, fine.
Right.
The government finds these people $10 per, every record popped
and clearly somebody like Equifax with what is 143 million.
Right. That's, that's $1.4 billion. I don't really care how big you are.
That, that's going to hurt nobody.
That,
yeah.
Well,
the tobacco industry paid tens of billions of dollars of findings still around.
But anyways,
the point being is that,
that will force or heavily encourage companies to go get insurance and
that means the insurance companies will force them to comply with
some basic sanity,
you know, in order to get their policy. And
the,
the point is we basically have to add
some sort of economic incentive for these people
to do the right thing because right now
there's no incentive like Equifax got popped.
Have they been fined yet? No,
there are class action lawsuits. Uh, there's now one in Canada
because apparently there were Canadians in UK, uh, people from the UK
that were definitely affected.
And, um,
you know, assuming those class action lawsuits ever happen, I mean,
those lawyers are going to make out like bandits,
they'll make a ton
and I might get like a rebate check for $5 off my next identity. Um, what is it?
What's that product they sell that they were pushing?
They, they remember because, oh, they hid the credit freezing thing behind like,
you know, signing up for identity theft protection service.
And then they also were sending people to a fishing site for like a week,
weren't they?
Well, some guy had like,
it was, what was it? The, the actual site? I think it was Equifax 2000 seventeen.com
and he registered
like security Equifax 2000 seventeen.com.
And yeah, Equifax was tweeting out and sending people to the wrong URL like
you literally had one job.
No, you know this. Ok.
So actually
I'm not going to, to knack them for this because
what, what generally happens is when things are crazy like this people,
people aren't, you're not operating
safely.
But see
right here's the,
you should have a plan for this.
-- They clearly didn't plan for anything. I mean, come on.
-- But it's like, it's like,
you know, it's like fire drills and fire safety. Right.
That's something we as a society have gotten pretty good at. Right. People
very rarely die in fires now and, you
know,
so much so that when they do it makes the news
because,
because like 100 years ago there were tons of fire deaths
and finally people cared enough to do something about it.
Right.
And so my thinking is, you know,
you should have a breach plan which
should probably include things like having a designated
URL like breach or security dot your company name.com for people to go to and,
you know, have something set up or ready to go.
That's not a wordpress instance with the, you know,
whatever. But I
mean,
to me this is kind of,
yeah, I get that this stuff isn't easy and it does cost money.
But come on, these are not mom and pop shops. This is
-- Equifax. See,
-- but it doesn't matter who it is because
nobody is ready for something like this. And, and unless you literally train for it,
you will not be ready and you will make mistakes,
right? Just period.
Yeah, I mean, ok, Equifax's gross profit in 2016 was 2.03 billion.
Now, granted that's gross profit.
So there's still stuff coming off of that but still,
you know, pre-tax income of $728 million.
Uh, so here we go. Uh, the net income profit loss was $488.8 million.
Ok.
I'm sorry. But they,
they definitely have the money to have prevented this.
The question isn't if they have the money to prevent it.
That's not the question at all.
The fact is
they didn't do anything about it,
but
I wouldn't either because there's no, there's no liability. Right.
Except for the class action lawsuit
which will take at least five or 10 years.
They're just going to settle those things for,
for pennies on the dollar of what's being asked today.
I mean. Right. That's what's gonna happen and, and they're gonna end up giving away
some sort of trifle
as, as the reward.
Well, if they're really smart, they'll give away like a year of free
identity
theft service,
free
upgrade to the pay one.
You know,
I know,
I know
to their own service.
But
anyway, whatever it,
I think the reality is this is just gonna keep happening because there's nothing,
well, first of all, there's nothing to stop it from happening.
It's not like all these companies are suddenly
going to magically get good at security.
No,
no, they aren't.
And, and, ok, look, and there's also the, the discussion you could have,
even if Equifax said
here's a billion dollars, I want to fix this today.
What could they honestly do That would make a difference,
inventory all their software and figure out exactly what
they're all running and then maybe start patching it.
But, but my suspicion is this, this
would that really matter.
I don't know.
I mean, it's, I, there's part of me thinks, like,
how do you actually siphon off 100 and 43 million
records without it being noticed and more to the point,
apparently it was noticed but nobody just
stopped it again. You know, that's a gross failing. I mean,
part of me thinks maybe you either. Well, I, I carrot and stick. Right.
Hey, if you notice a data breach, 100 grand
all of a sudden, I think maybe your employees are going to pay a bit more attention
maybe. Or they could cause a data breach.
Yeah,
exactly.
You know, the minute you start measuring and incentivize something you're,
you're, you're going to get people like,
oh, I found more potholes,
you know,
never
mind the jackhammer under my desk. Right. Exactly.
So, no, I agree. It's not, it's, it's, it's a very nontrivial problem.
Um,
I mean, legislation could potentially help but, I mean,
writing good legislation for this would be, wow, super nontrivial.
It's, it's probably impossible.
Well, I was going to say with all the lobbying power and money that these guys have,
there will never be by definition good legislation like they'll make, it's look,
I mean, look at the tax situation in North America.
We have turbotax and all these other guys
lobbying to keep the tax code a complete nightmare
and not allowing you to file like online directly with the government uh easily,
you know, you can do it, but it's a, it's a very non easy
task,
but at the same time,
uh I pay what, like 100 bucks a year for taxes.
I, I don't care enough that I'm going to put up a fight.
Right.
And see that's, that's the beauty of this rent seeking behavior is you make it like,
oh, it's just 100 bucks a year.
-- What's the big deal?
-- I have bigger problems than, than my taxes.
I just drop a bunch of paperwork off at the accountant and
that's all right.
Yep.
So,
no, I know, man.
Anyway, we should move on to a happy topic like like
Bluetooth.
Yeah. So,
well, like everything. I mean, Bluetooth is networking, networking
apps have flaws. I
know
it's that simple.
Yeah. You know, I, I, I'm surprised it took this long to be perfectly honest with you,
nobody bothered to look.
And, and that was actually one of the interesting findings in that report from the,
the Blue Barn where let's talk about Blue Barn for those
of you out there who haven't figured it out yet.
Um And, and of course, for future listeners in the year 2035 Blue Barn, look it up.
But anyway,
uh they did mention in the report that basically testing
this stuff is really hard to do because there just isn't
a lot of good hardware on the market that can kind of do
-- strange things.
-- Definition Bluetooth is terrible.
Like, do you know how much,
how I like a great example.
My partner, her phone and her car and their Bluetooth connectivity at
least once a week. She ends up swearing at it because it just doesn't want to work.
-- You
-- know, most of the Bluetooth things I have are pretty solid now.
They used to be really bad, but I haven't had too much trouble lately.
Interesting.
-- That's fair.
-- But uh,
no, I mean, the, the in general, you know, Bluetooth chip sets are,
they're really cheap.
Uh Yeah, but they're, they're also very specific as well. I mean,
think about some of the wireless hacking, like all the Wi Fi stuff.
There were, there were chip sets that were produced that let you
do some wacky stuff with the, the wireless radio
and it sounds like with Bluetooth, those don't exist.
So it's really hard to abuse Bluetooth the way we, we were abusing,
you know, kind of wi fi some years back.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, it's, um,
you know, the reality is if it's
code, chances are it has
flaws
and chances are some of those flaws are remote code execution
-- and
-- you know what
if you
look at it.
So a lot of these chips
that, that these people, like these Bluetooth chip sets, for example, are either
they're either kind of source code turned into a processors, you know,
they have security issues or
it's some sort of general purpose chip that's running firmware
and
sore
radio.
Right.
Exactly. Exactly.
And so, you know, those things are,
the chip itself has got to be just a disaster on the inside.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's crazy, man.
So,
but
the, I think the real uh problem with this too is, is
Linux as an operating system, you know, the, the Linux running on
computers like proper computers, desktops, servers,
those typically, you know, can get patched without too, too much hassle.
Now, that doesn't mean they do get,
so it's at least possible for distributions to ship these
updates and for people to actually apply these updates,
you know, and not have a bricked system most likely, or
if they do manage to break it, they can recover it because it's, you know,
a machine in a room that they probably can physically.
Yeah.
And then kind of sliding the scale.
We have like the IOT where all of a sudden we have, well, I sold you this device.
I have no real incentive to update it. So I'm not going to.
And it literally is that simple. Now, the good news is
the majority of IOT devices. Now, at least in my experience
they do Wi Fi, they don't do Bluetooth,
right?
I've seen a few that do Bluetooth,
but the vast majority do Wi Fi for the simple reason that
that's how they hop on the internet.
So that's how you hop onto them and configure them. Right? I mean,
we're not going to add an extra 10 cents in Bluetooth chip set when we don't have to.
Right.
That's why that adds up
and then
another sort of area
cell phones. And of course, uh I think all cell phones now have Bluetooth,
there must be a model that doesn't, but as a, as a,
I'm gonna make a general statement that like all cell phones have a Bluetooth chip.
I think we can agree with that.
Yeah, because you know, headsets,
keyboards, mice, all that stuff.
And, well, not only that,
a lot of these devices now you're buying like a system on a chip and it just,
it has Bluetooth, like you don't have a choice.
In
fact, I heard a thing the other day that most of these Android phones,
I guess have the ability to receive like high def over the air television
because that's like a huge thing in Korea apparently. But they, they just disable
-- it.
-- Well, it's like the FM chip set.
Right.
All the,
all these cell chip set chip sets have a
built in FM radio because it's some government requirement,
I think in the US
for emergency services or whatever.
And of course, they all disable it because, you know, we don't, the power budget,
whatever that is
a
FM radio.
Yeah, anyways.
Um, so that's the problem though is,
is
ok,
thank goodness this flaw is probably not in actual silicon
because if it's in the actual silicon then yeah,
you gotta throw your phone away and buy a new one.
So ain't nobody doing that.
So assuming it's in the software then again, in theory it can be passed.
But we go back to the old
and, you know, we've, we've gone over this topic like 50 times now that like, yeah,
if you have like something like a Google phone or whatever,
you can probably get updates if you have a carrier phone.
Good luck with that.
And if you're like me in Canada, then just, you know, that's why I hate to say it.
That's why I bought an iphone because I know
I'll get software updates for about three years.
And you know, and somebody was pointing out that like
something like 80% of these Android phones basically will or
more to the point can never get an update.
Yeah, that's going to be a problem for, I don't know, probably 3 to 5 years.
I think cell phones, realistically, once people have had them for five years,
they tend to chuck them.
Well, they're just gonna quit working eventually. I mean,
that, I, I can't think of a cell phone in modern
memory that, that has lasted more than probably two or three years.
My iphone three kept trucking until I chucked it.
I mean, the battery was toast on it, but
the electronics were fine.
And so I would actually use it when I traveled, I would have it plugged into a battery.
I'd go to T Mobile, get a $10 SIM card and
a
one gigabyte data plan for like 10 bucks because my carrier charges me 60 bucks for,
I think it's half a gigabyte of data in the US.
You know, it's crazy, man.
Yeah. And my, my, you know, having an iphone, it doesn't do dual SIM cards.
Um, so I would just haul around my old, uh iphone three, you know,
pop a T Mobile sim in it, get my data plan and that's now my gps basically.
And, or, you know, finding a place to eat
that won't kill me.
Oh, hey, good news. I just found a new Korean Fried chicken place. Amazing. So,
and apparently this is a big, apparently, like
there's, now I've tried three places locally that are Korean that do fried chicken
and they are all
like literally some of the best fried chicken I've ever had.
So apparently that's a thing in Canada. And I hope in the US too is that
-- apparently Koreans have mastered fried chicken,
-- I guess I've never looked,
but that's in, in, how did we get to this?
You're talking about cell phones?
Sorry.
Just with respect to the food,
you know, in the
epidemiology, not killing you. Right.
I always look at the Yelp reviews and stuff now for these restaurants,
it's good that we make it from talking about salmonella to Korean
Fried Chicken with a stop on identity theft and cell phone.
But uh
but yeah, so,
yeah, I mean, these phones are never going to be updated.
Now, is somebody going to actually exploit this on a massive scale?
And the answer is almost certainly not.
They, they can't, you have to, the proximity is the problem. Right?
Well, and, and in certain environments like say New York City or the subway or stuff,
you could definitely pop tons of these phones.
But then the question is ok, so you've hijacked these people's phones,
-- kind of, how do you monetize that?
-- Well, my guess is
this won't be a, a mass market problem.
This will be like a tailor access operation sort of thing, right?
Where you have and that's
in one organization wants to attack another organization.
And so this is one of the ways you can get inside of the wall,
right.
And the beauty is, yeah, it's, um, like, yeah,
it's definitely going to be used only
with like advanced persistent threat style people.
Right.
And I mean, the thing I really would
love to see is what's the feasibility of, you know, kind of
breaching air gaps by kind of,
you know, pop guy's home computer with Bluetooth, pop his cell phone,
have his cell phone, pop into the office, you know, and so forth.
Right. You probably don't even need that, man.
I mean, the home computer is probably logged into the office gmail, right?
I mean,
that's, this is, this is the crazy thing I think about with bring your own device
is
you have so little control over what's going on.
And I guess at the same time this is the world we have to architect for.
And again,
did you really ever have that much control when you were buying these devices
-- for these people?
-- No, you did not. And that, that's the, that's
-- exactly
-- right.
A lot of security people will say, oh, we have to disable remote gmail access.
That that's, that's the problem.
And in reality, uh number one, you can't
because then people are just gonna like run a proxy on their work machine, right?
That they connect into or some nonsense like that.
I know the government does that a lot and I actually
kind of envy it because when these people aren't at work,
they're not at work.
And, and that that is glorious. And that, that has a very,
I just figured out,
I think that's why a couple of my
coworkers actually have desktop computers and not laptops.
Sure,
I suspect.
And I just realized,
I think my next computer I get from work will be a desktop because then I'll be like,
yeah, no, sorry, not at home. Can't
see.
That's one thing I do try really hard to do is I keep
my laptop on my desk and it doesn't come off my desk.
If I'm doing something, I'm, I'm in here doing such stuff, but at the same time,
it's really nice.
Obviously, when I travel, I just grab it and go and, and everything's fine.
But,
well, I've also, so with my just having moved,
I've also basically decided to really embrace, you know,
Google's beyond Corp thing.
So right now my, it infrastructure at home consists of,
I've got my, uh my DS L and my cable modem.
They both obviously do
N A,
you know, because I, everybody has more than one device. Now.
They both do wi fi uh reasonably, well, not great.
Um I will have to plug a Wi
Fi like an actual Wi Fi router into the cable so I can get coverage in the backyard.
Um And, but that's it.
Everything else, the laptops, the ipads,
they're just sitting on those networks that I, I
have intentionally not plugged in or used my, uh like I have a PF SENSE,
hardware firewall,
you know, running, what is it free BS D I think is what they use.
Um,
so I've intentionally gotten rid of my firewalls and I, we were,
I know we were talking about this before the show and you were like, well,
but you know what if the ISP device is hostile?
And the answer is, well, yes, it probably is.
Regardless.
I still have that thing in my path of communication because,
and if all you care about is the net, then it's going to do its job.
Right.
Well, more to the point, almost everything in my house is mobile.
So having a firewall at home is nice. But,
you know, when I take my phone or tablet or laptop to the coffee shop,
it's on the public internet.
Well, or maybe not on the public internet, but it's at least within the coffee shop,
it's, you know, accessible.
Yeah. Yeah. And so more to the point I have to,
I have to secure all my devices as if they were properly attached to the true internet
because that's probably what's going to happen with them.
Yes. Yes, it is.
-- And you
-- know, so
I, I think I stopped
pretending like I, I can have a walled garden of safety.
I think that's exactly the right way to look at it.
There's, there's no other solution.
It, it is what it is.
Yeah.
Literally the only thing I can think of value for having
a home firewall now is if you have two internet links,
like me
-- and you have automated fail over.
-- Sure.
And, and I get that, that, that does make sense. I,
yeah, I've been thinking about this actually and I no longer have anything.
I've, I've slowly been
just dealing with my infrastructure and the only thing I have left
and in my internal network that, that is we'll say not an end,
end client
and client. That
makes sense.
Uh Anyway,
yes, that makes sense
is I have a file server that I use for backups and like that's it.
But even that doesn't have
any, nothing is open, you have to off
in some way to get to it. So, yeah, basically, I've reached a point where
because I used to have a guest network and I thought I was thinking this last night is
I can turn my guest network off. I have no reason to keep this on anymore.
And it's just a pain in my neck because
actually one of the things I found is if I have two devices that want to see each other,
like to play Minecraft or something and one is on the guest network and one isn't,
it's like, oh crap, you're on the wrong network.
Like switch that.
Yeah.
No, my uh like, yeah, my wifi used to be like, oh super secure password, blah, blah,
blah.
Yeah, I'm probably gonna basically set it up so that the password is like, password
or, you know, something along those lines where it's,
yeah, exactly. You know, like my home address or whatever.
Who cares,
who cares? Like, that's, that's the moral of the story.
Yeah.
Well,
I remember a few months ago we were at a nice Mexican restaurant in Cold Lake and, uh,
they had Wi Fi but no free Wi Fi.
And so my partner being smart,
she hopped on the restaurant named Wi Fi and
tried the restaurant name with the password and it worked
well done.
And, and my thinking there is like,
why bother even having a password at that point if it's the name of the wire, like,
if it's the name of the restaurant, right?
Like, it's clearly, that's quite guessable.
Who knows? Because somebody told them open Wi Fi is bad.
I mean,
but, I mean, that's it. Right.
I mean, this whole beyond Corp thing I think makes sense because quite frankly the
everything is going to end up on the internet
at some point whether you want it or not because
almost everything is mobile now. Right.
So, yeah, let's stop pretending. I mean,
but, yeah, you know,
uh,
I know all these government offices that have,
like Wi Fi locked down and they have their networks locked down and blah, blah, blah,
but they issue everybody laptops and it's not like they're physically
like they're locked to the desk with those little Kensington locks.
But obviously the people can unlock them and move them to the break room or whatever.
So obviously they can move them to like Starbucks
or whatever.
You gotta love it.
Oh, well, anyway, anyway, I think
going back to the bring your own device thing,
I think this is actually a positive thing is,
you know, for example, the cloud security alliance, right?
Our our technology requirement for you.
If you work for the cloud Secure Alliance is simple,
you have to have a device that can uh receive S MS messages.
Uh So that indicates some sort of cell phone typically
uh
which I think everybody has at this point.
Um You must also have a device that can run um
Google authenticator.
So the authentication app, so it's an Android or an iphone
-- device,
-- you can use a U two F key man.
Uh Well, that's uh also supported, but um
essentially you have to have a device that can at least run
mobile phone apps
and it can be a phone or, you know, it could be an ipad, I don't care, right?
And then that's it,
that's the technology requirement.
Then we basically are like, you probably want to also have like a computer,
like a laptop or something
and like it has to be able to run a web browser,
which basically means like anything in the last 15 years is probably OK.
You know, and that's it, right.
That's, that is our policy uh technology policy, right? Everything is in the cloud.
So
you basically have to have, yeah, we, we actually do use UTF KEYS.
Um,
you know, but they're, they're kind of a chore in getting them to remote people.
And also, you know, those, some of those factors
get it from
a
man and they're good to go.
Yeah.
Well, it's just, I actually, no, I'm not going to,
I tell them to buy an expensive because why, why am I gonna, you know?
Yeah, I, I'm not a logistics center.
That's what Amazon is for.
Like, that's literally what Amazon is for.
I could update my address with them. I want my packages.
Um
But yeah, so sorry just I,
I have to update my address with so many
people and it's so pointless because really the only
people that matters are the people who give me
internet because they need to know where I live.
So they know where to put, you know,
put the wires and Amazon because they have my packages.
It's true
and I guess Canada Post because they also have my packages.
Um
But yeah, so,
you know, that's the thing right is,
is we have literally no it policy other than you must be able to receive S MS messages
and you must be able to like run mobile apps
because we kind of assume being that it's like
past the year 2010.
But
you can figure out how to get a computer that can go on the way.
-- You think
-- so, except there's lots of organizations that are stuck in 2005
and, and don't do any of those things.
I
too bad
-- for them.
-- It is, it is, it is,
the world is changing at a dramatic pace
and we are not keeping up at all.
Well, it's funny too because the, the technology to do this.
So a great example, everybody's like, oh, if you bring your own device,
what happens if these people copy all the data off, blah, blah, blah?
Well, yeah, that can happen. But
you know, you can do things like Citrix,
right? The the desktop
stuff where,
you know, you, you log into a Citrix app and you essentially,
it's like a remote desktop thing
and you know, you can't visit, like you can't cut and paste,
you can't copy files off so you can screenshot for sure.
But
like come on, like to get a ton of data out via screenshots, you know, that's,
that's gonna be an onerous process.
Well, and not only that, like this is something I think about a lot is
how much,
what are you doing?
That is so sensitive that if it does escape, it's going to ruin your business.
I bet most organizations literally don't have something that if it leaked,
could ruin their business.
I I would agree the vast majority yet, quite honestly,
very few companies have amazing patent pending technology or, you know,
pharmaceutical data.
That's like super sensitive and quite frankly, most organizations,
even if you gave this data to them, they couldn't execute on it,
right? Like,
like a great example is ebay. They were not the first auction site by all means,
but they executed quite a bit better because I
remember using some of those other auction sites and,
oh my Lord, they were painful
and ebay made it, you know, about 10% less painful.
Yeah. And, uh, they won, you know, just like Amazon, right. I remember
Amazon. It was like, yeah, I can buy stuff from them. But this is like stupid.
Why would I buy stuff from them?
I can go to the store
and not wait.
And then of course, now I buy everything.
I had that conversation with my wife yesterday. We were driving home
from, uh, we, we were at her parents' place
and
we talk, we were talking about old stores because Toys R Us is declaring bankruptcy.
-- And like when I was a kid and Toys R Us
-- was,
-- it's official now because I heard they were thinking about
-- it.
I'm pretty sure they announced it officially last week.
But it was like, when I was a kid it was a huge deal. Right. And,
and we're talking about that, you know,
I remember getting the Sears catalog
was a thing, right? It was like this enormous phone book sized catalog of stuff.
And as a little kid it was like, look at how many things there are here.
This is amazing.
And,
and you figure these stores back in, in the early nineties probably said Amazon,
you know, online ordering.
Who wants that crap? Right. Nobody wants that.
And now you feel
-- like they're all gone.
-- And
the funny thing is that's how Sears started
the whole point of their catalog business was to
utilize excess freight capacity on the rail line.
Exactly.
And, and then I think brick and mortar
thing and, and people often forget.
And here's the thing too is this is the nature of disruption
and this is kind of the way security is as well is
there are things happening that are going to drastically change
our industries and if everyone knew what it was,
it wouldn't be disruptive.
Right.
True.
Some of it though, like for example,
bring your own device that will clearly happen because quite
frankly,
well,
yes and no,
it's here but a lot of companies refuse to support it or pretend it doesn't exist.
Don't keep working for that company.
You need,
you need to find a new job because your company
is probably not going to be around in 10 years
because here's the thing right, right now, like a phone,
a phone is a hugely personal device, right?
Like my whole life is on that phone, that phone knows what my home is, it knows,
you know, it literally,
I get phone calls and it's like this is probably so and so because I basically
strip mind all your email and found this phone number in a random signature line.
So it's probably this person. I'm like, cool. That's actually correct.
Thank you for that.
You think that is a personal device?
Think about augmented reality,
like a pair of glasses and some other things that
you use to interact with reality on an ongoing basis.
Right.
That's
like
underwear.
-- That's something you
-- cover this.
Yeah. Actually they did. Yeah.
Well, again, in the show, well, actually I think they covered this a few times,
actually. Yeah, that's true. Augmented reality.
I'm thinking of the one with the Facebook,
like app where people give each other scores.
Um,
I rock bottom. I think it's called
Yeah.
-- Yes. Rock Bottom. We'll put links in the, I guess, links to Netflix,
-- uh, whatever.
Just, yeah, if you're listening to this, you don't know what Black Mirror is.
Shame on. You go find it and list it. Right. Like pirate it if you have to.
It's worth it.
I didn't say that
anyway.
Uh, right. And I think there's one more thing we should talk about before we go.
And that is, uh, uh, Poor Trevor, the cockroach at Derby Con.
Yeah. So, what's the deal with this? I,
it's completely silly and in fact I didn't go to Derry.
Derry
comes on a weekend and I,
I have a hard time getting away on the weekend actually just due to family stuff.
And
so apparently
some,
somebody found a cockroach in their milkshake apparently at this hamburger joint,
one of the, one of the derby con attendees
and they put a picture of the cockroach on the internet,
but the cockroach is completely dry.
So my suspicion is it didn't come out of a milkshake
because I can imagine what a milkshake cockroach would look like.
And it's not that,
but
-- I
-- imagine you wouldn't find it because it would have been
-- or
-- you would have just drank it. I mean, let's face it. Right.
Oh, that's a piece of strawberry. Right.
Anyway, anyway,
yes, I want a milkshake now. But anyway, uh
and so in, in true hacker fashion, you know, posted on Twitter,
everyone's retweeting it and ha and this
funny and then apparently the restaurant like,
started flipping out and it's giving all these
statements and interviews and stuff about how,
how clean, how clean they are, which whenever, like if you, if you have a restaurant,
like you have cockroaches, just end of story.
Right? I don't care who you are or where you are. Like, that's just life.
Right.
-- Just hopefully they're well behaved and they stay off the counter.
-- Right. Exactly.
Yeah. Stay under it. Right. Cockroaches.
And if you listening, you're going to stay under the cabinets, right?
That's where it's
when the lights go out, then you're fine. But until then anyway,
and then,
and then apparently people, uh
you started a vigil at the restaurant and there's a picture on the link I put in the,
in the notes
where it shows like someone has a bottle of Colt 45 out and, and just all this,
this silly stuff for the obviously untimely death of Trevor the cockroach.
So it was,
I'm sad.
I miss Derby Con for this event only like all the
other stuff is on youtube and I can watch it.
But I'm sad. I missed this.
Yeah, I've added a link to the show.
We had a similar thing for a dead raccoon in Toronto a few years back.
Yeah, they, they built a memorial around them while the city,
I guess. Well, even better yet. Ok. So somewhat related topic.
Uh, somebody basically found like, what they thought was kind of a big house cat,
sort of chilling out on a piece of grass.
Uh, so they call animal control, right?
Because, you know, big house cat loose should be picked up.
Turns out it's like a bobcat and the animal control lady of course is like, yeah.
No, I do like dogs and cats. I don't do bobcats.
That's, you know, you better call fish and wildlife, you know, fish cops.
So she, and she just bails and what gets me though, these people are like,
posting pictures and they're like, oh, I kept my distance from it.
I was like, 3 m away from it, like 10 ft and I'm like
a house cat 10 ft away from, you will be on your face.
Like by the time you halfway blink and
jump and
a
cat,
like a bobcat will be like eating your face
in less time than it takes.
That's like, you know what I always think of in this is there was, there was some,
some guy, he was like a documentary filmer or something and decided to live
with the bears and they, they literally ate him.
-- Yeah,
-- there's apparently a sound recording of it.
That's what I heard. And it's, I just, I always think about stuff like that. And
what
do you
-- play stupid games? Win stupid prizes?
-- I guess.
It's just like,
what do you expect to happen? Right.
If you go live with the bears, they're almost certainly going to eat you.
They're saying a 1% chance the bear will eat you today. Right.
Someday your 1% is going to come up.
Oh, sorry. It wasn't a bobcat. It was a lynx.
And if you've ever seen a lynx, you know, that's not a house cat.
-- Yeah. I don't know if I've ever, you really
-- should know that.
I, I feel like, sure.
Uh,
but anyway,
they're like, 30 pounds
-- and they have, like,
-- that is
wacky ears.
It is not a house cat.
No.
Um, but yeah, so, and this comes back to security and that
we've made life safe enough that most people don't know.
Like a great example here is the tourists and the wild animals and they, like,
go and feed deer and stuff and like,
yeah,
anybody that knows what a deer is knows you don't do that because deers are vicious,
vicious bitey kicky animals.
Yes,
I've been chasing
deer.
It's like geese,
geese. Are,
they
use them as guard animals
in,
did you know? So, so get this.
I remember going to London some years back and there were Canadian geese there.
And I thought, why are there Canadian geese in London? Right.
I, I looked into this
and it turns out one of the kings thought the geese were neat
and they imported yeast and obviously
they're a total menace now and everybody hates them.
But it's like, why would you bring those things willingly to your continent?
-- I
-- mean, they make good eating. I'll say that they are tasty. They're so horrible.
They're like the worst creatures ever.
-- They are incredibly aggressive.
-- I hate the geese.
And, well, I ride my bike a lot by a river where there are geese all the time.
And, oh, my goodness. I get chased by geese so much. It's not.
And I always think like the problem is they're big enough.
If I ever hit one on my bike,
I'd probably fall off and then his friends would attack me.
So I tried really hard.
Right. Right.
All right. It's time to call it.
So I guess parting words,
-- if
-- it's bigger than a house cat, give it some
room.
That's good advice.
All right. So anyway, thank you. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can find the show notes at open
source security podcast.com.
We have links there to Twitter and Facebook and the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
hit us up with any, any news or notes, you know, let us know
-- if nothing else, Kurt, you have a wonderful rest
-- of
your day.
-- You too, I guess. Stay safe folks.
-- Stay away from the house, cats.