Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in package tracking crime. Josh Bresser
package tracking crime.
So I have an anecdote to tell you before we get on to the topic of the day.
So I lost power the other night
and
it was out for a couple of hours and power comes back on it.
Storm.
Yeah, that horrible storm. Crazy storm
power comes back on at 5 a.m. And I know this because
when everything turns on the bell beeps and it, like,
woke me with a start and I was awake awake.
Right.
So I, I do my usual go around the house, check everything and of course, I've got my,
like, rack of computers in the basement
and I dread looking at it and power was out long enough. The ups shut it down. Yeah.
And I dread this because obviously anytime something starts up,
something breaks and of course,
one of the computers doesn't start and I
name all my computers after Mario character.
So this one is named Luigi
and I'm like, this is the oldest computer I have by
a wide margin.
So I'm thinking
maybe something died for real this time. Like this is it, I plug it in.
I plug in a monitor because obviously there's no monitor on anything.
So I've got to get my monitor, find the right cables and this is a really old computer.
So I have to find a VG, a cable that I can plug in. I have, I have an old TV.
Yeah, it's old, I have an old TV. I keep as my like basement monitor
just because it is a VG, a plug on it. Like, just for this computer.
That's literally the only reason I have it.
-- You should probably replace that computer with a Raspberry Pi four.
-- So I, I want to.
But the reason I don't is because I run
a Bitcoin demon on it to download all the Bitcoin Blockchain.
And so I need a huge disk in a lot of memory. It doesn't need to be fast.
I just need the RA M and so it's got 32 gigs of ra M in it. But it's really old. Anyway,
machine is dead. Plug it in and it's like keyboard air.
It says I'm thinking keyboard air. What?
I've never seen a keyboard air in a bio, like in a long time.
So anyway, it says Press F one,
right.
Yeah,
I hit F one
and
it tries to do Pixie Boot and I'm thinking,
what,
like, where did this even come from? So anyway,
bio battery died. Yes,
that hasn't happened to me in so long. It took me
significantly longer than I want to admit to realize that
battery had died and all of the settings were lost.
It had no time. It didn't know where to boot from.
And of course I replace the battery. Everything's fine again.
But it's like, oh, my goodness, what?
It was just so silly.
Like I,
that's one thing I hate about my motherboards now is the two Windows machines I have.
Every time I upgrade the bios,
they lose a bunch of bios settings.
Not like all of them, like they keep their boot settings.
But for whatever reason, every time I upgrade the bios,
it
disables the secure virtual machine setting.
So I boot into windows and I try and start up a virtual machine and it fails
actually. So fun fact too. The other thing that made this exciting
was when it reset all the bios settings
it re enabled secure boot
with. And I know I'm using an old Legacy Bios
boot loader because the machine is ancient.
I don't, I don't even think Shakira
was enabled in Linux back when I installed this thing.
And I've been like, upgrading Debbie in for decades.
But
yeah, that, that was another part of it. I'm like, why won't you boot?
And it took again?
I spent like an hour getting this stupid computer started just because I'm like,
stupid.
-- See,
-- and that's why I do regular reboots on my systems is to
actually see if they reboot or not. And if everything comes up, like,
like on my desktop, I, for whatever reason I cannot get slack, the slack client to,
to start
on boot. It says it does, but it's not running.
Ok. So now here's something to think about
if I had just rebooted that computer and I, I do reboot it occasionally
it would have been fine because the power was still applied to the system. Right.
It was only when I lost this battery.
Like, this computer has probably been powered for, for a decade or more.
I have no, this battery could have died four years ago. I don't think I've lost power
coin ones. The cr
2030 twos. I've got like a box of them because
I,
I needed, I needed one at one point and I forget when this was, but I go, I,
I think it was, I went to the hardware store
and one battery in 10 batteries were like a dollar apart.
So I bought a bunch of them and I will never run out.
Well, the, the,
the best part was a lot of those batteries will degrade over time because I
bought a whole bunch of really cheap 2030 twos and two years later they're,
they're all dead.
-- Uh,
-- I bought Energizer, which I, I purposely don't buy.
-- Ah,
-- well, yeah, you name brand.
I do not buy cheap batteries.
I've watched a lot of youtube videos where people take cheap batteries and,
and kind of compare them to non cheap batteries.
And
it is clear
that paying the extra money for Du
-- Cell and energizer is money well spent. Yeah.
-- Yeah, I know.
I've had to scrape white crud out of my kids' toys once in a while.
All right.
Anyway, anyway, we have a topic today that is not the old hardware in my basement.
-- Well,
-- it sort
of is, it's so what's interesting to me is that more and more equipment,
especially things like anything that runs on electricity
now is getting a computer jammed into it.
Why? Well, because honestly it's easier to jam a
computer and then have that like a little 16 bit or 32 bit micro controller
kind of be the on off switch and power settings than it is to,
you know, for example, have like an analog thing, like back in the old days where,
you know, the more you pull the,
like a Rio stat on the trigger where the more you pull the trigger on your power drill,
the more power it lets through that kind of thing.
And so what's fascinating is,
and this is a bit of a segue into economics.
I did not realize this when you buy power tools, for example, at Home Depot,
Home, Depot doesn't pay for those, how those power tools.
So I didn't know this, I don't, I didn't know this. Explain this
-- straight up
-- because I always wondered, like I get,
there's,
there's companies that are big enough that they send their
own people out with their own trucks to stock stuff.
Like Pepsi is a good example. And Coca Cola, right,
you go to the supermarket and
quite often in the bigger supermarkets you'll see a
guy in a Pepsi shirt with a pallet of Pepsi
stocking the shelves.
Right. And they get a certain amount of shells away. Same thing with Whole
Depot Lowe's, you know,
Milwaukee DeWalt,
all those that literally you'll see like a big red
or big yellow truck in the parking lot with branding
and you know,
the the person is slipping in a shopping cart full
of power tools and putting them on the shelves.
So literally the way it works is Milwaukee or DeWalt
get an agreement with Home Depot and they get a certain
amount of shelf space in a certain part of the store,
you know, the tool corral and they stock it
and
that's it. Home Depot doesn't pay them.
Home Depot then sells the tool scans at a checkout
and then I assume some 30 60 90 day type of payment occurs after that tool is sold.
So like and Milwaukee and DeWalt aren't even getting paid
at the time of the tool being scanned and sold,
you know, they're getting paid later.
So the thing is essentially if those tools get stolen.
Yeah, Milwaukee eats the loss, not Home Depot,
right? Because it never got scanned out.
And, uh, the BC A VE youtuber who, you know,
he takes apart power tools and shows you how they're going to fail and how to fix them.
More and more of these tools have an RF ID tag,
not on the box, not on the tool, but
in the tool, like literally there'll be a, a spot in the casting on the inside of it
where
the RF ID tag is inserted,
you know.
And so they, they, you know,
scan it at the checkout and run it over the powerful magnet or whatever.
So it doesn't beep on the way out the door. But the problem is you can do things like,
well bring your own magnet to the store and, you know,
kill the uh kill the tag or you can
stop, stop telling everyone how to shoplift.
Well, every dude this is,
I was about to say there's a scene in a movie where they buy two cast iron bathtubs,
flip them up on top of each other.
So it's like a giant Fay
shield.
And before they do that, they fill it with power tools.
So they pay for two bathtubs full of bath
uh power tools.
-- I think it's Boondock Saints or something because
-- the store would never check
inside of that.
No, they actually wouldn't because you're buying two heavy bathtubs.
What they're going to make you pull them apart and look inside.
I would hope they do.
-- I,
-- I suspect it would work anyways. The point is
so
then the next step is, well, what if we add DRM
and have
like an enablement step at checkout? Right. So you check out and for example,
they
Bluetooth, uh I believe it's Bluetooth uh connect to the tool
and
essentially turn it on like enable it so you can steal it, but it's not enabled.
It's a, it's a brick.
-- Yeah,
-- this is a wild idea and we obviously have a story.
We'll put a link in the show notes. I read this in my, so I've got
-- couple of thoughts and this is
-- a lot of high
end cars do this right with the anti theft systems where
you have like a valet mode where they can be driven
like a mile or you have literally like Tesla's apparently have
when they're shipped,
they have like a temporary access card that you get and you can drive the thing,
you know, tens of meters.
And so what's interesting is with high end car thefts is, you know,
they'll pull up a car trailer, like right in front of the car, start it, you know,
get it to move a few meters onto the truck and then take off with it and,
you know, electronically got it later and you know, hijack it.
Is this actually a problem? How many high,
I mean, how many Teslas get stolen per year?
I believe the number is like single digits
and that's because
they call home,
right?
And that's, that's the second part of this story is
you can now easily make a device call home because,
well,
the Wi Fi and the Bluetooth is generally getting quite publicly available, right?
We just did that show about Amazon's neighborhood thing,
right?
But for example, Apple did this with Apple air tags, right?
I I bought some tiles tags a long time ago and tile tags are ok. They do Bluetooth.
So you know,
you put them on your key ring and you can find your key ring in your house kind of thing.
Um But they're not
super smart and
essentially they can only be spotted by other people running the tile app,
which is pretty rare.
Whereas you know the Apple Air tags will by default, everybody's
iphone and ipad.
Oh, yeah, I see an Airtag.
I'm going to report it home to Apple and, and apparently it's all crypto ma
secure blah, blah, blah. It's fine. No privacy issues.
Yeah.
Well, in fairness, like if I'm carrying an airtag around this Bluetooth beacon,
I'm kind of expecting it to be tracked because that's
kind of what it's for.
Well, but if, if I'm next to you now,
my phone is communicating with your Airtag against my wishes.
Yeah, I fully expect that.
I don't, I don't want it to, I don't want my phone talking to your filthy Airtag, Kurt
as I understand it. Does not communicate with the airtag.
It simply sees the, the, the Bluetooth beacon and reports it.
That's communication. No, no, no.
It's one way from, as I understand, it's one way from my, my airtag beacons,
your phone simply notices it and reports that to Apple.
Probably true. But again, I mean, we, I don't think we even know, but
-- regardless, regardless,
-- will there be no reason for my,
your phone to talk to my Bluetooth.
But it's,
it's collecting data from your Bluetooth and
then telling Apple about what it seems,
right? Which is something if I could turn off, I would. But I can't.
Well,
and
well, I mean,
and I guess that's the biggest part of this
whole problem is if you have a device that allows
software updates that you kind of have to install or are
in some Apple doesn't yet force software updates on you.
Like there are devices
and there are, there are hardware and network devices that
essentially are run by the vendor, right?
You, you cannot disable software updates on them, right?
-- There's that uh there's an HP product that does this,
-- there's lots of product.
I mean, easy example is Nintendo,
right? I own a Nintendo switch. I love Zelda and Mario games.
Like I my joke, I tell my kids always is.
Nintendo could literally put poop in a box and as long as it's called Zelda,
I will pay them for it like no questions asked.
Anyway,
there are constant hacks against Nintendo's hardware.
The switch obviously is, is the thing right now
and
they make it so you can't buy things from their
eshop unless you have the latest operating system update installed.
Because obviously, if you are running an old version, then you can hack it.
-- Whereas if you have the new one in theory,
-- I,
I don't like the word hack because it implies
some maliciousness. This is a device that you want.
I prefer the term root because you own this thing. Why, why can't you?
I don't think, I don't think rooting a device is a malicious act in any way.
But Nintendo has decided if, and, and the thing is they're not even
if you do it, they're just saying you can't play in our sandbox,
which they technically have the right to do it annoys me.
But whatever, I know a lot of people use it for piracy and stuff like that. But like
I, I have a three Ds that I've,
I've rooted because I love running homebrew stuff on it.
Like I think it's awesome. I've got emulators up the wazoo.
I've got weird homebrew things going on. I love it. It's awesome to work with.
Well, and that's, I mean,
that gets into a whole other argument about like people
pirating content because you literally cannot pay for it.
It's not available, but
that's another story.
But getting back to this sort of power tools thing.
What's interesting to me is number one, everything has a battery,
everything that has a battery by definition now has a computer jammed in it.
And that computer is often powerful enough to do Bluetooth and Wi Fi
and thus report if it's lost or stolen.
And what's fascinating to me is we're already at the point of
phones, for example, have long had, you know, the, the,
the find my iphone feature where I can remotely wipe it so that,
you know, the bad guys don't get access to my photos or whatever?
-- Well,
-- isn't there some sort of like global list of known stolen telephones? Right.
So the, uh, what is it ime, I, the international mobile equipment identifier.
Got it.
Wow.
Good
job.
Yeah, in theory there's a global IME I list of
phones that were reported stolen
that
you
actually used to be able to check publicly in Canada and that's all gone.
Now, I,
I tried finding it a few months ago because I
was actually buying a used phone for my son.
Well,
you know, this is like a year or two ago
anyways and I couldn't find it. Right. And it would have been nice because,
well, I could make sure I'm not buying a, well,
reasonably sure I'm not buying a stolen phone.
Well, I,
I think the purpose of the list was so cellular providers could just deny service.
Right.
Yeah, they would blacklist those phones.
-- So that, and
-- I would, I would hope they still do that.
Yeah.
So when you stole a phone, the idea is that,
that there's no more secondary market for
stolen phones because they just don't work.
Right. And
in theory that would, people would stop stealing phones because
people who buy used dodgy phones from a guy on the street
would know that there's a high chance it's not
gonna work so they would stop doing that.
-- So the demand for it would go down
-- and,
and I feel like I don't hear about phone theft very often these days
there's still a
bit of snatch and grab but by and large it's not as,
it's nowhere near as bad as it used to be. I think two factors. One
like Android phones especially are nowhere near as expensive as they used to be.
And number two, it's so easy to remotely brick them
also. True. Right. Like,
dude, we grew up with phones that you could not lock,
right? Like there was
-- like my first cell phones didn't have a lock function.
-- Oh,
I was thinking the phone on the wall like the,
you just
put it out,
you know, it's
so
that's the other thing, most people nowadays have a pin code
and
II,
I think
my first cell phone,
I don't think you could add a pin code to it.
I think it was just the like push star and push three or whatever to make it work.
-- I'm
-- trying to think my first cell phone was, it was a nokia.
-- It was a candy bar, nokia because
-- we all had nokias back then.
And it got 20 months of battery actually, in all seriousness.
My first cell phone I remember got more than 30 days of battery life,
but
we
-- use them nearly as much as we do nowadays.
-- That's true.
I used it like once a week maybe because text messages cost like $7 to sell.
So they
still do
in Canada.
I want, I want real all the way back to the beginning.
And I want to ask a super simple question about
uh power to.
So
once you start putting
DRM
in a power tool,
do you own the power tool?
I would say, and you're gonna hate this. It depends because if it's the kind of DRM
where, let's say, hypothetically you have a power tool with a Bluetooth beacon
and for the sake of argument,
a hardware fuse that gets blown once the tool
is activated and it's like a one way function,
then I would say, yes, you own that tool.
However, that's not what they're going to build because
-- that would be more expensive.
-- It might be where they start.
But that's, you know, you know where this story ends up.
Yeah, it ends up with the Peloton bikes that if you want that safety feature,
so you don't crash into a wall
or sorry, the Peloton treadmills, you know, they added that safety feature
and you got it. What?
I think it was, like, free for 90 days and then it was like part of a $40 a month package
after the fact, something like that.
And, and that's,
yeah, that's where it's like with TV. S right.
I am deathly afraid of having to buy a new TV
in the next five years because I just want a dumb TV
that plugs in a sound bar and an apple TV.
And it's a screen. I just want a screen
doesn't even, it doesn't even need to have speakers because I have a nice sound bar
and,
oh man, I
uh
yeah.
Anyway, I know the, the answer people give at this point is, oh,
just buy a TV and never hook it up to the internet.
I,
I think those days are maybe not over for TV.
S but in a couple of years they will be because these TV,
S are either going to use crap like Amazon's neighborhood or they're going to
just have a freaking cellular, you know, modem in them.
-- And so they're going to spy on you whether you want it or not,
-- you can buy devices.
Go on the, well, it used to be two G and three G networks,
but those are being phased out.
And I'm actually a little sad because I wanted
to buy one of those wristwatches for my son.
That was like, it's a two G enabled wristwatch that kind of lets you track where he is.
So if they get lost you can find them
and these things are crazy cheap.
Uh, but two G and three G are being phased out in Canada.
Uh, I think at the end of this year, actually three G goes away.
Yeah, it's, we're pretty aggressive,
getting rid of it because
come on,
like,
-- think about all that spectrum you get back.
-- Exactly. Right. That's exactly it.
Plus we really do need to move to five G and get, you know,
stuff working better because, well, that COVID ain't gonna mind control itself
that
you're leaving that in.
Um,
totally.
So
I
just,
there's like a great story where this guy has a relatively
nice e scooter and he put two apple tiles in it.
He put one in the wheel, well, where it was sort of obvious
it was like the decoy one and then he hit one in
the handlebars where it was much less obvious and his scooter got stolen
and so he
tracked, it wasn't able to retrieve it, went to black hat, came home,
alerted the police. This is New York City
and finally got the police kind of on site, went to,
uh find it. They found it at a used scooter and bike store and obviously
the scooter and bike store is like, oh, yeah, a lady dropped it off and uh, yeah.
No, we totally didn't get any information from her contact details.
Or anything, uh,
whatever. And my understanding is that's illegal in New York.
Like,
when you sell stuff you're supposed to get contact
details because funnily enough when people steal things.
Yeah,
they then have to monetize it and that the easiest way to
do that is to go to a store that sells you stuff and
sell it to them. Right.
Like pawnshops, there's a reason pawnshops have to keep logs of who gives them what,
especially jewelry and weapons because
that's what the bad guys do to turn their stolen stuff into cash.
Right. Right.
Same with power tools.
And so I kind of wonder about this future because,
uh, I know somebody that bought a really nice expensive AM G Mercedes from Germany.
And um,
it got lost
for a while.
Like, it didn't get lost forever, but like it, but, you know,
it's put in a shipping crate in Germany
-- while it's
-- being shipped.
They sort of,
yeah, they sort of lost track of it for.
It wasn't like,
it probably wasn't stolen, but it was just,
I remember Air Canada telling me
your bags are not lost. We just don't know where they are.
And I'm like, well, do you know which country they're in?
And they're like, no, I'm like, are they in Argentina or in Brazil or in Canada?
They're like,
they're, he's like, and I quote,
they're in
the system and I'm like,
well, like, what am I gonna do? Right. I can't, like,
ok. And then three days after I get home, a guy shows up at my door with my bag.
Right. Right. You know, it's kind of like, I'm glad this happened on the way home.
And holy cow, the border guys.
When you're traveling from Argentina with no luggage,
they do not care for that.
Oh, I bet. I bet. I never thought of that. Wow.
Yeah.
Yeah, that was, uh, that was not a fun trip home. But, yeah, so,
you know, if I could like, it blows my mind that when I order food on,
skip the dishes or whatever, you know,
I can watch the little Pacman delivery driver, you know, going beep, beep, beep,
beep, beep up the road and then he turns left and then he turns right and then,
-- you know, it's, there's about a 32nd delay on the feed. So, by the
-- time
that's,
-- that's a different problem. Right.
-- No, but what I'm saying is if I can track my pizza,
why, you know, why aren't we slapping a cell phone
or a satellite phone onto $100,000 car
for the,
let's, let's talk about power tools.
I think cars are a different story and that's, that's an easier conversation.
I mean, a power tool
is a great conversation because we're talking about a
tool that probably cost somewhere between 1 $100 and $1000. Generally speaking,
they hold their value for decades because
the good power tools. Like,
like I, I will tell anyone listening, like, if you're buying power tools,
the way I always do it is if I need, if I need a new thing and I'm unsure,
I go buy a cheap one.
You when it breaks, I buy the good one and the cheap one always breaks in like a year.
And I have, I have like 20 year old power tools made by DeWalt and like,
the,
the battery sucks. And I'm like, I wish I could buy a battery that fit this drill.
-- There's nothing wrong with it but it gets seven minutes
-- of life. I
wonder if
somebody 3d prints adapters
because you just,
I saw
-- on the
-- internet. I
anyway, it doesn't matter, whatever. All right. So,
so
the issue I see here is,
and this is from kind of
a,
maybe,
maybe a privacy angle is you've got a device that now has some sort of
embedded controller in it and maybe today the controller is basically on or off.
Right. Go to the checkout, checkout, turns it on.
But like you're saying, is the ability to do more.
Yeah, I mean, I, I is, is messed up as this sounds.
It would not shock me if someday there's like a, a
program
where you pay dal
$20 a month and
they make your power tools work and if you stop paying them,
none of the power tools work well, you know,
and, and that's the thing from a business perspective.
There's a lot of times where as a business I would far, far prefer to lease than to own
because maybe I only need it for six months or a year or more to the point.
I just want a power drill that works and when it breaks,
I don't want it to be my problem.
I just want somebody to show up with a new one and I'm not,
and that's entirely appropriate for leasing.
But as a home prosumer consumer, whatever,
I just want to buy a power drill that works
right. You know,
and I don't want to jump through hoops and I don't want to have
to worry about Dr And I don't want to have to worry about having to
pay some fee in the future to keep using the thing I paid for.
Yeah, I mean, so kind of one of the, one of the aspects of this
I, I think of is
so
I, I forget Sony is shutting down
the, I think they undid this because there is too much upper.
But there's, they have a little handheld called the Playstation Vita or the PSP.
No, I think the PSP is the old one
and they were shutting down the online store,
which meant anything you had purchased
that you hadn't downloaded, you would lose forever.
Well, I, I've already encountered that with my kids ipads. There's a ton of apps
that, for example, no, longer work on newer versions of I OS. So you paid for it.
Tough where,
that's a
great example or better yet. There's a really nice coloring app. I'm not gonna name
because it went from,
you bought it to now and I'm not making this up 3995 a month subscription.
Yeah.
And I'm guessing a few people accidentally
enable it
and thinking it's like, at first when I saw that number, I'm like, 0, 40 bucks a year.
Well, maybe.
And then I'm like, no, hang on a minute. Apple doesn't bill yearly. They bill monthly
40 bucks a month for this.
Ok. But anyway, anyway, so here's the thing, right?
So, historically, we have this view of purchasing stuff. Like I buy a drill.
I have a drill someday, the drill will probably die and then I have to buy a new drill.
But once we start putting computers inside of all this stuff,
it starts to get a little squishy because let's say I buy a drill
and
then I sell the drill to someone or whatever and, and the drill manufacturers, like,
-- wait, you're not authorized to sell that drill to someone else or,
-- well,
except you are for sale doctrine.
Well,
right,
Costco went through that with the watch people where
they were buying watches in Europe and selling them
in North America and Cartier or whatever was trying
to claim copyright to prevent them from doing this.
I think what's really interesting though is there are devices where legitimately,
there's like an ongoing cost to keeping it working.
So for example,
uh well, simple example, I, I buy an ipad, I buy software,
the software Apple still has to keep running the store so
I can download the software again after I wipe my ipad,
right? And so there's, there's ongoing costs.
Whereas typically when you buy a power tool,
the manufacturer has no ongoing cost to support it.
And if for example, the tool breaks and you want to send it back to get it fixed,
they're like, cool, that'll be 40 bucks for you to send it back and get it fixed
unless it's like a manufacturing defect. In which case, a recall and eat the cost.
Because I,
like I had a tool where, yeah, there's a manufacturing issue
and they had to not a recall but like a, a voluntary upgrade program.
And I cannot imagine that it was cheap because they
ate the cost of me shipping this tool to Ontario,
fixing it and shipping it back.
I mean,
ok, so
the more we talk about this, the more confused,
I think I'm making myself because you think about an ipad
and I think an ipad or a computer or whatever,
there's an expected
maintenance window, you have
the ipad
-- is useless without software.
-- It is completely.
And
like today you buy a drill
and you're gonna say,
ok, so the drill works,
no questions asked someday the drill's gonna have a computer in and now
the stories start to evolve and change and it's kind of a use case
that
we don't grasp because it's, it's too new and there's, of course,
the terrifying angle of the companies are going to screw this up,
which they probably will.
And there's a simpler sort of maybe scenario example that makes more sense is
you buy a tool that has some sort of computer vision system in it.
And,
well, yeah, you, you probably want that to get software updates and get better.
I mean, maybe, ok, let's, let's, let's take this to the absurd.
Just because we can't,
you buy a hammer.
Hammer is literally like the most simple tool. Like a rock can be a hammer. Right?
-- I buy
-- a hammer
that
we've all, we've all done it.
Every tool I own is a hammer at some point in time.
Every power drill I've ever owned is just scarred on that one side.
-- Uh,
-- you know.
Yeah, every now and then it's like I really shouldn't be doing this,
but I'm too lazy to go get the hammer.
So I just,
it away anyway. Anyway. Ok.
And on a ladder it's, you don't got time for that. Right. Right.
It's like, do not open paint, canvas screwdriver
anyway.
Ok. So a hammer,
let's say someone finds a way to add
a computer to a hammer
and adds DRM to it.
And now the hammer doesn't work unless you pay them as ridiculous as that sounds.
You mean initial payment or ongoing payment.
I don't know because
they want to stop shoplifting of hammers which
-- so
-- there's like a big spike in the handle and it retracts once you get it enabled,
whatever, something like that, you know, like
I feel like
when you there, there's like a line I think, whereas a human,
I feel like you're just adding crap to this for no good reason.
I feel like power tools are really close to that line.
I don't know which side they're on.
I, I think Home Depot might have an argument here for what they're doing.
I don't, I don't understand
the internals.
What's interesting is a Home Depot kind of doesn't
care because they're not the one eating the cost.
-- It's De Walter Milwaukee that are eating the cost.
-- Necessarily. My suspicion
is these power to manufacturers because if you read the article it talks about,
there's actually, it sounds like there's a lot of organized crime adopting power to
theft.
My suspicion is the,
the companies that make these tools because they're on the hook
for the cost have gone to Home Depot and been like,
you need to lock this crap up in cages
because we're sick of eating this and Home Depot,
it's like we don't want to lock it up in cages because then we think we'll sell less.
Right. And so you end up with this
and my guess is that's what happened.
And so they probably came to this compromise of like, oh,
let's put a computer inside of it and that'll save us all.
And
it's,
it is.
II, I can't say either way, I'm going to assume it makes sense.
I mean, a lot of people make security decisions on incomplete data
or they let their emotions take over and they end up doing dumb things and,
and I can't, let's assume this isn't dumb.
I kind of think it might be, but let's assume it's not. Right.
Well, and I think part of it is if DeWalt gets known for,
you know, you steal their tools and they don't work,
then hopefully people stop stealing them.
-- And
-- however, however,
DeWalt could become known for, if you buy
-- DeWalt tools, they might not work.
-- Right?
And I think that's one of the dangers.
Yes. And so I think a lot of this boils down to from the consumer side.
The one thing we do very clearly understand is am
I just paying upfront for this and I own this or
there's some sort of expectation of a recurring charge because
there are things for which a recurring charge is ok,
like the newspaper,
right? You don't pay upfront for the newspaper, you pay monthly
Netflix. Exactly. Like,
yeah,
and there's things where there's ongoing costs that are expected,
like I buy a house and there's maintenance.
So I think that's part of it is that doctrine of, for sale.
Traditionally, when you buy something,
you own it and that's it, it's, it's like if it's a car, yes,
you have to put more gas and oil in it, but
you don't need to keep paying the original owner,
like some sort of fee or something for usage or for driving to another country.
Tesla is trying to do this with autopilot where they,
they want to charge you like 200 bucks a month or something for,
for fully autonomous mode.
And that's,
that goes towards that argument wrapped around.
Well,
what about a thing that has a software component that you
want to get better and you want to be upgraded?
-- Well,
-- and that has to be paid for by somebody like that costs money to develop.
I hear you.
This one's again,
I think the conversation just comes back to the fact that
power tools are really close to that line of like,
-- does it really, I mean,
-- and so I think the reality is because, and this is,
I think why IOT security in general is so terrible is people buy iot light bulbs
and
unless you pay a recurring subscription
or,
and this is what Apple does, which I find in
Apple bakes the cost of upgrades typically into the product,
which is one of the reasons their phones, for example, cost a lot more.
But a perfect example,
we just, my mother's laptop was full like 99% disuse and I'm, like,
looking around and I'm like, ok, well, before I start messing with this too much,
like, what version of Mac Os is it running?
It's like some really old version of Mac Os. I'm like, what the heck?
Like, why aren't you upgrading this moment? And,
and I look at, I'm, like, hang on
2011. Maca.
Oh, that, yeah. No. Ok. Ok.
We're going to Apple dot Store and buying you a
new laptop because this thing is 10 years old.
Right. And she got 10 years of use out of this laptop.
Yeah, it costs more than say, a cheap Lenovo.
But she got 10 solid years of use out of this thing.
Right. And Apple built in that cost same thing with their phones
and as a consumer, I'm, I'm, I personally am.
I understand that and I'm much happier with it because I don't,
I hate being nickeled and dimed to death.
So, here's, here's the example I'll use because we need to wrap this one up.
World of Warcraft.
In theory.
I'm actually glad I never got into World
of Warcraft because I have a strong suspicion.
My life would have turned out very differently because I'm,
I'm one of those people that takes things to an extreme sometimes we'll say,
and
World of Warcraft would have, uh, yeah, I'd probably be homeless and unmarried.
But, but anyway, anyway,
and I had been fired from every job I ever had.
But so like,
my complaint with the World of Warcraft is always you had
to buy World of Warcraft and then pay them per month.
And it was like, I will pay you once or I will pay you per month,
but I don't want to do both.
But those servers legitimately cost money to run. And my understanding is they
-- did improve the game and add stuff to it.
-- Right. Yeah, they're constantly adding.
But you understand my point,
I would be happy to pay the monthly fee if I
didn't have to pay the whatever start up cost is it,
it was like
50 bucks back
then. You know what I mean? Like that was always my complaint, one or the other.
Not both.
All right, I have more questions and I, I have anything as usual, I guess
we get to watch and see
that's,
I just realized that, you know what, I would love a nutritional label on the product.
This product costs X upfront.
Here are, for example, the minimum recurring fees here are other, a great example.
This is iphones, right, iphones. Here's, there's an upfront cost boom done.
But realistically you only get five gigs of icloud data and people
fill that up in about a minute of their personal photos and videos
-- so
-- survive without that.
Well, you can get your contacts and stuff in there. But,
but what I'm saying is realistically if you have an
iphone and you have your photos and life on there.
You kind of do want to spend the extra two or three bucks a month on icloud storage.
It would be interesting to see,
like total cost of ownership,
assuming you'll have the phone for three years or whatever.
-- I mean, that'd be kind of neat
-- given regular usage patterns, given,
you know what I mean?
Like here's an actual realistic,
like, you know, cars do that. Right.
Um, I saw one brand of car because they're quite fuel efficient.
They were saying on average you're going to spend X amount of fuel for this
car for a year and it's like a pretty low number and it was like,
oh, that's nice.
-- That's true.
-- They do do that.
Yeah, interesting.
Anyway, if someone knows there's something doing this, let us know
and
cool. All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to our security podcast.com. Head up our show note, Suzy Pound
says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media.
Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You
-- too and wear your work gloves. Everybody.
That's right. Thank you, everyone. Bye bye.