Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Pressers.
What's not a lot?
The weather's kind of crap this week, but it'll be nice on the weekend.
So I'm ok with that.
Except people could be listening to this
in the post apocalyptic future
where the weather is always snowing because of the nuclear winter.
Uh
Well, but
I honestly
would that be
much worse than global warming?
Maybe it's the, well, that's,
-- that's like global cooling,
-- right?
My worry always is that some bright spark is going to be like, hey,
we have this global climate change with a lot
of extra energy in the system and warming.
And, you know, people have proposed like the sun shades in, you know, Lagrange,
was it Lagrange five orbit right between the sun and the earth.
And my worry is some bright spark will be like, hey, you know,
I was just checking the old literature.
What about this nuclear winter thing?
Do you ever see the Futurama episode where their
solution to global warming was to mine ice and then
when they ran out of ice, they, what made the,
they moved the earth farther from the sun and made every week or every year,
a week longer because of the robots
-- and the robots were the cause and solution to all our problems.
-- That's right.
-- As I think now it's just a, I and ML, it's the same idea. Right. Yeah. Pretty
-- much.
-- Pretty
All right. Anyway, anyway,
so we have a new executive order in the United States. That's exciting.
Which one is it again? What's the number?
I don't know, it doesn't have a number. I don't even care if it does.
All executive orders have a number. Hang on a sec. Where is the bloody
Biden executive cybersecurity? Ok.
Biden's is, oh, come on, give me the,
because you need the number if you ever want to find anything because
like the previous one from the Trump administration is missing on White house.gov.
So you have to go look it up in the federal register.
-- All right. That's
-- fair.
Ok. So the White House fact sheet president signs new executive order
and they don't give the order number.
I haven't seen any sort of identifying information
to accompany it. It doesn't matter.
This is Biden's cybersecurity executive order that we're all
going to forget about in like three months.
Anyway. So, what's the difference?
-- Well,
-- yeah, because there was 4636 and there was 1003,
800. That was Trump's
-- the earlier one was Obama's
-- and those all worked out marvelously, right?
Just trying to think if there was, I mean,
13 800 actually specifically mentions things
like supporting transparency in the marketplace,
which I mean, there is so much transparency in the software marketplace.
Like it's just,
and I like that they actually explicitly call it
resilience against botnets and other automated distributed threats like,
oh, I don't know, ransomware
maybe against an oil pipeline
or you know, an assessment of electricity disruption,
incident response capabilities.
Right. Anyway, anyway. Ok.
-- Well,
-- in fairness though Texas is not part of the federal grid, so it would not be,
would the Texas grid be beholden to this executive order?
No, they, they specifically wouldn't be because they,
they purposefully deregulated themselves.
So they wouldn't have to follow these federal guidelines.
So then it clearly worked because only Texas was affected.
I have a rock in my front yard. It keeps the tigers away.
Do
you? You should put that thing on ebay. I bet you could make a fortune selling it.
Well, apparently people in Houston need that.
And I love how the end of the story is like the tiger was found safe and returned. Ok.
And I'm like,
that's not at all how I thought this was going to play out for that poor tiger,
right. Yeah, I don't. Anyway. Anyway. All right. All right.
So I want to talk about this executive order and I want to take a unique spin on it,
I think as we often do anytime we talk about this stuff and I
want to lay the groundwork of this by saying I fully support any sort of
effort by any organization, be it the government, be it a company,
be it whatever to take an honest look at the cybersecurity we have
and try to, we say nudge us in the right direction.
So I don't think anyone would disagree with that statement.
Now, this executive order is something from the United States kind of, I,
I know about half of our, our
listeners do not live in North America. So I'll try to explain this as best as I can.
I am not a government expert by any stretch of the imagination.
But the United States has this kind of
bizarre government structure where you have the president,
which we call the executive branch and then you have Congress,
which is the House and Senate,
which are just like basically
completely dysfunctional organizations these days,
the legislative branch.
There you go.
See, I'm Canadian. So I have to know this.
I know which I chuckle at.
And as an American, I know nothing about your government, but that's not true.
But most people don't.
Anyway, the House and Senate passed bills they sent to the president,
the president signs them, everyone goes on their Mary White,
but the president is in a position where
they can issue these executive orders which are,
we'll say quasi
questionable from a legal perspective.
There's been a lot of writing on them but they
had the ability to basically tell these federal agencies,
these are the rules I want you to follow.
-- And as the president, they generally do
-- federal agencies, not state and local.
Right. Exactly.
So you can tell, for example, like the Department of Defense, like,
I want you to do these things, you can tell, you know, nist or whatever,
some of these groups.
But here's the thing, the president say these things,
but the president has no authority to control the funding.
The funding is specifically and this is even called out in the Constitution
of the United States that the funding is controlled by the Congress.
And so the president can say federal agencies, I want you all to start logging
all your data
and that's easy to say, but that costs money,
right? And so where does the money come from?
And that's kind of the question. And so these are what we call unfunded mandates
where the president says go and do this
except you don't have any money to do it.
Now, here's a question because I'm not clear on this.
Can the president, so the president can't
specifically spend money in this situation?
But can he forbid the spending of money?
-- Can he block the spending of money?
-- Maybe?
Probably because the, the president has the ability to tell an agency
you can't do a thing.
And we actually had a lot of that in the last administration of a lot of don't do this.
Like, you can't help these people, you can't do that whatever. And so they can.
But at the same time, if, if spending the money is enshrined in law,
you end up in these weird situations.
And like my favorite example of this is in
the United States,
there's thing called the James Webb Space telescope that's being developed
and it's like years behind schedule and it's hilariously over budget.
And
the federal government
has like literally written into the law funding the James Webb Space
telescope that the James Webb will be launched on one of the,
one of the rockets NASA is building, I think it's a SLS the space launch system,
rockets which, and they think that we will build one of these rockets
to launch the James Webb and then probably never build them again because SpaceX
is like 1/10 the price, right? Like this is a hilarious example.
-- What's the other one? The Amazon
-- one blue origin.
Yeah, even they're making progress.
Yeah.
Yeah, they're, well, they're, they're,
they're making engines is my understanding.
I know they've launched certain things.
I don't think they've made it into orbit yet, but, but whatever, it's,
it is obvious at this point
that
private industry
is bringing the cost of rockets down
at a hilarious pace. And so the, the SLS rockets are, they're a lost cause, right?
They're going to be 10 times times the price,
probably more than 10 times the price by the time they build it,
I actually can't even think of an analogy.
That's this bad.
It's, it's literally,
I literally can't think of an analogy where something
is so technologically and financially out of date and,
and
-- ineffective to boo. Right.
-- And, but because it's written in law,
they pretty much have to do it.
And
it's one of those things that
there's nothing stopping the government from, like,
basically rewriting this part and being like, uh,
instead of sls you can use any rocket you want.
Right. But, no, no,
it's in the law and of course,
someone's also building this and they're gonna flip out if whatever contractor is
building this rocket is suddenly not given their huge pile of money.
But you get the idea. Right. It
is. It is silly. So, anyway, anyway,
onto
the unfunded executive order there is, I'll put,
I'll put some links in the show notes.
There's a really, really nice, what do they call this thing?
A fact sheet from the White House that kind of breaks us down.
Because if you actually read the executive order it's very, very long and very,
very dry.
-- Yeah, I actually printed it and annotated it and it's,
-- did you really,
it's,
it's quite interesting.
-- I mean,
-- it is, I agree.
It has some interesting things in it but we will keep it a little more high level.
We'll say, than the,
and the long boring
executive order.
The first one is remove barriers to threat
information sharing between the government and private sector.
And
I don't think anyone would disagree with this. Right.
-- Well,
-- a lot of companies would because they don't want to, you know,
air their dirty laundry.
Even government let alone
even the government doesn't talk about this.
No, I think information sharing is critical because, well,
a perfect example is the not Pech
attack where certain companies
like Maersk got
almost destroyed.
Like they literally recovered their active directory infrastructure
because there was a server in Africa.
That was offline. That's right.
And had a clean copy, right? And had to like
they, they hand delivered, flew the hard drive up to London. You know,
like the whole story is just insane.
I think it's in another show note and then there's companies that had a,
they didn't even get the sniffles from it.
So it's clear that some degree of sharing and some degree of coordinations
is needed because we're having such widely different outcomes.
You know, what's going to happen here though is I bet the lawyers,
especially in the corporate world are going to be like no effing way.
Are you sharing this information?
Well,
one thing I've seen is with incident responses where they
immediately start c seeing their corporate counsel and stuff.
So it becomes a privileged communication.
That's right.
Boom, mic drop,
which is on purpose because you don't want this information getting out.
Let's take the colonial pipeline
is an example of this pipeline shut down for a week.
I can only imagine the lawsuits that are going to come from this.
-- Everyone and their mother are going to sue this company
-- for what you have.
-- No stand like
-- no, you can, you can definitely show financial.
I think of all the, all the gas stations, all the companies that couldn't get their,
I mean, there's, the supply chain is deep
and, but here's the thing
-- you don't technically need standing to file a lawsuit.
-- Well, yeah. No, I know you
standing to file a lawsuit,
but it's going to get chucked out and Colonial
pipelines has deep enough pockets to actually fight these,
you know, they're not some mom and pop shop.
No. No, I agree.
But at the same time,
if the lawsuit ever makes it to the point
of discovery now you can start requesting all these documents
and it'd be like, oh, crap, the intern downloaded porn, you know, or whatever.
Well, or that, you know, from what we,
what I've read is it looks like colonial just shut it all down
because they wouldn't be able to bill people for the product delivered.
But it, it, and it doesn't matter. Right.
The point is information sharing is a great idea in theory.
But I think from a liability perspective,
it's going to be a challenge and I think the government needs to put
basically protections in place for these companies
to say if you share this information,
you will not be held liable if
a third party tries to use it against you.
Ah, see, no, you can't, you can't do that because what if it's a criminal act?
-- And that's, of course, one of the difficulties there
-- is a simple solution to this.
And it's funny because you just brought up True Star before the show.
So True Star is an information sharing platform actually that, you know,
partnered with the
CSA the cloud security lines.
And for example, it has anonym organization stuff so that
you can
more safely upload and share like technical information,
like indicators of compromise like OK,
so we found this malware on our systems and
it was talking to this IP address in Russia.
So this IP address in Russia, if if your systems are talking to it,
well, they're probably compromised by this malware,
you know, or this host name being looked up or you know,
this file name or this file hash, you know, signature.
And so there are existing
systems and platforms to sort of anonymize this technical stuff.
And so that's basically not a problem. That's a solved issue.
I feel like this executive order though, Kurt it the text,
the wording they use makes it sound like they want more,
they want to go deeper than just that.
And they want like literal breach
information from a company, this one feels obvious to me though.
Like, sharing is good. I hope we find a way to do it.
That doesn't create a bunch of,
you know, legal liabilities. But,
yeah. Yeah, I don't, I don't think this one's exciting. All right, let's keep going.
The next one says modernize and implement
stronger cybersecurity standards in the federal government.
And this one basically boils down to use the
cloud more and single sign on which again,
like this kind of feels like duh,
-- it's
-- actually a bit more subtle than that.
And uh it's not use the cloud more, it's use the cloud first.
Well,
that's,
and that's a big difference.
They're pushing for a cloud first model which obviously I'm in favor of like,
I've been doing cloud security for over 10 years
and well, no, but, and the reality is it's better in most cases, right? Most people
just something quote unquote as simple as an email server.
And I don't mean like a proper email server,
like Google does with all your calendaring and docs
and everything I'm talking about just pure email.
Even just pure email nowadays is frightened
technical and sophisticated, right?
And most organizations unless providing email is like a core competency,
they should not be doing it.
And by most organizations I include not just like fortune 10,
but like governments that's becoming more and more apparent for everything from,
you know, expense reports,
time tracking, just everything, right.
-- The majority of organizations cannot run it that well.
-- Right.
And now I, I would say that lumping cloud and zero trust together make obvious sense.
I don't know if everyone always does it. But
no, if you don't have single sign on,
you basically can't exist in the cloud properly because you
-- don't want people with 700 log ins
-- zero trust architecture.
And the software defined perimeter is meant
more for it's essentially moving the security up
to the application level so that the application is aware of and can control it.
Because traditionally we split the data plane and the control plane.
And the problem is then
the data plane where stuff is actually happening.
Oh, you know, the VPN dropped and you were sending the data over clear text,
but the application doesn't know, right.
So we we do more and more stuff with TLS at the application level.
Well, this is moving that authentication and that authorization
again to the application level,
but more similar in style to like what firewalls have traditionally done
as opposed to, you know. Well, here's a login screen, good luck. So
that will happen. But it's going to be tough to forklift a lot of these applications.
And
the good news is is you can just,
you can basically wrap them and technology for
that art exists and it's getting better,
you know, cloud flare is doing this at a scale.
That's ridiculous. There are VPN tunneling and whatnot solutions.
What it boils down to is cloud first though, which is very different. Right.
It's, we're going to lose a lot of on premises stuff, which is good.
And what kills me is these, it,
people that fear for their jobs and the reality
is there's always infinite workload because you can always,
with white collar work,
there's always something you can do to add value to make it less painful,
to make it better.
Right.
Like, if you spent a billion dollars fixing all the it problems an organization had,
you would still have the opportunity to make stuff better and more efficient.
Right. So there's infinite work.
All right. Let's keep going because we're going to run out of
time otherwise. All right. Next one is improved software supply chain.
We've talked at length about software supply.
I don't think there's anything exciting to add at this point.
I think that the one thing that I, I
-- think is worth thinking about
-- what's,
there's timelines in this one and that's interesting.
Well, there's timelines in all this stuff and of course,
the timelines are all going to get, you know,
not enforced and we're going to miss them all. But whatever, it doesn't matter.
I think I stressing that this isn't a, oh, let's just maybe do this someday.
It's good. Right.
Because then they can,
you can bring people in and yell at them if they're
not doing the work at a speed you approve of.
Well, or in theory, you can hold uh vendors feet to the fire and say
you're in violation of this order and we can't pay for this.
Uh
Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
I just, I wonder how those software purchasing contracts are written?
Like does this executive order sort of count as an act of God and that
it can override the contract or is it essentially the contract is the contract?
There's text in the order that says you can get
waivers for all this stuff and that's what will happen.
Some of the suppliers can do this stuff. Some of them can't.
And at the end of the day,
what it really comes down to is you've got work
to do and you're going to get the work done
well and at least with the waivers though, you'll now know where the pain points are.
Yeah, that, I mean that and that's a good point is that,
that's an easy way to say these are the things we should work on first.
-- Well, no
-- more subtly,
it'll give you a hint of which suppliers are in compliance and
which are out of compliance consistently and that'll affect future purchasing.
Hopefully.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Anyway, look at the backlog.
We talk about supply chain a lot and I'm not
going to talk about it today because we'll get,
we'll get in a rattle.
All right, the next one says establish a cybersecurity safety review board.
This one sounds really interesting to me because I feel like this is a good idea.
-- It sounds like they want to create a board.
-- Well, it's like the N TSB. Yeah.
Right.
Right. Yes, that's a great example.
Now, I like this in theory, but I think we kind of come back to some of that,
like information sharing liability problem at the beginning of,
is anyone going to want to work with them?
Because like you think things like the NTSB,
they companies work with them because the insurance
company said if you don't do this,
like we're not insuring your cars, you know, they've got like that, that,
that carrot dangling there of you have to do this.
So there's a really interesting series of youtube videos that I
binge watched a long time ago from the chemical safety board.
So, CS b.gov
and they have these youtube videos where, you know,
they forensically break down what happened at these chemical disasters
and some of them are horrifying and,
and really simple mistakes like a tanker truck
comes by to deliver some horrifying acidic compound
and they hook
it up to the outlet instead of the inlet valve.
And of course, when you put that into the system at the wrong place,
it goes boom, just all sorts of disasters.
And because when you have a chemical related incident, you tend,
it tends to be expensive
because stuff gets blown up and people get dead
and we're, we're getting there with the cyber incidents.
Uh as far as I know, nobody has directly been killed or died because of one of these.
But
for example,
the colonial pipeline incident was very disruptive
and had a lot of opportunity cost.
You know. So I think that this will
happen because it's just we're gonna,
the point where we're not learning anything from all these
incidents and they keep happening exactly the same way.
-- I'm
-- hopeful that this goes somewhere.
But again,
I feel like without an economic incentive behind it just saying we should do it,
I don't think is enough.
We need to either
have someone like the government say, if you're not part of this,
we're not buying your stuff or we need something like
insurance companies saying if you're not participating in this,
we're not insuring you or something.
Right? Because today
funding, absolutely.
Well, not just funding,
it needs incentive for the companies in the private sector to participate in this.
-- So
-- one sad thing is it could be privately funded,
which would be an incentive to do it because
then the companies kind of can control it more.
We have a thing here in Canada, for example, where there's a,
there's a banking regulations,
obviously and there's a government sort of ombudsman banking regulator
where you go if you have a problem.
But here's the best part, apparently,
the banks are able to opt out of it and go to a privately funded one that they pay for
and there was an article today because, like TD and Canada Trust before they merged,
basically, apparently lost a bunch of people's R SPS and they're like, well,
too bad it's gone.
And the agency that would actually investigate this
is funded by them and they of course,
found no real wrongdoing.
So there is actually a strong
incentive for, you know,
industry to fund this because then they can control it
and kind of make it go away a bit,
but that's not a win.
That's not good.
No, no, I agree. Like Esrb is another
one of my favorite examples, right?
The video game rating people where like the industry completely controls it. And
you can, I mean, honestly that one,
I feel like isn't a total train wreck but every now and then
it's like this is weird
anyway. Anyway. All right, let's keep going, let's keep going.
I do hope this one works out because I think it has potential.
The next one says create a standard playbook for responding to cyber incidents.
This one, I have a strong suspicion there is,
I think this is going to be less about doing the
work as it is about just collecting all the crap.
N
that's been writing over the last two decades.
I like putting it in a binder for people.
Well, and some of it is best practices because for example,
how do you do incident response with a cloud?
-- It's not like you can go image the systems. We'll get
-- to that.
-- That's where logging and other things come in. But,
-- well, no, no, no.
But what I mean is having a playbook and a checklist
would really help a lot of people because it would.
Yeah. Right. Right. Like an 80% solution is so much better than a 0% solution.
Especially when things are on fire.
Yeah. And,
and the on fire part is the most important is because,
especially when you're inexperienced when you're in the middle of an incident
and you've never really done this before.
It, you feel the pressure, like you feel the weight crushing you and you're like,
I have to do something now and sometimes
-- doing something is worse than doing nothing.
-- Perfect.
Example, colonial pipelines paid a $5 million ransom. They bargained it down
and apparently it wasn't effective because their actual
internal backup and resource systems were faster than the ransomware stuff.
That's what, that's what I heard,
which is,
yeah, they had so little faith in their, it or their,
it was not able or competent enough to say no, no, no.
We actually have all of this backed up properly. We can recover this.
Apparently it'll take X number of hours. So don't pay those Russian schmucks.
But again, I mean, I assume they weren't operating off a playbook either. Right.
This is probably pretty ad hoc is my suspicion.
Yeah. So again, I feel like this is, this is a good one. I have no complaints.
I think it's something we should totally do.
There's a reason people use recipes to cook food
and don't just free wheel it all the time.
Well, ok. No, that's, that's a really good example though because if you look at
the truly professional and gifted chefs of the world,
they don't use recipes.
But
-- we don't have truly gifted chefs at places like colonial pipelines.
-- That's right.
And, and nor am I right. Like I am not,
I have some things I could like to cook that I have written down on
my recipe cards and I follow them because if I try doing something different,
I'm going to end up with an inedible dish.
Yeah.
The reality is the majority of these companies don't have that level of,
they don't even have line cook competency in most cases.
That's right.
And if you do have that level of expertise, that's great.
Yeah. But you're not a private company, you're like a provider like
AW
s or Microsoft because somebody with that talent is not going to work at mcdonald's.
No, I agree. But also you can have one person with that level of talent.
-- You're not going to have a team with that level of talent.
-- This is all team sports.
-- Now, this is not one person.
-- Right. Right.
If you're a team of one, like your life is going to be terrible.
So you don't,
you don't need a playbook because you don't have time time to follow
a playbook because you're just busy putting out fires all the time.
That's what, that's how it works anyway.
All right.
So the next two are the last two and I want
to clump them together because I think they're vaguely related.
First is improved detection of cybersecurity incidents on federal networks.
And this is things like, obviously
kind of having your,
your sim your security observable solutions and Endpoint and all that stuff.
But then the second one is improve investigative and remediation capabilities.
And this one is kind of like logging, right?
This is this is a big part of logging all your stuff.
And I I think these two things are com are squished into
one in my mind because obviously all of your detection capabilities,
feed your logs and your logs, feed your detection
-- solutions,
-- right? Investigative and remediation are operational, right?
You got to do something
you need people like boots on the ground, so to speak, doing stuff.
And remediation is interesting because remediation
has changed so much.
I mean, remember when it used to be basically OK,
we cloned the hard drive that's a backup except now it's like,
but the system is distributed across how many servers across how many time zones,
blah, blah, blah, you know, there's data on the fly,
we can't just freeze the disc and image it.
Um And now of course, it's moved to the cloud. So it's like, hey, Amazon can I get
all my data out well. And the answer is
-- sort of if you know what you're doing
-- well.
But now,
now here's the thing that makes cloud really cool though is when you're using, say,
you know, Google or Amazon or whatever,
they can give you extremely detailed logs of what's going on in your environment to a
degree that I would say the vast majority of on prem solutions just can't do.
Oh, yeah.
What I turned on cloud front and cloud trail or sorry, cloud trail, you know,
for logging every single thing.
-- It was just like, it's amazing. It was just this giant S3 bucket of stuff.
-- Right.
But now you have to do something with it and that's the challenge. Right.
-- Well, and the good news is there's automated solutions for that.
-- Yep. Absolutely.
There's tons of solutions. I mean,
I work at a company that does this kind of stuff right.
Where you take in like terabytes of stuff and then you
have to sift through it and figure out what matters.
-- Figure out when Bob got hacked.
-- That's right. Right.
And it's, it's hard to do and it's complicated and, I mean,
the tools are getting better every year.
I mean, if you look back a couple of years, the tools kind of suck,
they're pretty good now and they're just going to
-- keep getting better
-- and that speaks to the tools,
keep getting better.
The humans don't. No,
no, no
making a tool twice as good is possible because you do one tool,
you embed a whole bunch of people's knowledge and energy and effort into it.
But making a human being twice as good does not scale.
-- No,
-- humans are never humans have flat lined, right?
Like we are a flat line
of talent,
I would say, whereas all of our tooling, well,
it's probably only growing linearly in many instances.
At least it's growing.
It's, well,
the one thing I find interesting with tooling growing linearly is
that the whole ecosystem grows and then you gain new capability,
right?
It's like, for example,
it doesn't matter how good of a tire I could make for
a car in 1900 because the rest of the car was garbage,
right?
The transmission just couldn't put out enough power to make use of a modern tire.
You know, I'm always reminded of top gear when they, they raced, uh
like a 10 year old or 20 year old Porsche
against a minivan and the minivan just clobbered it.
A modern minivan.
Yeah.
Yeah, because a 20 year old Porsche at that time is, you know,
it's this temperamental piece of whatever.
When, when was this show? I mean, 20 years ago, it was 2000,
it was a long time ago. But the point is
like I bought a used car that's not high end and
its performance is quite good.
You know, compared to like it, it would have been a super car in the 19
-- up through the 19 fifties and sixties.
-- And that's fair.
I don't think anyone would argue with that.
We're seeing that with the security technology more and more where I, for example,
I, you know, we're in Google.
So we have single sign on through Google and a lot of our apps support that and
-- it just all magically
-- works even when we look at things like our endpoint tools now or
I mean, all these capabilities even, I would say a decade ago,
it was very much a
like AAA you had to do all this work, you had to,
you could do it,
but it was an enormous effort where you had to install lots of little agents.
You had to watch just the right files on the disk. You know what I mean?
You had to log them somewhere and it was, it was a nightmare.
And now like these are, these are pretty solved problems.
So I feel like this particular part of the executive order,
I don't think it's going to be exciting because I think the vast majority of
the federal government is already well on the way to doing all of this stuff,
I think standardizing it.
-- So
-- it's time to wrap this one up. But I feel like this gives me some hope.
I think the lack of funding is going to be a problem for parts of this.
But I think kind of like you said just
having some standardization and consistency with most of these topics
-- will probably go a pretty long way
-- well. So the bad news is this is all I mean,
Obama's executive order 13 636 specifically said
develop a technology neutral voluntary cybersecurity framework,
promote and incentivize the adoption of cybersecurity practices,
increase the volume timeliness and quality of cyber threat information sharing.
Incorporate strong privacy and civil liberties protections
into every initiative to secure critical infrastructure.
OK? That one was different and explore the
of existing regulations to promote cybersecurity.
OK?
Look,
here's I think the big difference though is I I looked at that
executive order and I gave it a chuckle because it didn't happen.
I feel like the difference is this,
this Biden order has
dates
and they say who's going to do the work?
They say like this in the DH S is has 17 days to compile, you know what
I mean? And,
and I think in many instances like Nist
already has a lot of this documentation somewhere.
Oh,
there's probably people at Nist that were crying
with happiness when they read this thing and
they finally get to take it out of their filing cabinet and show it to somebody.
It's not even in a filing cabinet. It's freaking published on their website.
It's just like someone needs to like go and take it
and say here we're going to put these two documents together
and this fulfill, you know what I mean? And so I feel like that
makes it slightly different. But again, the devil's in the details.
If there was, if there was a bag of money behind this,
I would be far more optimistic than I am, but I do think some of this is going to happen.
-- Some of it won't,
-- I'm not sure money will solve this problem.
To be honest,
I think there needs to be some fundamental changes
in how we view and treat these things because
back to money. Well,
we have money in the system and here we are with the security, we deserve to quote you.
I mean,
we totally do.
No, no, here's what I mean,
when I say money is so if the federal government goes to a vendor and says,
you have to give me an S bomb,
ignoring the fact that they probably can't process it in any usable way right now.
But they tell a vendor,
you have to give me an S bomb and the vendor doesn't have an S bomb.
They're going to say we need to raise your price $20,000
because we have to build the team to make S bombs,
right?
But you don't have $20,000 in your budget. So now what
you're going to say, well, I guess we don't need an S bomb.
We'll just waive this one if the federal government said, ok,
everyone gets 10% more in their budget because you need S bombs. Right now.
Now we're talking where you can say yes, vendor,
I will give you 10% more and you will give me an S bomb.
-- I seem
-- to remember we gave a whole bunch
of phone companies money for rural broadband too.
Yeah. How'd that work out?
So, that's why I say,
I'm not sure money giving money is the incentive or the solution here.
Not always. I agree with you and look like now we have magic Space Internet. So.
Right. No one's going to care. But pretty much again,
-- I don't, I don't have the answers.
-- Well, the good news is nobody has the answers.
-- That's the problem. And I don't think we're even agreed on the question.
-- That's,
and that's ok. Right.
That's,
that's how you have to start because I think
we often like to jump to solutions when we have
no idea what the problem we're trying to solve is
hopefully some of this helps us understand our problems.
So,
all right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to open social security podcast.com. Head up the show.
Not to Z Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag hit this button. Social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.
The