Welcome to another exciting edition of the open source security podcast, the post
election show. Ha Yeah, let's talk about politics.
So this week, Kurt is again out,
I'm assured by him that he'll come back next week to grace us with his presence.
He's at a CV E board conference.
So once again, I'm being helped by the honorable Dave Seine.
Say hello, Dave.
Hey, everybody. Thank you so much for helping out. I appreciate it.
It's always a treat,
not a problem.
So
Kurt is at a CV E board conference next week,
I think we're gonna talk about CV E actually and what that
means and some of the things he learned at his show.
So
I, I'm sure it will be
an enlightening episode to say the least.
It, it'll be, it'll be riveting.
That's right. As exciting as CV E can be. Right. Right.
So
I'm gonna start with, with listener feedback, which I was ecstatic to receive.
There's a fellow who I,
I think his name is Co Coh cos musings is the name
of his blog and there'll be a link in the show notes.
And
basically this guy took what we talked about in the, the primal
of prime numbers, which I still don't think primal
a word, but whatever that I love the title,
uh,
and, and, and kind of tore it apart and, and talks about the,
the actual real math behind a lot of this prime number stuff and,
and it's a fascinating read.
I'd highly suggest anyone who has any interest in this
to take a look.
Right. Yeah.
It, it, it, you know, looking through it and uh you know, II,
I pulled it up again this morning just to,
just to kind of glance at it real quick again and it's, it's
just the side of a master's thesis, right? On, on prime numbers in the math behind it.
And um you know, I, I've, I've,
as you said, this is, this is great,
this is a great feedback because we're not experts in everything, right?
You know,
I'm an expert in nothing.
Yeah. II, I cringe when anybody introduces me as an expert quite frankly. But uh
you know, it, it,
it, it helps,
you know, we talked on, on this podcast a lot.
You and Kurt talk on this podcast a lot about um
you know, the, the education and,
you know, we as security professionals, you know, how do we give back?
How do we, how do we help people with that? Better understanding? This is perfect.
This is, this is, I, I believe exactly what we talk about when we talk about
you know, how do we get there? How do we get there as a, as a profession?
I completely agree.
And, and I guess there's two things that, that come to mind when I look at this is,
first of all,
I feel like we weren't completely wrong, which I consider a success. Mostly wrong.
I can live with. Completely wrong.
I'm not ok with.
But then the second thing always, and,
and this is something I love about the internet is
there is always someone smarter than you.
There is nothing you're going to do that. There isn't someone smarter than you.
And, and if you're in the lucky, well, I guess here's the thing. Right.
So you can take two views of this.
You can either say
I don't like this guy because he's smarter than me.
And, and he wasn't very nice or you can
elate in the fact that there is always someone who can teach you something
no matter the topic on the internet, which is awesome.
Right.
And, and, you know, iii, I will elate in the fact that, that he took time out of his,
I can imagine very busy schedule to
educate,
educate us. Right. I, I mean, it,
and, and, and did it in, in a way where it's like
informative, not
demeaning
because
seriously anyone who has this level of knowledge clearly just watches TV, all day.
Right.
Exactly. Right.
Right. Yeah. You know, he's on hour 30 of his Netflix Binge right now.
But, but it's, and, and it, it,
it heartens me. Right. It, it, to, to see this kind of effort to, to educate.
Yeah. Oh, totally. It, it's fantastic.
So, so I guess co if, if that is your name, if it's not by all means, uh,
shame me on Twitter.
But thank you so much for the write up. It is, it is absolutely fantastic.
And, and I love it. It,
anyone else who wants to do a technical write up of why we're wrong, please do.
And we would be happy
to give you a shout out on the show.
And II, I don't think, I don't think you mentioned this, Josh, but um, I'm,
I'm sure we'll put a link to this in the show notes.
Oh, absolutely
without a doubt. And, and,
and the show notes will be an open
source security podcast.com for those of you playing along at home.
So by all means, go check it out. It's awesome.
Open SSL Day.
Uh It is open SSL Day
who doesn't love open SSL?
It is,
we have an election
that, that maybe was hacked. Probably not.
But uh
no, I shouldn't say that
I'm gonna rouse someone up
open SSL. We, we'll talk about open SSL.
So there was a new release of Open SSL, like literally earlier in the day.
This is uh Thursday morning and I think it was an hour or two ago.
It is, it is world ending. Right. Dave, should we, uh,
as, as, as, as with all, uh, open SSL releases. It is, uh, the criticality is high.
Um, yeah, I mean, it,
it's always, it's always good to see work being done, um, on open SSL.
It's in everything and I think you, and you and, uh, Kurt spent two shows, uh, uh,
-- talking about Open SSL
-- and certainly we've talked about it at least twice.
It is.
it,
um, but it's, it's
just a nice, a nice reminder that, that it's out there,
it's everywhere and it's consistently being updated.
Um, you know, looking at the, looking at the release notes here.
Um, you know, we've got uh
cha cha
20 Polly 1305, you know, head buffer overflow fix, right?
Um
You know, so that's uh
interesting,
I guess.
Yeah. No, I mean, it's fair.
It's, they, they, now that one is the important part there,
I guess is it only affects version 1.1 0.0
which,
and oh man, Openness cells, like I've never cared for their,
their versioning scheme.
So the latest version will be 1.1 0.0 C
and my brain doesn't, numbers and letters don't mix well.
So I, I've always struggled with that,
but I guess the point is this is, uh
unless you're running the latest and greatest, which you're probably not.
But even if you are, the world will not end,
it's
it.
Yeah,
don't please please people don't create an, a logo for this. It doesn't deserve it.
Yeah. No, seriously. And,
um, that, that, that, you know, you good, good point there. Uh uh Josh is,
know, know, know what versions you are running, right.
Yeah,
because you said 1.1 0.0 is super new and I
think most things out there are probably running 098 something.
Uh, some iteration thereof.
Yeah. Well, I it's 09 end of life.
Um, it is, but it's still shipped with a lot of stuff. It,
since, since when does end of life mean people stop shipping it.
Well, there's ok. Yeah, man, we should have a conversation about this someday.
It's, it's complicated because there are, well, there's two end of life.
There's the upstream end of life,
which means open SSL isn't supporting that version anymore.
But then you have things like Linux distribution such as Red Hat or Debian or whoever
that will continue back. Courting security fixes for the older versions. Right.
But then there's also people who took the upstream version and put
it in their product and it has never been updated ever.
Not once since it was added to whatever it is they have
and it's still vulnerable to heart bleed and nobody knows or cares.
Yep. Let's, let's, let's not dive back into the IOT.
Right. Because that's,
that's exactly, that's exactly what that is. Right.
We're, we're gonna bundle all these libraries into this thing.
That's just going to go out there into the wild and never, ever,
ever see an update ever again
and it costs $2
$2. That's exactly,
actually, it's so funny enough. The mirror botnet
is
been something that normal people have talked about.
Well, they don't know what it is. They just talk about the internet broke. Right.
That, that's kind of their,
the most elaborate way they can describe what happened.
And I've gained an immense amount of joy
explaining to them
kind of the,
the nuance behind IOT and its cheapness and the
inability to update and the fact that quite frankly
nobody cares and they don't have a reason to care
and,
and like everyone you talk to, they got like, oh, but this one thing we'll,
we'll do this, we'll do that and everything and by the end of the conversation,
like you can just see the, the horror in their face and then I know I,
I have a job well done at that point.
That's, that's exactly right. You know, that's exactly right.
Because, you know, and I think, I think you've mentioned it on the show before where,
you know, people aren't gonna wanna spend the $5 extra, the $10 extra for a device
to have it up update.
Right.
I'm a security guy and I'm pretty confident I would save the $10.
-- That is. Right.
-- Right. Right.
But, but we are, we are our, we, we, we're the worst hypocrites out there. Right.
You know, to tell, tell people they need to do certain things and then we,
-- we, we know better.
-- I'm special, Dave. So the rules don't apply to me.
Right. Right. It, it won't happen to me. Right. That's the,
that's right.
And speaking of being special,
there was an election on Tuesday which I know
we both stayed up far too late paying attention to
and then we woke up on Wednesday and the
world didn't end in open SSL release on Thursday.
The world still hasn't ended.
So there's still, there's another day this week for the world to end.
One.
-- Come on
-- Universe. There's, there's one work day, there's there.
You got the weekend too, right? Yeah.
World keeps spinning.
Yeah, that's true. That's true.
So
I will, I will have no comments on politics on this show
because
nobody cares what I think.
At
least of wit me, Josh.
That's fair.
That's fair. So, uh
Red Hat released a security API command line interface tool,
which is about the most exciting name you could ever give something.
So why don't you tell us about this, Dave?
There's actually some really cool stuff going on here.
Yeah. So, uh this is, this is actually a very interesting tool. Um
So those who may not know, uh Red Hat has a uh security data api uh for,
for customers to be able to access our security database.
Um And what that means is you have access to
uh all our information on CV ES, you know, the, the scoring, the,
you know,
what packages are affected, you know, where
uh the Rh SAS are. Um you know what the R hr H SAS are for the uh for the fixes.
And that's um
the Red Hat security advisory.
That's, those are the um Arata that get released for CBES.
Um
And what this tool does is it gives you a handy
uh command line interface to be able to access that data,
you know, on the fly as you're sitting there,
you know, at your terminal and somebody mentions a CV E,
you can quickly just fire off uh uh uh
search via the command line and get all the
information you're gonna need on that CV E.
Yeah, that's, that's very cool. It's,
it is one of those things that I think
people don't appreciate the value in until they need it
because there's nothing more annoying when you were like,
I wonder about this particular thing and then you have to figure it out.
So, I mean, it's cool, like something fun.
I'm glad we did it.
Yeah, absolutely. Um
You know, I, I think it's a, it's a nice little uh
it, it's, it's a nice little gap filler, right? Um
For,
for, for the quick, for the quick analytics, you know,
outside of things like satellite or, or insights.
Um you know, which also give you, give you this information. But
you know, this is that quick one off. Hey, I need, I just need some quick information.
Let me get that. Uh
you
here totally.
And,
and I'll put a link in the show notes and there's
kind of an example of running it because I mean,
as exciting as showing off command line interface tools can be
which we should all create videos of these things happening.
It's a kind of AAA cut and paste sort of deal on, on the, on the website.
So yeah, go, go check it out. I if
even if you're not a red hat customer,
you could probably gain some interesting insights from trolling through the data.
That's right.
And, and you know, I, I think uh I think I'm, you just inspired me, Josh,
I'm gonna go ahead and I'm gonna create a youtube channel solely to
curate uh uh the best command line utility youtube videos out there.
You totally should and make sure that the resolution is
small enough that I can't read what's on your screen
while you're typing away.
That's, that's
a, that's, that's one of the requirements. That
would be
one of the
criteria.
And, and I would suggest you put the microphone very close to the keyboard
so I can hear all of the typing you're doing as it goes on.
Uh Yeah. Oh Absolutely. Absolutely.
As close to the keyboard as possible and as far away from your mouth as possible.
-- That's right.
-- That's right. Yeah. Yeah. It's much echo and background noise,
man. God bless you too.
Uh,
actually, you know, funny enough.
So my kids are like,
obsessed with trying to make youtube videos of them
playing Minecraft and stuff and it's like they are like
these are bad guys. I'm sorry.
Right. Right.
Oh,
yeah. It, it starts, it starts young too. Right.
You know, my, my oldest right now, uh, every time I'm taking pictures or I'm, I'm,
you know, take a video of them or something.
It's, are you gonna put this on Facebook? Are you gonna put this on youtube?
Where is this gonna be? Can I get a Facebook? Uh
-- God help me.
-- Well, in effect, you know, it's so funny enough. My uh my son is 10
and he carved shovel night into his pumpkin this year for Halloween,
which for those of you who don't know shovel Knight is a video game character.
They, this company, I forget the name of them even now. They made a
like retro style game where it looks like a bit Nintendo esque in
its graphics
and, and he loves this game
and he carves the, the the character in like it's eight bit glory, right?
Like it's all cubes and squares.
And then he says, dad put this on the Google and I'm like, what?
That doesn't even make sense. What are you talking about?
And like he wants to type in shovel night pumpkin and see a picture of his pumpkin.
And I said, I'm like, buddy, I, I can't make that happen.
Like that's not how things work.
A,
a after we get off this, uh, af after we close out the podcast,
-- I'm totally gonna Google the shovel night pumpkin and there's
-- a couple of
his has not appeared yet as he asks me almost daily to search for it.
Oh, the web crawlers haven't found it yet.
Well, look, I, I posted it to Twitter to shut him up. Like
let's seo optimized Halloween pumpkin pictures.
I mean,
anyway, anyway, anyway.
All right, we've got,
why don't you talk about this o
of two problem since you are, uh, way more expert than I am at, at of two.
And this is kind of,
this is one of those things that I, I think really interesting in, in, in the lab,
but I question if it will have a ton of validity in the real world.
Yeah. So, um,
where I get all my news, you know, I saw this story pop up on Twitter earlier this week,
um,
where it came out that Facebook and I believe it was Facebook and an older,
uh, implementation of
OO two.
the way they implemented it left it
vulnerable to, uh, um,
being compromised and,
and, and
basically they're, they're talking about how this, this can be used to,
to pop both Android and I OS devices,
um, via this faulty implementation of
OO
two.
And
I think I
while it's, while it's an interesting lab experiment and, and uh you know, you,
you may not be
sold on the the implication in real life.
Uh This, this speaks volumes to how prevalent um
you know, ID PS are becoming, right? You know, things like O
A two and Sam ML and open ID connect and things like that, right?
Where, you know, you're using different authentication mechanisms, you know,
hey, I, I want to look into my bank using my Facebook account,
right?
Uh I
please please don't take that advice
from my phone.
If, if, if, if you, if you work on the, if you work on the web team for a bank,
please please don't take that advice.
That's awful, awful advice. But um
you know, it
the prevalence of using these other, these other authentication providers,
you're really depending on that underlying framework and,
and the implementation, right?
Because
while the protocols are, are,
are good and solid and the standards are good and solid.
Um
implementation is a case by case basis. And
um
yeah, II, I just think that this opens the,
yeah, this just, it opens up the the the prominence of, of that,
you know, sso infrastructure and, and how it can
really cause a lot of problems.
It can, I mean, so there's two sides to that argument though,
you can say that using some sort of centralized identity
is poses a risk which it certainly does.
However, having 10 million passwords
also poses a risk because they're all gonna be crappy. But more importantly
is if you have like the two bit web form.com
that you're logging into using your own user name and password,
you know,
they're not protecting the user names or password
or any of the personal identification pi I data
in that case. So I think
even if these large identity providers are
po pose a certain risk,
I still suspect the risk is lower than
rolling your own identity for every single service.
Sure.
Yeah. No. And, and I mean,
I'll, I'll be open and honest here, right?
And personally, you know, for things like,
you know, Bob's discount, chicken and waffles, you know, forum, right?
Uh I'm,
I'm not super careful with the passwords that
I choose for those types of environments,
right?
But, you know, when it certainly, when it comes to things that are more important,
you know, I use the tools that are available to ensure, you know,
as solid a password as possible or, you know, please implement, you know,
two factor authentication anywhere you can.
But yeah, this and, and I use it all the time, right? You know, I use the,
please sign in with your Facebook account. Right? Yeah, sure, no problem.
Um
But it, it,
you know, again,
how careful are people uh when they, when they choose to do that?
-- That's the problem. That's the question.
-- Well, well,
and,
and you're speaking in the context of this
issue for clicking sign in with Facebook now.
No, but here's the thing though too. I don't know how much you read about this.
I, I'm not an expert. I won't, I won't say I am, but
it sounds like the target is mobile users.
And
you also need a
man in the middle proxy installed on your phone, which that's kind of right.
That's the, that's the hand wavy part of, you know, step one steel underpants,
step two, you know, oh install the man in the middle proxy on your phone.
Um And then step three, we steal your password.
It's like, whoa hang around there guys.
Now that said,
I think it is important to not disregard things like
this even though it has a difficult to improbable.
Snap
is that's how research starts. I my favorite example here right now is Row Hammer
where Ro Hammer started, we're looking, we're like, yeah, whatever
it lab only. No big deal, right?
And now we're like, oh crap like you can use like a web browser to trigger Ro Hammer.
This is terrible. What you know, why didn't we pay attention to this?
So lesson learned guys
and and that that basically happened in the last week, right?
The last week, week and a half, you know,
people are really building on top of that
and the attack has been out for probably a couple of years now.
So it's,
it always takes and, you know, this is like any industry, I guess, is
research comes out that people think is a waste of money or ridiculous.
And then a couple of years later somebody figures out
how can we do something awesome with what was silly
or impractical research from a couple of years ago?
Right.
Yeah. No, exactly. Exactly.
Um, but you know, one la, one last point on the, on the oo
two
issue here, you know, the, the hand wavy man in the middle.
Um you know, IO I can see, you know,
having less of an issue here because the uh as far as I understand the,
the app store is still very controlled uh under, under Apple's control.
Um but when you talk about Android devices, right? Um
It's still pretty, it's still pretty wild west out there with, with the
Wild
West
is generous.
So, you know, so somebody can be like, oh, well, hey, this game looks interesting.
Let me check it out.
And by the way, I'm gonna go ahead and install this, uh this proxy while I'm at
it because I
read
how, how many people actually read, hey, this,
this requires these permissions to run.
Right.
Nobody, nobody does.
Right. Right. It's like it's like reading the itunes user agreement. Right.
Yes, that's,
oh my goodness.
It's, now, I will say though,
one of the really cool things Android has done recently is
in, in the newer version, I don't remember if they added this in version five or six.
I don't, I don't even remember version one now. But
when an app needs permissions,
you don't
just accept it blanket.
When you install it,
it will ask you as you're using it when it needs the new permission.
So it kind of has two advantages. Firstly,
if an app doesn't act like for example, if you're using something that doesn't
uh access a camera
ever,
it won't ever ask for that permission even if it could in theory. Right?
And secondly,
people don't just be like, wow, that's a lot of crap, you know, install.
So they have to actually see
these warnings that pop up.
Now on the downside though,
you will get security fatigue with a certain group of users
if you continuously pop up things for them to click,
accept or deny or whatever.
So
it's kind of back and forth.
But for, for like my selfish purposes,
I love the new way because I always read those pop ups.
I do too, right?
Because it's like, oh, hey, something is looking to do something new,
what's going on and I love that it breaks it down per uh per request, right?
Per requirement.
Um And it's not just that blanket, here's this long list of things that this app can do
-- except for deny totally.
-- And I love that I can also
kind of go in and twiddle permissions if I want
because then, you know, yes, app.
I'd love for you to tell me more about that, you know,
notifications off there problem solved.
Right.
Which, ah,
man, that, that's something that drives me nuts. That's been
III, I always feel
similar during election season as I do with, like,
all these apps that have all these crappy pop ups.
It's like, no, I don't care. Stop telling me this stuff. It does not matter.
I do not want
it.
Right. Right. Right. Right.
Yeah,
it, it, you know, when you open up your phone,
first thing in the morning you got 3030 little alerts across the top of it.
He's like, why, why do you do this? Not me.
Although it always, it always horrifies me when I'll, I'll be talking to somebody,
they'll pull their phone out and I'll just see across the top.
Like it's completely filled with a little alert icons and I'm just thinking like,
what kind of monster must you be?
Keep ignoring these horrible things. Come on, man. Like clean up your mess.
But
in, in my, uh wisdom, I no longer yell at people. So II, I accept their decisions.
Right. Right. Right.
Free will and all right.
Um No, no, they're wrong but it's fine.
-- I, I accept it as them being wrong and making poor choices. That's
-- fine. That's fine.
But they, they can freely choose to be wrong.
That's the key.
-- We'll say
-- that.
Uh So anyway, I guess the, the real story here is stay tuned folks.
Let's see what comes out of this because we have no idea.
But I'm certain there will be something interesting and, and I guess as well as,
as o
of two becomes more and more popular and more and more important
there will be more and more people looking at it,
which is just the nature of the universe.
And that's a good thing though.
That's a good thing because as researchers find problems,
we can fix the problems and that just makes things better for everybody.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, e even at the, even at the enterprise level, right.
You know, it's not, it's not just logging into some web form, you know,
enterprises are looking at SSO and they're looking at, you know,
all two and Samuel and
ID,
you know, to solve a lot of real problems. So,
you know, it's, it's, it's important to keep, keep an eye on these things.
I mean, man, I remember even,
it's probably 15 years ago
when
there was no centralized authentication. Every Linux machine I logged into.
I had, uh, well, the same password,
you know, essentially a password for each one of them.
And it was,
-- oh, it was terrible be
-- because, because when you built the new box,
you just copied over the Etsy password and Etsy shadow file, right?
-- But like any good admin did, uh,
-- did I even do that?
And I think I was too lazy to even do that.
I just,
and so all my, all my U I DS were different across all the machines and, yeah,
whatever, who cares?
It doesn't matter. No shared home directory, whatever. That's too much work.
I'll just like SCP things when I need them
and,
oh,
man, those are the dark days.
I don't want to think about it.
All right.
So, let's move on to a happy topic.
Let's encrypt. Do you use, let's encrypt, Dave.
Oh, I do use, let's encrypt.
Uh, man, I was, I was on, I was on that boat, you know, when it, when it was in beta,
it was a
game changer. A game. It is a game changer for me. Right.
You know, especially since, uh,
as far as I know the let's
encrypt, uh, root C A is now shipped standard, right?
Um, if you, if you were to go pull NSS right now, it comes as part of that,
-- that
-- all the browsers support it.
And
I won't lie. I was late to the game. I had a free certificate from my website
and I waited till it expired to get let's encrypt because
I'm like, uh, it works, it works, whatever. And then it expired.
And I thought all right, it's time because,
and now it's great because I'll never have to think about it again.
You know,
magic,
magic, magic htps.
But, but the,
the purpose behind bringing this up is there's a a report
that came out and I know Mozilla has done something similar,
but uh chrome just released that
half of the website is loaded with chrome because
Google is totally not spying on everything you do.
Half of the websites loaded with chrome
are loaded. Uh http S now, which is,
that's a crazy number half
and, and they do, they, they actually call out let's encrypt as
the primary driver behind this because then let's face it.
Nobody wants to pay for a certificate
and not just even that, even if they were free. Have you ever
-- gotten a certificate from, uh, uh, I guess a traditional C A,
-- you, you're, you're,
you're, you're talking to our resident PK I guy Josh.
But
yeah,
so
it's terrible. It's a hassle.
-- It's a huge hassle
-- apart from screwing up the
certificate probably two or three times during generating it.
Right.
Then you have to send it off to somebody else and then what magic happens and
then they send you back a sign certificate which usually takes a period of time.
It's not instantaneous
and it's, it's a huge pain in the butt and let's encrypt it.
If you, if you've never used it out there,
you literally run a command and it basically does everything for you. It's amazing.
Exactly. Right. You know, and, and that you hit the nail on the head. Josh. Right.
You know, because historically speaking,
you had to know how to generate a CS R. Right.
Um, and
Google is full of bad advice on how to generate CS RS.
Oh, it totally is.
Well, let's face it.
And I'm even guilty of this when I needed to generate certificate.
You know, things we'll say
just search for it. Oh, stack over.
I'll pick that one, you know, copy and paste the first thing that, that's
listed
the
first result. And, yeah, that's good enough. It's fine
-- change variables where applicable. Right. You know, if
-- you're lucky.
Yeah. Right. If you're lucky. Right.
You know, so, and, and that's, that's the, that's the problem that,
and that's where, that's where let's encrypt is, is,
you know, the game changer for a lot of people. Um,
because it does simplify that
well, in, in, so the important thing I guess I,
I like to talk about is there's free as
in money where let's encrypt doesn't cost money,
but it's also, I won't say it's free as in time,
but the time investment for let's encrypt is substantially lower
than a regular C A and that I think is the key.
Right.
Yeah. No, it, it is because time is money. Right. Yeah.
You know, people want to spend more of their time doing new,
innovative things than going back and doing the housekeeping of,
oh, well, let me go ahead and, and get this, uh SSL cert renewed.
Oh, by the way, my C A provider doesn't have a, have a mechanism for renewing certs.
So I got to generate a brand new CS R to get a brand new cert signed and,
you know, it's, it's a hassle.
Yeah.
Oh, totally, man.
-- Oh, I'm so glad I never have to do that again.
-- And,
and, and it's, it's, it's funny because, um, you know, iii, I remember
the time an abstract for me but,
um, I, I remember some time ago, uh, you know,
people were talking about Litz and Crypt being,
you know, the place where, you know, malware providers are going to be getting,
you know, legitimate certs, you know,
for free to flood the internet with problematic things.
Right. And I, I just have not seen that bear, you know.
Well, I mean, ok, so let's face it. There are unquestionably
bad guys using glitz and crypt,
but they also use like electricity and they eat food and, and it is,
it is normal part of society for the bad guys to
use the infrastructure that exists in some way that benefits themselves.
Right.
Exactly.
And this is kind of Bitcoin is another example. I love this.
You like, oh,
if we didn't have Bitcoin ransomware wouldn't exist and it's like it would,
it just wouldn't work with Bitcoin.
Right.
-- Right. Criminals
-- are opportunistic.
That's exact. That's exactly right. They'll use whatever tool is best for the job.
Exactly. And, and, and, you know, II, I laugh at this sometimes but I mean,
crime inc in terms of cybersecurity now is
I, I fear
getting ready to eclipse the good guys in terms of, I guess, knowledge and tooling
and,
-- and maybe they have already
-- and not just not
just knowledge and tooling but innovation as well.
Totally
because, you know, the news flash, you know, a spoiler alert,
crime isn't hampered by,
you know, overhead a lot of times. Right. And,
and you know, institutional and institutional curmudgeon.
Oh, so, well, not only that man is crime inc is a
they generate revenue
whereas security in most organizations is a cost
center.
So
historically speaking, if you are a revenue generator,
you get more attention than the cost centers do because
obviously you want to put as much investment into revenue as
you can and as little investment into cost as you can.
And so
this is the great challenge we have is,
and I, I wonder if this
does this problem exist elsewhere
where you have essentially a a revenue generating adversary against a cost center.
And I mean,
maybe, I mean, you could maybe talk about support in this context,
but I don't think that really applies either because in in the case of support
you, you, I I had to say to use the word adversary in the context of the white board, but
you know, the the customer
is
-- not looking to ruin you, they just want some help.
-- Right. Right. And I mean, ex
Exactly. Yeah. And the the there are nuanced arguments that could be made about how,
you know,
the support isn't necessarily a call center
-- because the improved customer experience could result
-- in
ignoring that argument because I'm, no, I'm not gonna go there. But
it's,
I mean, you kind of have loss prevention in retail where, you know,
people are going to be essentially stealing your stuff and
you just accept that as part of doing business.
But even,
yeah, I don't know. I mean, outside of that example, I can't think of anything
that really applies in this context.
No, because, you know, the, the,
the only other analogy that I can think of
that's often used in these types of scenarios is,
you know, militaristic, right? You know, you have the arms race where,
um, you, you know, they,
your enemy builds a bigger wall, you build a bigger trebuchet,
right? I, I mean,
the way, the way it works today is building, building,
you know, bigger, bigger walls and building bigger trebuchet
are both revenue generators for a lot of different people. So I, I think that analogy
part.
Exactly because in,
in the military context there are
defense contractors making freaking fortunes and
like, yeah, you guys should totally build a bigger wall.
That would be great, you know, sign here.
And
like,
that's not exactly the case in
cybercrime.
This is, oh, man, every time I think about this, my head starts to hurt and it's,
it's already starting.
I don't, I
don't think this week I can handle this conversation
but it's, it's such a weird problem. I,
I have no idea. And the,
the thing that frustrates me to no end is
in so many of these security conversations,
they just end with like me throwing my hands in the air
and decrying as we're doomed and there's nothing we can do.
Right. II, I mean, ho honestly, short of
having,
short of taking the cost burden away from
the enterprise and putting it somewhere else where
just a team of researchers works on building
that bigger wall or building that bigger trebuchet
to stay ahead of crime. Inc I think, I think it's always gonna be,
-- you know, reactive, super reactive.
-- I want to build a security trebuchet.
I don't know what that means, but it sounds awesome.
Security tribute.
OK?
-- All
-- right.
Figure that out.
I'm gonna put, I'm gonna put that down on my white board.
-- I'm gonna do some word, I'm gonna do some word clouds about it right.
-- There you go.
I like it. I like it.
You can start a consulting company, right?
How to build your security
buche.
That, that, that'll be the company's name.
Rebut.
I like it. I like it. This is, this is the best idea yet.
We won't fix anything, but we'll make a lot of money making the problem worse.
No, goodness. No, we'll throw a git hub up and
the community will take care of everything else.
-- We'll just collect the checks,
-- the community's magic.
Oh, my goodness.
So, anyway, I guess in summary if you're not using lets encrypt you totally should.
So, get on that. I, I'll second that.
And
all right,
the last topic I have here
is a
doozy
and this,
I will
do my best
to stay neutral.
So, for those of you who don't know,
Google recently disclosed an issue
with, with Windows
to Microsoft and they gave them seven days to fix it
and it's, it's a pretty serious issue.
And so the disclosure debate of course erupts at this point
and the disclosure debate essentially comes down to the fact that
when a researcher finds an issue
and
they're reporting it to whoever needs it.
In this case, Google is the researcher, Microsoft is the organization,
it's being reported to
what should the rules be in the way these groups interact
if Google says we're going to disclose this in seven days.
And Microsoft says, can you give us 10
for example? And I know that's not exactly true,
but in Microsoft did release a fix for this.
So it's like twoish weeks, I think maybe about a week after it was disclosed,
it got got released.
But anyway, where,
where do we draw the line here? Is
I if, if the company asks for more time, the researcher says, no,
now they hate each other.
It's
or the company says like I want a year
is, it's so
it's such a crazy conversation. I've been on both sides of this more than once
and
I do not have an answer to any of these questions
there. I
don't think there is a good um
the, the there's no good answer to this, right? Because it's a case by case basis.
There, there is
n nearly no way to set some sort of guidelines or framework around
when to disclose vulnerabilities and how to disclose vulnerabilities. right?
Because
uh
you know, if somebody asks for a year on a super critical bug or
the
how,
how do we know that that's not gonna get found in the wild and exploited
within that year.
It, it, it probably will be.
And so in the case of this windows problem, the reason Google Google usually gives,
I think 90 days
and they gave seven to Microsoft because they knew it was being exploited in the wild
and that does change the rules a little bit. I I will not disagree.
So it's,
this is such a weird problem and well, in fact,
there was they, they just released something for Mac Os
where in the time when they talk about like apple
executives contact Google executives and and get extension of deadline,
right?
So
maybe Microsoft just didn't talk to the right people when they,
when they wanted their extra days instead
or,
or it could have been, we're Microsoft, you're going to give us the extra days and
also plausible, right?
But
Uh, yeah.
And, you know, it's, it's interesting the, the disclosure debate because,
you know, timing, timing is one thing and,
you know, II, I think it ties into this a little bit. Um, you know, to
speak of those who aren't here, Kirk, uh,
he had a, a poll on his Twitter, uh, this week as well. Um, asking about
internal, um,
internal disclosures are internal CV ES versus external CV ES. Right.
You know, should you keep CV ES internal right there, there's,
there's debates about how to,
how to even deal with uh vulnerabilities on software that's just in house, you know,
-- in
-- house.
So I, although I, I think in that case
that
II, I think that's less of an issue because this would be like,
let's say
you have your own personal dictionary with words in it. You won't share with me
that doesn't make sense.
And that's kind of the, I, if it's, if you're using CV ES,
there's really no purpose in not publishing them
because it is a public database of artifacts,
this would be like you making up words and not sharing them with anyone else. And then
what purpose would that even serve?
Nor, nor would you even use the words outside of your own home? Right. That why,
that doesn't make sense.
Right. Right. Exactly. Um, but it, it, it doesn't make sense.
But I think, um, you know, in fact, I think, I think I'm, I think I'm sidetrack the,
the more important discussion around their timing and how to,
and how to disclose vulnerabilities.
But,
um you know, I, I think it speaks to, you know, even if you're doing it internally,
if you're speaking the same language and you have the same
syntax and you have the same framework in which to,
to document and follow and track um and disclose vulnerabilities like CV E,
I think that's, that's of huge importance to even, you know,
inside uh inside of an enterprise.
I think you actually just hit on a really important point. Dave is having
the correct vocabulary and frameworks
is really what's important because I mean, at the end of the day,
researchers and organizations are probably never going to agree on everything.
Even if someone said here is the new disclosures policy of the world
and they laid out a bunch of dates and whatever numbers,
no one's going to agree
it. You will never make everyone happy. That's the reality of it.
And so in that context, I think it is more beneficial to have common language
and common concepts.
So even when there are disagreements,
people are at least on the same page enough to even understand they are
disagreeing because let's face it too back in the early days of disclosure,
like
nobody even knew what was going on and there'd be
companies that like they just didn't understand what was happening.
And then all of a sudden there's like a, you know, some horrible o day dropped on,
on full disclosure and they're like, ah, we have no idea what's going on.
You know,
it's talking, talking about wild west. Right.
You know, to bring, to bring that back up. It was,
uh,
awful. Right.
And, and I think, I think we're moving towards that, uh, a good direction and I,
people,
people need to agree that,
you know, the tooling that's in place today and, and, you know,
I'm sure Kurt will talk more about it next week, you know, after he gets back from his,
his uh CV E boondoggle, right?
Um
uh that, that,
you know, e even for internal issues, even for internal issues,
if you stay within that same framework, people are gonna understand,
people are going to be able to
understand what you're talking about and figure out how
to act based on the information that they're given.
And uh you know, and not just, not just your own internal people,
like your admins and your, your security practitioners inside your walls, but,
you know, say you've got auditors coming in, right?
You know, I,
I'm probably speaking a little out of school here but I'll,
I'll bet you dollars to donuts.
If you had an auditor come in and they saw
that you had a facility in place that mapped to
the CV E framework for internal security issue, uh disclosures,
they would be
ecstatic,
right?
Because they understand that they can follow that and they can see that,
you know, you're at least trying to do your due diligence. Right.
You may be right. I, I don't like it
when,
when people are right. And it's about private things
but, but you, you have some very valid points. I will, I will think about this.
Now, now, we should start talking about, uh CV E NAT
where you have special internal only CV ID pools that anyone can use. Right.
Oh,
goodness, I'm gonna, I'll add that.
I'll add that to the white board and I'll, I'll, I'll submit it to
-- you. I'll submit it to NIST. Right. You know, we'll get it
-- approved.
Oh,
man.
Yeah. So, so anyway, anyway,
rather than dwell on the disclosure debate for too long, I guess it's,
it's interesting to point out
that
two giant organizations
that probably should have more in common than not,
can't even come to an agreement here.
And I think that's one of those instances where,
like you said, it's easier to just have tools to communicate
than it is to even try to solve
this problem because it is almost certainly unsolvable.
Yep.
Let's just, let's just make it a little bit easier on the people.
So now in our list of uh solved versus unsolved problems,
the solved category is still empty and unsolved is enormous
a job well done.
We're, we're, we're, we're gonna, we're gonna overflow some,
some memory here on the, uh, the,
uh the, the, the un unsolved problem,
man. That, that table, yeah, that, that, that tables wrapped about 10 times now.
I think it's, it just, it never ends true story.
Oh, my goodness. We're doomed. Dave, we're all doomed. That, that's all I can say.
Uh, yet the world, the world continues to function even though it shouldn't.
-- And we don't know what
-- it's right.
We're all doomed. But just
put that smile on, keep moving forward, just keep doing the best you can do.
That's my philosophy.
But I'm, I'm, I'm forever the hopeless optimist.
-- Josh, that's,
-- that's why I, it's a funny thing is,
is I always have to pull that out after I've,
I've scared people to death explaining why,
like everything is broken from the security perspective and,
and occasionally someone looks like they're ready to cry.
And so it's a matter of, but, you know, uh
everything still works
and so
we're probably wrong then, then the world is fine again.
And so
I can see no, no better note to end the podcast on
than admitting we're all wrong.
And you've probably just wasted like 50 minutes of your life
and, and just, and,
and just remind people that security started with locks on the door and
to this day it
still doesn't work, right? Uh And,
um,
you just reminded me, I don't know where my, my locks are.
I should go find them. I, I, if you know, black picking man is fantastic.
And I just realized I, I don't,
I thought they were in a box right on the shelf over there.
But I look and it's gone. So which either means my Children have stolen them or like,
or I misplace them
and I'll put a, I'll put a link in the show notes.
Uh There's an interesting gentleman. Uh, uh, I think his name is, uh Skyler.
Um, I forget his last name.
Uh, He,
I'm a member of the Richmond Information Security Users Group and we have a,
a yearly conference and he, he comes there, he does lock picking,
he brings all his locks and his picking tools
and he has a little lock picking village because
every good security conference needs a lockpicking village. Right?
Uh And,
and he's done some presentations on the history of locks
and the history of locks and security and it's,
you would think that it would be the dullest material ever,
but it's super interesting.
I should, uh, actually in all seriousness, you should give me a copy of that
because this is something I've been really thinking about a lot for a long time is
if we look at the parallels behind specifically locks,
what does that look like if we parallel it to computer security?
Because I, I'm not gonna say it's gonna line up. Exactly.
But I suspect there's gonna be some very similar
coincidences there. Like, like an example is,
you know, a couple of 100 years ago, even
doors just didn't have locks because they were obviously very expensive
and you probably didn't have anything to steal anyway. So, what did you care?
And, and that's obviously not the case anymore and, and like, let's face it
20 years ago with computers,
you didn't have anything worth stealing was generally what, what happened there.
But now
a lot of organizations have very valuable things
but they lack the locks to protect them.
And so I'm curious if we look historically,
how valuables and society have driven locks
because obviously locks did not build society, right?
I mean, that that's the reality of it.
So, yeah, totally. Um,
and we should talk about that at,
at a future date because I think this is a super interesting topic.
So
I guess with that, thank you so much, Dave for helping out.
I can't wait to have you on again at some future point.
I'm available.
It, it, it's fantastic.
I, I do appreciate it and, and, and Kurt will come back next week.
So I'm told, assuming he doesn't die in a horrible plane crash on the way home.
But, and,
and we'll have what I'm sure is the most
interesting conversation about CV E held in history,
which the bar is very high here, I imagine.
And so with nothing else, uh folks,
if you wanna catch any of the links we talked about,
it's open source security podcast.com.
Thank you so much for listening. I appreciate it.
And with that you all have a fantastic week. Thanks, Dave.
Thank you.