Hit record.
I'm annoyed that like, I wish there was a way for the tab to signal like
the red dot signals that my microphone is active but not recording.
Whereas my brain says red dot means recording,
you know,
December 20th,
-- December 20th,
-- we're so close.
So the question is,
is some two factor authentication or multi factor authentication better than
no two fa
M
fa or are there cases where the two of A and M FA is so bad?
-- You'd be better off not having it? I
-- and this is a very contentious topic actually.
And I go back and forth a lot and I think about this a lot.
I have a simple answer, please.
There's two kinds of attacks, there's targeted attacks and there's
the broad don't target, just credential stuffing attacks.
And here's the thing, the two fa and M fa will help for the broad non targeted attacks.
Absolutely.
But for a targeted attack,
there are situations where your two fa or M fa can actually make things worse.
A great example being S MS, you know,
because you cannot protect yourself against a SIM swap, you cannot.
And we talked about this on a previous show,
but there's this guy who figured out a way to protect himself against a SIM swap
and it involved setting up his own bloody phone company
and you can have up to what is it,
11 layers of security to change your phone account details.
That
basically proves my point that you
cannot realistically protect yourself against a SIM
swap if the solution is you got to set up a phone company.
And, and now
I think for normal people,
-- the S MS is probably acceptable in many instances
-- until they're targeted.
And the problem is also sim swaps apparently are
becoming less targeted where they will just break into a
phone operator and sim swap a whole pile of accounts
and just randomly hit Facebook or Gmail or whatever,
using that phone number for the password recovery and reset
-- because
-- you can enter a phone number into those
because you
might have forgotten your email account because apparently people do.
And so for example, I entered my phone number and you know, of course, Google's like,
well, which account do you want?
Because there's a whole pile of them with that phone number attacked.
I'm like, oh, bloody heck. Right.
And so that's the thing, right?
If my phone number were to get compromised through a SIM swap,
all those accounts now can be compromised.
And that's part of the problem is the Attackers kind of don't care what they get
because if I attack 10 or 20 or 100 Facebook accounts and compromise them.
I'll get something useful in there.
Well, and my,
my argument here is always that a targeted attacker
cannot be stopped no matter what you do,
whether if you have two factor authentication, that's just going to slow them down.
It's not going to stop them.
If they have enough dedication and resources, you cannot win. Yeah.
-- But
-- that doesn't mean you shouldn't try
things
that are not agreed.
-- One
-- 100% agree. Like you should always use two factor off. I think having a
wider net being cast against S MS authentication is interesting
because this is one of those situations that I guess
this was not one of the concerns I ever ever had is I always assume that S MS you know,
Sim Jacking was going to end up under the targeted attack category.
And if it's not,
then that creates
a different problem, I
-- think
-- the thing is also, it's something I cannot
myself against. Right.
For example, if my bank, my bank,
one of my banks uses biometrics voiceprint and I'm like fantastic, except there's
good Lord at this point. How many hundreds of hours of recordings of my voice? Right?
You know, they don't even need to deep fake it. They can just cut and paste it.
I will try to dig up the episode. But there's a podcast called Cyber.
I like to listen to it.
They did that where they took the host's audio,
they extracted the words needed defeated into one of those, like,
like voice duplicating A I fake things and then they had the fake
host do a bunch of talking and the real host is like,
this is ridiculous and you knew it wasn't really him, but it was pretty good
-- and it was hilarious.
-- We can replace ourselves with pearl scripts. Finally,
I, seriously, if it wasn't so much work, I would totally do this to you.
But it's a lot of work.
Now, the question is what I notice,
what would the audience notice is the real question?
Well, as long as I don't listen to the episodes, I'm not gonna,
but,
and they have, they have interns that could do the work, right?
Like we need an intern, that's what we
-- need.
-- Yeah. So if you're willing to work for no money,
-- if
-- you pay us, we get,
go get
the most valuable resource of all.
-- I'm told you can use exposure at many fine restaurants for foods.
-- That's right.
-- You can totally eat exposure
-- to be clear.
I hate this whole intern working for free thing on so many levels. I agree.
It's awful. And I love the fact that it's actually illegal in most of the world,
-- like in the US, that interns can't do real work. They can. I
-- love how our topic is.
Multi factor authentication. We're talking about interns now. It's lovely.
But anyway, we're out of time. Multi factor authentication, I guess.
Use it is bad two factor oth better than no two factor oath. I
-- think,
-- I think the tipping point is we're getting there but we're not there yet.
It is a contentious discussion for sure.
And I dare not weigh in because I find myself
changing my mind in either direction on a regular basis,
-- which I think, I
-- think that's a good sign means you're thinking about
it.
It is. I agree. I agree. So, all right. 21st tomorrow. How exciting.