Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurtz Fried and my partner in spreadsheet shenanigans.
Josh Reser
-- spreadsheets. I don't know how spreadsheets even work, man. They're
-- magic.
It's funny because we um I did a, a presentation last night with Yee
and then actually we ended up having a one hour discussion afterwards.
There's about 20 of us and a couple of new people that want to break
into the industry and it was comical because one of their questions was like,
what kind of math do I need to know?
And all of us were like,
what do you mean? Math?
Right? Like
we do spreadsheets and charts sometimes. But like, unless you're making crypto,
that's a reasonable question. I think,
especially a researcher because like,
if you're doing any sort of vulnerability analysis,
it's not uncommon at all to need to know, like weird binary and hexadecimal math for,
you know, changing addresses and stuff like that.
Well, that's more an encoding issue.
But he was thinking like, you know, do I need to know algebra or crypto?
And we're like, no,
like, really? No,
that's, that's true.
But then I, I did point out, for example,
I use a lot of estimating sort of on logarithmic scales.
Like, is this a 1 1,000,000 or like million problem?
Because it's a one or a 10 problem I can deal with it
and if it's a million problem. Yeah. No, I, like we need to go talk to the government
and get policy. That's true.
You know, because I can deal with a sick kid but I can't deal with a million sick kids
as we've discovered through this pandemic scale matters
actually. So it's funny you bring that up because I've been fighting with this.
Remember several episodes ago,
I talked about how I'm downloading all of the N PM
data and I'm going to write a white paper about it.
How's that going for you?
I have, I have all the data now and it's taken a while to get it all.
I just downloaded the downloads data, which that's
sounds hilarious now that I say it out loud. But one of the challenges is
you're dealing with 1.9 million packages,
25 million like releases where it's 1.9 million times a
number equals all the releases of N PM data.
And when you have numbers at large,
it's really difficult to try to tease out useful information because
looking at 25 million data points is extremely difficult
and there's often an enormous amount of noise.
Well, like if you chart it out is that
an actual pattern or you're just like seeing the shape of the clouds.
Well, and that's just it.
And so like one of the things I've, I've realized and this is uh I,
I'll give a little teaser here is the 95th percentile.
Basically,
if you look at all the packages in N PM and how many times they've been downloaded,
the largest packages have been downloaded billions of times
and the, the 95th percentile, the cut off like the top,
the top 5% have been downloaded 20,000 times or more.
So you think about that, there's
1.9 million
and only 5% of those things have been done in a year.
Mind you,
this isn't over the life of the package because I
can only get a year's worth of download data,
but like 20,000 is zero
compared to a billion and that's 5% which is maddening.
So anyway, that's one of the challenges.
Well, I imagine a lot of the stuff in the N PM is like a, what is it called a power
curve or whatever where it's just like it goes from like
1000 down to like three and then there's like a long tail
that it's like asymptotic.
-- That's right. Everything is that
-- or in this case actually may hit zero.
I would actually assume there are packages that have hit are at zero downloads.
-- Uh
-- There are 20 thou no. Um
Yes, but I don't remember the number at the top of my head.
It is a very small number compared to everything else.
Strangely enough,
there's a massive spike around 100 downloads and I don't know why that is.
I assume it must be some sort of automation or something.
Well, I mean, because, yeah, you would think statistically
you, I don't want to say you get a bell curve, you get like an inverse power like a,
a steep,
steep ski slope curve. Yeah.
Yeah, that's exactly what you get.
But like having an actual, like,
because I think you said what the number 95 popped out or something, right.
Yeah. Yeah. 95 specifically has
an extraordinary number of downloads.
Well, I should say an extraordinary number of packages have like, between 90
100 downloads, basically.
Like, what an odd number, I guess two downloads a week, basically.
Anyway, it doesn't matter. I'm working on it.
Weird. It's too bad. You can't get some data to correlate. I'm working on it.
It's coming, well, this and this is what we're talking about.
We're talking about like security kind of at this weird scale in a,
like industry wide year long trends.
That's right. That's right. All right. Let me, let me pull up the name of the report.
So there was
Tux care sponsored a white paper called the State or is it a white paper?
I don't know, whatever it's called the state of enterprise. Linux Security.
Management, the P
on institute did it, which I love the word Ponemon
because it's spelled Ponemon.
-- But every time I hear it said out loud, I think Pwnmo N
-- I actually,
at first when you said
like when I read it, I was like p
on I'm like, is this, did they misspell p
like what?
No, no, they did not. I imagine the Pony
Man Institute is a long storied institution
that unfortunately has a name that has been co opted in recent years.
But like Pony
on is the real deal. They do real good research.
So Tux Carere sponsored this data and I'll put a link in the show note how to get to it.
It was really interesting.
And so there's a couple of things that just kind of stand out to me and I want to jump,
I'm not going to start at the beginning because I think
starting at the beginning on a report like this gets boring.
I think the most fascinating data point I saw in this is on,
it's on page 10 of the report.
And they asked
the respondents and at the very end,
they talk about how many people responded and all that stuff.
I don't care. I'm not going into it if you care, go read the report. But
they asked
the respondents,
does automation successfully reduce your time to respond to vulnerabilities?
And
33% say it's significantly shorter.
21% say slightly shorter 27% say no time to
respond and 19% say increase in time to respond.
Now, if your automation doesn't change your time to respond or increases it,
why are you paying for that?
Like,
you know what I mean?
Well, I mean, on the one hand you could,
uh just devil's advocate here is that maybe they're still taking,
like they might have broken process or the automation might be hard to kind of like,
get it to do something.
But once it kind of decides to do something, it goes and does it efficiently.
II, I don't know. Right.
Like I've, because all the automation I've used consists of like shell scripts or,
you know,
kind of these larger products where it's just like
once you make a decision and push a button,
it's just like poop
and it's basically done, right? Because that's
kind of the whole point of automation is to press a button and loop.
-- It's done
-- the graph right before this
has, it says if your organization uses automation, what steps do you automate?
And this one says 67% patching, 53% prioritization,
50% reporting and 41% assignment.
OK.
I can speak to that prioritization thing that's already all that is, is,
is glorified
CV. SS scores from NVD in
a, in a spreadsheet style layout
that's in there too.
But time kind of what you've assigned priorities on your internal infrastructure,
right?
So if you have like an internal accounting
server running red hat enterprise links versus like a
red hat server running the toilets or something or the cafeteria sign boards,
you know, one of those is more important than the other.
So, so they actually have data on that and that this is on page eight.
No, I actually, I've got a bunch of paper notes. I'm holding a real notebook.
So now I look at page eight and they actually asked the question,
how do you prioritize vulnerabilities?
And this one shocked me a little bit.
They have,
they have four options they list and there's other at 5% which doesn't count.
But
so the top one is vulnerability factors such as exploit availability, right?
Which is kind of what you were talking about a little bit of and that's at 53%.
They have type of system impact at 51%.
And then, but then,
then the third one says business risk of
systems affected by the vulnerability that's 47%.
And I feel like those two are potentially the same.
-- I don't know how I would tease them apart.
-- What happened?
There is at least my experience was sort of a type of system impacted.
It was more things like can this be easily upgraded? So for example,
an accounting server I can upgrade and if it kind of whoopsies, well, it'll,
we'll spot it pretty quick
and we can roll it back.
But if it's like an industrial skated control system for an oil refinery.
We can't run that risk of like, hey,
let's upgrade the software and see if something breaks and if it breaks,
we'll roll it back.
But isn't that business risk?
Well, no business risk would be more like, well, ok, perfect example,
when I work for that small, well, not small, medium sized firm payroll was done.
Every Friday, a big pile of checks was printed out and given to the 500 electricians.
Is there a business risk not printing them their checks? Absolutely.
Those guys were strong and there was 500 of them. But here's the thing.
Could the owner have said like, right, whatever,
run 500 checks for three grand each and just hand them out.
-- Uh That's true. That's true. Right.
-- And they could have done that.
Like, so that's the thing. Like sometimes there's like a, a sort of a pain.
Like there's a,
my favorite example is Revenue Canada because Canada Revenue Agency
basically has the policy of if everything goes all crazy,
we just turn the website off because
you have to pay your taxes,
right? Like we'll extend the filing date and you just have to
pay them and we can turn the website off for a week and deal with log for J
-- Right. I remember that. Yes. No, it wasn't log for J though. What was
-- it?
And heartbleed?
-- No, they've done it for heartbleed and log for J, oh,
-- they did it for Log for J also.
That's neat.
-- Yeah.
-- But it didn't make the news because it was in December and who cares?
Right.
But for heartbleed, it was the week of,
like, when you're supposed to pay your taxes
and they had to extend the filing deadline.
So, that's the thing. Right.
Like, there's like, revenue, Canada has a captive market
and thought,
like, you can't
take your business elsewhere.
whereas Amazon can't shut their website down for a week.
That's true. That's a good point.
Actually, anyway, I don't want to dwell on this one.
And then the fourth is CV SS score
-- and it's 46%. So it's
-- a lot. Well, it's the default number, right?
But I was shocked CV S S's last, I mean, this is what,
what comes to mind here is we live in this weird security bubble where
we think certain security things are vastly more important than they really are.
And so if you would have asked me,
I would have said CV SS is the
number one way people prioritize prioritize vulnerabilities.
And it's clearly not because this is a survey of like normal folk,
not security goons.
Well, here's the problem.
They are talking about CV SS scores, but they are not talking about CV SS scores.
They are talking specifically about the CV SS base score only
and that's the trick is CV SS scoring is actually also a temporal score,
which is things like exploit code, maturity,
remediation level and report confidence
and
the environmental score,
which is to put it bluntly how important is this thing to you.
And so the idea of a CV SS score is what it's supposed to be is vulnerability plus,
exploit plus affected system.
But obviously NVD can't do that. Like NVD doesn't know what the heck you're running.
And so they assume a worst case scenario.
I think there's another piece to this and it's
not that they're going and finding CV SS scores,
they're using an automated system to tell them the CBS S score functionally.
Right. I mean, that, that's where these come from. It's not,
no one is going and seeking out scores on
their own because finding them is terrible and then,
you know, getting them shoved somewhere useful is even worse.
There's a number there. Where's the,
-- let me check my notes here. Um
-- Did you actually? Oh, yeah, that's right.
-- You were using handwrit notes today. I do
-- have some handwrit notes.
Uh That's not what I want. Um
They do have a note about
how, who's using automation
and ok, here it is. What is automated?
Oh, we talked about that already because patch is 67%.
So here's an interesting number. The very first thing they talk about on the,
on the report, it's, I think it's technically part of the executive summary
is they, they ask,
they say once you detect a critical or high priority vulnerability.
How long on average does it take to patch?
Oh, I know. Right.
-- That time frame
-- and, and so here's what's interesting, 44% said,
within a month and 56% said five weeks
to more than one year,
which seems like a, it's like five weeks or more. But
I hope a lot of that is a quarter and not more than a year, like,
I hope they kind of lumped it all together.
But
I worry that there's actually a lot of, although in fairness,
if you don't patch it in 30 days, then kind of 123, many,
I, I agree with that. I agree.
But this kind of goes to my,
either you're patching or you're not because if
you're not patching it within 30 days,
then, well, yeah, like you're basically not patching.
I
kind of agree with that.
And now here's what's interesting tying on to that.
See, this is where like this report feels a little out of order.
Well, maybe just from my, my view,
I guess this again is probably the security bubble.
But
one of the questions he asked said,
did any of these cybersecurity incidents occur while a patch
was available for a known vulnerability but was not applied.
55% said yes, 40% said no and 5% said unsure. So you figure the most, 56%
are taking more than five weeks to patch and 55% are having cybersecurity incidents
with a patch available like this feels like a self fulfilling prophecy.
-- Well,
-- but how much, I mean,
how many people still believe firewalls work to keep the bad guys out?
It depends whose marketing materials you, you read.
You know, I, like, I run into this all the time like it was,
it was actually quite comical.
I was on a call with Cloud
and they were,
you know, trying to mention the, um, the cloud FFL teams, which is the VPN stuff.
And I'm like,
and he, he starts talking about it and I'm like, oh, I have some good news for you.
And he's like, what I'm like, we don't have any infrastructure.
He's like, huh, I'm like, we're 100% cloud based. Like we,
we, there's nothing to VPN to,
right. There's literally the cloud security lines.
We don't have anything to VPN connect to that.
They're just, it's like, we, we, it's like,
you know, it's like Africa, they skipped to fiber optics and cell towers.
There's no landlines, like just,
it's, uh, that's not a thing for us and never will be.
And he's like, oh, ok. Then I'm like, yep.
Well,
we both worked at Red Hat and what was
Red Hat's Support Lifetime for Red Hat Enterprise LX.
It was 13 years
and it wasn't 13 years because Red Hat wanted to do that
forever.
The answer is forever.
It wasn't 13 years because Red Hat, you know, felt like that's a good number.
It's 13 years because that's what customers demand.
And I remember there were some banks now, this was a decade ago.
I don't think it's the same,
but there were banks that wouldn't use the latest version
of or rather the version of Red hat enterprise.
Linux
they would use,
would they would only start using it when it entered the long life? What do we call it?
extended support or whatever? Basically critical updates only
because they were like, this is moving at the speed we want,
we don't want this fast moving
operating system.
And by that point it was like five years out of date and it's like,
what infrastructure are you even running on this stuff?
I
like Swift. Swift is running on this stuff
that you
like,
I mean, all, all the stuff but,
and that's the thing, right?
Like stuff like, well, like you look at like Saber and the, you know, the airline,
uh the travel stuff,
it's going on horrifically old mainframes and whatnot and it's kind of like,
yeah, it's not very amazing or sexy or cool, but it kind of mostly works and again,
it gets the job done.
-- Well,
-- if you kind of have a captive audience, you know,
like revenue Canada and IRS are running on old old code,
you gonna take your business elsewhere.
Don't have
a
job, you know, like you're an airline.
Are you going to take the risk of dealing with some small start up who's like, hey, we,
we rewrote Saber in like rust with a web responsive front end.
That would be an enormous risk because then you wouldn't exist
in any of the booking systems that are already being used.
-- Well,
-- yeah, and there's also that minor problem of like, why does
swift work? Well, because everybody uses Swift. Why does everybody use Swift?
Because everybody uses swift?
That's right. All right. I don't want to get stuck in this.
I'm going to keep this moving. All right. So here's another interesting data point.
60% of the respondents said open source is
as secure or more secure than proprietary software.
Now, Red Hat asked a similar question in one of their surveys.
They released a couple of months ago and they
said it was 89% of respondents answered that question.
I suspect a lot of people when they think of closed source,
they're actually thinking of the hybrid closed,
open source stuff that is pretty much everything now like
Windows is a hybrid of open and closed source.
Everything is a hybrid now.
Well, and not only that, I have a suspicion that Red Hat asked a different question
than Tux Carere did because I suspect Red Hat was looking for that answer
and this particular report isn't about the security of open source.
It's about patching your systems.
I'm always reminded of that yes minister scene where you know,
he asked the question two different ways about youth joining the military.
And it's, you know, to get two different answers.
Yes.
Anyways, I, I think, I,
I, like,
I remember 20 years ago when there was
stuff like Solaris that was 100% closed source.
Like they, they wrote their own
everything, device drivers, you name it
-- and that's just not possible anymore if you want to relevant. No,
-- I, I agree.
-- It's completely out of the question. You know,
-- like a and especially if you,
uh,
well, at a minimum, you're gonna need an I PV six stack,
you're gonna need a Wi Fi stack.
You're gonna need a secure web server and client. If you want to talk to anything
and those three things alone,
you're gonna need a team of 20 to 100 people who are really sophisticated
or if you're lucky or
you just grab an open source library and you're done in five minutes.
No, I, I agree. Absolutely.
You can't justify those kind of business decisions anymore.
And I mean, heck, even if Solaris is open source now, I think,
or maybe it's under that terrible.
Well, I know that,
but
like I'm just saying,
one of the attempts, one of their Hail Marys was to open source it
with open Solaris
and
that went about as well as one would expect. But anyway, anyway,
we're not here to talk about
-- Oracle is a great supporter of the open source world. Look
-- they actually are.
I don't want to get into some bizarre rant bashing oracle.
You can edit that part out.
No, that
I'm,
it's too late. You said it? It's recorded. Alright.
Here's one of the other really interesting graphs I think. Which is,
let me, ok, on page eight, they ask,
how often does your organization scan for vulnerabilities
and 25%
don't have a schedule, which is
honestly a little smaller than I expected.
I'm
kind of in the same boat because for example,
we get this question all the time at the CS A and that do you scan on a regular basis?
You know, for CV S in your software?
And the answer is, well, we don't do it on a regular basis.
But every time they build the software, which is like 2 to 3 times a week that happens,
I would say your answer is yes. In that context,
I think the problem is we don't do it for security reasons.
We do it because it's just part of our build process now.
Like it's,
it's, you know, it's like, how often do you clean your teeth hurt?
-- Well, II, I just brush daily because that's what people do.
-- I think you're
splitting hairs and I think not scheduled in this context means people are YOLO
this for the most part.
True. I think that's what that means. Now we can go farther.
There's more than four weeks, 20%
every four and Now, mind you, this is the largest, right? 20% every four weeks, 90%.
So monthly, obviously, right,
every three weeks, 15% 2 weeks, 11% every week is 10%
2 to 3 times a week is 2%
daily is 7% and more than once a day is 1%. And here's
what I guess kind of stood out to me when I looked at this particular one is if you have
a modern automation system that can
basically catalog what you're running,
you can effectively run these scans like every
10 minutes and there's no system load.
But if you have like the legacy style scanner where it has an
agent that's causing some sort of disruption to the system and load,
it becomes a big deal.
And I think given these numbers,
I would say the vast majority of respondents are using legacy system
scanning because so few are doing like the very fast scanning model.
Well, ideally what should happen is you should have it
on change,
you scan that thing, like you do a software update, you scan it,
you do a config change, you scan it, you do like anything to the system, you scan it.
And then I would say concurrent with that, you should probably also do
like a daily or weekly scan because there will be systems that don't change a lot. But
you kind of want to keep an eye on them or make sure the agent didn't die or, you know,
whatever.
Right.
Yeah. Yeah. No. Absolutely.
And again, like, yeah, that requires modern it, which by definition,
if you're a large enterprise,
-- you have a mix of stuff from 20 years ago and stuff from like
-- now
that
you have every single piece of it ever made.
-- Like
-- at the CS A,
like we're 100% cloud based and the effort it's going
to take me to get rid of Jira is significant.
Like we're, we're transitioning out of,
we made that choice actually quite a while ago because honestly,
the text editor situation alone in Jira is so
painful and the collaboration aspect of it is terrible.
So we're moving to air table and going from Jira to air table,
like we've got about 80% of it out,
but that kind of last 20% most of it's my stuff is
I'm seriously getting to the point of like just we're going to
like walk away from it and I'm going to have to recreate
the data in air table manually or something because there's no good,
there's no good migration path.
Well, that's
fault then
it it's well, but it's also Jira fault in that they don't give you,
they don't make it really that easy to get at your data that you want, right?
Like you can do an export, but I kind of want like a live cut over,
not just like a dump and run.
I might have to end up doing.
But basically, like, even to shift from one cloud service to another cloud service
-- is, it's a significant amount of effort.
-- No, I, I agree. I agree completely.
You know, and so I can't even, like,
I haven't touched traditional it in a long time and I, I
can't even imagine, you know, if I had a fleet of like, 1000 red hat servers doing
back in the stuff.
Oh,
man,
like I do not want to remember those days from 20 years ago
when I had like a fleet of 20 machines to maintain and it took forever.
So, so I feel for these people.
All right, here's our next very interesting data point I thought is they asked
respondents,
what they thought their ability was to prevent
and detect a data breach or cyber attack
based upon obviously the tooling they're using in their infrastructure.
46% said they have the ability to prevent a data breach.
And 52% said they have the ability to detect the data breach.
I feel like those numbers are much, much higher than your reality.
I was going to say, I think they're very optimistic.
Yes,
this is like what percentage of people say they're better than average drivers,
80% of people think they're better than average.
I,
you know,
it's funny because we've been having this discussion with
a lot of members of the CS A where
they're discovering, for example, like within Aws or within Microsoft,
you can basically take data,
have it flow through the system and like handle it securely.
And so, you know,
you can have like your very sensitive data that's
locked down in your like public data which,
you know, you can serve on a web server.
But the moment it leaves that ecosystem, it loses that sort of security taking and
you can't
like do enforcement on it, right.
So you can't take the data out to an external system and still have
it like locked down or not locked down when we're talking with them.
They're, we're also teaching them things like you can say no to accessing data.
But then have like a fallback of like, you know,
Bob tries to access the data but he's accessing
it from a weird country that he's not normally in
and he gets denied, but he can f the help desk and maybe escalate to get access by,
you know, authenticating manually or something.
Right. Sure.
And they're amazed by this, like, they never, like they've never heard of this,
never consider this.
And in reality, the majority of technology does not support this.
And so a perfect example of this that does
it really well is the Microsoft family accounts,
right?
I have them set up on windows
and so both my sons have a, you know, a family sub account
and I have my one son set to be able to play video games from 330 pm till eight pm.
And so like the last two days, there was no school,
there was uh Easter Monday and a PD day for the teachers.
And so of course,
he's wanting to play Hearts of Iron Four and Roblox at like 10 in the morning.
And so he
tries to run it and it basically will block him and say,
do you want to ask for more time?
And the second he hits yes to ask for more time.
I get a notification in an email about five seconds later
saying, you know,
Felix is asking for more time on Roblox or
Hearts of Iron Four or Paradox launcher or whatever.
Do you want to say yes or no?
And if you say yes, is it like 10 seconds all the way up to three hours kind of thing?
And I click that it's just done, but that doesn't exist in the enterprise world
and yet like we can do it for video games for a 10 or an 11 year old.
-- And that's the kind of stuff we need that.
-- That is, that is funny. That is funny.
And, and you know, you know, what else has reminded me of?
I don't want, I don't want to dwell on it too much.
But I think there was an article one time that was like a
survey of grandmother reveals 100% of
grandchildren are above average and like just
-- it anyway,
-- remember when Blizzard and World of Warcraft had two factor RS A tokens.
They'd mail out to you for free.
Yep.
And that, like, my bank still won't do good to fa,
I
-- know. I know. But banks have insurance and, and Blizzard
-- doesn't.
Actually what's been happening is Canadian Banks have been, uh,
just telling people tough.
What?
Yeah, there's been a bunch of news article,
like R BC basically misfiled a bunch of wire transfers and was kind of like, too bad.
So sad.
And then of course, once it hit the media, yeah, it, they're like, oh, we, we fixed
it, we accidentally said the wrong thing.
Yeah. Um anyway, so,
but yeah, but what gets me is like enterprise soft,
especially enterprise security software is a really,
really hard market because you have the old stuff that is kind of
trusted in the sense of like, it won't,
you know,
it'll,
it won't break or mess up too badly. I mean, it will but we pretend it won't.
But then there's all the new stuff that actually does new and useful things,
but nobody wants to take that risk.
All right. All right.
I want to move this on because we've rat holed and you,
you've just transitioned into, I think the last point,
the last thing I've written down in my notes that I want to make
and on page 11,
they asked the respondents how important is live
patching and the idea behind live patching is,
let's say you have like an old system running
and there's a kernel update and you don't want to reboot.
You can like live patch the kernel
to remove the security vulnerability or whatever.
And you can do this now in a lot
of systems with like kernels and binaries and whatever,
right?
And the idea is minimize downtime. And obviously when you're
old gear, minimize downtime is the reason you're running old gear,
72% say the importance of virtualization stack live patching, which
that seems really high,
-- 70% database live
-- patching.
The problem is if you have to, if you have to take down your virtualization stack,
you have to take everything down.
I mean. Right. No, II, I get that. I, I agree.
And basically all of this,
these uh the response and it's just live patching services, whatever.
It doesn't, it doesn't really matter what the details are,
but basically 60% and above
are live patching stuff in their infrastructure, which I,
I'm not surprised by this, but I didn't realize it was that pervasive.
I think it became pervasive because it allows you to paper over cracks and bad it.
-- I
-- mean, I guess that's true because if you can't reboot,
it's because you don't have a reboot strategy or, or fail over or you know,
high availability.
So live patching is the band aid for not
having all these other best practices in place.
Even I suffer this locally.
I reboot my son's computer and then I have to immediately log in
as myself. Otherwise, the Plex server doesn't run
and if the Plex server doesn't run,
then my other son is going to be very annoyed because he's going
to go into his flex client and none of his media is available.
You know, you can run Flex on a Raspberry Pi. Right.
Yeah. But this thing, we have like six terabytes of content. It doesn't care
anyway. I know it's,
it's just from a management interface perspective. It's a bit easier to do it on a PC.
That's fair. And in fairness, this PC is like, you know,
it's a, it's a Ryzen 5 5600 X with 32 gigs of ra M and
all the storage.
Ok? I wanna, I wanna bring this all home now because we're running out of time.
And I think this is
so
we talked last week about
kind of patching and,
and speed of updates and all this stuff and then this data falls into our lap,
which I think shows the reality of this problem.
And I think this is where if you listen to security Twitter,
it sounds like you need to be updating quickly
and it's the most important thing in the whole world
and you're going to get hacked by Russians if you don't or whatever.
And I think the reality is stark contrast to the security people.
And so I think if you're a security practitioner,
you need to read reports like this and understand
where people are coming from and they're not doing this because they're stupid.
They're doing this because their job is keeping
this infrastructure running their job isn't applying patches.
And I think that's one of the big disconnects we have as security people.
We forget what the incentives are for the behavior of nonsecurity people.
-- Well,
-- it is the servant of the work, not the other way around.
And, and I see that so much with security people like, oh you can't do that.
Like every time security people say no.
And then people just short circuit around the security people
and security people are all horrified and it's like,
but they have to get their job done.
We're being so careful of the UBQ roll out of the
CS A because I'm like this cannot impact or be negative.
It has to be a good experience otherwise people won't use it.
Um And sorry, I just want to put out two more data points.
There's now uh CIA has been doing fantastic work these last few months.
Like they've really upped their game
with the known exploited vulnerabilities catalog and we'll have
a link to that in the show notes,
but it has about 700 entries now.
And
um
it's, it's actually kind of fascinating because
what's fascinating to me is if you said Kurt, you're going to have an own exploded. V
Andre
got like, I'd be like, oh, that makes sense because so you're gonna like,
see stuff kind of coming out on the regular, put it in the catalog, blah, blah, blah.
But what's fascinating to me is there's like the most recent stuff is a 2018 Zim,
a 2019 meta platforms.
A
2022 Microsoft Windows thing like, OK, you know, the, the most recent print spoo
uh thing that was out like two weeks ago or whatever.
Yeah.
But what's fascinating to me is these things that are like they've been out for four
-- or more years in some cases, like
-- a week ago,
they added a bunch of flash player stuff from 2015.
I
-- was running flash player
-- anymore.
Well, and if you're running flash player like, yeah, you're like,
well remember that Chinese um train
company or something was running their
scheduling or something on flash.
It was like there was an article a few years ago about how it just all went,
it went tits up when flash either got attacked or
stopped working or whatever.
But the, and then the second thing is, and uh dang it, let me find the,
sorry, I rebooted just before this. But there was that the Google article
or the article about Google tracking, what was it? 58
0 days last year?
Yes. Let's just make that a topic for a future show because I think
that is super interesting because the number of zero days
has gone up drastically and they actually talk about,
well, the number of detected zero days.
-- Yes. And, well, they, they kind of discussed some of that that are
-- publicly known.
-- It's,
-- I think that's a fascinating topic and I wanna,
that's too good
to
waste in the, like seven seconds we have remaining.
So
I think we're entering an era of better data because let's face it.
Like, I, you know, I,
we've been in this industry for 20 plus years and if you basically said Kurt, well,
you have eight hours today.
What are you going to patch?
And I'd be like, uh you know, and I basically, I would kind of go, well, honestly, I,
I pick CV SS scores because then if it's kind of wrong, it's like, well,
but NVD made those numbers so it's not my fault and don't fire me, please.
And I think there's a lot of that, like, I don't want to take some risk and be like, oh,
I think, you know, I'm just reminded every time at Red Hat
when there was some stupid thing where I was like, oh,
this is so dumb and then it blew up.
Oh,
I love it when that happens. Actually, that was my luck for Jay story.
I thought L for Jay wasn't that big of a deal. I was wrong.
Well, oh, and speaking of spring, uh for Jay or whatever,
it's called somebody privately.
DM. Ed Me on Twitter.
Saying they have a customer with a real world
situation where they got attacked and compromised by it.
So it like exists and, and he can't go public
with it. But
that's
cool. And I kind of was like, oh,
you know, that's a,
that's a valid point.
And I kind of said and thought that, well, you know, with, with all the it we have,
there's gonna be somebody who's vulnerable.
I mean, that's true. All right, man. I, I gotta cut this one off. I'm ending it.
We will discuss
zero day
very soon.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to over
social security podcast.com.
Hit at the show notes, UZ Pound Os S podcast hashtag do hit up,
hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.