Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 167 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Bresser. How
-- you doing, man?
Uh Quite well. Thanksgiving was nice.
-- Ate some good food.
-- Oh, fake Thanksgiving. That's right.
Yes.
Right. Which I guess is ironic because Canadian Thanksgiving
is on
Columbus Day in the United States.
Both of which are probably hideously insensitive topics for the native peoples.
So Thanksgiving is a harvest more of a harvest Thanksgiving thing here than a,
you know, thanks for signing over those rights.
I
see. Not, not like American Thanksgiving. I got you.
OK.
It's not quite as bad, I would say.
All right. All right. That's fair.
Although in the US now they are celebrating indigenous peoples on Columbus Day,
which I like and is very nice.
In fact, where I live, the state governor recently signed,
I, I don't know, executive order a bill or something or other
that, that made Columbus Day Indigenous People Day, which is awesome. So,
and if you don't know people, but Christopher Columbus was a terrible person.
Go look him up. All right. Cool. So I have uh,
an interesting story to tell prior to
our, our main topic that we want to discuss today.
So I have Phillips hue light bulbs
and I've owned these for nearly a year now
and
they are,
they will say amusing to me,
they change colors and turn on and off and whatever normal light bulb things.
Right. And one of them died.
-- I'm pretty sure
-- changing colors was not a normal
light bulb thing when you and I grew up.
Well, that's fair.
That's fair.
Uh, mind you not play music.
I wonder if I can make it play music if I made
it turn on and off really fast or something and whatever,
I'll figure this
out
anyway.
So,
one of them died and it was really interesting because it would
just start flashing on and off and it was super annoying.
-- And so it didn't
-- like die, die. Like the, it made light is just
whatever.
So
stuff and it died.
I don't know. I don't know. That's the question.
And so, and what's interesting though is it would still basically turn on and off
when I would command it to.
It's just, it would also
usually it'd be on for a couple of minutes and it would start to blink,
flash on and off and
it started out where it would do this maybe once a day
and eventually after a couple of days, it basically,
like after less than five minutes it would happen.
And so I contact the manufacturer
and they asked me a ton of crazy questions, which I found really interesting.
They wanted to know how many hours a day I left it on. They wanted to understand
is it connected to a dimmer switch? Which it's not that one.
I get, they wanted a picture of the lamp,
they wanted me to test it in another lamp and take a picture of that and like, they,
it was kind of wild but it kind of got me thinking as well.
I guess in
the
history of light bulbs, like what you plugged it into has basically never mattered.
And now it totally matters because there's
a computer running inside of the light bulb
and
it's broken
-- and now they want to know why.
-- Well, and I could definitely see heat being an issue.
I mean,
heat used to be a problem with light bulbs and that
if it were way too hot they would burn out.
But, I mean,
it was kind of a binary. It either worked or didn't work.
-- And when it stopped working, it stopped working.
-- These cue bulbs get pretty hot.
And so I bet if I installed them in like a can light setting up on the ceiling,
it would probably cook itself because it's,
I, I wouldn't say it's too hot to touch,
but it's uncomfortable to unscrew when it's on is what I would describe it as,
which is, and that's a good point.
I haven't installed any of the quote unquote, smart light bulbs. I have in a
enclosed fixture,
like they're all in lamps or things that
are meant to where they get ventilation because
quite frankly, I don't 100% trust them to not catch fire if they get hot.
Right. Right. Right.
So, so anyway,
but the coolest thing and I'm gonna give Phillips a
huge plus plus for this is I answer other questions.
I send them all the pictures they asked for
and then they basically just replied finally with,
we put a new bulb in the mail for you.
And I was like, what?
I
want the old one back. No.
And now, I mean,
I, I'm tearing that sucker apart. Right. I'm gonna, I want to know it's inside.
So I want to, I want to see pictures of the insides of it.
I will totally blog about this
and, and make plenty of noise when I do it.
So, yeah, by all means, I mean,
I'll let everybody know when I do because like what's in it?
I don't know.
Let's find out and,
and if I'm lucky they have J tag enabled so we can really do some fun stuff with it.
But
there
space for that in there
for J tag,
they're all just, they, they're surface amount contacts now.
It's not like the good old days where it was like a big freaking plug you plug in. Yeah.
Yeah, you just solder stuff on whatever. It's
no big deal. Doesn't matter. I'm ruining it anyway.
I mean, I just, I wonder, like, with the volume they're doing, you know,
removing J Tag saves them 1/10 of a penny, which,
-- when you're making light bulbs that adds up,
-- I don't know.
Well, probably not though because, I mean, J tag is such a standard.
I bet they use most of the chips.
They have probably come with its standard and it gives them a really
easy way to test the gear before they ship it out the door.
I bet, I bet it's there.
And what can happen though is in most production
settings you're supposed to disable the J tag on
before it leaves the building and like nobody does that. So that's good though.
That's great if you're a hardware hacker person. So, so anyway. All right, cool.
Uh Yeah, that's, that's why
story. So I'm, I couldn't believe it. It's like this is fantastic.
And then of course, the security weirdo in me thought, oh, I should,
I could just do this and, and pretend all my light bulbs are bad.
And then I thought,
I bet after the second one they're gonna make me start sending them back in.
-- Did they have you send them the serial number of the
-- bulb? Yep. Yep. Serial number.
They actually had me take a bunch of pictures of
the bulb with all the weird writings on it.
-- So.
-- Oh, maybe they wanted to make sure it wasn't like a counterfeit.
Oh, that's fair.
I didn't even think of that. But, yeah, I bet you're right
because those few bulbs, I think,
I remember when I looked at them last a year or two ago they were not cheap.
Yeah, they're like 50 bucks a bulb for these particular ones.
They were, they were given to me as a Christmas present. So
now you can get cheaper
ones
that are because in fact, on my garage,
I have less expensive Phillips bulbs that I think were $10 a piece.
And they obviously turn on at night and turn
off at daytime and the convenient thing about those.
So the reason I have hue bulbs is my,
the far end of my garage is pretty far from my house.
It's an ex, it's a detached garage
and Zigbee
does like mesh networking between the bulbs and so the far bulb can't see my Wi Fi
but it can see the bulb next to it, which can see the bulb next to it,
which can see my Phillips U Bridge.
-- So
-- it works.
I kind of want to see how many light bulbs you can put in a chain. And
I,
I did wonder this, but I have never tried. I also wonder this with
like mesh networking for Wi Fi. How many, how many, how many Google Wi
Fi access points?
I'm sure they have some programmed limit,
but I don't I wonder what it is and I actually looked
it up and I could not find an answer to that question.
People kept saying
-- you really don't want more than one
-- hop. I'm guessing it would be low.
It, yeah, it's probably like, three or less is my guess.
And everyone online kept saying you don't want more than one hop.
And it's like, well, yes, I do because I want to see how many hops I can do
but whatever, whatever anyway. Anyway. So Pew research,
you know who Pew research is
vaguely.
Yeah.
Ok. I'm not an expert either.
I'll say, but they're a research institute in the United States that is well known
for doing like polling data
and understanding various social trends we'll say.
And
they just released a report
because it, it hasn't been long since the time of this recording.
I just ran across it and it intrigued me
where they asked people what these seemingly bizarre
questions about kind of the internet and online.
And I thought
this is an extremely interesting topic
given we're always talking about social issues
with security and how we can't fix people and the technology and this,
that and another.
And so I thought this is a
amazing topic for us because it hits on many of the points we have.
And the last question is the best we, we, we'll kind of go through the questions,
we can talk about them a little bit and then
we can cover some of the results which some of them are really interesting.
Some of them are expected, I think. And so we'll start with number one.
And these are, these are strangely worded. I won't lie to you.
I didn't write them whatever we're going to roll with it.
The first question it sounds like was phishing
scams can occur on social media websites,
email or text messages and they don't use the Oxford comma in this so shame on them.
But
uh my answer to that would be yes. Yes, they can.
Yeah. Right.
The I think the answer to most of these is yes, actually.
But so 67% of people that responded to this answered correctly.
And now mind you, there is, uh I, I looked at some of the, the, the people,
the respondents and it looks like you have a pretty fair breakdown between age
demographics of age as well as education level is how they broke it apart.
So it's not like this is heavily weighted in one direction or another because
obviously what we'll get to in a little bit is like some of the questions
we'll say we're, we're heavily dependent on age
or, and most of them had a pretty typical breakdown, I think between
uh level of education where you had like high school or less,
you had some college and you had college.
Plus.
Well, I'm always reminded of that whole, what was it somebody,
it was like a Yahoo or a Google type thing where they did that thing on the street,
you know, what's the address bar?
What does it mean?
There's one of those in here,
you know, and people just really did not
by and large were not all that we'll get
over it.
So, anyway,
67% of people
knew that phishing scams can occur right by email, text messages, whatever.
-- So
-- 60 7% said yes.
Was there an option to say like some of the above or was it just yes or no?
So it looks like there is yes or no or unsure appears to be the the possible response
and you had 18% got it wrong. 15% didn't know 67% got it right.
And I feel like this is one of those things that everyone is so exposed to. Now,
if you are even remotely aware, I think you're going to understand this.
And I feel like we also have the situation of 20% of
any survey you ask like the people probably have comprehension issues.
So I think anything
near 80% is basically 100% for the most part.
Yeah, but I mean, you know,
I I was just looking through my spam folder today and I I got that email saying,
you know, my my email inbox is at 510 megabytes out of a 500 megabyte quota.
And my first thought was like Holy.
I don't think I've had only 500 megabytes in my email in box since about
-- 2001. Yeah. But
-- you know what a megabyte is.
They might as well have made the subject line.
Like your email is using six bananas out of eight quick.
You need more bananas and like most people would,
yeah, that would make more sense to them because they know what a banana is.
But here's the thing. It's not a matter of
do the phishing scams work or not. It's just the awareness of it.
Well, but that's the thing is I would say that
even though people, ok, let me put it this way,
are pretty much all drivers exposed to people using turn signals.
Yes. Do all drivers use their turn signals? No.
Right. Like the number of drivers I see doing really illegal things.
You know, we just did a road trip for Thanksgiving this weekend and
some of the stuff we saw on the highway, you know, people like tailgating us.
So we
pull off, you know, because we're passing, they're tailgating us,
we pull over into the slow lane
and they pull over and tailgate us some more. Like
if you want to go fast, that's what the left lane is for, you know.
So
-- I don't,
-- this is the least interesting question.
All right, we're gonna, we're gonna keep going.
So the next one I found this one interests me.
It says cookies,
allow websites to track user visits and site
activity and 63% of people got that right.
-- That shocks me. I'm amazed that 63% of people know what a cookie is.
-- You know what?
Probably because of all the GDPR warnings.
Oh,
I bet you're right. The
last
couple of,
like,
whoa.
Yes,
-- they work. They're actually good for some.
-- Holy, I'm not
holy crap. I'm not
sure. What, what was the rate before the GDPR warnings? Like 60%.
I mean, in all seriousness, I think before all those terrible cookie warnings,
it was probably very low because you'd be like a cookie.
-- What, what, what are you talking about? Well,
-- you don't see them, right?
Like, unless you're a weirdo like you or me who runs like a cookie manager,
I mean, and, and I'll be fair to be fair.
I, I'm still somewhat shocked when I go to a major site,
the amount of third party cookies and everything getting jammed in there. Right.
It's
like, um, I think it was like it was, or even you go to, um,
like wired or something and they, they're doing like 20 cookies
and some of it I get, they're like your screen size and your
-- whatever. But.
-- Right.
Right. No, I, I know, man. Why not go, go easy. They work. Right. All right.
We'll keep, we'll keep going. All right.
So, anyway, I guess chocolate up for GDPR or whatever the cookie law is,
I don't think it's GDPR.
I'd be curious to know if,
if people knew about the other tracking methods that are in use,
like using HSTS headers or the html canvas.
No, they don't know about those. Come on.
No way.
Actually,
I'm going to see if they have historical data on this now and I'll see if the
cookie answer existed maybe a couple of years ago and if people got it this right.
So that, that's interesting. Interesting. All right, I'll keep going.
So this one, I'm
shocked
is as high as it is also as well.
It says advertising is the largest source
of revenue for most social media platforms.
And 59% of people said yes, 9% said no. So like who are those 9%?
And 32% weren't sure.
So I feel like
59% is
I, I want to say it should be higher, but I'm not surprised.
I suspect it might be one of those classic things where, well, I guess they must be
making a bunch of money, but
I suspect a lot of people would be quite shocked if they knew how much money, you know,
a Google or a Facebook or linkedin.
And, and not only that, how little their data is actually worth,
which kind of puts it into perspective of
how many people are actually using this stuff.
So I, because I mean, I, well, I know the answer to that is yes, but at the same time,
I also know it's kind of, it's
somewhat nuanced in the sense of a lot of
these sites aren't actually making a ton of money,
you know,
or they're losing it hand over fist because
they're still in their growth phase or whatever
when people pick up the newspaper and it's like, you know,
there's a reason that only costs 25 cents,
no newspaper costs 25 cents anymore.
And this is one of my primary complaints about the newspaper.
I love reading a paper newspaper.
I love sitting down in a chair opening the newspaper and drinking my coffee
while I read it.
Except the actual paper newspaper has now become so ridiculously expensive
that I only subscribe to online editions because they are like
1/10 of the price and it breaks my heart because print
is so it's like printing and distribution is expensive and hard.
But anyway, all right,
we're going to keep going. So now here's one
that confused me.
I'll say it says privacy policies are contracts between websites
and users about how those sites will use their data.
25% got it wrong. 48% got it right. 27% didn't know.
And the hang up I had here though is I don't know if this is exactly the wording.
They asked the people,
but the word contract hangs me up a little bit because I feel like it,
-- it
-- depends on jurisdiction because I know,
you know, in the US under, I'm spacing out, what is that law?
The old one that basically says, you know,
terms of service on a website or a contract and that if you violate them
civilly you don't be charged. Oh, it's the old one from, like, 20 years ago anyways.
But, you know, there's other jurisdictions.
My understanding of a contract is, you know, both parties have to enter into it
willingly and knowingly. And
I mean,
I, I go to cnn.com and I'm,
-- I don't remember clicking through a contract,
-- right.
-- I feel like this one has a lot of ambiguity. I think
-- the intent is that, yeah, I mean,
in theory,
the privacy policy is what they are and are not going to do
with my data and there's some sort of legal teeth to that,
especially now with, you know,
a GDPR in Europe.
But fundamentally, I would have answered that question.
Yes, because I, that's the answer they want.
But I would actually, I would generally argue that the answer is no,
because they also every single one of those agreements reserves the right to,
you know, modify the terms of this at any time with like 30 days or no warning or blah,
blah, blah.
And I, I read further in this report and it was,
they, they didn't explain away any ambiguity that I saw.
So
I don't know this one. And now this is really the weirdest one I think
in terms of bizarre expectations.
So anyway, take that, take that for what it's worth. I know. Here's a good one.
It says net neutrality describes principle that internet service
providers should treat all traffic on their networks equally.
Now, this one was interesting. 12% got it wrong. 45% got it right. 42% didn't know.
-- And I feel like that's probably in line with
-- that actually doesn't shock me at all.
Yeah, that,
-- that's about what I would expect because
-- a lot of people
don't know what net neutrality is in the first place.
And even if you've heard of net neutrality,
it is a rather subtle and difficult concept to explain
because what does it mean to treat network traffic equally?
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
And most people don't even know what network traffic really is. So, it's,
it's not a truck. Right.
I thought we were series
-- of tubes.
-- Yeah, with trucks that jam the tubes up.
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
That's exactly it.
So, yeah, I don't know that, that one is interesting.
I don't have a lot to say about it. I think it's kind of expected. Now, here's the one
that I think
tells the story.
Http S colon slash slash in a URL means
that information entered into the site is encrypted.
15%. Got it wrong.
30% got it. Right.
53% didn't know. Holy cow.
I would say that's an ambiguous question because number one,
the
traffic is, you
know,
I know,
but I'm
saying, I know the intent, 53% of people don't know what HTTP S means.
That is what that question says.
Uh turn on your web browser and go to a website
and tell me if you see HTTP S
and the answer is no, you don't. They took that away.
That is fair. Chrome did take it away.
So you're not wrong
but
on my phone
hasn't for
so
in fairness. The other thing too is, I mean, well, this is the classic.
Sure, the, you know, the channel between me and CNN
edge or whoever's edge is encrypted. But
you know, the actual data I'm sending to them is then
decrypted and generally handled in plaintext. I mean,
people generally don't
properly
bad
stuff at all. So I'm not at all surprised that people don't know what HTTP S is.
I mean, because we had 20 years of the lock icon and, and what,
what was the result of that?
Well, they decided to get rid of the lock icon.
Uh They
-- did, well, they got
-- everybody got rid of the lock icon.
It's
-- true.
-- There's no, now there's only a not lock icon, which is,
yeah. Ok. You're right. I'll agree with you.
-- Oh,
-- actually, no, we're wrong if you click.
So in Chrome it shows me a lock icon next to the website and if I click the URL
spans it to http SF
slash slash, but
does
that.
Well, yeah.
Ok. So
this is, I feel like,
oh, and it does show a lock on my phone. I'm also mistaken on my phone.
-- Yeah,
-- I see a lock here actually.
But who's tapping the address bar?
Who's tapping the address bar on their browser?
-- You're gonna edit it? No.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
Well, most people don't.
Ok.
I,
I got you. That's fair. That's fair. Maybe they should have asked about the lock.
So, anyway, let's keep going. Whatsapp and Instagram are both owned by Facebook.
22% got it wrong. 29% got it right. And 49% didn't know.
Uh, I know whatsapp is owned by Facebook for sure. I'm pretty sure
-- Instagram is because they
-- both are.
-- Yeah,
-- because my understanding is Facebook is not
hot with
-- kids. So the solution is to buy the stuff that is hot with the kids, which
-- is
-- Facebook, Instagram,
-- which is Instagram, WhatsApp and Snapchat. Uh,
what about,
-- isn't there that one called tiktok or something? Uh,
-- is tiktok an app?
I thought tiktok was just a video website thing.
I'm over 40. How would I know?
That's true. Get off my lawn. You kids?
Seriously.
-- I'm using the internet on the computer.
-- I assume it was a Vine Replacement.
-- No, it's an
-- app. What's tiktok is an app? Well, no, I know it's an app but I don't.
Is it a social media app or? I guess it can, youtube is a social media site. So.
-- All right.
-- Yeah. Is Instagram a social media app?
Ah, yes. All right. Whatever.
I'm, I computer Kurt. It's fine.
Anyway,
I mean, can you imagine asking people basic questions about electricity? Like,
how many phases of power does your house have
-- usually?
-- Well, my house has two but they produce it in three. Whatever.
I'm,
I'm the worst person to answer
that question because I'm actually insanely educated
or, or simply put, you know, how many, what AMP service does your house have?
Is it like 100 or 200?
-- I
-- have two 100 AMP service which I have some funny stories about how I got it.
I got it for free
due to a variety of hilarious events.
Oh,
it's, I'll tell the story. It's a long story. I will not tell it today.
But yes,
basically I got my service upgraded from 100 to
200 AMP for free and they buried my line
because basically
I, I live in an old neighborhood. They were sick of trees falling on the lines.
So they, they had, they had a deal I couldn't refuse.
That was actually a pretty short story. Anyway. Uh So putting that question now. OK.
So, so this one was actually interesting, I think.
No, no. Hang on here. It is. Uh
Right. So the whatsapp question was super interesting
when you look at the, the age demographics of the question because basically
anyone from the age of 50 plus
like, had no idea.
And everyone 49 and below, for the most part knew this in terms of the breakdown. I'm
assuming
the 50 year olds don't use that app at all.
Right. Exactly. They're probably like, I don't even know what this is. That.
That's kind of my, my suspicion there as well.
So I found that one interesting though.
So. All right. Let's keep moving here.
Now, here's another one that's depressing and says,
can identify examples of true two factor authentication.
-- 55% got it wrong. 28% got it right. 17% didn't know even my
-- bank gets it wrong.
They're like, I, I know you have a security question that's totally different.
And I'm like, no, it's, it's a password.
They're like, no, no, no, it's not a password. It's a security question.
I'm like, it's a hidden piece of data. I have to remember
that's a password. Like, no, no, totally separate security question
also.
Can you tell us your mother's maiden name?
Right.
I'm not shocked by this and I think it's depressing and
I blame places like banks for helping spread disinformation where they,
they had me enter
like my favorite one always was
I, I don't even know if I still use this bank anymore. It was a long time ago
you enter your log in information and then it would show me a picture I had picked out
to prove it was them. And I'm like, this doesn't prove anything.
And it was like, oh, my goodness, this is so ridiculous.
-- I,
-- no, that was actually as a direct response to a common class of, like,
uh, web browser hijacking
software that was popular a few years ago.
But the thing is that, that solves like one specific avenue of attack.
It doesn't actually give you strong to.
Yeah,
I picked,
oh, jeez, I think.
Yeah, they, I, I forget the one bank I deal with does used to do that and it was,
I forget if I got to upload my own picture, I don't think I got to upload a picture.
I think I had to choose from like 10 pictures
and it was like playing cards or something and other stupid stuff. And
yeah, I,
yeah. No, it's, this is not proper two fa, I mean, it's technically two fa because
no, it's not, it's not two factors.
It is one factor, authentication.
Yeah.
Well, it's one type of factor
but just
you're not helping.
This is the problem.
Well,
that is the problem is that people define two
fa is two factors but are they different factors?
And that's where we, we never held them to account.
I would punch you through the microphone right now
if I could stop putting technicalities on this question.
And this is, I think the problem with two factor off today is we keep saying, well,
actually when the reality is no, like
you should be having a user name and password and get a freaking UBI key or something.
And that's what, that's how it needs to work.
Well, here's a great example is phone based two fa
like something based on your phone number. Is that proper two fa or not?
Yes.
And it is acceptable in most situations because I
-- believe
-- there's a question later in the thing that
I only knew who that person was because of something related to this.
Ok. We'll get, yeah, that one's coming up. Uh,
we're not going to argue about if S MS
counts as two factor authentication because that is a,
a den of snakes
that
-- has no good end to it.
-- I think
that it is weak to fa
-- ok. I'll agree with that. Yes,
-- it is easily hijacked.
I'll agree with.
It's not easy to hijack.
It's, if you are a specific target, it can be used against you.
If you are a random person, you are fine.
That is
not the warning. A lot of it's, it's anyway,
I'm gonna do
it.
We're
doing
it.
We're going to move on right next next. Uh Right.
So this one private browsing mode only prevents someone
using the same computer from seeing one's online activities.
They suggested being like your ISP still knows what you're looking at.
Whereas the person living with you may not,
I would say private browsing attempts to do that.
I'm not sure that it actually accomplishes it.
Whatever, man, it does it for most people.
If,
if I'm using your computer with a private browser on
and then you walk in and I quick close it,
I'm probably fine.
Well,
-- unless I have some other software running to monitor which you
-- probably don't,
it's fine. Everything's fine.
Whatever. See, again, you're getting into these ridiculous technicalities.
Normal people don't have monitoring software.
-- Parents
-- generally do with their kids computers and
maybe they do.
Maybe they don't, please don't spy on your kids. I don't think it breeds trust.
It's not that I want to spy on my kids.
I actually really don't want, I don't have time for that,
but more to the point I do want to block.
Like, for example, I would like to give my kids access to Wikipedia,
but there's definitely a couple of pages in Wikipedia that
maybe at the age of eight, they're not quite ready for yet,
you know.
Uh I'm not, I could make so many jokes right now and I won't.
So, ok, so private browsing mode, 25% got it wrong. 24% got it right. 49% don't know.
And I feel like that is a completely expected distribution.
-- I
-- think that don't know, is actually in a way
good in that these, well,
at least for the purposes of the survey they're willing to say, I don't know,
but my question
or concern would be that in real life, what do they
-- do?
-- Or maybe they do know.
And they're just being cool because their partners next to them, like private
browsing. What does that do? I don't know what would look at with private browsing.
I don't know.
Like this weekend I fixed a friend's laptop and I, well, I don't know that I fixed it.
I made it less worse for sure. Like it booted up and then the web browser
just didn't even get the sad dinosaur. Internet broken
screen. It just did not work.
And so I finally, you know, at first I was like, ok, and I made a recovery,
um,
antivirus scanner stick and scan the machine.
I'm like, oh, no, it's, it's actually clean. Like, what the heck.
And then I started poking around. I was like, oh, you got Komodo and it's out of date?
Ok. Get rid of Komodo. Hard reboot. Hey, she works again.
And, you know, and it was funny because this guy is like, oh, yeah,
I'd meant to get rid of Komodo.
-- I just hadn't gotten around to it yet
-- for the last seven years.
It's been more like a month or two, but it had been apparently completely hosed
and,
you know, they have another computer that does work.
-- So, hey,
-- is it called a chromebook or
no? But,
so, I mean, that's, that's my fear is there's oftentimes people will,
if you ask them, they'll say, I don't know.
But if they're actually in that situation,
uh,
it's not that they won't say they don't know.
But by definition, if you don't know, where do you even begin to look?
What words do I type into my browser to learn about this?
-- No. Really?
-- Right.
There's,
they could rename it to something more inappropriate
but
private browsing. Ok. The Wikipedia pages front and center.
That's actually not bad.
Ok. Ok. Well, whatever, whatever
I will say though, from the professional perspective,
I love having private browsing because I can open a window that
doesn't have any of the cookies that are in my other windows.
So I can, like,
look at a site as if I was not someone logged into
like every freaking service on the planet in my web browser,
which is nice.
I like that
anyway. All right.
And here it is
the question.
The one that you didn't know either,
can they correctly identify a picture of Jack Dorsey?
7% got it wrong. 15% got it right. And 77% didn't know.
So, wait, wait, wait, I thought the question was who is Jack Dorsey?
Because I was like, I know he's a tech leader CEO or something.
But like, I have no idea what he looks like.
Well, that's the beauty of Jack Dorsey.
His, his pictures,
as I told you in Slack earlier is they kind of range from pimply faced youth in his
younger days to star Trek villain to a guy who probably should own a nightclub in L a,
like, he has this incredibly different
-- kind of range of photos of him.
-- Yeah.
I'm just, I, I just googled it and number one, he wears a lot of black so he's, I guess,
Channel Tim Cook or whatever.
I, a lot of this seems to depend on when he last had his beard and hair trimmed
in.
-- Exactly,
-- because it goes from, like,
straight up homeless to billionaire in the space.
Exactly.
Exactly. So, I don't,
I feel like if someone showed me a random picture of Jack Dorsey,
there's probably a very high probability.
I would say, I have no idea who that person is.
And so, but why, what is the purpose of that, this question?
And I'm looking at this like,
and then he's shaved and he looks totally different as most men
do when they shave their beard off and cut their hair.
I don't,
I don't know why they asked this and I even read in their explanations and like,
there doesn't seem to be a purpose behind it.
And my, my, the only thing I can figure is
you figure api bet a picture of Mark Zuckerberg
would have a much, much higher
-- success rate of people identify.
-- Well, he's got that very infamous robotic look to
-- him.
-- He, he does, right. The android manufacturers hadn't gotten it right yet.
-- You
-- know, the whole I am a human too and enjoy waffle.
Yes. Exactly. Exactly.
Smile at exe right now you could ask about,
say one of the Google founders and I think they would
be even less well known than Jack Dorsey in most instances.
But I, I don't know, I don't, what, what, what does this prove?
I just looked up a picture of Sergey Brin.
-- He looks totally different than he did 20 years ago.
-- I believe it.
I don't think I've seen a picture of him in 20 years
and so I'm confident I would have no idea who he is.
It's honestly generic white guy.
That's it. No, that's all, that's all I can say straight up. Like, uh,
maybe I don't,
II, I don't know what to say. I really don't know what to say about this one.
I think, uh,
I think the only time that question is kind of fair is around something like saying,
maybe the queen of England, especially if you live in
a country where she's on every single piece of money.
You know, then, then that's an interesting statistical point because it's like,
wait,
how do you not know what the queen looks like if
she's on every single piece of money you've ever handled?
-- But
-- do you only have pictures of the current queen or
do you have young queen on some of your money?
-- What depends on how old the money is?
-- Ah, so it's conceivable.
Someone could be looking at an old coin.
I believe there's about four or five different pictures currently in use.
Well, in in common use in the sense of like,
you know, currency, like there's bills or, well, more, well,
not really bills anymore.
We got rid of all the paper money but, um,
coins that are older and floating around with the younger pictures of her.
But, yeah, like who I, I think maybe, um,
well, I'm just, yeah, I don't understand the point of that question at all.
I don't get it and I feel like that is exactly what I would expect.
I, I'm kind of surprised that anything above single digits could identify him,
to be honest.
Right. Right. Yeah.
Yeah. I, I don't know. I don't understand that question in any way.
Whatever.
I mean, it makes sense for an actor. Like, you know, here's a picture of Keanu Reeves.
Do you know who that is? And if they say no, it's kind of like, seriously, like, but
I
watch TV.
I, I could fall in that trap.
I don't know a lot of actors and I don't
care because I basically don't like to watch movies.
So I don't know, very like Keanu Reeves.
I know just because he's been in so much sci fi stuff. But
he is, he's awesome.
Uh, actually, you know what? I, I rewatched Johnny Mnemonic the other day. Holy cow.
That movie is still awesome.
It's, it's funny
because they talk about what he has, like 300 terabytes in his head and they're like,
oh, there's so much data like,
ha ha.
-- That's
-- nothing. Yeah, 300 gigabytes
-- with a ra M doubler or
-- 300 gigabytes. Thank you. Right.
I'm like, ah, that's barely any but
it's like, yes, the key, my key chain in my pocket has more data.
But anyway, it holds up.
But anyway, yeah, there's,
there's tons of Hollywood people that I would have no idea who they are.
So, I, I don't know, but I feel like Jack, whatever, whatever it doesn't matter.
I think an interesting question would have been like, have you ever, have you,
you know, have you ever used Twitter for more than five minutes?
And I suspect again there would be like
a
-- cliff of a drop at 40 or 50 probably.
-- Yeah. Right.
Because I mean, I'll never forget I had, someone
will say an older person one time asked me is Twitter hard.
I'm like, oh, no, is tweeting hard is what they said.
I'm like, I can't answer you just stop talking to me.
Like I don't, if, if I answer your question, I'm going to end up in a discussion.
I don't want,
I think philosophically the person who asked that question,
-- the answer is unfortunately,
-- yes.
No, Kurt, that's not the intent of the question that was asked.
And this again is my security gets into
trouble because instead of answering their question,
you go on
some ridiculous philosophical tangent that nobody cares
about the person was asking like,
what do I have to do to tweet and the answer
is install the app and type crap into that box.
But no,
it's not a philosophical question
anyway. Anyway. So I guess
I look at these survey results and
the, my, my main takeaway is that I feel like
we live in a different world than everyone else
because we're very aware of all of these technologies,
we know how a lot of them work.
And so
while we would have gotten almost all these questions, right?
It is
understandable. Most people don't.
And I don't know if that's, I would like to say it's a bad thing,
-- but maybe it's not,
-- I don't think it is.
I mean, I, I go back to electricity, for example,
almost nobody really understands how electricity works.
And I'm going to put you in that category too because
like explain magnetism to me in 10 words or less,
nobody can explain magnetism.
If you, if you, if you understand how magnetism works, you,
you won't answer that question because you can't.
It's like, actually,
did you ever see the question where the reporter asked
Richard Feynman that and he basically goes off in this crazy
rant and says, I can't answer your question for you.
It's beautiful. It's beautiful.
-- But
-- more to the point as long as you follow the,
you have an electrician who follows the electrical code,
who cares? You plug stuff in it works
well. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the
show notes to
the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag to hit us up with social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too, everybody.
And I guess uh invest in flash cards of tech leaders.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.