It doesn't matter, leave it at the end. Maybe I could put it at the beginning.
I don't know. We'll see what happens.
There was no episode 214 and at first we were talking about, oh,
we'll make a joke about how the government censored us or something.
And I realized we live in tumultuous times right
now and I don't want to make this joke.
So the reason there's no episode 214 is because I can't count.
And that's all like there's no conspiracy. Just
I typed 215 into my system and there was no 214 and I made a mistake.
Well, I'm fixing, it would have taken like three or four minutes.
-- No,
-- I don't think so though.
Because of the way podcast networks work,
I think we would have ended up with episode 214 and
episode 215 both being exactly the same published on their sites.
So I thought it's easier to do nothing.
And more importantly, the most important part of this
I have changed my,
what do I have a process? Yeah, the process sounds good. I have changed my process.
To make sure I cannot make this mistake again,
which is the most important part of making mistakes is
doing something to make sure it never happens again.
So, there you go.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Breit.
This week's bias is anchoring.
The first thing you judge influences your judgment of
all that follows what we're gonna be doing.
Biases. Logical biases
are,
yeah, they're good. Well, they're not good. They're a problem.
-- Actually,
-- this week's sponsor is
Anchors Anchoring.
Also, we would, uh, an anchor sponsor would be fine because, you know,
it's annoying to me.
I finally
learn how ship anchors work
because, like, as a kid, I just sort of thought they,
like dug into the bottom of the ocean and like
anchored you, it turns out no, what anchors you is,
you have the anchor and a length of chain and then a
cable and it's the length of chain lying on the ocean floor.
Simply put friction from that is what keeps the ship from moving.
I have no idea.
I did not know that. I thought like the anchor was dug into the
dirt or the silt or whatever.
-- And so I always, you know, kind of wondered like, how do they get it back out?
-- Right?
Why, why do they even have an anchor then?
-- Why don't they just throw a piece of chain over the side
-- my understanding is you
need something at the end with a little bit more like that has more friction.
-- So it digs in a bit.
-- It's possible. I have no idea. But,
yeah, anchoring. Ok.
What about anchoring? What are we talking about?
-- This
-- news of life on Venus is a great example of everybody hears life on Venus
and
yeah, the poor scientists that the actual report is a
-- little bit less sensationalistic.
-- I think
I would say it's substantially less sensational.
So I am a huge space nerd and I love all space news in every possible way.
And
I saw this article headline of scientists detect life on Venus.
And I thought, I bet you that the article has nothing in it.
And you know what it always reminds me of is my comparison here is water on Mars.
How many times have scientists discovered water on Mars? Probably 40
the
-- everywhere but,
-- but sorry, are we talking liquid water or
-- whatever
-- anything? Right? Or like how many times his Voyager left the solar system?
Like
it's one of those situations and this, I think is completely relatable to security
in the context of there's what the scientists are saying
and there's what people hear and they're not the same thing
at all.
No.
Yeah.
No, these, when I first saw this, I was like, ok,
somebody with a title or is making stuff up and then I actually read it and I'm like,
oh, this is actually completely reasonable.
-- Yeah,
-- it is. They found a gas that
on earth
in our current
-- perspective of science,
-- I would say understanding of science not perspective
in
a
right.
They, they found a gas in our current understanding of science
on a rocky planet.
-- This gas is only created by bacteria.
-- Well, uh so it's on earth
and under earth conditions, it's only created by
like
um life.
It can also be created in a laboratory, obviously.
But my understanding is because I read a little bit about this,
the conditions needed to create this gas in a laboratory
are generally not sort of naturally found on earth.
And, and,
but here's the thing, right?
And here's how I would, I, I'll, I'll frame it in this context.
I don't want to dwell on specifically Venus for too
long because I think there's so many interesting parallels here.
But I was listening to an astronomy podcast. Uh This has been like a
year, it was a long, long time ago
and they were talking about like weird stars and the
host basically said these are stars that shouldn't exist.
And of course, as soon as you say that in astronomy,
we find some because when you have,
when you have a universe that is so monstrously large,
you can't possibly imagine it.
Everything that you claim is
is never going to happen because it's too rare.
There's probably millions of them out there.
Well, like they say, you know, one in a,
is eight times a day in New York
and, and this is the same deal of something was found
on a strange place.
And so
maybe it's normal there. We don't know.
And, and, and so anyway, here's,
here's a parallel I think we should draw is when
security people try to talk to normal people about anything,
anything at all, the people don't hear what we say.
-- Well,
-- nuance is hard.
Like that's the thing, you know,
pick a good password. Oh man. Oh man. Oh man.
I just want to start punching stuff because I'm like, no,
you know what my password manager is going to do it for me.
-- And then I know it's good. And
-- so the way, the way I would explain this to people is that
if you want to prove to me life is on Venus. Make me a hamburger from a Venus cow.
That is the bar.
Well, and I love that, you know,
they basically people were talking about it and it's like, well, you know,
what really needs to happen is we need to have a sample returned
to earth and get into the hands of a bunch of humans.
And like my first thought from like a pro
-- principle is like, no,
-- yeah, that's how movies start.
But now here's, here's the other part of that though.
You can, you can't even claim that because we could send a craft to Venus.
-- We could capture a sample, we could bring the craft back,
-- crashed into earth.
Like that previous one.
There was a sample return mission that,
-- like crashed into the Australian Outback or something that
-- was for comet stardust.
I think that was.
And yeah, it crashed and they recovered a little bit of stuff but it was,
they were supposed to catch it with a
helicopter sky hook. Like it's an amazing,
it's a Rube Goldberg machine.
-- Like none I've ever seen
-- what kills me is like they were
doing this stuff in the Cold War all the time for satellite.
-- Anyway.
-- Anyway. So, so here's the thing though, right?
We bring our sample back to earth
and if the sample we get looks anything like stuff we find on earth,
they're going to say
maybe we accidentally sent bacteria on the spacecraft and
now we just brought back what we sent.
Well, look, they've had tardigrades go on
missions to outer space and come back alive.
Well, I mean,
and it's really cool because from a scientific perspective, like, hey,
we just proved t
grains
for five other
didn't mean to. But you know, there it is.
And so anyway, like this is part of the nuance of science.
And like you pointed out saying,
pick a strong password is the same problem that to a security
person who understands the industry and understands some of the nuance,
you can say,
pick a strong password and you're going
to immediately go to something insanely long,
randomly generated stored in a password safe.
Right.
But a normal person gonna hear, pick a strong password, they're gonna be like,
fluffy seven,
the seven makes it strong
and I'll put a question mark there, you know, like, no, your password sucks.
You can't name it after your dog.
The thing that really gets me is
these poor scientists are actually really trying, you know,
if you read the actual sort of guts of the
article and I don't mean like article in the news,
but from the actual, you know, science type people, basically, they're saying,
like, look, here's what we found
and here's like six probable ways to disprove this and that we're wrong.
And, and then of course, people are like, ah, see the scientists aren't
and it's like, that's the whole point of science, right? We come up with this,
you know, this idea
and we, we make a hypothesis.
We, we, we basically try and understand the world a bit better
and then we test the bejesus out of it so that
we actually do want to disprove it because if we disprove it cool,
then we move on to the next thing.
But if we don't disprove it, huh? Maybe this is true and it works
and always gets me about science above all other
things is science lets you predict the future,
it lets you
make predictions. Like
I'm going to put a hole in the ground here and oil is
going to come out because this data says so and my understanding of,
you know, geology says that there's like a,
an oil deposit here or we can design a car this way with crumple zones
and people will die less
-- and get less hurt
-- now. But here's the magic part of it as well.
And this is a lesson for us and we'll tie this
back to passwords momentarily is sometimes when science is wrong,
that isn't a failure.
It means you just have more data now to make better decisions in the future.
And a better understanding of the underlying thing, like, you know, for,
for the longest time we had Newtonian physics, which, you know,
if you're playing billiards.
Absolutely.
But then you want to make a nuclear reactor and
-- things get a little weird
-- or relativistic speed travel,
right?
I mean,
yeah, not a problem for us yet.
I mean, no, but it is a problem. I mean, think about like the GPS, right?
Like the GEOS station or not,
but the satellites for GPS need to take
relativity into account because of the earth's gravity.
I bet that if they did not take relativity into account,
we would just end up in one of those classical, like, ah,
there's these weird glitches with our navigation system but, you know, whatever.
-- No, it would be unusable. The margin of error. Would it actually be
-- bad enough to be
-- like
-- meters,
like tens of meters? Is the, you'd be
not
really
if you don't take
my understanding of all this is quite poor
and I'll be the first to admit that.
And by understanding of this, I mean, basically everything, not just gps. Right.
My understanding of pancakes,
pancakes. Anyway. Ok.
So here's,
here's where I want to bring this before we end
up on some crazy tangent about whatever bears or something.
Pancakes.
Yeah,
I love pancakes. Maple syrup. It's maple. Oh, I love maple. Anyway. Ok.
So if we look at passwords specifically in the context of science and learning,
my favorite example is Nist released password guidance
and we all followed it. And then one day someone actually did real science
-- using real data
-- also at NIST.
-- Yes, I know
-- that well.
And people did this prior to Nist as well, but he's
-- never
-- right. They basically said
the guidance Nist has been giving is wrong
and here's the data showing it's wrong.
It's one of those situations where Nist actually did the right thing they said, ok,
we made a mistake.
We shouldn't be doing this. Here's some revised guidance,
but there's like there's still and it baffles my mind
where there are people I talk to that say,
yeah, I read that.
I, I disagree. And it's like, no, you can't. Like this isn't an opinion piece.
The the data shows this doesn't work. You can't
-- like no,
-- I think a lot of people conflate facts and opinion
to put it bluntly,
-- I'm shocked for you to say that in our current political climate
-- curt.
I know, man. Oh my God.
But yeah, it, it really blows my mind that these people literally think that they,
I have anecdotal evidence.
Therefore this peer review study with a, you know, a sample size of 10,000.
Yeah, I'm just going to
it. But the kid down the street told me that.
Yeah.
And, and I've been wondering about that for a few months now.
And I just,
it's a human thing because I think in past the world was generally simple enough
that most people could wrap their head
around the world and generally understand it.
But a great example would be traffic light patterns.
I did a bit of research into that because I
was kind of annoyed by some of the time they changed
some of the timing of the lights on some major
roads near me that really makes it kind of screwy.
But it's clear that the point of this
was to get people to stop running the red lights and having accidents.
Like there's, there's enough,
let me put it this way.
I've personally witnessed, I'm gonna say, well, the, the minivan,
like I've personally witnessed the outcome of four accidents
and I mean, one of them was pretty bad, like I was driving up stony,
saw the double flash of the red light camera, this was at night,
you know, a couple blocks away because it's pretty, pretty bright
pull up and there's a minivan on its side, there's another minivan off to the side.
There's people out helping making phone calls, blah, blah, blah.
But, you know, it was,
it was pretty bad or another time there was a Cooper mini up on the, um,
on the landscaping, smashed into the big sign.
And so,
you know,
it's a set of major interchanges where people run red lights and cause accidents.
And so they've changed the timing of the lights
and it sucks because you can't,
you know, hit the green and hit the next screen and get through,
you hit a green, then you hit the red or you hit the red and
you know what I mean? Like, so they've basically staggered it
and it has really
made it about
1530 seconds slower consistently,
but there's probably going to be less accidents.
And that is a huge external cost like that is a huge cost. Like one accident is
hundreds of thousands of dollars in medical bills borne by the taxpayers. Exactly.
That's huge. You know, compared to wasting 15 to 30 seconds of people's lives.
And that's the thing. Right.
So something as quote unquote, simple as a red and green light timing
it,
I'm guessing there's somebody working for the city of Edmonton with a spreadsheet
and, you know, and,
-- and a model of how intersections work and how people abuse them that made that
-- call,
I would assume that is the case.
I obviously don't know for sure.
And I mean,
if traffic lights are that complicated how the heck
can we expect people to handle information security?
Well, we can't. And that's ok.
Well,
if they listen to the experts and the experts are good and true then the system works.
But the problem is this anti intellectualism thing where people don't want
-- to listen to experts
-- and it's more complicated than I think though.
And I'm going to not address this in the
broad universe today because I think there's some other
socio-economic problems around all this.
But let's just focus on security specifically. And
-- my argument is that our experts suck is what I'm going to call it.
-- Yeah, they do.
How long did that
password guidance go for before somebody checked it out and went, whoops,
-- this is wrong a very
-- long time.
And so the way I like to always look at this is when I viewed the security universe,
there are
the experts and I'll put this in air quotes here.
You can't see me, but I'm making air quotes in my fingers.
So there's the experts and what most of these people are experts at
is is making themselves very public where they give lots of interviews.
They,
they do keynotes at conferences and all this stuff
and the vast majority of them say very little.
And then you have people who are like the
scientist experts that are publishing the papers like,
well, we found this
obscure gas on Venus
and a lot of those people are doing, you know, like the work,
but they're not in a position to communicate the work they're necessarily
too busy
doing
-- or they're not
-- good at
communicating
here's and not to pick on the password guide,
but he kind of messed up because he wanted to do password guidance,
which is commendable, right?
We want that, we want expertise.
But, and I quote, he had wanted to provide guidelines based on real life data.
Cool, great. That's what we want.
But there wasn't much empirical data on password security 15 years ago. In the end,
he had to rely heavily on an outdated white paper
on computer password security written in the 19 eighties.
And so I would say part of this is on him in my mind, I hate
making
generally broad large scale recommendations when I don't have data.
And, and I've had to do this a few times in the past.
And I've literally said, like, look, I don't have data,
but my gut says this and it's possibly wrong for these reasons.
But here's what I think and, and more importantly, why do I think this? Because
if I say here's my decision and here's why I
made my decision and here's what it's founded on.
Hopefully somebody's going to go uh Kurt, that's not correct and point that out and,
and you need to revisit that on a regular basis.
But now how many security decisions happen
because they're based on data
and how many happened because of their opinion
-- and how many are ever revisited, how many
-- happened? Because you need a decision and,
and some of them do. And that's ok.
And ok, actually, sometimes, so one of my favorite arguments in this space is so
I actually just had a meeting
with,
it was github.
It was, it was yesterday, man. It feels like it was a year ago. But anyway, so github,
github
has, you know,
they've got their advanced security features and all
this stuff and they were basically saying,
oh, look at everything we've done.
Uh We want you to use some of this.
And I said, OK, here's the deal, right? Like I can't use this because of this reason.
And, and like an example is they've got their dependency checker,
but the dependency checker, the, the way
the organization is set up too many people are getting the dependency checker mail.
So he turned it off and I'm like,
I need the ability to just send the mails to like me and not everyone.
And the guy says,
oh, but you just need to reset up your organization like this.
I said, you don't understand
that is not on the table. II, I cannot do that. And more importantly,
as a security person, I'm unwilling to stick my neck out and say,
like we have to do this like no screw it.
I will do nothing before I will try to do that
re architecting how the users and groups and permissions and whatnot
are set up in a cloud service once it's working.
-- No, the answer is no.
-- Exactly.
But, but I mean, this is what ends up happening in a lot of cases.
And I think a lot of security people will say, oh,
we have to do this for reasons and sometimes no, you don't.
And sometimes if you try to force something through you actually damage
what you're trying to do more than just doing nothing at all.
-- This
-- also assumes that what you're trying to do is actually useful and helpful,
which it isn't always.
-- Dependency
-- scanning is definitely a mess
and a perfect example is so OK,
dependency scanning cool.
So I'm going to get a report of like all my
out of date dependencies is that actually going to be helpful.
I know
we have a process in place to actually do deal with this uh using some external tools.
And as much as I would love to leverage what github has or, or my other favorite
is they're talking about
automatic dependency resolution where they have a tool that basically says, oh,
this dependency is out of date.
-- Here's a pull request that'll update it. It's like, holy crap.
-- No.
Well, and again, if you're,
if you're just hacking on some open source software that you run on your laptop,
that's
OK.
But if you're running a company on top of that or worse yet,
you're pitching that software over the fence to other
people to run and they care about it working
well. And here's what actually happens because we tried to use a tool like this
and basically
the tool would submit the pill request, then the C I would run and it would fail.
And then so now you have a choice.
Does a human look at the failed job and decide what happened and how can we fix it?
Do we ignore it completely?
Like, like where do you draw the lines in making this stuff happen?
You obviously can't auto commit if you're failing your build tests,
but now that you failed it,
whose job is it to figure out why it failed?
So you're creating stupid, annoying work.
Well, and the reality too is any automated system that can handle.
This is pretty much by definition going to be,
have to be pretty much as complex as a human being.
Yeah. Exactly. Right. Because this is,
yeah, I've looked into this too, like my devs, you know, again, they're like, hey,
Kurt, you know what's the best way for us to monitor CV S in the rails ecosystem?
Like, don't.
Right. And they're like, what, what do you mean? Don't? And I'm like,
you guys update the software, like weekly and ship updates, like every two weeks.
They're like, yeah, and I'm like, well, keep doing that
and I'm like, if there's a big emergency,
it'll show up in the news and stuff.
You know, if there's an actual, like, really bad flaw, that kind of matters.
Yeah, we'll probably hear about it and I'll poke you guys with a stick and
see if we're affected and if we need to update or not,
you know, and that works for us because we're just, you know,
we're the only ones running the software that they built.
But by and large, you know, for a lot of these companies, like,
can you ship an emergency update in less than 24
hours without making everybody drink seven pots of coffee.
And the answer to that in almost every organization is no.
Now, can you do it in a week or a month?
A more reasonable time frame, in my opinion, and most can't do it in a month.
-- Ok.
-- A month is too long, obviously, but a week is probably fair. Now, I
will say,
I think this goes back to the kind
of security people blowing things out of proportion and
not communicating correctly is if you think you need to push an update in 24 hours,
you're probably confused or
not living in the real world because I can think of very, very few instances
where making an update happen in 24 hours is actually necessary
-- and reasonable.
-- Well, and the simple fact is what
an organization will typically do is just turn that off.
I mean, that's happened here in Canada Revenue, Canada, sorry,
the Canada Revenue Agency got hit by three separate attacks this summer,
basically just turned off a huge swath of features on the website.
Like,
and these are major features like the one is tying your service accounts into
cr A so that like you can access your account and they just,
we definitely got hacked through this.
So we're turning it off and it's been off for a while and that's ok.
I mean that during heartbleed
they had to get an exemption to lengthen the time people had to file their taxes
because again,
revenue Canada or Canada Revenue Agency shut down their
website like two days before all taxes were due.
-- You couldn't e
-- file Harpley is a great example.
So there's a security issue and we know it's maybe bad, maybe not bad.
-- Yeah,
-- it turned out it was pretty bad. It,
it could be.
I mean, it depends how you're using it though.
There were so many weird what ifs around heartbleed
and
it is, it is a situation where I think trying to rush a patch out in 24 hours
-- is not, not that this happened, obviously heartbleed is different but, but,
-- well,
it happened with shell shock.
We ended up with like four or five patches.
Yeah, because there was like, the story is ridiculous, of course.
But it's one of those situations where by trying to rush stupid
mistakes got made instead of standing back and being all right,
what's actually going on here?
And part of the reality is Shellshock wasn't that big of a deal because you
needed such a bizarre combination of things to happen to exploit it that again,
if people would step back and say, ok, here's what's actually going on.
I don't think it would have been near as nuts.
I suspect the patching was more disruptive than any attacks. Like, globally.
Seriously. 100%. Yes. Absolutely.
You know, again, I don't have data to support that,
but based on what happened to the industry at that time
and the number of people who, you know, pulled all nighters and stuff,
definitely the, the cure was worse than the disease.
Absolutely.
Well, the way the cure was done,
the way it was released, right. That's the thing. It's like, here's this vaccine
-- except it's in a pill the size of a basketball. Good
-- luck.
And you have to swallow it all at once.
Oh, no, it's, no, it's not that kind of pill
-- anyway.
-- Wait, you can swallow pills now,
some of them.
But, I mean, so again, kind of coming back to
the news on Venus
and what's happening
and just kind of the way security exists.
I'm actually more excited if the news from Venus
is our understanding of how chemistry works is incorrect
because that would actually be quite useful.
-- It totally is,
-- you know, if there's ways to synthesize this chemical on earth in,
well, essentially Venusian conditions.
You know, we don't understand that yet.
Like if it's not life and it's an actual mechanical or whatever you want to call it,
chemical reaction is Venusian.
A word Venusian. Yes.
Anyways, and conversely, if there is life on Mars or on Mars, on Venus,
see that shows how old I am.
-- Right. It's always about life on Mars
-- we'll
take either.
And if there is life on Venus, that is also pretty damn cool.
It would actually be hilarious if it turns out there is life on Venus,
but not on Mars because we've been looking on Mars for so long and like, oh, look,
it was over here all along
anyway. Anyway.
So, ok,
I wanna,
I wanna tie this all up together when we look at security people and we
look at the way we're messaging things we often speak in a manner that doesn't
make it known that there's nuance in what we're doing or saying and,
and additionally, even if we do, it's going to be misunderstood just like this,
this Venus news is where
the reporters say one of the ways this gas could be created is life.
And the headline says life found on Venus.
I think part of the problem though is if
you try and make a properly qualified statement,
number one, it's going to be too long for a sound bite.
And number two people aren't going to understand it anyway.
So you have to make these declarative, simple statements.
Like for example, on Windows 10,
I will use the Built in Microsoft Defender stuff
because it probably won't make my system worse.
Whereas third party A V will almost certainly make my system worse.
And on my Macs, I just don't do A V.
And what's interesting is apparently Apple agrees
because Apple is doing that whole,
you know, code signing, code
checking hack
is right.
There was that whole thing a few months ago where they turned it on and all
of a sudden everybody's scripts take like an hour to run the first time they run.
And so, you know, Apple, I think, understands too that how do I put this nicely?
Number one, you've got defaults and people almost never change defaults.
And number two, then when they,
when they do start to change the defaults or install third party software,
is this going to make the experience significantly worse?
And the reality is for a V software, the answer is absolutely yes.
A V software always me
is up your system. And how often do people complain?
And I'm talking like people in corporations with
like expensive V about how this is like,
totally messed up systems.
So I think, well,
what I'm saying is I think we have to speak declarative and in some cases,
-- I don't want to say lie for the good, but
-- no, we don't lie out of the question.
Well, I don't want to say lie but, you know, we simplify things.
-- Let
-- me ask you a better question. Does
work.
-- Sometimes
-- the only the answer you can give is, I don't know because we don't,
there's data but the data is crap.
And I, I, I'm, I'm very skeptical anyone's done like a legitimate honest study of.
If A B even works at all.
I've seen people do demos where they test it and it like blocks a virus, demos
don't count.
Does it statistically make things better seatbelts
statistically make things better for everybody.
Yes, one or two people will
to a pond and die.
And that's very sad,
but the majority of people wearing their seatbelt won't
go flying out of their car in dots.
Now,
does it statistically make things better or worse? I don't know.
And you have to remember there's,
there's big picture here too because it's not just about stopping viruses.
It's about overall system performance about wasting time dealing with broken,
but there's many things to consider.
And again, this is where security kind of fails is we, we a lot of this data.
There's nobody looking into this and saying yes, this makes sense or no,
this doesn't.
-- And that is, I think a huge problem
-- even a simple
and I'm air quotes, big air quotes, a simple study about a V,
what is the failure rate of A V in the sense of not like it fails to detect something,
but in the sense of it,
like screws up the system and ends up costing you time and money to recover it.
We have no idea. None at all.
I know for a fact most companies don't track this kind of data. I mean,
you know, I've worked for companies where we did activities that were core and,
you know,
we both talked about measuring these activities and finding out what they cost
-- and we're very quickly told, no, don't do that.
-- I, I remember that where
we'll say a,
a company I used to work for.
No one knows who I remember. I said, like, how much does a security flaw cost us?
-- And they said, don't, don't look at it.
-- Let's use an example.
We can talk about the government, right? I, I've worked for
the provincial government once upon a time for six months.
And I, I know lots of people who work for the provincial government
and literally
like they do jobs where they're paid like 80 or
90 grand a year to do something where I'm like,
you know, like you can make that a fillable PDF.
And the best response was, yeah, that's what they did in BC.
Like the province next to us has that process like automated.
You have to do it or not. It's not a fillable PDF. You do it through a website, right?
You have to fill out this form on a website.
Whereas in Alberta, like you actually talk to a human being,
but we're paying an ungodly amount of money to
type your answer into a computer for you.
And, like, this kind of thing is totally common and of course,
you know, is the government ever going to measure that or, or deal with that?
No, of course not. I, my goodness, we can't do that. Right.
Doing these kind of studies is,
-- is actually quite time consuming and expensive and it's
-- hard,
it's really hard to do studies like this.
Well, yeah, to get to do it correctly,
you know, to make sure you don't have sample bias,
to make sure you have a big enough sample size and at the same time not to be like, ok,
well, do we need a sample size of 1 million?
Well, crap, we can't do this.
We are basically out of time and I guess
here is my closing thought on this matter of everything
is
one of our challenges
in the world of security
is
our messaging is often too nuanced
and our data
-- is rotten.
-- If we don't have data, let's let's stop pretending.
-- But
-- you know what I mean?
This is,
this makes for a very difficult position to be in as a security professional.
-- And
-- when we do have data, we ignore it.
Like a great example is our passwords, a good strategy. Well,
you know,
the website have I been pwned with 10
billion records would seem to indicate otherwise.
Yeah. Passwords suck. Everyone knows. Passwords suck.
-- You know, 10 billion failure scenario examples.
-- But it's hard to change.
So it's easier to pretend everything is fine and that is where we are at.
I guess the solution is we just pretend everything's fine. Like the dog in the fire.
-- No.
-- Look, this is how progress starts.
I mean,
think about medicine
200 years ago, they, they thought people's blood was poison and they would drain it.
And it's like now we look at that and think these people are idiots,
but they thought they were doing the best thing and
we have people who think they're doing the best thing.
But the, the answer to this is rather than saying, oh, I'm doing my best is to say,
let's figure this out
and that's what we need people to start doing more of is just saying,
let's figure this out.
And that's,
that's one of the more common and simpler types of things I think we should be doing is
what are we doing? And what is the actual effect of what we're doing?
Like, is it effective getting people to do that is essentially impossible.
It is not impossible. It is step one. We're still bleeding people to death
instead of saying, let's figure this out.
-- So
-- what you're saying is we just need better leeches.
Sure. Maybe.
I mean, we've got plenty of those.
We got a lot of weasels. Are those useful
anyway. So
anyway, all Right. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, everyone for listening.
You can go to opens sources, Security podcast.com. Head up the show, not, it's U
Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag do hit us up on social media. Kurt.
-- Have a fantastic rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
There's one thing I'm going to add here at the very end for anyone who made it
this far who's probably nobody because I always skip
the last like 10 seconds of a podcast.
But
we're gonna do, I take,
I
don't know, whatever it doesn't matter. Leave it at the end.
Maybe I could put it at the beginning. I don't know. We'll see what happens.
There was no episode 214.
And at first we were talking about, oh,
we'll make a joke about how the government censored us or something.
And I realized, uh,
we live in tumultuous times right now and I don't want to make this joke.
So the reason there's no episode 214 is because I can't count. And that's all like
no conspiracy.
Just I typed 215 into my system and there was no 214 and I made a mistake.
-- I'm,
-- I'm well, I'm fixing. It would have taken like three
or four.
No, I don't think so though.
Because of the way podcast networks work,
I think we would have ended up with episode 214 and episode 215.
Both being exactly the same published on their sites.
So I thought it's easier to do nothing.
And more importantly, the most important part of this,
I have changed my,
what do I have a process? Yeah.
Process sounds good.
I have changed my process to make sure I cannot make this mistake again,
which is the most important part of making mistakes is
doing something to make sure it never happens again.
-- So there you go.
-- Root cause failure analysis.
That's, that's why planes mostly stay in the air
when they're
supposed to. That's all, that's all. Thank you. Maybe I'll put it at the beginning.
We'll see
the.