Hello and welcome to episode 119 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
Oh, man, we haven't talked to each other in forever.
And I love how through the magic of podcasting
it appears we had a chat last week even though it's been like two weeks.
And I love how anytime we do this, we cut our last recording
and then the whole world lights on fire.
Oh Well,
it always reminds me of like
just all these things like the Middle East or Russia where it's like,
and then it got worse.
Like,
II I remember doing this reddit comment where the
history of Russia can literally be summarized in one sentence
and then it got worse,
you know,
and that, that's the thing with Ted, right? Like
it just like I'm dealing with a GDPR troll. We'll mention that later in the show
and, you know, it's just,
I'm not,
yeah, I don't know what to say. Like,
like this Google plus thing is like
just such a cluster
on so many levels,
you know.
Um or, you know, like, let's face it neither of us are ever going to work at Facebook.
So I'll say it, you know, my,
my favorite Reddit comment was talking about the Facebook data breach.
Well, why is it a data breach? Well, because they didn't pay for the data.
Right.
What, what, what's, what do you mean? They didn't pay for the data.
Facebook, one of Facebook's core business things is to sell
your data to people. Right.
Right.
That's kind of, isn't that a data breach?
Technically, when they give all your personal data away to somebody for money,
but I gave it to them.
Well, no, it's not because then they sold it and it's,
it's under contract. That's OK.
But you know, when somebody takes the data for free, oh, that's a breach. That's bad.
-- Right.
-- You know, it, well, that's the thing that gets me right.
Like, like all these companies that have exposed people's data, it's like,
except that company's core business model is selling that data,
you know, like, uh what was the one Equifax experience? All those guys
that had these data breaches.
Well, their, their core business model is selling that data to other people.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
And then once it's out to those third parties, it's not like you can control it.
Well, I actually, so it is a data breach from the,
from the, well, we should have relativistic data.
Uh That's, that's the answer.
But you think from the perspective of Facebook from their reference point.
It's a data breach because they didn't sell the data from our perspective. It's
pretty much the way everything else works with Facebook,
a
third party
data from Facebook.
Right.
And I didn't tell them they could have it. Oh, wait, that's, that's everybody.
And this is what I find so offensive about Google Plus.
Now in Fairness,
Google plus wasn't again technically a data breach because Google
claims that nobody really maybe sort of got affected,
but we should back this up and explain what the
heck is going on just because it is conceivable.
When, when future historians review our podcast, they'll be like what happened?
Well, more to the point which Google plus breach,
you know.
Anyway,
-- so, ok,
-- well, let's start start with explain what happened at Facebook,
let's say first.
Oh, well, so Facebook, well, again,
which data breach are we talking about the
-- most recent one with the like feature
-- thing?
The View
a
breach.
So, so Facebook had this feature called View
Oz.
-- It,
-- let me look at I could, for example, look at my profile as Kurt,
right? Well, so, so what happened was from my understanding is
they have a feature that I could for example, say what does my profile look like?
If, if Kurt is looking at it
and the way they accomplish that is they basically
built a URL that had like Kurt's a token
to like kind of log in as Kurt to load the page and then some people found out.
Well, hey, we can just reuse this token and do other stuff as Kurt. That's neat.
And it is neat.
Yeah.
Yeah. So, yeah.
And it turns out at first it was maybe 500 million now, it looks like only,
only air quotes, 30 million people were affected by this.
-- And
-- this is part of the beauty of it is. I just read 50
earlier today.
They have no
effing clue.
We
see
this.
Well, I'll talk about a bit this later, but in theory, these,
these blank is a service companies and Facebook is a blank.
You know, it's Facebook is a service, right? It's a, it's a online application
in theory,
they could have logs of everything and actually
be able to trace down their data breaches.
But in practice, well,
I mean,
they generally don't have logging as great as they should and
expensive. Well,
yeah. And more to the point. Why bother. Right.
Because you have a data breach, you move on.
Right. Because really what's ever happened from a data breach?
Has anybody ever had a massive fine yet?
Not yet? Maybe it'll happen.
So, here's what I love and then there's the counter argument. Um,
so moving along, Google plus had a sort of quasi breach
here. Let me just read this
very
polite
way.
Google says it discovered the bug was part of an effort called project Strobe,
which was launched to quote review
of third party developer access to Google account and
Android device data and our philosophy around apps,
data access unquote according to Ben Smith, blah, blah, blah blah blah.
So the idea was basically is that, you know,
like when you're in Google Drive and you want to say edit a PDF, well,
Google Drive doesn't do that.
So you can
go to this like one of these online application providers that provides PDF editing
and it's like I need access to your entire Google Drive to like,
edit your PDF and you're like you click, ok,
which is a terrible thing to do and it should be sandboxed.
But I digress.
Um, you know, it's like whenever like you,
you log into something from Twitter or Facebook and it's like,
I will need access to all your Twitter history and the ability to
post as you on Twitter so that you can log into this.
And it's like, nope, not doing that.
Actually, I had an app. I found the other day that wanted
the ability to post as me on Facebook.
And then it said, like, we promise never to do this.
We need this law that,
you know, is, it's a terribly written law, but we promise not to enforce it.
No, that's not how that works.
So
anyways, I, I think so, Google Plus had this thing and
here's
the biggest problem around this is that
they covered it up.
Yeah. Right. Exactly.
Right. They, they found some problems and then they covered it up. So
that to me is, is a cardinal sin like lying.
Like, you know, I'm teaching my kids, like, if you break something, tell me,
you know, but if you lie about it, I'll be super annoyed.
And they found this what in May?
And we're talking in October and I think they, they,
they acknowledged it in September.
Right.
-- Yeah.
-- And see what I find really offensive is Google. Plus we were all opted in.
Remember
when it just showed up one day?
II, I wanted to be part of Google Plus because I thought, oh, this sounds neat.
And then I looked at it and I'm like, man, this sucks.
But that was,
that was way back in the day,
man. That was a long time ago. But yeah, Google Plus never went anywhere.
Well, you know,
and then they had that real name policy debacle where they
exposed a bunch of people's real names where they probably,
you know, wanted some privacy.
Um But
so anyway, so Google Cardinal and number one, the cover up, right? Because,
you know, you can do bad things.
But when you start doing bad things and lying about it,
see, now, I'm forced to wonder, what else have they covered up
and not got caught doing right? Because we know for sure they tried to lie to us once
every company does that
I'm, I'm gonna, I'm not gonna pull them too
in in high esteem in that respect.
Well, but it, but the problem is and then it got worse. So for example, here I love,
I love so one great part of this,
we made Google plus with privacy in mind and therefore keep
these this A P I's log data for only two weeks.
This means we cannot confirm which users were impacted by this book.
Thanks.
So, you know, I love that as part of their statement. You know,
they basically say blah blah blah blah blah.
Our privacy and data protection office reviewed this issue,
looked at the type of data involved
whether we could accurately identify the users
to inform whether there was any evidence of
misuse and whether there was any actions a developer or user could take in response,
none of these thresholds were met in this instance.
Now, number one, we don't know what the thresholds are,
right?
And we don't know what this means like,
like because they also just said that we only have two weeks of log data.
So we don't know if anybody got popped.
So they're literally are they literally saying, well,
we don't have the log data.
And so we don't really know if anybody got affected by
this and there's nothing really they can do about it.
So, you know, we feel like we don't need to tell them
because that's what I'm reading.
Oh man, I've been in conversations just like this,
I'm sensitive to this problem. But I feel like
at the end of the day, you probably need to just say it happened,
right?
-- You
-- know, because we're going through this with the CV E for cloud services, right?
And
we, you know,
we we finally figured out why we're having so many arguments on
these calls because we actually haven't defined what is a vulnerable.
So in the classic CV, for software case, we have a trust boundary is violated
as the gold standard for, you know,
whether or not this is a vulnerability or exposure.
But in a cloud context,
you know, this is a bit more difficult.
So a great example is one of the major vendors is like, well,
we do keep a ton of logs and in a lot
of cases with these sort of cloud breach type things,
you know, we'll have a researcher come to us and say, hey,
I found this like wiggly little problem
um looks like a security flaw, you know, the vendor confirms it and says, yeah, oh,
wow, thanks, you know,
and they fix it
and then they go through their logs and telemetry
and in some cases can conclusively say 100%
this was never exploited or used,
right? Just full stop,
right?
So in that case, you know,
was there a vulnerability?
Well, there sort of was in the,
in the physics sense of like a vulnerability was observed,
you know, because that's the thing with software, right?
You have a vulnerability and you don't know if it was exploited or not because,
you know,
people run software on premises and half of
them forget that they even have it installed,
let alone have proper logging or firewalls or whatever.
So, you know, but with a service in some cases, you can
very
confidently say
we can prove the negative. Nothing bad happened. End of story. Right. We're good.
Right. Right.
And so in a case like that,
well, does this need to be treated as a vulnerability?
Now, in the case of Google, I would say yes,
it needs to be treated as a
vulnerability because there's so much uncertainty wrapped,
you know, wrapped around it.
There's two weeks of logs. So
like you said, this was floating around for several months.
No, it's, it's been around since like 2015.
They learned of it in May.
Oh yeah. No, no, no, I mean, yeah, sorry.
I mean, yeah,
the flaw has been present for years and but Google's only been aware of it, you know,
in that again, in that physics sense, you know, the observation
of the thing makes it
exist in a way, right? Because
all security flaws exist
while they exist.
But you know, if nobody knows about that security flaw, does it exist?
Well, for all intent and purposes? No,
you know,
there's, well, no, there's been, for example, Linux,
there's been Linux kernel flaws that were fixed and
only later found out to be security problems,
you know,
that happens a lot. Yeah.
Yeah.
So in a service, you know,
this gets a little messy because sometimes we can
say with certainty that this was not exploited or
uh this feature was not enabled for more than a few people or whatever.
But like I said, in this case,
I think there's enough uncertainty wrapped around this
Google thing that they should have come clean,
but they didn't want to.
Because where was that lovely quote?
Here we go.
According to the Wall Street Journal,
it was fear of regulation that led Google to not disclose it.
Google exposed the private data of hundreds of
thousands of users of Google plus social network.
Now in fairness,
this would have exposed everybody's data,
whoever tied in an application to Google Plus,
right? And uh
and then opted not to disclose the issue this past spring
in part because of fears that doing so would draw regulatory scrutiny
and cause reputational damage according to people briefed on the
incident and documents reviewed by the Wall Street Journal.
Yeah, this is way better. Yeah.
Well, this is, this is the problem I have with cover ups. They don't work
right by and large cover ups
-- get leaked
-- seriously.
It's I tell my kids this like you nothing is a lie forever, right?
You might get away with it for a little while.
But like the the truth comes out sooner or later and
I know, that sounds like very high and mighty ish.
-- But I mean, for real
-- well, especially when you document it and send emails around,
right? I mean, if you're going to do a conspiracy in a cover up,
-- don't write memos about it.
-- It's true.
Do it, right, guys. Come on,
you have, you know,
you have physical conversations with your lawyers in the steam room,
you know, to make sure nobody's recording it.
You don't send out
when you start sending out memos saying
we're afraid of the legal consequences of doing the right thing here.
Yeah.
Yeah,
you lost, you know, it's like the diesel emissions, stuff like.
Yeah.
Uh huh.
Yeah. Good. You know. Nice paper trail. So,
this is what gets me, I mean, they documented this. They, I'm,
I'm surprised it took this long to come out.
Um, but less than six months. That's not bad.
I, I guess, I don't know how they got it.
It, it wouldn't shock me if there's more than this even that they've,
they've hidden away.
Well, see, that's the problem. They've, we now
know for sure that they've tried to lie to us once.
Right.
-- We have proof.
-- I'd be shocked if this is the first
that we found out Google lied to us.
I'm pretty
sure there's others. We just don't care.
But in past we could have pretended like they weren't lying to
us because we didn't have proof that they have lied to us.
Yeah. There's probably some of that,
you know, and that's what I keep trying to explain to my Children is that
if you lie
more than a few times people will think you're a liar
-- because
-- that is the definition of being a liar.
Yeah. Exactly.
And that is, you know, that's the, with these corporations and organizations,
especially with these data breaches.
Yes. You know, the majority of them I don't trust at all anymore.
So going back to this, I mean,
on the one hand, I suspect it wasn't widely exploited. I suspect that actually
all things considered probably not that bad.
The problem is how Google handled it.
Yes.
Now, now let me ask this,
should we still trust Google and Facebook to be things like our oath
providers for our logins?
You pose this question like we actually have a choice.
You can pretend you have a choice.
I mean, most websites have their own user name and login form, right?
So
I need email, I need calendaring, I need documents.
What are my choices? Google Microsoft. No, I'm serious. Like, what are my choices?
I think Amazon technically has some solutions wrapped around this,
but it's not great
and there's a bunch of third party solutions and quite frankly
getting all my data properly out of Google and into one of these other things,
it would be really hard.
Doesn't sound like a lot of fun
and more to the point are they going to do a better job than Google. Probably not.
Nope, definitely not. Are they going to lie to me about data breaches?
Probably.
And, and that's just the reality of it, you know,
-- are my utility companies jerks now and going to try and, like,
-- now
they've always been jerks.
Yeah, exactly.
I just had the experience of, you know, getting a quote for a water heater and the guy,
like, it'll be, like, 75 bucks a month and I'm like,
what do you, what, like, what, what does that number mean? Right.
Like, don't, I just pay for it and he's like, no, no, no, you can rent it from us.
And I'm like,
no, no, because, like, I get renting certain things makes sense.
Like a car if I'm traveling or something. But,
ok, so I rent this hot water heater from this company.
Can I get a bigger one for the weekend? I'm having a bunch of people over. Well, no,
you know, there you're guaranteeing you'll fix it with some sl a Sure.
I believe that. Uh huh. Yeah. Sure.
Um,
but that's,
that's the thing, do we,
you know, with Facebook?
I have a Facebook profile because I, you know,
people use Facebook and if I want to talk to them and communicate with them,
I don't really have a choice.
I can be that guy who doesn't use Facebook and then I don't learn about things,
family events and whatnot.
That is true. You know, same thing for linkedin.
Do I want to have a massive linkedin profile?
-- Not especially do I need to because I'm a, you know, it worker. Yeah.
-- Oh,
man, I,
I just got an email from linkedin today
that said I can add my phone number to
linkedin and then router recruiters can call me directly.
That sounds fantastic.
Yeah, let me, how fast can I nope out of this.
That's the
last
-- I have enough problem with that.
-- Well, and that's a great example. Remember,
remember when Facebook was like, 02 fa put your phone number and I'm like,
I'm going to regret this, but I did it anyways
and now they use my phone number for tracking.
I don't think I ever did that.
They, they know so much about you already and, and I guess this is,
this is one of the things I,
-- but
-- again, it's kind of that they lied about it, you know.
Well,
you're an idiot if you believe them. I'm sorry.
Well, that's what I mean. So fundamentally with Facebook,
are they going to sell my data or accidentally give it away to people?
Yeah, that's kind of,
that's
what they do.
Well,
that's like I saw another news story where someone was saying
there's voter information available on the dark web for the,
the upcoming election in the United States
and, and, but here's the best part is, people are like, you know,
you can get this for free if you just
like the state and, and some, there's some group
that,
that has this data and most of them give it away if
you ask for it and some of them charge a nominal fee.
So it's like
whoever is selling this on the dark web,
probably like legally obtained the data and then slapped a
huge price tag on it and put it out there.
I love it. It's just like what?
-- Yeah. Anyway,
-- I don't know the whole thing.
I, I think this,
how do I put this nicely?
I think the whole notion of data breach is flawed in the sense of
how can you have a data breach when the company's whole raison
D
Etre is to sell your personal data to third parties and they do so
well. No, no, we didn't have a data breach. Facebook had a data breach, right?
That's what I'm saying is how can we call what Facebook
did a data breach when fundamentally their whole purpose in being
is to sell your personal data,
right? And it's basically the same thing with Google plus, right? Where, where?
Yeah, like Google done made a mistake, but let's face it there.
They are almost certainly
sharing and selling this data already.
Right.
-- Well, that's their business. Right.
-- Exactly. And, and we, we give it to them.
So I
guess in summary, there was no data breach as far as we're concerned.
It's just business as usual.
Yeah, you gotta love it man.
Well, and then, you know,
the whole GDPR thing comes in and this is what frustrates me with GDPR.
The,
I, I like the intent of GDPR but
I would say it's a,
it's not a well written law because I'm
currently dealing with the GDPR troll effectively.
So uh
the distributed weakness filing thing, you know, CV, stuff,
uh I need you to
MC WF, needs you to accept the CV terms of use so I can use your data, right?
That's just a standard part of how it works, you know,
it seems fair.
So I people fill out the form, the form is public, the form is labeled as public
they put in, you know, the CV details, their email address, I email them
saying, you know, here's the CV terms of use. I need you to type in I accept and reply
and this artifact, this copy of this email will go into this G
repo at this URL,
right?
You know, it's, it's informed, it's as informed consent as I can get,
you can't accidentally miss click.
I've even had people type I accept like they deleted
the subject line and put I accept and I'm like,
no, you need to put it in the body like the email says
um
and then one guy did that like three times and then he typed, I accept this blah, blah,
blah and I'm like uh close enough, you know.
Uh but anyway, so this guy
submitted, used his email address,
submitted this and then now a year or two later is gone.
He emailed me and saying I want you to remove my email address.
My response was I'm sorry.
But no, and he's like under GDPR, I'm invoking my right to forget.
And I'm like, yep, still sorry. No, because
I think for a valid business purpose, I need this email address
and for technical reasons, I can't actually remove it,
remove it because it's in git,
right? Like without rewriting git history and like rolling it back and
doing all sorts of funky things, you can't actually get rid of your data.
It's like, well, you can just like hide it and that's good enough for me.
And I'm like, well, still sorry. No, because
you gave me really like informed consent
and you know, GDP R's right to forget is not absolute right.
You can't go to your local tax authority and be like,
uh I know I owe you money but I need you to forget all my personal data
or you know,
you go to the bank and you're like that million dollar loan I have with you.
Yeah, I want all my personal data redacted from that loan,
right? The bank's gonna be not, they're not going to do that. So
there are for legal and technical business and business reasons that you know,
the right to forget is not absolute.
So
he then went and complained to
github,
which, and github, I suspect their sort of GDPR plan,
like many companies was where possible, just whatever, uh, pass it on and, you know,
if you don't play nice, we'll boot you.
Right. Which is fair. Right. As a company, I don't want to deal with these jerks,
you know,
totally.
And so that's where we are now, we'll see what github
says.
But, um, I'm just realizing now,
so what constitutes personally identifiable information under GDPR?
Well, email address is for sure. But you know what about URL S? Right?
Uh I used to have my personal blog at kirk.cried.org, which obviously is my name,
you know,
uh your name is pi I your phone number, your address, uh national ID numbers,
things like that.
But I'm thinking of all the software out there, for example, with copyright notices
or your email address is in there somewhere because, you know, you're one of the,
one of the authors
or URL to your blog or something or where you posted about it or
you put something into a
github issue
or, you know, so it's not even in the source code but maybe it's in a github
issue.
And I'm realizing this is a problem for, you know, not just github, right?
But for all these other places that sort of allow essentially an, I
don't want to say anonymous, but, you know,
pseudo anonymous or anonymous data upload of just random stuff.
And yeah, I'm curious to see how it turns out. Right.
I've, I've left the ball in Github's
Court because quite frankly, they need to decide,
are they going to do this overly broad interpretation of GDPR,
you know, to sort of just, we don't want to deal with it either.
You,
either you do what this person says or we boot
you because we don't want to deal with this complaint,
you know,
or do they start doing something a bit more intelligent and selective and you know,
we'll see.
So if the DWF disappears from github, well, now, you know why?
Uh
-- but
-- like I said, I'm going to put my money on TWF disappearing
if I was,
if I was going to be.
Well, and the other thing too is this,
this email address was in there for a couple of years,
right? So the email address was also given pre GDPR.
That doesn't matter though. That's irrelevant.
No, it doesn't matter. But I just from the point of you had two years to ask for this.
Now, only finally, are you asking for it,
man? I,
I understand this.
I, I feel like it weakens the case.
It, it kind of, but the point is, I mean, so the intent of GDPR is to basically avoid,
we don't even know if this guy is in Europe.
I don't know. That's complicated too. That doesn't always matter
like I was just in Europe, right? So obviously that affects now, now I fall under
the rules of GDPR while I'm there.
It's so, anyway, anyway, I guess here's the thing though,
the, the intent of GDPR is to basically avoid the,
the disaster that like Google Plus and Facebook have created
and,
and like, obviously Google solved the Google Plus problem by killing it.
Well, the problem though is, is even if you have the right to be forgotten,
you can't
realistically
to, to use these services like Facebook and Google Plus, fundamentally,
you ha you are forced to give up personally
identifiable information,
right? And in some cases, they have real name policies now where they
want ID or a great example being, you know, Facebook to sign up for Facebook.
Now you have to give them a working phone number.
Well, ok. No, no, but here's the thing,
the,
there's the intent of GDPR,
there's always the intent of the law and the letter of the law and the
intent of GDPR is to empower users to have some control over their personal data,
which let's face it.
We've completely lost control. Right. Full stop.
I don't think anyone's going to disagree with that.
GDPR wants to give some of it back, but it's, it's not well written, it's very broad
and
we,
we need to refine it over the next couple of
years and here's one of the issues you run into.
Well,
actually it's much worse than that because
here's a trick question who enforces GDPR?
Oh, my goodness. The answer to that is like a seven hour podcast.
My understanding is that it's any
one
of the data
regulatory agencies
-- in any of the countries that fall under GDPR. So for example, you
-- can,
all of the countries can have different rules and regulations around them.
So you could end up under the in Poland or you
could end up in the Czech Republic or the German.
You know,
we all have very different data regulatory systems and
cultures and enforcement
and capabilities even, you know,
one guy was pointing out that one of these countries had something
like 17 people working at the agency and that was it,
that'll scale.
But so, so anyway, here's, here's kind of my point,
we know GDPR is broken and I'm certain Europe knows GDPR is
broken and there's things like trolls abusing it like in the,
in the kind of the context you're seeing
that's obviously not the intent of the law, but it's the letter of the law.
And so how we deal with that really becomes kind of the, the question for the future.
And of course,
companies don't want to deal with it because like their goal is to make you go away.
And if look, if you're moving your email address, makes, makes them go away.
Great, do that, right. Get rid of them, don't care.
And, and you have a different incentive than github does.
And, and so I don't know how it's going to work out,
but I know it's definitely not the first or last instance,
we're going to see something like this and it's
going to take years unfortunately for this to shake up
until we know what happens.
Yeah, because I had some questions around, you know, enforcement of this.
My first question, this person requesting this takedown,
all I have is the email address.
I, I don't know where this person is. Are they in Europe?
And then I was actually asking some people, you know, at
what point do I become a subject of GDPR?
So for example,
if I emigrate to Germany and become a permanent resident or whatever,
the equivalent of that in Germany is clearly I fall under GDPR, right?
Uh What if I'm there on a student visa?
I probably fall under GDPR.
Well
as a Canadian, I don't need a tourist visa to go to Germany.
So what if I'm a tourist in Germany?
Am, am I is my data now subject to GDPR?
Yeah. Yeah, it is
that that's clearly defined, they call it. Uh what is it European persons?
I think it means a European person is just a human in Europe
or a European somewhere else.
It's quite, it's, it's pretty broad and it can affect nearly everyone.
So then when I receive a GDPR request for the sake of argument,
how do I have you prove that you're a European person
without ironically giving up a whole bunch of personal data,
I don't know if that's defined in the law. We, because
I, I mean, for example, I deal with some of this at elastic is we, we don't care,
we've just taken the attitude, we're not going to ask you to prove anything.
If, if you make a request, we're going to,
to at least listen to you and deal with it as best as we can.
We don't care where you live.
-- And
-- to be honest, I think that's actually the correct way to do it
right? To be generally, I'm not
against the right to forget,
but it does seem like it was
not well written and that trolls can definitely use it to cause a lot of problems.
And I've actually thought about this.
You know, I have um my email address is in a huge
number of email archives.
Like look at me, we have a freaking podcast, right?
There's so much information about it.
So for example, let's say I ask
all the emailing list archives to remove my personal information,
right?
Because I posted the things like bug track and full disclosure. It's in
millions of places.
Oh, seriously, man, we have, I'm sure thousands of messages in,
in like what is the mark.info mailing list archives sites?
I'm, I'm in there
probably in the thousands of times for my emails to
goodness knows how many lists over the last what like 30 years.
And that doesn't even count like my fake names. Right.
Yeah. Well, and for example, you and I were both assigning CV S.
Well, if you take away that
information, it kind of,
you know,
those archives really become a bit broken in that a fundamental
piece of an email archive is who sent that email.
Uh
Sure. And, and of course, in the context of, of you and me, like we don't care.
But yeah, I, I think the trolls are trolls ruin everything, right?
That's kind of the, the moral of the story and, and I'm sure there's some,
some European privacy people shouting at their computer right now over us,
which is fine. I don't mind.
Uh Right. Anyway,
I don't know, man, I,
this is one of those things that it's going to shake itself out in time and
I, I guess the one thing that always fills me with, with comfort is
even badly written laws usually get fixed,
right? And we know GDPR is badly written and it's going to get fixed.
All right.
Anyway,
we should probably call this one and we've
rambled on long enough about Facebook and Google.
So I guess in summary, uh yeah, there you did not have a data breach.
Facebook and Google had data breaches.
Your data is still being sold just like it was before.
No, that's interesting. Let's rent data.
Well, you know,
we promised to get rid of it at the end of the week when we are done renting it.
Oh, I'm Sure. Yeah. Yeah, I haven't copied it off to a spreadsheet that
never
happen.
And I'm storing in a Google Drive.
Oh, man. All right, sweet. Any last thoughts, Kurt,
you know, II,
I don't know anymore.
It's too late to opt out of these things and it's
not like you can opt out of your credit score.
So
I guess go live in the woods
-- that
-- even, that won't help. Look, we, we've lost control of our data.
GDPR wants to help get it back.
I hope they do, but I'm not totally convinced they will.
I mean, that's the reality of it.
So anyway.
All right, man. Thank you. Thank you very much for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes.
You can use the P
and Os S podcast hashtag on social media to get our attention
-- and Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your
-- day. Thanks. You
too.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.