Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with Josh Brushes and myself.
Kurt Siefried.
Uh, you skipped a lot of whatever. It's December 2nd. Happy December 2nd. Kurt.
-- Well, no, it's not December 2nd. It's door number two, door
-- number two, whatever.
It's December 2nd.
That's the point of the advent calendar. Door.
Number two is opened on the second of December. It's the second of December.
It has not been 17 seconds since the last episode
for you and us for everybody else. Time dilation occurred
anyway.
So this time we're talking about even though we have numbers, do they matter?
-- What
-- kind of numbers do we have?
Like, I have plenty of numbers,
70% of organizations say that they believe
their security risk increased significantly in 2017.
-- So
-- what we have are statistics about the security industry.
Well, we have statistics that were gathered
probably not very well.
And do they even matter?
Like
here's a good 1 90% of hackers cover their tracks by using
Du
du du encryption.
OK. So
I will put a link to this particular story in the show notes.
And oh, for, for those of you who haven't caught on yet.
Every one of these is going to be its own episode.
I'm not trying to do anything clever because I've listened to
weird special Christmasy type Advent Calendar podcast before
and when they don't put the episode number in it,
it's very difficult to put them in the correct
order if you accidentally get them out of order,
which I did.
So that is why I'm doing it this way anyway, I'll put it in the shorts.
But OK, continue. Sorry. Thank you.
Well, just, you know, it's just like these numbers are even with some context.
OK, there's a lot of numbers without context, they are useless.
And then there's like a whole bunch of numbers with context that are still
not
useful or actionable.
They aren't.
I agree like, well,
and some of them are amusing because it's like I would have guessed higher,
but like 75% of organizations infected with ransomware
were running up to date Endpoint protection,
which kind of says that most of that endpoint protection
doesn't sound all that useful.
I mean, but that, that, that statistic in itself has, I mean,
that's correlation is not causation.
-- Exactly.
-- Well, yeah. Well,
yeah, let's ignore correlation causation. Let's just ignore that.
Let's just ignore that because II I got nothing here
but like
91% of cyber attacks begin with a spear phishing email.
-- Well, yeah, because it works.
-- So I've been thinking about this story actually.
Because I read it and I had a,
we'll say less than positive reaction initially and then I've
done a lot of thinking about it and I think,
you know what the biggest problem is,
the vast majority of these numbers come from companies,
marketing departments like this is an independent research.
Well, you know, there's selection bias and then there's, yeah,
then there's marketing departments.
-- That's a good quote.
-- Yeah.
No, I think that pretty much sums up this episode.
Are we the marketing departments or are we the selection bias?
Uh, I
-- feel like I'm selection bias.
-- I'm gonna go with incompetent marketing department.
Yeah.
Anyway,
so I guess the, the, the,
-- I don't know what the takeaway here is.
-- Well, ok.
No,
I do think there's a takeaway and I think there's two really
important things we can take away from this data is number one,
we need to find good,
reasonable,
proper independent data and it might exist and I just don't know where it is.
It's obviously not in this story.
-- I'm
-- going to interrupt you and say the first problem is
we need to figure out what we need to measure.
I mean, that's the second part of what I was going to say it. So,
yeah,
it is difficult sometimes to understand what data means and sometimes it doesn't
mean what we think it means and sometimes it doesn't mean anything.
And this is where not focusing on marketing driven data is hugely important.
But as an industry, I think in security
we don't even know how to tell them apart because I don't
think we rarely see truly independent research data on what we do.
Uh, there's the eff and,
uh, that's about it.
I mean, there's some universities doing some work like this but,
and even what they're doing,
I'm not overly familiar with it and I don't even know where to go find it,
which I think is part of the problem.
Well, I mean, the classic answer would be you go to Gartner, buy some data.
They are
because, you know, the magic quadrant.
I'm not.
Anyway,
I
think that's the end of this episode right there is,
got a magic quadrant, I guess. I guess
we'll see, we'll see what the magic quadrant says on December 3rd. Right.
Unclear.