Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh
Reser.
All right. Uh No one knows this because again, the pre roll is secret.
But um we have a guest today uh and we,
we spent in a surprising amount of time talking about microphones,
which is always amusing to me.
But anyway,
so
today we're joined by Dustin Childs who is a communications manager for ZD.
I and their chief
paler
and I'm really excited to have Justin here because Kurt sent
me a story about some research ZD I just talked about
and the first thing I said was, well,
why don't we try to find someone competent to talk to us
about this instead of us just kind of making crap up?
And so Dustin is here. Thank you so much, Dustin. We're super excited.
-- Uh
-- Well, thanks for having me.
I'm happy to be here and, and for those wondering, I'm unsure SM seven B,
which is also the same mic that he used to record.
Thriller, which is I think that was the deciding factor when I bought the mic.
That, that's epic. That is amazing.
I didn't know that.
Wow, that's even cooler now.
No, I'm not. We are not doing this. Ok. So
this is a security podcast. Why don't you?
Oh, my goodness. Who are you? What is ZD? I? And why are you here?
Let's just start with the simple ones.
So ZD, I is a zero day initiative and we are the world's largest vendor
agnostic bug body program.
And that means we buy bugs from researchers
around the world in various types of products.
So whether it be Microsoft or Adobe or Apple or Google or whatever,
including open source products too,
we do buy open source bugs and so we buy a
whole lot of them as we are the world's largest one.
We've disclosed more than 10,000 vulnerabilities in
the lifetime of our program since 2005.
And over the last few years, we've noticed kind of a disturbing trend which is a
decrease in quality of security updates and a decrease in the
clarity of communications around those updates.
So that's what we went to uh Black Hat to talk about and offered a
lot of examples and uh also had a few incentives that we hope to use
to get vendors to get it right the first time.
And a few guides for enterprises to at least understand
how poor patch quality is really affecting their risk assessment.
OK.
That's a lot to unpack
one quick question and I don't want you to fully answer it right
now but is closed source doing a worse job than open source.
Are they both degrading?
I, I would say they're both degrading
now with closed source.
It's a little bit easier for us to track just
because we buy more close source bugs than we do.
Open source.
Open source is something we're definitely trying to
expand in over the last couple of years.
So we just have a smaller data set there.
But it is a problem we see across the board and including open source. OK?
I think we just put the cart before the horse, which is
totally normal.
So Dustin explain to us the research that was
presented because I think once we understand that context,
the question, Kurt just asked will probably make a lot more sense.
OK.
So what we presented was we just looked at uh first we,
we kind of described the the quality of the
communications on the problem uh about communicating around patches and
uh enterprises have to look at these communications to judge risk
and patches come out. I mean, there was just a patch for Google Chrome yesterday
right now,
enterprises are judging risk because rolling out patches cost money to them.
Uh So how fast do they need to roll out this new patch? Is it something they need to
engage emergency resources for what the standard procedures do?
Uh What, what else do they need to engage?
Because a lot of vendors don't understand that defenses go way beyond just patches.
I mean, patches are just one part of an overall defense.
So if you're getting bad patch information,
you might not be using your defenses appropriately.
So that's the first part of our program.
Uh The second part was looking at uh problems in the patches themselves.
So the first ones we described were placebo patches,
which is patches that actually do nothing.
-- Either they have no C code changes at all or they have no effective code changes,
-- no co
changes at all.
That's correct.
-- So the binaries have the same hash or
-- yes,
exactly, same,
-- same hash that they released as an update.
-- Hold on, hold on, hold on.
I've never heard of this before.
So you're saying vendors release,
we'll put security patches and making air quotes which no one can see but us.
So vendors create security patches. They release an advisory
and there's literally nothing different in the binary.
-- There's literally nothing different
-- than
like,
did they just mess up and ship the same thing or
-- that's our assumption? Did they at
-- least try to lie convincingly about it?
Uh
Well, the advisory looks nice, I suppose. I don't know.
Uh I don't want to put any intent behind any vendors,
but we've seen it with multiple vendors.
It's happened multiple times
with multiple vendors. Thankfully, it is somewhat rare,
but yeah, we do see it uh where uh they ship absolutely no code changes whatsoever.
-- I just, I don't know what to say to that. We assume
-- it's just a mistake.
We assume it's really bad. Q A that somebody
just checked a box that said, I checked it and they didn't really, but it, it,
it happens.
What's more common is they ship fix, they do make code changes
but it doesn't actually fix the reported bug.
So the bug is still reachable and exploitable
to thread actors.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I know you've experienced this. Yeah,
me and Josh have far too many stories about that.
That's what we're here to talk about today, right?
Is literally that exact data point because
I read the story about what ZD I reported and I thought,
I mean, Kurt and I have seen that we've been part of broken patches where it's,
it's not on purpose.
It's just,
it's not uncommon that you send a developer
reproducer and they fix that one particular corner
case and there's 20 others next to it that were ignored or not noticed or whatever.
-- And there's a million reasons for that,
-- right?
-- Well,
-- or
even simpler, like we had a,
a customer report 600 cross site scripting vulnerabilities in a product.
And
the des are like, oh, it's this one class
and they fix the one class and they all went away. But
I mean,
well, in the reverse of that anyway. OK.
OK. So, so Dustin here's where I, I value your input and, and this is where
our conversation without, you would have started going off the rails is
why do we think this is happening?
Do you have any data to back up the
pattern you're seeing of more vendors doing this more often
today than they were
at some point in the past?
-- Uh
-- Well,
there are a few reasons that we look at and that we kind of think why this is happening.
Um
The first is just a shift from sustained engineering towards development.
Once a product is released, no one wants to care and feed for it anymore.
Like everybody wants the puppy, nobody wants to take care of the puppy.
And that's kind of the way I look at it
so that the resources just aren't there for a lot of organizations,
especially smaller organizations
that they're just not set up for sustained engineering,
they're not set up for support.
They don't have a robust response process
to be able to deal with bugs. And we see this especially when they try to
like set up a bug bounty program and just aren't ready to receive the amount of bugs.
Researchers have a lot of different motivations, but it turns out cash is a big one.
Weird. I know,
but they're just not ready to receive the bugs.
So they start getting these bugs and they just can't handle them.
Uh, and they,
they don't fix them properly.
Another big thing that we've seen is just the
shift away from Q A and testing organizations,
people aren't really investing in testers anymore.
And, and I don't know if it started with Microsoft and Sasha Nadala.
When he came in, he eliminated a lot of the test positions. A lot of the Q A positions.
He used to be a holy trinity at Microsoft DEV test PM.
And he just essentially took test out of the
equation and said DEV can do all the testing.
Why do we need a separate org for this? And a lot of people agreed with him and, and
moved away from having a separate test organization.
We're seeing a skills gap now and whether that's a cause or the effect of the
skills gap that having a that person who
really understands the security issue at hand,
you talked about like, oh, it's just one class.
Let me take care of that.
That's kind of a gap in understanding the security problem.
So not only do you need someone who can test the
uh the product that you have,
but they need to understand the security problem that was reported,
those people are fewer and fewer these days.
Uh and they tend to be more and more expensive.
So businesses are shying away from them.
They're putting more on the developers themselves to handle the testing.
And it turns out maybe that automation, maybe that reduction
uh in personnel is not working the way they wanted it to.
So just one quick comment, I
in line with your skills gap comment.
One thing I've noticed is I almost want to call it a culture gap.
So we're all old enough that we've managed production systems and
been called at three in the morning to fix them.
And what I'm noticing is the majority of devs
in the modern world have not like they go to school and they go into a Dev position
and I've, I've literally spoken with Devs whose response to this is, oh,
if it breaks somebody, we'll complain and we'll fix it.
And I'm like, well, why don't we
make it?
So it doesn't break and have like end to
end testing and have like telemetry in the code.
And they're like,
but that would take work and I'm like, yes, yes, it absolutely would take work.
But then the system won't just fail randomly. And they're like,
but it almost never fails. And I'm like,
oh, well, you're not wrong because the, yeah, like,
you know, it's like I use cloud fla and when cloud floor goes down,
I go and I read a book because what else am I gonna do?
What
are you needing?
You know, like all these people are like, oh,
we have a plan to shift off cloud fflur in five minutes and blah, blah, blah.
And I'm like,
it happens maybe once a year for 30 minutes. I can live with it.
You know, we're not Amazon
and um
and I can't help but think that
the skills gap is the symptom that, but that the real thing is this culture gap of,
like,
I, I don't want to call them kids,
but basically everybody under 30 has grown up with networks that just work,
like getting on the internet is easy.
Yeah, I mean, I started my career in the late nineties in the Air Force and, and just
that culture of response,
that culture of things are going to break at two o'clock in the morning,
they never break at, you know, one o'clock in the afternoon,
they only break on five at five pm on Fridays and like in the middle of the night,
that's the only time things break.
Yeah,
you get that response mentality and you understand the
investment upfront is gonna save you in the end.
You know, that investment in testing and design and architecting and,
and yeah, that's expensive and yeah, that's the boring part.
And yeah, we just want to put it on production and see it run.
But
trust me, if you know, if, if five hours of test in the middle of the day will,
will save me a 30 minute phone call in the middle of the night,
I'm willing to make that investment.
And I think a lot of people right now,
yeah, I am but a lot of other people I don't see that return on investment.
They don't see,
they don't see. Well, that's five hours for 30 minutes.
Why should I spend the five hours here?
Well,
and I think on the flip side too is we grew up
in an era where like building and deploying software was incredibly expensive.
Like there was not
the level of automation for anything basically,
like having a make file was considered the gold standard
straight up. Right.
And um
and I, and I can't help but think in some ways they're not entirely wrong because
my dads can push out an emergency patch in like 2030 minutes.
Like they basically just do some stuff in github,
hit a button and, and wait five minutes. Well, it's about seven minutes. I think
so. Yeah, deployment is much faster these days than what it was.
I want to relis
a little bit back to the topic. So we, we just mentioned deployment
versus product. Now, is your data focused on
all bugs because obviously a bug bony can cover
a service, it can cover a product, it whatever, right? It doesn't matter.
So,
is your data focused on products like that are
deployed specifically or does it also encompass services?
We don't typically buy bugs and services. So it's really focusing on products.
Most of our data is based on the bugs that we're purchasing.
And again, we purchased a whole lot, we, we'll purchase about 1700 this year,
but it's also based on third party reports as
well because we're not the only one seeing this
Google project zero.
Is reporting this, there are other research teams that are reporting this.
Obviously you've seen busted patches.
So, uh,
fi
busted patches. You,
-- it, yeah, same here.
-- Like shell shock. Anybody. Like what, five CV S later.
Exactly.
Yeah,
that's a story. But that's for another day.
Ok. That's interesting that
I, I'm not shocked by that, I guess.
And then the other thing that I, I did want to bring up is there's just human error.
I mean, like with the patches that, that have zero bits changed,
I, I can only assume that's just human error.
And as long as patches are created by humans, they're gonna be mistakes.
So I don't think we'll ever see perfect patches.
But, uh, we certainly hope that we see fewer busted patches than we're seeing now.
Well.
And, and so my, when, when I read this story about your research being published,
my first thought wasn't malice of any sort.
Just rather
this is pretty typical human behavior
where
there is
the, the problem isn't people trying not to patch there is either,
you know, they're not given enough time to create a proper patch.
They don't understand the, the root cause of the problems or, you know,
it's something else.
I, I think
I don't want to accuse any company of being like, no, only half fix this problem.
-- Like, don't fix it all the way,
-- even just simpler.
Given a reproducer, I made the reproducer stop working.
No,
I did not spend 10 hours trying to dig into the legacy
code and understand how this really works and the root causes and
oh crap, we got rearchitect this whole thing
because
yeah. No, like nobody's got time for that. I've got like 17 features to add
or just make sure the integer is greater than zero and line 13.
We see that as well.
I mean, uh point fixes are definitely a problem with, with the patches. We had one,
we demonstrated in our attack an Adobe fix and we sent them
an integer overflow and we sent them really good proof of concept.
Uh And essentially what they did is they took the value from the proof
of concept and dropped that into the patch and that was their patch.
It's like broke, it broke the Poc.
But then within an hour the patch being released,
the researcher sent in another bug which we had to buy again
and all he did on the Poc,
all he all he changed on the POC was a new value there.
And sure enough, boom code execution right again.
So yeah, Adobe fixed it better the second time they added in math
uh which is good in fixing energy overflows.
But yeah, I mean, that's the sort of thing we see too.
We just break the POC doesn't repro
ship it.
OK?
I don't want to keep beating this horse because
I think we all mostly understand the problem.
I find
it. It's fascinating and I'll be really excited to, to
read more into this in the future as more and more.
I'm sure organizations do the research. But
now one of the other pieces to this is ZD.
I is not just complaining, which I think is easy to do.
You have some plans of behavior changes
to hopefully make this better. And so I would love to hear more about that.
Well, our standard disclosure timeline is 120 days.
That means when we contact a vendor,
if they have 100 and 20 days to
either produce a security update or some other remediation
to resolve an issue.
Otherwise, we disclose the bug publicly. We don't go full disclosure,
but we do provide some information publicly so
that defenders have information that they can protect themselves
and what we're doing uh with bugs that we
buy that result from failed or faulty patches.
Uh We're going with a tiered system.
So uh for patches that are critical rated
and where attack is imminent or already detected,
you now have a 30 day disclosure timeline
for critical and high severity bugs where the patch offers some protections
uh and attacks are not uh immediate where 60 days and then everything else is 90 days.
One of the things we were seeing is it would
give somebody 100 and 20 days to fix something,
they'd fix it right at 100 and 20 days,
we, they'd release the patch and within an hour of the patch release,
the research or somebody else would bypass it and then go
right by it and we'd give them another 120 days.
So it's another four months at the vendors that the enterprises are at
risk because the vendors are taking so long to fix busted patches.
So we're trying to incentivize them to get it right the first time.
Otherwise they're going to be on much tighter timelines.
And one example of this is uh in July Microsoft
fixed a patch that was under active attack and they,
they later said it was an Austrian private threat
actor was using the bug to spread subzero malware.
One of our ZD I researchers bypassed that patch within two days.
Uh In fact, he bypassed about 10% of the entire release within two days.
So, and that's, but that particular bug,
that's the sort of thing we reported it under the 120 days.
But under this,
it would be a 30 day disclosure timeline because it was under active attack already.
Got you.
That makes sense. I mean,
so if I report a bug to you
and
-- the vendor, the vendor gets 100 and 20 days for the initial report.
-- Yes. Correct.
Yes.
And then if they don't fix it correctly,
-- then the 30 days can kick in if it's
-- critical
severity and we think attacks are imminent were already happening.
That's awesome. I think that's fantastic.
Have you received any feedback on this policy by chance?
We have surprisingly enough.
So most of the enterprises we talked to are
are very happy with it and encouraged by it.
But what's really kind of shocking to me is most of the
vendors we talked to because we talk mainly to their response,
people, not their engineers directly.
The response people were like this is great.
This is something we can take back to our developers and go look,
you got to get it right the first time or this is gonna happen.
So the the response from the vendors has
been much more positive than we actually expected.
We expected quite a bit of pushback.
But no,
the the response has been overwhelmingly positive with
very few people being really negative about it.
Well, I mean, speaking from experience, one of the biggest challenges had as, as,
as the security people,
we didn't control the devs,
right? Like we had to ask nicely and, or convince their managers to do stuff and
yeah, we didn't have
-- a lot of push or control.
-- No, we used to call it influence without authority.
Yeah, exactly. Social capital
and everybody hates security people because we just keep coming to
them and bugging them for stuff and interrupting their schedules.
-- We,
-- we don't come to them and say, hey, nothing's broken today.
-- Maybe
-- that's what I should have done. But uh yeah, I understand.
I mean, I've been that security person too, you know, in the Air Force at Microsoft.
And it's, you know, it's tough going to developers who just want to work on
the next
and say, hey, sorry, remember that code? Somebody checked in 12 years ago.
Yeah,
it's broken and you have to fix it now and I
know that new feature you're working on is really cool.
But really you have to take time off from that and, and fix this one thing and it's,
and it's tough to get them to do that.
It's tough to get them to see the value add of, you know, fixing legacy code,
especially on certain projects.
So,
one of the things that we've seen uh more recently with
certain hardware vendors is we'll go to them and it's like,
hey, uh, this entire hardware line has these bugs
and they go, oh, really?
That's funny because I just into life, that entire hardware line,
like, oh, well, I guess that's one way.
No, I could see it because I know for a lot of that hardware stuff,
they're not gonna sell any more of them.
So
they're not gonna sell it anymore. So why support it?
So, yeah,
that was kind of astonishing to us because we didn't always buy bugs and hardware.
That's a little bit harder for us because, you know, you report a hardware bug,
we gotta go buy the hardware and then reproduce it and
all this sort of stuff takes a little longer for us.
But, uh, yeah, we were kind of surprised when we started buying hardware bugs.
That, that was a valid response from the vendors.
It's like, oh, we'll just end of life the entire product line, like, oh, ok.
Well, that's the way to go, I suppose
because they know they're not buying,
they're not selling any more of those
wireless routers except at Walmart or something.
And, you know, I, I guess they don't care about those customers.
Well,
it's, I mean, even us being all knowledgeable in this industry, like,
can you definitively say what, you know, is the security policy
affecting your hardware? And the answer is no, of course not.
Well, so one thing I'm curious about is because I've been looking at
this for the last 10 years, sort of in economic terms, you know,
because there's a lot of bad incentives like, hey,
I sold you that hardware or software,
like I have your money. Why? Like, why would I care?
You know,
and that's one thing Red Hat did that I liked is
Red Hat had a subscription model so that Red Hat had
an incentive to support the damn thing because like we want,
we want you to keep paying us every year.
And um
I'm just wondering,
so it,
you're trying to create some better incentives with
that shorter disclosure for the more critical stuff,
which also has the nice effect of actually
hopefully protecting the people being exploited because they get a patch
in 30 days instead of 100 and 20. That's
goal. But
the thing I'm wondering is, is how or even can we
kind of,
is there anything we can do for consumers to help educate them or, or get them to
demand better behavior consistently from the vendors? Right? Because
I, I feel like that that demand side of security is something we always ignore.
We were focused on the supply side.
Well,
I think the biggest thing that both consumers and enterprises can do
that we're not really doing right now is vote with our wallet.
Money, money is a big motivating factor in creating a profit.
I I told enterprises on stage, it's like, look, if you've got an RFP
include in there, what is your patch policy? What is your disclosure policy?
What is,
you know, how do you handle bad patches, that sort of thing
because you'll be really surprised with, you know, what you can get.
I know based on my personal preference purchases.
Uh I won the, the home wireless system that I got is really, really fast
and it's really,
really awful for security and I won't be purchasing that brand again because of it.
Now, I won't be replacing it for a while either because it's, you know,
Wi Fi six and it's mesh and it's, you know,
I just put it in a year ago and hopefully it'll last a couple more years.
But that's the sort of thing. It's like I'm going to look a lot more closely at,
uh, what we can do and,
and I don't know how that translates to consumers
because obviously we're more prosumer than we are consumers.
I think that's the term. But
how, how do we get the average person purchasing whatever,
whether it be a phone or a piece of software or hardware
to think more about the security of it.
So that,
that vendors will be rewarded for having better security.
And I don't, I don't know how we get to there, especially on the consumer side,
I can see a path on the enterprise side, consumer much more hard.
Uh Just because they care more about features than security. Just in general.
One trick there I've found is is when people ask me, you know,
what should I get for Wi Fi phone, whatever?
And my answer is go buy it at Costco
because they have a one year money back guarantee.
And so if it is problematic,
like you can literally return your Christmas tree in July and they'll,
they'll, you know, give you a stink eye, but they will give you your money back.
So it kind of comes back down to that sort of insurability piece of like, yeah,
just buy it at this place that will make you whole if it's not good.
And
obviously that doesn't work for everything
because Costco is very limited selection.
All
right.
All right. I want, I want to reel it back in again.
This is basically my job,
but this is,
I think a fascinating tangent we're on right now where we're talking about,
you know, how do we create some incentives?
But what about the incentive? Like I'm, I'm, I'm a vendor
and I want to make sure
my developers don't have to release
the same patch two or three times.
What are,
how do we start fixing that problem? Because I think there is,
that's like a layer cake of difficult problems
all the way down.
Yeah, it definitely is a layer cake of uh there's a lot of things that could go into it.
The first thing I would do is is really look at your sustained engineering.
Like what, what really are you doing to
test and to verify stuff as it goes out?
Uh Both before and after uh a product release.
Um That's the biggest thing to me is we've,
we've pushed so much into automation and we've pushed so much on to developers.
I think we've pushed too much in those areas, too fast
and maybe I'm wrong on that. That's just my opinion.
But we're seeing the push for automation really have
kind of a negative impact in the patch world.
Uh because a lot of the reporting that we do now
is through API S uh to different vendors and that,
that push towards automation has definitely hurt
in some ways that I don't think the vendors intended.
It's one of the reasons why the communications
is worse because a lot of those advisories,
you just push a button and it kicks out from a database someplace.
There's not enough context around it.
There's not enough real data in the, in the advisories
to make a smart decision. And this is all part of the automation.
So you have to look very closely at your processes
and figure out if what you're doing is actually working to make
things better or if it's working to make things easier on you.
And I think in the end,
a lot of the automation is it's just helping to make things
easier on the vendor and not actually making anything that much better.
Well, and there's some vendors who goes well, that's good enough for me.
That's lowers my bottom line. That's all I care.
-- Well,
-- until they have to fix the patch three times in a row.
Again,
this is something I keep coming back to is my understanding of it
was the whole point of it was to automate stuff using computers and software
that can work really well because you can take a bunch of smart people, you know,
boil their knowledge,
distill it and turn it into a web browser or a blackjack simulator or,
you know, a GIS program or whatever.
But
the thing I keep finding and I'm not sure if this is true or not, but it seems to me,
like, every vendor treats security a little bit differently.
Like, there's no sort of,
there's no, generally, like, there's best practices but there's no, like,
actually here's no, just do this.
Like, here's the list.
Like
if you're going to get your car fixed,
all the mechanics are basically trained the same
way and they all will quote you like,
ok, you want me to do this,
this will take 2.7 hours and we will charge you X dollars per hour.
And whether or not it takes 2.7 hours is not your problem.
That's what you're paying, right?
And I feel like in the software industry, everything is this artisanal bespoke
mess.
And
when they are
making air quotes here automate it, you know, they,
they basically just take that mess and jam it
into a computer and I can't help but think
so. The challenge is we don't really necessarily
have the knowledge to actually automate it.
And when we do automate it,
are we kind of keeping that knowledge? Like, again, car mechanics,
they have training programs. They have manuals like
I've never been through real proper security training.
And this is my job like this is my career.
What's interesting is when it comes to this though, there, there are standards,
there is an iso for vendor responses to bug reports
that lays out how long you're supposed to do certain things.
29 1 47 is supposed to be uh
there for you to, for vendors to comply with.
I, I don't think
no,
at least no one that I've seen recently has really cared whether or not they're iso
29 1 47 compliance.
But if we were to go towards that,
that would at least give that baseline of what you're talking about to go.
Ok. Here's our baseline.
We need to be do this and it has the things like
you have to respond to a bug report within five days to acknowledge receipt.
Uh You have to, you know, have a timeline for fixing it,
whether it's 100 and 20 days or 100 and 80 or 90 or whatever, lay it out,
you have to have a contact point.
Uh Sometimes for certain vendors, it's hard for us even to find who to contact
like when we and not even just
open
source library is one thing we, we, we know we have that problem,
but especially when like some big vendors and you're like,
there's no Secure at whatever.com. That's,
that's tough.
That's one of my criteria for picking vendors that we use at the CS A is, can I find a
thing to report a security vulnerability to? And
like nine times out of 10,
it takes about a minute and a half and then the other one in 10 times, it's just like
they really don't want to hear from us. But the one thing, speaking of iso standards,
the one thing I've not seen is
like, how does the vendor get there?
So, a great example is we're,
we're currently evaluating um instant management software at the CS A
like better up time type stuff like website falls down.
We get an email, not only do we get a page or an email,
but we get like a system where we can talk about it and like
panic and like, uh
turn it off and on, turn it off and on.
But what I like, like when we worked at Red Hat,
the whole security response thing was this custom built Rube Goldberg machine.
And, and that's been my experience with all the vendors I've dealt with, like,
they all have their custom Rube Goldberg machine.
And that's kind of what I'm getting at is there's no like,
package I can buy off the shelf.
That's like, you know, oh, we're, we need a security response
block
thing.
Like,
why can't I buy that?
-- Yeah,
-- that's the better mouse trap, I suppose.
I mean, we've seen that in other industries as well where it's like,
how do I run a bug bounty program?
It's like, oh, well, I can't let me just hire
hone or bug crowd to do that for us.
But then it turns out that that's not as easy as they,
they think because there's problems inherent with that.
So,
yeah, if we could build that better mouse trap,
I'll let you know and I'll sell it to you for a good price.
Uh I'll give you, I'll give you that discount. I don't know.
But uh I retire off that if I build that. Um, you're right.
I mean, there's not, it would be great if we could have this.
Ok, let's go out and build Response maker 5000 and that would be it.
-- But yeah, I don't know. That's the better
-- mousetrap.
I mean, it's, we're not answering that today.
A
lot of that starts with senior leadership buy in,
like if you don't get buy in from your senior leaders that this is important,
it's never gonna happen.
And I think in a lot of organizations,
whether it's open source or closed source or service or products or whatever,
getting that senior leadership buy in to say this is
a real problem and we're going to fix it is,
is really hard to get.
I, I agree. I agree and I think that's let, let's take us out on that kind of note is
it's always, you know, everyone takes your security seriously. Right.
There's no organization on the planet that
hasn't uttered those statements at some point.
But I, I think you're correct that
it's,
you talk about interacting with product security
teams like P cert teams or whatever.
And
I've never met a P cert team that doesn't want to take security super seriously.
But then
they have to go to development
and now development's getting pressure from everyone. Right.
And so it can be, security is one aspect of what they're doing. And
as
I think it was pointed out in one of the quotes I read from you about how
a lot of developers features are, what make the money, right?
Sustaining engineering isn't what makes money generally speaking.
And I get that like, I, I understand that, but I think this is where you're right,
like when you have senior leadership saying this needs to be a priority,
that's how you make it a priority. And, and I, that makes sense to me.
Yeah,
it's just tough to find that senior leadership who's
willing to stand by that because like we said,
features make money
and sustained engineering doesn't.
And I think we're all the three unders, no matter where we're at,
we're understaffed, underfunded, under pressure.
So, you know, it's,
it's tough when you're trying to allocate those limited resources,
what are we going to spend it on?
You know, we're gonna add this new feature, we're gonna fix this old bug and,
and sometimes that can be a tough decision for businesses to make.
I think it's especially tough now too because stuff gets
rolled and phased out so much faster than in past,
you know, like
software used to come on a CD that I used for five years.
-- Yeah,
-- especially with like a lot of agile programs and cloud resources.
I mean, there's
so much churn on that code
and there's so limited integration testing.
Uh And there's so limited documentation that uh yeah,
we see that code churn happen just a lot.
Uh
And that that's good and bad, you know,
just because it means we can get things fixed faster,
-- means we can break it faster too.
-- I love that. I, I think let's call this one.
I can think of no better statement to end this on. I
Dustin. Thank you so much for joining us.
I'll put links to all the various stories and Dustin's
Twitter account and whatever else in the show note.
So just go find him there, go to open
source security podcast.com for the listeners. You can use the Pound
do
podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Dustin and Kurt. It has been an absolute treat.
I want to thank you both for the conversation.
You're very welcome. Thank you for having me. I really appreciate it.
It's been a fun talk. Thanks everybody.
Awesome. Thanks everyone and thanks Dustin. Bye bye.