Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 164 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh
Reser. Uh What's new man? Just uh it's fall and kind of enjoying the leaves turning.
It's nice.
That means they fall down and I have to rake them though.
And I don't want to actually, I need to buy a rake. Thank you for saying
mine just broke.
I was
gonna say, how do you not own a rake?
Like no, no, I had one and I was,
I don't even remember what I was raking at this point but it, it like broke,
it was a metal rake in the end, just kind of broke off.
It was, it was old. So it's not like it was defective,
but I need a new one because my, my other rake actually, I have no rakes now. So
anyway. All right.
That is irrelevant to this podcast. I just mow my lawn and mulch it, well, you can't,
all the leaves. Do you have one tree that barely has leaves on it or
uh mostly I have conifers? Yeah, I have a thick, that's pine trees for you.
You uncivilized.
So, yeah, pine needles.
But, um, yeah, I only have one or two trees that shed all their leaves. But yeah, so,
no, the last place I lived, I had two giant maple trees
and, um, I could regularly like,
and this is filling trash bags and stomping them down.
I would average about 3035 trash bags of leaves
in the fall, which, I mean, it was a gloriously huge pile like my kids loved it.
I'm familiar with this problem because it is the problem I have.
And so yes, mulching my lawn is definitely out of the question.
You need a flamethrower or I need like slave Children, labor people, which I have.
Although they're not, they're not the best rakers in the world. So they do need a
of prodding while they're working. But
anyway, anyway. All right, man. Uh, DNS over http S friend
or foe.
Yes. Come on. That's not, that's not interesting. Ok, so
I'm going to go back and quote myself.
If your security relies on you behaving like a Nation State attacker,
you're going to have a bad time, long term.
What? That doesn't? That's not an answer.
Yeah, so I'm ok with DNS over http
because that will help foil Nation State Attackers.
And if that makes somebody else's life a little more difficult.
Well, ok, sorry,
that's kind of too bad
because here's the thing fundamentally, if you legitimately need to secure
a device then you typically get to control it to some degree.
So for example, with a smartphone or a laptop, whatever,
if you really are that paranoid,
you can install endpoint security on it.
Right.
So this kind of, I mean, I get it though, the, the convenience of like, as a,
for example, you know, parents are like, oh, I just want to like,
you know,
filter DNS so my kids can't get into the bad stuff
and it's just easy and convenient and you set your,
uh, you know, on your router,
you set the DNS to point to trying to think of who provides these things.
I don't even know anymore.
I think open DNS has a service where you can say like I'm a parent,
don't let my kids look at naughty things and your kids totally know
to get around that, by the way, just fy I and,
or they just go to the local Starbucks where they don't filter internet or
the library where they have computers with unfiltered or the neighbor's wi fi or,
or whatever.
So I
get the convenience aspect because I like convenience because
I'm a lazy person because I'm a person.
But
fundamentally the trade off,
I think between annoying some parents and whatnot and some businesses versus
making a whole big pile of people safer against nation state attacks.
And
more importantly,
all those attacks that attack routers redirect their DNS
and then all sorts of nasty shenanigans happen.
So, I,
I think overall DNS over http addresses a problem that
needs to be addressed and is a good thing.
Yeah, I totally agree.
And I love that my ISP can't spy on any of the DNS traffic anymore that's happening.
Which is fantastic. I'm, I'm not even too worried about that.
I mean, well, because you were involved in that Twitter discussion about, you know,
the low bar versus the high bar of security and how, you know,
we need to raise the low bar for everybody, which I agree with.
We, we should do that. You know, we should make the world less sucky.
And this is one of those ways to do that.
You know, if a major part of my life is tied into Google and Apple's systems,
you know, all my email, all my personal data is in icloud and Google Drive
full stop. It just is.
So, you know, when my computer is talking to Google,
I would feel a little bit less worried and I, you know,
much safer knowing that there's no
way for DNS shenanigans to happen
and for, you know,
my computer to actually be talking to something
in some other country that's not Google.
Uh, you know, I, I don't disagree with you. I think
it,
it amuses me a little bit watching the
arguments against this because I think they are weak
and they often represent
a, I,
I would say a lack of understanding of
modern infrastructure is how I would describe it.
It's the old way of thinking and
the best part is fundamentally,
let's say you're using a VPN or whatever and you need access to magic DNS.
You can, you can make that work.
It's not impossible to do.
Yeah, it might be an extra step or two.
But at the same time, if you're one of those people,
you already have such a unique setup,
adding one more step to it really isn't a big deal.
My only real concern honestly would be the argument where I
have IOT devices where I can't really control the end point.
And so I do need to do network level security for them.
That would be about the only real argument I can see because
I do own my IOT devices like I paid for them. But like,
you know, it's a binary blob that unless I reverse engineer it,
you know,
I have no idea what my skylink net security system
is doing unless I'm monitoring it on the network.
Yeah, but
it's not using DNS over hhps. It probably never will. So who cares?
Well, but you know, five years from now, right?
My light bulbs are doing it or whatever.
So, I mean that, like I said, that would be my only concern is where
people legitimately can't
get access to the end device.
And,
you know, for all the people that are like, well,
why don't you buy open source light bulbs.
Yeah. I mean,
yes, if
those even exist, I don't, I don't think they exist.
You know, I'm looking at my home security system and I'm looking at possibly
going with, um, the ring stuff or the nest stuff and again, it's like, proprietary.
Like, I don't know what it's doing and that's a trade off.
I have to make because there is,
unless I construct a security system completely from scratch,
using a pile of like raspberry pies,
there's no way I'm going to have real visibility into it.
And so it boils down to, I have to trust
the manufacturer just like I do with my car. Right.
I don't have the source code for my car.
You know,
I just hope that those computer chips in their work and don't magically decide
to smash the gas pedal down when I'm putting it in a park.
Right.
No, I, I don't know. I guess fundamentally I love it. People might not like it.
It's ok.
You'll get over it.
Well, how do I put this nicely? It's gonna happen whether they like it or not.
No, it is. It's, it's pretty much game over.
I, I hate to argue that sort of, well,
it doesn't really matter what you think because they're doing it anyways.
So, your objections are duly noted and overruled.
Google has to protect themselves and their
customers and Google has decided there's a,
you know,
there's a couple of ways they're doing this and one of the ways they're doing this is
encryption everywhere. All the things all the time, right?
Because like to go back in time,
their
Children,
there used to be a time when Google data
centers talk to each other over unencrypted links.
And then Google learned about the NSA and encrypted all their links. Yep. Yep.
That's right.
And I mean, man, I'll still, I will never forget this.
I have a memory burned in my brain forever is when SSH came out,
I talked to a friend and I said, doesn't this look neat?
And they said, why would anyone want that? We have talent?
I remember thinking,
I, I can't really argue with you today because
man,
in the middling a network was very difficult back then and
the number of people who could do it were small.
But at the same time, it's like
I know this is going to happen because it's better.
Well, ironically, man, in the middling networks, actually,
in some ways used to be really hard and really easy.
It was really easy in the sense of everything was hubs, not switches.
So, yeah, for those of you that don't know what a hub is.
So the way old timey network equipment worked is
you had a hub that you plug 10 computers into
and one computer would send a message and
the hub would basically replicate that message,
that electrical signal to the other
nine computers.
And then basically, you know, it was up to your computer to ignore and,
or listen to what it was supposed to.
And so
the funny thing is
the software to actually kind of listen to those messages or to redirect
stuff was really hard to get a hold of and remember Doug song.
He wrote SS A sniff and, and all that and I mean, I wrote an article about it
and, you know, I got death threats because people were so annoyed about this.
You know,
it used to actually in some ways be really hard to
do man in the middle because the software to do it
didn't exist like you, you would have to write it yourself and it required a pretty,
you had to be pretty knowledgeable about networking and operating systems
to write the software. And if you were though, it was not that hard,
but the thing is kind of, here's the thing.
Once one person writes the software and releases it on the internet,
then kind of everybody has it. Right.
Well, in the bigger problem always wasn't even man in the middling,
it was just sniffing credentials because when you had hubs, I mean,
I remember doing this
in, on networks where
they, I mean, it was, it was like a party trick as well.
I went, I didn't go to good parties but,
you know, you'd tell someone log in, log in with T NE
and then you'd have,
it was, we call it Wire Shark.
Now it was called Ethereal back then,
but you'd have it running and like you would print their password to the screen.
Like, how'd you do that? And I said you did it, you know, I didn't do anything.
I literally one time was uh trying to diagnose a pop log in like
a, an email login problem on one of the mail servers I was responsible for at an ISP.
And so I ran um TCP dump, you know, port 110.
Obviously,
I'm not going to bother passing at the
IP address and everything at the local machine.
And I'm like, and then II, I just traffic starts flying by and I'm like, right. Right.
Oh,
I have all the passwords now. Yeah. And it was, the ISP was using a hub. Good, good.
Well, that's good. Switches were expensive.
They were actually,
they, they actually were like 100 bucks support.
It was, yeah. Right. Exactly. 10 megabits.
I remember getting a switch for the first time when
I was in college and I worked at the university
and we had just this, this closet full of hubs.
It was an insane number of hubs for all of the, the sun workstations.
And we got switches and we got them at like cost and they were still really expensive.
I remember we plugged those suckers in and the first thing I did
was just start like moving some files around and it's like it's so fast
because I mean, so the problem was for, for you young uns who may not know
when you had a hub, there was a concept called the collision.
Only one person gets to talk at a time. Right. Exactly.
So, if two computers tried to talk at the same time,
you'd have a collision and then everyone stops and you
back off and then you try again at a,
after a random interval, which is, this is all in the Ethernet spec,
you should read it sometime.
It's very exciting. And this works great
until you get to about 80% network utilization and then it falls off a cliff.
Exactly. And so if you're copying a huge file, it actually doesn't do a great job.
It was very, very bad. Hey, but I mean, this was better. I had, um,
anyways, we're really deep into the old
stories. But
so basically, I, I like
anything that makes it harder for Nation States to attack people.
I think overall is a good thing. Any attack hurt. I mean, let's face it.
It screw Nation States, whatever those guys are. What do they know?
But I mean, for real, like anything. Well, but the thing to remember too is like
a lot of people now use networks that are really open to attack, you know,
public Wi
fi. Oh, no, no, Kurt, we're security people. We should never connect to public
wi fi. Well, see, this is what drives me nuts is all these people
in security that spend all this time and effort securing their home network.
And I'm like, cool. So, your home network is super secure.
They're like, yeah, like, my laptop cannot be hacked from my home network, blah,
blah, blah.
And I'm like, cool. Like, you go to Starbucks, right? They're like, yeah.
And I'm like, so
you bring your home network with you? How does that work?
Oh, no, we're all supposed to run VPN S.
Yeah. Well, but my point is
like,
I treat every network everywhere like it's directly attached to
the public internet because at some point chances are,
well, if it's, if it's my phone, my tablet or my laptop, it's gonna
go talk to a public network at the library at Starbucks at
IKEA.
You know, on IKEA, I'm gonna hop on their Wi FI because they, you know, they,
the way they built their building, it's the, um, you know, it's the,
it's like that corrugated metal that they
concrete on. Dude. It's a huge fair day cage.
That's what every IKEA building is.
And like Home Depot is terrible as well because all the metal shelves, like,
you know, the, the two or three outside aisles of the building. Sure, whatever.
But once you're inside the Home Depot, man, like, you know, the,
my cell phone data is just like crawling.
Yep. Yep. Exactly.
And so I,
I like the beyond horizon idea of Google where
just treat everything like it's the public internet because
either it is the public internet or chances are
that thing will get plugged into the public internet
at some point. Yeah. Totally, man. Absolutely.
A great example is like, my, my local network does I PV six
and
my ISP hands me. I think it's a slash 56.
And that's the IP S my Google Wifi is handing out internally. So
I've never really tried,
but I'm kind of guessing that you can maybe
just talk directly to the stuff from the internet.
No, you can't. I at least
go.
Well, I shouldn't say that
when I tested it. I couldn't, I don't know who is blocking that traffic,
but I could not reach my IP D six gear from the,
I should probably try at some point, but more of a point I,
my suspicion is the Google Wi Fi was blocking it.
I should probably confirm this at some point,
but more of the point I just can't be bothered to care anymore.
Like
my stance is everything, is the public internet. Yep. Yep. I, I agree.
I agree completely.
I think it is absolutely the right way to treat all of these problems
because it, it, it, let's face it,
we have limited mental capacity
and
if I only have to deal with one situation, it's a lot easier than two or three.
Well, it's like the old GDPR thing.
And now California talking about privacy laws
that are suspiciously similar to GDPR.
And I'm like, oh, cool,
because you know where I work, we basically did the GDPR dance and I was like,
we're just doing this globally because
my biggest thought was with the right to forget.
Well, how do you prove that you are a subject of GDPR?
Because I'm like, ok, so if you like,
live and work and reside in Germany and you're German and you have a German passport?
Ok. You're under GDPR very clearly.
But you know what if it's a tourist who's in Germany
and emails us
saying I want you to forget my email address, but they're an American, you know,
at what point, like, do they have to have a visa?
Do they have to be
living there? Do they? I don't know. Right.
So, I was just like, I was like, because, you know, nobody's,
I haven't seen any answers for this and,
and the response was like,
we're just not going to worry about it. We're just doing GDPR globally, right?
It's the
only right way to do it.
And I have a suspicion the European Union knew that would happen,
which was part of the
companies
will do this.
It's, well, it's like the California stuff where they do emissions control laws on,
say, cars and the carmakers are like, yeah,
we're not building a special car for California.
We're just going to build them all a bit better.
Yeah.
And, yeah, So, I mean, again, you know, it's just, yeah,
having one standard to adhere to and more, like I said, more of the point.
I just, there's no way I'm going to be able to,
without getting a whole bunch of pi I from you.
And even if you do give me all your pi I and like a scan of your passport,
I don't know how to validate that.
Like, how do I validate a Slovenian passport? I have no freaking idea. Right.
So actually I just got a new driver's license the other day.
It was, it was amusing when I went in because they
now you have to,
they have this thing called Real ID in the US where you have to kind of prove your, you
and if you have a passport,
it's easy because a passport is like a magic
document because getting one is actually not simple.
It's real ID compliant already,
right? And so I remember I went in lady's like, do you have this? This is,
I'm like, I have a passport. She's like, oh, you're fine then.
And it was,
it was,
well, this is one of the reasons II I love having a nexus pass.
You know, it's like all of a sudden
at all these places. It's like uh oh Nexus. Cool. Yep. Yep. Exactly.
What's interesting to me though is I understand these people are angry because
a lot of their network security posture relies on being able to,
you know, closely examine and filter network traffic and
the anomaly detection of, oh, there's encrypted traffic going out to,
we're not quite sure where.
So it's potentially malicious. Let's go take a closer look at that. So
this whole kind of in a way increase false positives and whatnot.
But like I said,
I, it's gonna happen
your choices to not use web browsers. Maybe, I don't know.
No, no. I mean, so actually, you know what I would tie this back to is
a couple days ago, from the time we are recording this.
Actually there,
there's this other podcast I listen to called the Defense of Security Podcast.
It, it's quite good
and I'd suggest anyone, they, they took a hiatus, one of them got very ill
and they, they had an episode.
But anyway, they were talking about the capital one data breach,
which while it happened a long time ago happened while they weren't recording
and they had AAA really good point that they brought up during this,
that I think it's very related to, to all this is they were talking about the fact that
if you look at a cloud environment
and you try to apply kind of the traditional networking viewpoint to it,
you're going to fail miserably because
while some of the skills carry over, it is a very new way of thinking.
Well, there's also different capabilities,
like some things that you used to be able to do.
You just can't do in cloud.
And conversely, there's stuff I can do in cloud that I, there's no way
I could do in the real world affordably.
Like, like with Amazon, I enabled Cloud Trail, it's literally three clicks
and every single
administrative event in our account gets logged. Right. Right. Exactly.
It was three clicks. You and I have had to do this stuff at our previous jobs.
And, I mean,
folks, this is basically impossible
logs. What are those? Well, you know, my favorite thing is like every time I hear
about things like not pet
or whatever and it's like, ok, so bad patch management.
Number two, like how did we get infected?
It's like, don't you people have file auditing, turned on on your Windows machines?
No,
or my all time favorite is when people
complain about performance at remote offices of files.
And I'm like,
you know,
like Microsoft specifically has built a huge pile of capabilities into windows
for like shadow file copies and a whole bunch of stuff.
So that number one, you have like kind of live backups of your data.
So if somebody does delete a file, you can recover it in like 30 seconds.
And number two performance will be better because you'll
kind of have a cached copy locally of your data
that's at head office or whatever.
You know, it just magically works and like literally these,
it people who run Windows networks are like,
oh yeah, I guess we could use that. And I'm like, ok, lovely.
So, with Cloud. Yeah, it's,
I, it's tough though because part of the prompt too,
I find I've dug through Amazon Google and
Azure
trying to figure out what all are their capabilities, for example,
with relational databases and backups and with like
the S3 style of buckets and backups,
there's just too much, there's too many options. It's brutal. I agree. It's
like I, I need to, you know, literally find some, like
there are probably people out there that have
spent the couple 100 hours learning all three
of those systems inside out and can make a valid decision in comparison of them.
I'm not one of them. No, I, I agree. And this is,
this is one of the unique challenges I think we're sitting in the middle of.
I mean, we're, we're, we're living through a time of disruption
and
the last one was kind of the birth of.com,
right? Which I feel like was
that, that felt more like a,
a kind of rip and replace where we're replacing an
old way with a new way where this is more of
a kind of a transition where we're taking existing technology
and knowledge and we're trying to move it somewhere else.
Well, forklift it into the cloud, right? And a lot of it doesn't work.
And so it's, I mean, it's hard man
and it's hard to keep up. It's hard to know what's going on. I'm not gonna lie.
No, I, uh, I, once a quarter I try and review all the Amazon services just to, you know,
because I'll discover new stuff where I'm like, oh, I can, like,
I was running gluster on a bunch of my servers and I'm like, oh, elastic files for.
Ok. Poop.
You know,
for four bucks a month now, I have
20% less stuff to administer and worry about. Yep. Yep. Exactly.
No, I know exactly how that goes.
I, my only complaint is still,
I wish I could like mount an elastic file system
over the internet because that would make my life great.
You can,
you just don't want to jump through the hoops. No, you can't, you can't do it.
You have to
do
it.
You do an NFS re export, you do what you have like a micro instance or whatever,
mounting the efs and then you just reexport it.
I don't want to do that.
I just want to mount the EFS because then now I have
to take care of that stupid micro instance and screw that.
Your better option is go buy one of those S3 file thing of a jigger for
your local machine that so that you mount an S3 bucket like a local file system.
I don't want to do that either. I want an EFS anyway, whatever
a
complaining, I want it my way. Shut up. So you want your posi
file system?
That's Right.
That's right. What you do, what you really want is just file storage.
I don't even know what I really want it for. I just think I want it. So
I don't, I don't have a good use for it even.
It's whatever, whatever, whatever, just pay black plate. What is it?
Black Back Blaze
Blaze, which is not a sponsor.
They sponsor a lot of podcasts actually.
No, II,
I don't use them because from my investigation into
them they seem to actively discourage exactly the way I
do my backups where I have all of my stuff goes to one central location and then I,
I mirror it out
and I don't want to abuse their services.
Well, they really do want people who just back up their local computer. Right. Yes.
Exactly.
And this is a perfect example.
Do you?
I remember reading about back plays how people were complaining, like,
I can't disable it, backing up my C drive and back is like, yeah, ha,
because we used to allow people to disable that and
people disabled it and then a bad thing happened to
their computer and then they called us and cried.
I believe that. You know, so they're like, we just back up your c drive.
That's it. Like it's going to happen
and I could be wrong. Maybe they've changed that since then.
But, you know, I, I personally,
yeah. No, I think that's a reasonably safe thing to do. Yep. Yep. I agree. I agree.
Let's, uh, we got a couple more minutes.
I just want to briefly touch on one topic because I
know we're going to revisit it in the future more properly.
But Github
is a freaking CN A. How cool is that?
Yeah. They're going to help boil the ocean.
They're not going to help Kurt. They're going to boil it or, or? Yeah, I don't know.
So, why don't we start at the beginning?
Give us like the 32nd tour of what does it mean to be AC N A.
So A CV numbering authority is AC N A is
an entity that can assign CV numbers and typically
they have a scope of what they cover.
And typically most CNAs have a scope of the stuff that they produce.
So for example, Red Hat covers
Red Hat software and Red Hat software that software that they consume and reship.
They sometimes also cover, like,
say the Linux kernel Microsoft covers Microsoft oracle covers oracle, you know,
simple.
Now github
is a little different in that I'd spoken with them originally and they,
they definitely wanted to be AC N A for the github
software like github desktop, things like that, you know,
stuff that they produce and ship and that would be fine. That would be good.
But no, no, no, no github uh decided to go
all the way.
Um So they want to cover github.
Basically, they want to cover github.com/star
for everything that isn't actually already covered by an existing CN A so,
like Red Hat, you know, has like over 100 github
repos
and organizations scattered all over.
I remember inventorying it when I, before I left Red Hat, it was,
I think 100 and I found 100 and 21 that I could track.
Everybody is on github.
Exactly as they should be. It's awesome. You know, let's face it. right?
You and I use them
as does everybody
uses them.
Yeah.
So basically what that means is in theory,
once they kind of build the software and process to support this, I mean, go to github
and do a search for cross site scripting flaw fixed or, you know,
fixed buffer overflow.
While in theory, every single one of those now will have a CV.
And the best part is they can do a lot of deduplication,
um you know, with, with projects that
kind of embed stuff or whatever. Um
because they have the dependency graph of all the software in github.
And for most of these things, it's, it actually works quite well. Like
they've already started doing security alerts, right?
Like I got one for uh an older version of Noo
Gary in
a couple of projects, you know, where
a dependency was pulling in an old version.
And the coolest thing too is they're really, I mean,
if they just did security alerts and like
traversed the dependency graph and said like,
hey, you're pulling in this dangerous version of X, I'd be like, that's awesome.
Like
that is,
that's awesome.
But they're doing, they're going even further of like, well,
you know,
do you want to enable us to automatically create
a poll request against that to fix it?
So now it goes from, oh, you've told me there's a problem to, you're also
suggesting the solution and if it's correct in which cases,
most cases it will be correct,
I just hit accept
and
the problem is fixed
and they're even doing some magic with C inc D and like looking at your, you know,
do you want us to let us read kind of your build results so that we can see like,
you know, like this thing, I, I suspect the logic looks something like,
you know, this component is kept current and kept up to date.
So probably updating to the next current version of it
is safe versus like you version lock to this component.
Hm, maybe updating that isn't so safe, you know,
and you need to take an extra look at this
and um but regardless they're doing an awesome job. Right. Right.
It's, it's super cool. Did I mention free?
It's part of their business model, right, because they have the enterprise
offering of github.
And obviously, if you're an open source project or you're something small,
you can obviously use this for free.
But let's face it. If you're more than probably five or 10 people.
You're gonna need to actually work with them in a formal relationship. And so
it's, it's not exactly free.
I wouldn't call it that we're paying them and it's coming in like,
at all my private repos and stuff, it, it is zero cost to the users
apart from the fact that there's people who don't pay github
to use github, like, like me for my personal projects
and then there's companies, but their assumption is by making it so compelling,
you won't go anywhere else
eventually you're going to pay them
once you reach a certain size, right?
Unquestionably sort of, if you, if you're willing to have all your stuff public,
you can still do it for free.
It's when you want to go private that you need to pay, right? I mean, huh.
Ok. I'm gonna throw my bank, one of my banks under the bus here.
Uh Scotia Bank calling you guys out.
They had a whole pile of public get repos with internal code.
It looks like basically they just weren't willing
to pay the couple of bucks a month so
to get their repos made private. And so
they had a whole bunch of software in there with credentials and stuff
because in fairness like doing proper credential
storage and management is not easy.
But at the same time, like this is one of Canada's like four or five big banks.
So shame on you,
you know, as a customer, I'm kind of annoyed. Well, in Kurt, it, it's,
it's not even just about private repos because I mean, you can get private repos now
on, on the free tier.
There's also, you know, user management and you know,
the permissions and tying this stuff into a single sign on system.
And there's all these super cool features. There's
in all seriousness if you are an organization
that uses source code management in any way,
which is basically everyone at this point.
If you're not doing source code management, please let us know.
So we can short your stock, right?
But I mean, for real, you know, and I know github
has some competitors, there's GIT lab, which I get lab is really cool.
They do a fine job also. But it's just, it's kind of one of those things that
it's, it's what is, I forget the, the, how this the breakdown always works,
but generally in any sort of environment like this,
you're going to see 80% goes to the first player.
You'll have like 10% to the next guy
and then it's long tail after that. And I mean, I, I assume it's github
and GIT Lab are basically number one and number two at this point.
Uh I guess I don't, I've actually, I've literally only used Git lab
once and well, you know what that was, right?
It was a kind of a paranoid installation and
that was very much the exception to the rule,
like I've in the last five years outside of that one use of
GLAB, I've, I don't know anybody using it.
Uh There's a handful of open source projects I've
had to interact with that are using it,
but at the same time, they all have mirrors on github.
And the only reason I found them at GI lab is because I went to
github
and the reading, he said, oh, we moved to get lab and I said, OK,
so,
but there's a mirror, there's a perfect, they're generally a direct mirror on
github.
OK. In fairness, I'm looking at the Git lab explore thing.
There's, there's a lot of stuff in there.
Just mostly stuff I don't ever use or interact with. It's good.
I mean, I won't say there's anything wrong with it.
It's perfectly good at what it does. I would assume it's comparable.
Yeah, definitely. It's
there, there's, I know there's some people that
there's the whole open source ethical conundrum where Git lab is very open github
less open
and that's fine. I'm, I respect that if that's your thing. Go for it. I, I get it.
I've fully embraced the as a service world run by other people because you know what?
I
am still the director of it at the organization I work for and it
better be a part time job because I also have my real job.
I need to get done
to put it bluntly uh that's fair. But anyway, anyway,
so, yeah, we're gonna, we're gonna hopefully talk to
github in the near future about all this and that way,
instead of Kurt and I making crap up,
we can get someone who actually knows what they're talking about.
So we're very excited.
But yeah, in the meantime,
go
play your github
settings and maybe enable some of the cool new security stuff
because like,
I literally came as a surprise to me one day I was digging through and I'm like,
what does this give me automated alerts of security
notifications?
Like, what is it?
We, I thought we talked about this on the podcast. How is that a surprise?
Oh, I think it was before that. Right.
And then, but I was more surprised by the whole, like,
do you want us to automatically fix your security flaws?
And I was kind of like,
yeah,
like, please, yes.
Is this a trick question? Right. Right.
That'll be, that'll be the new defense like, oh, I didn't fix it because github
didn't fix it.
And anyway, all right, man, let's call it. I think it's time. So thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to Overs Source Security podcast.com.
Head up the show notes use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag do hit us up on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.