Hello and welcome to episode 32 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
32 5 bits wide.
How
exciting.
Yeah,
it's, uh, only about 3000 more to go.
Right.
That's right. That's right. How exciting.
So, how you doing, Kurt
better, better getting a new cold. So,
this podcast should sound ok. But the next one, I'll probably sound like I'm dying.
Well, we're in RSA. I imagine we'll do some recording there next week and then
we'll probably sound like we're dying anyway from
not sleeping and being around the conference.
In which case,
we'll all catch some terrible disease and bring it home to our families,
which will be the best.
The thing I love though is it's San Francisco.
So the humidity for me because I live in Edmonton where, like, we,
we don't have humidity.
It's just not a thing here. Like
you can drop wet clothes anywhere you want and they're dry in an hour.
So every time I go to San Francisco, like within an hour of being there, I just,
my sinuses feel amazing.
I bet your hair frizzes all up too. Right.
-- I don't have
-- hair.
Right.
Awesome. No, it should be fine. It'll be good. Nice and cold.
Oh,
yeah.
Right.
Yeah. I'm like, I'm like, do I even bother to pack a jacket?
-- I'm looking at the forecast.
-- You know what?
I made that mistake one time going to San Francisco.
In fact, it was in July and I bought a coat
and it's sad when you're buying a jacket in San Francis.
-- Weirdly cold, damp, microclimate. Yeah,
-- it's wild, man.
It's crazy the way it works. Absolutely.
In fact, I, I remember I was in,
in Florida one time in February and I brought only shorts and T shirts
and I had to buy all new clothes because it was the coldest February,
I think in Florida history while I was there.
What, what? Ok. Just for reference. What does coldest February in Florida mean?
-- It was
-- like the near zero °C slightly above only.
It was,
it was,
it was cold.
It was very cool.
Yep. Yep. It was crazy, man.
Yeah, I think last night was minus 27 with a wind chill.
That
terrible weather.
It
is gross.
All right. So
I think the most interesting story I ran across last week was about randomness.
Yeah, I think, um, well, should we,
should we roll to check if we're going to talk about it?
-- Yes, let's roll for initiative, shall we?
-- Ok.
18. That's a terrible initiative.
So, uh, you can go first.
-- Uh, I'm gonna have to believe that you rolled an 18.
-- That's true.
You have no idea what I rolled. I should have lied and said I rolled a one.
Yeah,
it's part of the beauty of random numbers. Right?
And is the dice fair?
Did I roll a dice or did I just, you know, throw my pen out here? Who knows?
Nobody knows.
It's like you've seen that Dilbert cartoon where, where he's in,
I think he's in hell.
And there's the random number generator who just
keeps saying four over and over again.
Well, and that's, you know,
and that's a great example because technically speaking,
that could be true randomness. But the problem becomes
when you talk about security and
as a subset of security, when you talk about cryptography,
you suddenly move into a whole pile of requirements for random numbers where
we're not gonna talk about it because it just gets horribly complicated,
horribly fast.
-- Whatever,
-- man, we should totally talk about it. Let's do this.
Let's start with the slot machine story.
OK.
So the, and OK, so I'm not 100%.
I've, I've read this story, but I'm still not 100% clear on
the random number generator in the slot machines. Now, this is the part I'm on
II, I actually,
I know some things about this due to a variety of
conversations I had off the record as well as reading various
Nevada Gaming commission documents.
I don't know why. But I became obsessed with slot machine, random numbers
at one point.
So I know a whole bunch about this strangely enough.
So, finally my useless knowledge has value.
Nice.
Yeah, I've read a little bit and I have to admit, like,
if you look at what their requirements are from, like a security perspective,
they're, they're pretty solid.
Like, uh,
my understanding is you have to file the source code online with them and you have to,
um, you have to file.
Ok. So anyways, the deal is,
um, people are going to casinos
and playing the slot machines and winning
just under $1200.
The reason for that being apparently
is if you win more than $1200 at a slot machine,
it now requires a human interaction to do some paperwork for the winnings,
for
taxes.
So, yeah,
-- for taxes,
-- the story is even crazier than that.
Well, so, and they, they're looking, you know, they're like, what?
So the way slot machines work in the
modern world is they're like all networked together.
And you basically as a casino say, like let's, let's, uh,
let's take like 3.7428% away from the punters and then like dial
that back at 5 p.m. to get more people in the door,
right?
So you, they literally have like a dial to adjust the, the odds, which, you know,
statistically speaking, over time
that works.
And so what they noticed was,
is that their slot machines were paying out like
a whole lot more money than they should be.
Right.
Like,
statistically over a period of time they should
do X and they were doing something different.
So, being a casino they pulled their surveillance tapes.
Right, because they have video cameras everywhere. And I,
yeah, and, and let's face it. Right. Data storage is so cheap now you can't,
you know, it'd be stupid not to keep a couple of years of data. But anyways,
and they pull these tapes and watch them and watch them and watch them
and they found these people um
that would basically play at the slot machine for a
little while and use their uh phone to like,
do something
and then they'd leave the slot machine and come back a
few minutes later or whatever and then they'd play and like
win
pretty consistently.
And so
uh through various investigation and going to like rental
car records and a whole bunch of other stuff,
they managed to identify one of the guys involved and um arrested him
and well, so as I understand it, the long and the short of it is
the person plays at the slot machine for a little while and
uses their phone to record the output of the like the,
the spins.
And when I say spins, I'm talking about like a video
image, you know, showing like a roll, uh a roller spinning,
they then upload this to some guys in, what was it? I think Saint Petersburg,
we'll say,
we'll say Russia
who I guess, then analyze this and then send back uh essentially,
like they know what this,
they can determine the state of the random number
generator and thus predict what's going to happen.
And, and this is where it gets, I mean, where I'm really impressed is, for example,
um they then tell the person like
when they're playing again, when to, you know,
hit on the machine with a quarter second, advance notice,
which is basically human reaction time.
And so then these guys, you know, basically consistently win or, you know,
have a much, much better advantage of winning.
And, um,
obviously this is like all kinds of illegal according to various gambling laws.
But, you know,
apparently the deal is that it see in my first reading of these stories, I assumed
that
they had hacked the machines or they put somebody in to modify the source code.
But apparently that's not the case.
It sounds like
the perpetrators
have figured out how to predict
the output of the random number generator inside of the slot machine.
Yeah, which I mean,
is entirely believable because let's face it right
when people start doing random number generators things,
uh, they quite often will do it wrong for just values of random numbers,
let alone security numbers, let alone well.
And luckily this isn't cryptography,
-- but this is a security application of numbers
-- in
cryptography.
True,
true.
Yeah. Well, and a perfect example. Right.
Because like,
true randomness means you would have say a string of 100 fours in a row at some point.
-- It is conceivable that that would happen.
-- Yes.
And obviously that would be a terrible thing to have happen to a casino machine.
You know, when somebody's playing it and
has a, has a good idea that this might happen.
Right. Right. And I suspect that's exactly the case.
So let's start here. Computers suck at random numbers.
Right?
Because math in general is very predictable. If one plus one
didn't always equal two.
Well, the world would be a mess.
Well, the real challenge too is, um,
so like the dirty secret is like Linux, for example, not just Linux, basically,
all the things
rely on some sort of random what's called entropy.
So, basically random sort of noisy data that can't be predicted or,
or even if you do have a set of it, you can't, you know,
um, find patterns in it. Really? Right.
It's just, it's like one of those, it's like a faucet dripping, you know,
at certain levels of water flow, it'll drip like once a second,
then it'll become chaotic and random and then it'll go back to being, you know, like,
like just a stream of water if you crank it up high enough, right?
And you kind of want that in between state where it's like unpredictable and,
and random.
Um, but the problem is on a computer, you know, where do you get
unpredictable random data?
And so in the past we've done things like, oh, you know,
the user typing and using the mouse and
events off the network and the, the hard drive doing stuff.
But, you know, especially like a slot machine, for example,
doesn't have a keyboard and a mouse hooked up to it.
I hope
it doesn't, it does have humans
pushing buttons.
Yeah. And you really probably don't want to rely on them for their source of entropy.
OK. So, but here's the deal is
in the computer universe, there are something called pseudo
random number generators and the intent behind this is
that they aren't actually producing random numbers per se.
It's a mathematical algorithm designed in such a way that you feed it a seed or input
right to start it off
and then it generates a string of numbers that may as well be random.
OK?
And now
if your random number generator,
if you can observe the output
and determine the internal state, basically the current seed
that is an insecure random number generator.
And that sounds like what happened in the case of these slot machines.
Yeah.
Part of what I'm wondering is like,
did they use a seed that is not big enough because it's kind of like passwords, right?
Like if you have a banking website and they only allow like a four
letter password.
You know, it doesn't really matter how good a password you try and pick.
I only have to guess, you know, a couple 1000 passwords to
and I can brute force it, you know.
And that's what I'm wondering with this seed. Like, was it a 32 bit seed?
-- Was it like for all we know, like a letter?
-- Well, it doesn't even matter.
The seed size, quite frankly, is even borderline, irrelevant to the discussion.
Because so, so the way it works in a lot of PR NGS
is
you input your seed, whatever.
And then every time you make a call to the random number generator,
it does some sort of math internally and it returns you a value.
And
ideally what happens is it doesn't give you the whole value.
What happens is say it'll generate a 32 bit number
and it will give you 16 bits
-- out of it,
-- right?
-- And keep 16 for generating
-- the essentially as part of the,
the new seed for the next call.
So you don't want people to be able to observe the
entire state of the random number machine as it were,
right?
And that, that's the intent. Exactly. And not only that when you're dealing with
something like a slot machine,
ideally,
you don't want it to be that you're only asking
for a random seed every time or I'm sorry,
a random number every time someone pushes a button or pulls the handle
you want it to be generating random numbers constantly.
And it,
it sounds like they may not have been doing that correctly
in this case because if there's some level of predictability,
you have a problem. Right.
That's the whole point is that the pseudo random numbers are unpredictable,
which means they're as good as random.
Yeah, I, I know I've looked in the past for test suites
to determine is the output of this thing,
random number generator or pseudo random number generator.
Is it
actually random? And is it actually random for the purposes of security?
And then worse? Is it actually random for the purposes of cryptography?
And as far as I know, we don't really have any such test suites.
No, there is there, there's a great one actually.
Yeah.
Yeah, there's a couple of them,
but the one I really like is something called die harder.
There was a test suit called die hard and then obviously somebody took
it and made it better and it's called die harder now and it,
you can feed it like literally gigabytes of randomness
and it will conduct a ton of tests over it,
looking for statistical anomalies in your random numbers and, and funny enough,
and this is part of it too when, when you run these tests,
it is expected that some of them will fail because if it's truly random,
there will be outputs that aren't statistically random, right?
So, but what happens if you for example,
take your random number source and then run it through like AES
to block encrypt it to even further mungle. You know, munge, the data
does would, for example, has,
have you tested it with like say like what should be bad input
mangled sufficiently? Does it pass?
I, I mean, in that case,
it probably would because if you're doing something like AES encryption,
it's designed to and, and I'm
so really
that's basically what a pseudo random number generator is, is you take a,
a known input something good and easy.
And then you put it into something, say like AES
and
it just keeps mangling itself as it produces
output and you take some of the output and
shove it back into the input and you end up with kind of a feedback loop.
One of the problems you get if you kind of do
that and you have to be smart about your algorithm.
And in fact,
if you have a series of books called The Art of Computer Programming by uh Donald
Knuth,
he spends quite a lot of time talking about randomness.
But one of the issues you get is any time you have kind of that feedback loop,
you will eventually repeat
where the this the machine will kind of reset itself and
start over from the beginning and output the exact same outputs.
And so obviously, one of the challenges
is to make sure that mathematically your algorithm can run for, you know,
I don't know, a couple million years maybe before it kind of loops.
And it is believed, for example, that the Linux kernel pseudo
random number generator could run for thousands of years before
it would have a loop of constantly output cryptographic.
Well, I shouldn't say cryptographic but rather uh secure random numbers.
Yeah.
So it's, it's a crazy topic, man and it's super,
super hard to get this right as we see and
I would expect slot machines to be better than most.
We.
Are there any good libraries for this or is it like a case of roll your own?
Because that's like we see this in the crypto world all the time with like
an even simpler example, like go connect to a remote host over TLS
and the vast majority of people get it wrong.
If you're rolling your own random number generator, you probably have issues.
I mean, this is just like rolling your own crypto, right? This is really hard to do
now, I don't know what kind of operating system a slot machine runs,
but I would assume
they should be able to rely on the operating system for a statistically random
number generator that they can use. And now it is conceivable they can't
do to various regulations because I know like when you're
dealing with a slot machine is uh especially in Vegas,
the, the Nevada Gaming Commission has very strict requirements about how it works.
And what it does
and you have to give them copies of source code so they can review it and there's,
there's all these rules.
And so it would not surprise me if
the random number generator was rolled by somebody.
And now additionally, so it is the way the story works.
The slot machines that were reverse engineered were
commandeered in Russia, reverse engineered.
And there are some of the same machines in Las Vegas,
which means you're dealing with a machine
that has been shipped to various places on the globe,
right?
And anytime you're dealing with
various,
we'll say multinational
organizations such as this, it,
things can get difficult because everyone has their own rules.
But fundamentally,
if you can
view
the output of the the wheels on a slot machine and determine its internal state,
there is some crazy problems going on and you
are obviously using a terrible random number generator.
Well,
and the thing is it doesn't even have to
be a terrible random number generator just has to,
you know, even a 10 or 20%
advantage
is enough.
Oh, yeah. No.
But I mean,
what I'm saying is like even a subtle mistake is
enough for the bad guys to win in this case,
you know, and that's part of the real problem, right?
Um You know, blackjack's always my favorite example, right?
If you play it clean, the house has a slight advantage.
If you card count wrong the house now has a 20 to 30% advantage.
And if you card count correctly, you now have like
an advantage in the single digits,
like, have fun with that.
This is, this is why I will never card count because it just sounds miserable.
I, I agree. It, it's a lot of work and, well, not only that, I mean, what's the real
payback here? All right.
Well, no, no, but I
mean,
I'm never gonna be betting enough money to really make a difference.
And so I view kind of petty gambling as, you know, entertainment,
not as I'm going to make money doing this because, I mean, let's face it,
like getting a job and working will often pay better.
Yeah. Sort of gambling scam.
Well, it's, it's happened in the past though. Uh, for example, uh, yeah, here we go.
Um, there was a, um, a Toronto, uh, I believe it was a professor anyways.
He, um,
found a pattern in the scratch lottery tickets
because so scratch lottery tickets obviously again,
used, like,
they use some sort of random number generator to not
only generate these tickets but then they have to,
you know, make sure that they have a certain amount winning and not winning.
Right?
Because you don't want to, like,
generate a million winning cards out of a million cards.
Zero
winning cards. Right. That's called fraud at that point.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. So,
um, he found a pattern in these cards and he was able to, like,
actually go and look at the cards and be, like, I'll have like, that one,
that one and that one and that one.
And it's funny because he phoned the Ontario Gaming commission and they're like,
yeah.
Yeah, whatever. Crazy guy.
So he actually, like, went out with the OL G apparently. And, um,
he's like, let's go to, like, a gas station, buy a bunch of cards and, like,
they'll all be winners and he did that and the old G guy basically pooped himself,
you know, and they had to recall the game.
But now at the end of that article even, he says that if he, if he did this, like,
as his job, he would make less money than he does as a professor.
Yeah, that's the thing.
Yeah, he was like, I could make max about 100 150 grand a year doing this.
-- I don't
-- think it's even that because I doubt
your professors are making 100 and 50 grand.
I think it was like an incredibly paltry amount
and it's a lot of work.
Let's face it because you have to keep
going to different gas stations and buying lottery
tickets and figuring out which ones win and
which ones lose and then scratching them off.
And
it's,
it's one of those instances where, like, the crime just doesn't pay.
So, but I'm wondering with these, see, one of the things I'm really wondering.
So, I'm assuming these lottery machines, like,
what's the deal on software updates for them?
Uh,
you mean slot machines?
Do they get software updates? Like, is there,
do you like? So I know a bunch of these things are based on Linux.
Do they get like a yum update with, you know?
No,
no, they don't.
I mean, no, no, you got to think this is like an industrial control application,
right? Where
things
get.
-- So
-- let's face it. First of all, first of all,
when you have a slot machine on the floor with
a button or maybe six buttons,
you're not kind of the threat model. There is different
than if it was on the internet, right?
I mean, let's face it if there is a slot machine with a public IP
but you're doing something terribly wrong there. Ok.
Let's just start with that.
And so
these things unquestionably will receive updates for various reasons,
but it's obviously well understood and it's gonna
be rolled out in a controlled manner.
It's not like, oh, hey, it's, you know,
Wednesday night time to update all the slot machines.
No, no, there's a reason for it. Right.
And, and people are gonna understand what's happening, why it's happening.
It doesn't make sense.
You know, it's like I said, it's just like industrial controls where
if you have a temperature sensor, let's say on a machine,
you're not gonna willy nilly update it, right?
You're gonna wait for the machine to go down and then you're gonna be like,
does this make sense?
Do I need this?
-- And you might not? Right.
-- You might, because the other problem is, is, um,
some of these things,
are they using random number generators that are tied to the hardware?
Maybe
it is
conceivable that some of them are.
I, I don't, that part isn't totally clear to me
because I
know
-- you remember
-- back in the day A MD came out with that, um
They came out with a hardware-based R and G based on thermal noise within the CPU
and it was able, you know,
or Intel has their um oh
jeez, I'm forgetting the name of it. RD. Rand,
you know, uh that then aes encrypts it and shoves out like,
what is it like 10 gigabits per second of random data or something if you really want?
Right. Well, it should be clarified that the,
these internal hardware, random number generators are,
the trick is, and I, I think this is probably true of when you're dealing with,
with like a slot machine.
It's,
it's difficult to prove them
right or wrong sometimes because they could be broken
and
you don't know.
-- Right. Well,
-- speaking of broken, uh I don't know if you saw yesterday
um Intel's Adam C 2000 processor family
has a, like a defect in the timing circuits. And so like,
yeah, I'm a little annoyed because I own one of these.
Like,
I have a PF sense firewall here that
apparently might break itself if I reboot in about
a year.
So I'm a little bit annoyed.
I mean,
-- that's
-- a feature planned obsolescence.
I would assume that these places are rolling their own,
uh,
crypto and not relying on the operating system for that exact reason you just
stated is that they can sort of then say that they control it more
and perceived control is, you know, better. Right. Even if it is terrible.
Yeah, that's, that's probably fair.
And this is something that's really hard to get, right? Random numbers are hard.
Does G Lipsy not have a slot like slot, you know, random underscore slot.
Uh G
lib C just added actually, no, no, they, they just added a
system call on the version that came out a couple of days ago. In fact,
that's
true.
No, it's not the hardware stuff. It's the kernel based,
right? And, and so essentially where the kernel gets
its entropy and randomness from is up to the system administrator to decide because
like you said,
you've got the Intel and a MD hardware-based providers which you can use,
you can add cards to your systems that add randomness, you can
-- do nothing.
-- There's actually a website you can get randomness from
-- uh
-- which one, the lava lamps.
No,
there's like an actual website that will return random
data for the purposes of use with cryptography.
And I don't know if it was a joke or legit.
-- But it's, there,
-- there are,
there are various things that do that and I would be hesitant to trust any of.
It's
probably
not.
Right.
It, it depends what you need it for. Right. In some cases it could make sense.
In many cases. It could not.
Well,
I remember back in the day there was a website that would use
lava lamps to generate entropy and it had webcams set up taking pictures
-- actually
-- random.
I assume they are, they look fairly random and he had like 10 of them or something or
like a whole bunch of them on a wall.
And like he had this all automated because like a lava lamp,
you're supposed to turn off for eight hours a day or something like that.
And so various lamps would turn on and off and then I, I think it was,
the picture was taken through like a prism or something.
So it even messed up the image even more. And,
and he did all this crazy stuff. Generally speaking,
it sounded relatively secure.
-- But
-- a perfect example of this is uh the enigma
machine that the Germans used in World War Two,
right?
It had, it had the, it had a um so they basically had two main
um
systems. It had the rotors
and the rotors had like basically 26 letters on each
side and they were like randomly wired to each other.
So like on one side, A was on the other side, it was R and like B to Q and whatever.
And so there were three of these rotors originally
and then four and then I believe at 1.5.
Um And so the rotors would also rotate.
So essentially, every time you sent a letter through it would,
you'd get whatever response back plus, then it would rotate the uh rotor once and,
you know, once that rotor had rotated 26 times,
then the next rotor would rotate once and, you know, so on with the third one
and then there was also the shucker
board, the like sticker board, which was
you manually plugged like
letters together using wires.
And so there would be like a day code for the stucker board like, you know,
today QSP and RS,
whatever,
despite all this apparent randomness and mathematically like it
on paper was like, you know, 10 to the some obscenely huge number.
But, you know, there were some subtle flaws in it that allowed the allies to do
crypto analysis and build the bomb machines
that could then brute force the, the codes for the day.
So
I,
and so it looks great and they added all these
because what's interesting is the Germans actually got this design.
It was a Swiss commercial design originally, right?
The Swiss guy did it for commercial,
you know, companies to use, like to send, you know, secret messages, you know,
like go by IBM stock or whatever.
Um and they, you know,
and they took it and they, like,
made it more complicated because that's one
thing I've noticed with a lot of security
people will add complexity and be like, oh,
it's better now because there's like more steps involved.
-- And
-- uh,
yeah, you know, so like, uh a great example of that being two factor authentication,
we can easily complicate authentication and add stuff to it.
But
it may like my great favorite being my bank has multiple factor
authentication in the form of I have multiple passwords with them,
right? They have my secret, they're known as a secret question.
Well, and it technically is multiple factors, but they're all the same type.
So they all have the exact same failure scenario which is somebody like
watches me type it in or somebody sniffs my keyboard or whatever, you know,
but one attack will get all of them.
-- Ok.
-- But let's go back to enigma first. And the
topic of randomness is
the enigma itself
was
pretty good.
The
problem,
the problem wasn't really the enigma.
The problem is the Germans sent the weather report every single,
like very German of them, right?
Every day, same thing.
And so the allies had a message
-- they could, they were looking for,
-- they had a known plain text attack, right?
Because yeah,
this guy started the weather report at the same time with Heil Hitler and all that.
But even without that,
they, the allies still would have been able to crack it.
-- It just would have been much, much harder.
-- It would have been different.
I don't think they would have had near the rate of success they did.
I mean,
they reached a point where they were cracking the code for the day by lunchtime.
Right. That would not have been the case. Had there not been,
you know, known plain text
or
even with them,
like cracking the day code from a week ago and reading
all those clear text messages would still be hugely helpful.
Yes.
And so this brings us back to the slot
machine now is if you're doing randomness correctly,
even if people can figure out what the random
number is inside of the random number generator,
it shouldn't be valuable to them.
And this is even more crazy than that
because this isn't just the internal random state.
This is seeing something on the outside which, you know, every,
every time you use some randomness,
you should essentially be shedding some bits is the idea.
So you, you know,
the the random number generator doesn't return all the
bits and then if you're doing something with it,
you wouldn't return all, you know what I mean as it's as it's going along.
And so I would expect by the time
it makes it to
the end user,
you, I would, I would think you've gone from say 32 bits to like six,
right?
And if you can figure out the random state from that
you have a seriously broken generator.
Yeah. No, it's well and well, and actually I'm gonna s
technically disagree with you on this.
I mean, you may have a valid generator but you're using it wrong.
That too is possible.
No, I'm, I'm gonna say no, if you can
predict the internal state of a random number generator,
it is a broken generator by design. And I'm just going to categorically say that.
-- So
-- you're saying the generator internally should already be hiding and masking
-- part of the output.
-- So,
so essentially we're not allowing people to do dumb,
like even if they do do dumb things, the generator itself will be like, no, I,
I've already internally accounted for that.
If I collect a gigabyte of random data from the Linux kernel,
you know, dev you random
and I give it to you. You should not be able to figure out what the next bit
or I'm sorry
the next bit. Yes, you 50% chance of guessing. But the next bite
that comes out of that generator, right? You should not be able to do that.
If you can do that. That is a broken generator.
No, I'll agree with you on that.
And I mean, I guess it really boils down to is, you know, how much of this
is sort of happening within the generator and how much is the
generator passing stuff to the application which then does stupid stuff.
It's probably a combination of everything
right
now. We always assume sort of that. Oh, they made a mistake.
But how do we know this wasn't malicious.
I, I wouldn't say it's impossible but I would guess it was
an accident.
I think the vast majority of problems like this are accidents.
I suspect this is true. But,
uh, at the same time I, I mean, the people writing this stuff, I, I
would go to Ockham's Razor and say that no,
they're not so smart that they're maliciously doing this.
It would be like, no, they're,
they took comp sign and they're good at
comp sci but they're not good at random numbers
and that just people are people and this is where we ended up, you know,
much like, you know, every time we build a bridge that falls down,
like the engineers really didn't mean for that to happen.
That's right.
So I've been watching disaster, uh, documentaries again. Some really bad ones.
I just really small flaws.
Like they painted over the cracks so they couldn't
visually inspect them and then like 50 years later,
oops, it fell down.
Right. That what a great idea guys,
-- it'll
-- be,
you gotta paint the bridge so it doesn't rest.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, you do.
I, I won't disagree with that,
but it's damned if you do. Damned if you don't
know.
Uh, I guess maybe the moral of the story is they should all buy a di somatic.
What is it? Di somatic?
-- This
-- guy built this crazy mechanical machine that rolls a bunch
of six sided dice like a million times a day.
Right.
-- It's got the most beautiful, horrible
-- noise.
It is fantastic.
It was not only did you ever see that the dice wear out rather quickly, actually.
Yeah.
Yeah, I was, uh, II, I don't remember if I saw a video or I read a thing about this, But,
yeah, he was talking about the long,
well, you gotta think as you roll a square, dye
it round around. Right.
And so eventually it becomes nearly unusable because it's so rounded
because I know casinos, like, regularly, like,
I think on a daily basis or even more change out their cards and their dice and,
-- you know,
-- oh,
man, they change them constantly.
I mean, so the last time I was in Vegas,
actually I bought a bunch of cards and dice because they,
they sell the old ones in the shops
and it's, it's fun, you know, I,
I love casino dice because they're so big and cool looking
and in theory they are perfectly balanced.
Right? So they
say,
but no, no, it's, uh, they have rules about when they change the dice and, like,
if you roll, I think every time when you're playing craps you roll, uh, 21 snake eyes,
they change a dice
like every time.
Yeah. Yeah.
And there's, there's a bunch of rules. Well, I mean, I get it right.
They want, they want to keep the dice moving because none of this is perfect. Right.
I'm sure they're doing,
probably trying to palm
the dice and swap them and God knows what else.
Yeah, I'm sure it happened.
Well, you're gonna get your legs broke but it's conceivable.
It's conceivable if somebody tries. But, I mean, practically speaking,
if you change the dice constantly then it's just
you,
but you,
unless you bring like a purse full of them,
but here's the deal, right?
Is the casinos are probably buying dice by
the truckload and they probably test what,
10% of them, maybe less for, for various, we'll say dice quality issues.
I have no idea what that means.
-- Sigma worked out.
-- I have no doubt. I, I can,
it would be fascinating to watch what they do
but they'd probably have to like blind or something.
One of the funny things is for dice.
I know one of the simplest tests is they have a spinner for it.
They have, it's two little arms that hold the dye
and they just spin the dye.
Uh, you can do that with, with water.
You, you, uh, if you drop, well, not all dice, I've tried this, a lot of,
a lot of my dice actually sink.
But
if,
if you, uh, mix salt in with water and drop the dice in,
you can see if they're evenly weighted or if they are consistently kind of, you know,
falling to a certain state because obviously one side's heavier than the other.
But anyway, here's my point about casino dice. Right.
They're buying it by the truckload.
They're testing a small number of them
and you know, that some of those dice would fail testing if they were put in testing.
And so obviously, by changing them on a consistent basis,
even when you might have a set of dice that
favor the player or favor the house for that matter.
Right? Because let's face it. When you're a casino,
you, you don't want to win all the time.
Because if you, if the players never win, they don't come back. Right?
They have to win sometimes
in psycho
psychology, right? Like they've done the thing,
the rats where if you give the rat a lever to get a
food pellet every time the rat eats as much food as they need
and leaves and goes and has an out. But if you make it a random reward,
-- those poor little rats just sit there hammering away at the lever.
-- I
know it's uh you know, that's the thing I love about Las Vegas. It is,
it is like a place built to entertain monkeys
because everything there is about just like it appeals to that, that monkey brain,
you know, prehistoric of humans to draw you in and keep you there.
And it's like everything blinks, everything makes no, you know,
push button win push button.
Win. Yay me. Look what
it's just,
oh, I love it. It's, it's amazing
on so many levels and, like,
I know they're just abusing every innate feature of my brain when I go there.
But I still like it amuses me to no end. And I love it.
You know, it's funny you mentioned this,
we didn't have this in the show notes for today,
but Google apparently has started hiring
some,
you know, neuroscientists and whatnot
to help them make better security warnings. In Chrome.
I
saw that.
That was
awesome.
Yeah, because I'll admit to, you know, so there's this, there's a well known, uh,
thing called alarm fatigue.
Uh, and a great example of it is hospitals, right? Like
you have all this equipment that like beeps and buzzes, you know,
if your heart rate drops your, whatever, you know,
you fall out of whatever parameters are set.
And so the problem is like, um, you know,
these things are going off constantly and then people start to ignore them.
Right? Because 99.9 times out of 100
it's nothing really serious.
It's just the sensor shifted or the guy rolled over or whatever. Right.
But it's, you know,
and then that one in 1000 times the poor guy is having a heart attack or whatever.
Um,
and so what they found at one hospital is they disabled,
like 90% of the lower level alarms and
they actually found it vastly improved things and,
you know, the same thing with here, right.
We're, we're dealing with, you know,
every time people get that browser warning that pops up says that.
Do you really wanna like, install like dancing hamster dot exc and you know,
and one day they're, they're either going to accidentally or otherwise
click. Yes.
Well, it's even more crazy than that is, let's say a browser boarding pops up
as you're watching a youtube video.
What are you gonna do? Right. I, I'm watching a dancing bear.
I'm gonna click, go away now because I wanna watch that bear dance.
Whereas if they wait till the video is done
now, I'm like, oh, wow. A pop up. What is that? Right?
I totally get this because
I have been in multiple situations.
Like my favorite example is when you're about to give a presentation,
you plug in your laptop and it's like there are 400 critical updates for you.
Like click, go away. Right? You're not gonna install them right?
Then you're about to give a presentation.
Although, although funny enough,
I've also been in talks where people plug their computer in and they
start talking and Windows is like rebooting to install updates and it like,
they don't have a choice, right?
And you just sit there. It's like if you ran Linux
it wouldn't do that.
Yeah. I always like the day that I leave, I, I update
-- everything.
-- I never update the day I leave. I usually do it two or three days before.
And so funny enough, I was on a trip one time and this was, I was gone for, I think,
eight or nine days
and on the,
I get to the airport and my phone tells me there's an update to Android.
I'm like, I so wanna click install but like,
I can't do this while I'm not at home
because if my phone disappears and no longer works,
I'm like, totally out of luck.
You think?
Well, these days when you travel, like my plane tickets on my phone,
my taxi is on my phone, my directions, like everything is there.
If I didn't have my phone,
you find me like wandering, you know, alone in the streets,
homeless with no clothes or something.
Like it would be horrible.
No, I agree completely. Like, uh
yeah,
this is one of the reasons I take my ipad with me is
I sort of have a copy of most of what's on my phone,
on my ipad.
I have a tablet and that's true. I could.
No, I'm not going to find out. No stop this. It's not
iphone. It just all auto
-- sync and yeah,
-- you know, it doesn't matter. Right?
And an iphone can poop itself just as easily as an Android phone,
right? But I mean, it's easier to keep an iphone and an ipad in sync.
-- But
-- then I would need an ipad and then I'd probably need a Mac and it would just,
it would be like the downward spiral curd.
I don't need that.
II, I,
I gave up a long time ago. I just don't want to fight with stuff anymore.
I know. I know. I know. We, we discuss this all the time.
Yeah. But, uh, going back to the random numbers. So
these Russians, you know, they're, they're not giving people the software to do it.
Although I'm guessing that, you know,
the software to do it probably requires some CPU time or whatever.
And I'm assuming they're renting time on, like GP US or something to crunch it.
But, um, because of the way they've set it up, uh, the,
the, the article in Wired stated
that these guys who are actually physically going to the casinos
and playing to win the money then have to send like,
90% of it back to Russia.
Yeah.
Well, not only that, the, like you said,
they're using their cell phone to essentially, like, like Skype, the, the,
you know, the mothership
and they're doing and the beauty of that as
well is even if the authorities confiscate that phone,
they don't know exactly what's going on. Like, we don't know exactly how this works.
We have no idea.
And so, yeah, I mean, it's just,
it's really interesting that they maintain that level of, you know,
the bad guys are, are, I hate to say it,
but the bad guys are getting really smart and this is a, you know, an extremely,
you know, an extreme form of DRM effectively,
you know, it's, it's, well, it's,
yeah, it's cheating
service, you know.
Right.
But, but, well, you have a great point here is you, you mentioned, you know,
crime is getting more, I, I guess complex and nuanced is,
you know, crime inc is kind of being become known as a thing.
I've seen it referenced in, in much literature up to this point.
And if I was going to say so,
I think Crime Inc is innovating faster than our industry is.
-- Oh, for sure.
-- And that's kind of terrifying,
but they have more of an incentive to,
they have a huge,
you know, every time a hole gets plugged, they,
you know, like, remember I remember back in the day, you know, like when they would,
um,
they would just register domain names because you had like,
what a couple of days to register it for free before it lapsed
and they just, they, they killed that by what is it a 25 cent fee now?
Boom, upfront, 25 cent fee.
So it's not really worth it.
So now, you know, they're,
they're hacking people's domain accounts and setting up subdomains,
you know.
So, like,
because the reality too is these guys, like, they're, they have budgets,
right?
They have to have return on investment otherwise, you know,
Luigi is gonna break their legs.
Yeah.
Well, So this is one of the challenges we have as well is in a lot of security work.
There isn't really a return on investment.
There's ideally something terrible doesn't happen,
but you can't prove something terrible.
Like, how many times did you not get hacked today, Kurt?
And see
that's, and I told you this phrase. But, uh, for our listeners,
I was watching an airline safety thing and it was a case in Brazil
where they ran off the runway and crashed big time and there's a whole,
there's like basically three different sets of factors.
But, but
anyways,
the point being is the senior guy talking about this,
talked about how
they,
they need to investigate this and they need to deal with this so that they can quote,
continue improving the safety record unquote,
not like prevent air crashes and not like, make sure this never happens again.
But just overall, statistically, like, globally, you know, when you get on a plane,
there's like that chance of you not stepping off that plane alive,
you know, it keeps getting better and better.
Like chances are you're gonna be ok,
you know, same thing with cars, right?
Cars with airbags and with seat, you know, three point seatbelts and with
now side impact airbags and with, you know, crumple zones and all of that, you know,
every time you step in a car now you're, you know,
there's less of a chance you're not going to get out of that car alive
and I, I eagerly,
-- our computer overlords driving us everywhere we need to go.
-- Oh, me too.
Yeah,
I rear ended some poor lady last night at like
five kilometers an hour on a sheet of ice.
And I just physically could not stop.
Like, when I actually got out of the car to make sure she was ok.
I almost fell over on my ass because it was so slippery
like it. Yeah, because people were spinning their tires.
We had some fresh snow and so boom, I,
you know, it's a left turn lane, right. Awesome.
Um, but anyways, you know, and, but I think part of the problem is, you know,
we don't have any sort of overall like safety
board for computers or the internet or whatever.
So we have no idea what our current accident rate is.
It probably wouldn't be very good.
No.
You know, and then part of the problem too is like, we don't,
a
lot of what happens in computers isn't really accidents.
It's like a hacker doing something intentionally malicious,
you know,
and most industries don't have to deal with the
level of this that we have to deal with.
Right. Like,
you know, mcdonald's, for example,
doesn't have like a million people trying to
walk into their stores virtually with knives,
robbing them,
you know, same for banks. Right. They have a lot.
Yeah. But I mean, it's a, it's a known and understood pro problem.
Like, you know, uh, if you go to a bank now they have like,
that little armored ATM computer thing where
all the cash comes out of it and all the cash goes into, you know,
they don't have drawers full of cash anymore,
-- or at least in Canada they don't
-- vault has no money in it.
Yeah.
You know, I went to deposit some cash and, like, in past I haven't done this in like,
10 years and past they would have shoved it into their drawer.
Now. She, like, fed it into this, like, big armored, the machine and it, like,
disappear.
-- Well,
-- it's, it's very similar to the safes in gas stations,
electronic and the,
the guy working behind the counter can't open it and the register
has a couple of 100 bucks in it at the most.
Yeah, exactly.
And so, you know, we're dealing with the unique challenges but fundamentally,
and this is one of the reasons I, I want to extend CV is I wanna get AAA,
I wanna get a sense of how bad it is.
You know, every time I see these, uh, articles like, um,
that article from France where they were talking about like
25 or 27 or whatever, 20 some 1000 cyber attacks from Russia regarding the election.
And I'm like,
what does that even mean? Like, is that a port scan? Is that an actual login attempt?
Is that
like what?
Right. Yeah.
And it's not well defined and a lot of
these organizations that publish this kind of stuff,
they have an agenda so they wanna play it up.
Right.
Yeah, I mean,
technically every single port scan is a hack attempt or is it a part of like,
just one guy running n map against your entire entire class?
B?
Um, so, yeah, speaking of the cyber,
you know, there's that guy that scanned,
like all of North Korea like repeatedly because apparently
North Korea has like a slash 22 of address space
and then like two other address blocks one through uh what was it?
China, some Chinese telecom provider
and the other one through a European satellite provider. And it's like,
does that count as a cyber attack or
-- did
-- he shut down their
delink router or, I mean,
actually he found a Cisco router with remotely
accessible sh port 8443 and something else.
But yeah, so going back to this, I mean, with these things, we just,
we kind of don't know
the state of how bad it is, you know, I mean, I've, I've not,
I've seen numbers on supposed losses to cybercrime
and they're like all over the place.
In some cases, I've seen, you know, hundreds of billions of dollars.
Well,
it's a very political topic still because you have the defenders want to
play it up because they want more budget to do what they do.
And then you have some realists who try to be like, uh, I don't think it's quite there.
-- And then
-- you have about your militant moderates,
-- yes,
-- militant moderate. That's true.
Uh, that my, my blog post, we won't get into that right now.
We can, we can cover that maybe in the future.
But then you've also got essentially people who deny it
who think everything's great and nothing's wrong and who's right.
You know, if I had to guess it's in the middle, I mean, it generally is. Right.
Any time you have people on either side of any sort of argument,
the answer is almost always in the middle.
Yeah. No, it's, um, well, and the problem too is it's not evenly distributed.
Right. So, for some people it is truly terrible and for other people it's like,
mm,
I
mean, that's fair. That's fair. Right.
I, I can only imagine what the likes of Facebook and Google see per day
on the attack scale. It's gotta be outrageous.
One thing I discovered I was buying some Ticketmaster tickets.
You have four attempts to lock in to log in before they lock your account.
-- That seems fair. I think most online
-- all you
-- need
-- is a person's email address.
-- Yeah. And then
-- you
-- can
-- lock to lock their account.
I assume you can unlock it somehow.
Right?
I hope so. Oh, ok.
If not
poorly designed, you should. I know your email address. Kurt, I'll, I'll find out.
Please don't. I'm still trying to get some tickets swapped.
I see.
Well, let's face it too in the case of that,
like worst case you pick up your telephone and you call them, right?
And they're gonna help you out on the phone.
So as long as there's alternative means to go around some of these, it's ok.
-- I don't have an issue,
-- but that can also be a problem because for example,
I know someone that just had their Instagram account hacked.
Um, you know, they tried to,
they got, um, an actual text message from a friend saying, you know, I,
I tried to take you on an Instagram picture and it says your accounts like
wonky or something. So
this person tried to log into their account and they couldn't.
And then they, um,
uh, it basically said, like, helpful, you know, like we've changed, uh,
they went to do the, uh, the password reset and they're like, oh, you know,
we've emailed your new password to, you know,
um, a partially obfuscated email address ending in.ru
and this person's like, whoops. No, that's not me.
Um, and it's,
it's crazy is Instagram and Facebook actually have like a reasonably sane
account recovery procedure that involves like filling out a web form.
And then essentially they have you send like a
proof of life picture of like yourself with,
uh, like a, it was like a seven digit code number written down on it.
Like you have to write on this piece of paper, your name,
your email address and this like seven digit random code they send,
you take a picture of that and send it back to them.
Uh, and then, you know, hope, well, you'll see what happens. And, I mean,
it's interesting to me because there, for example,
like Facebook and Instagram theoretically would,
well, they'd have pictures of you quite often.
Right.
Right. Right.
Well, I, I wonder if their a is, are smart enough to figure out that, you know,
the guy who just sent a picture uh in is,
is the same guy in, you know, 90% of the pictures that are on this account.
Although
that wouldn't always work because like, in my case, in various things like that,
I never post pictures of myself.
Well, but, or even simple things like just,
just reset the account to the previous email address and reset the password,
you know, unless the person sold the account and is then hijack
it back to resell it again or something, you know,
it's generally not going to be a huge problem.
I would hope there's not a huge market in selling your own Instagram account.
-- Uh
-- There is for Twitter, that Twitter bot
thing that was like, what 350,000 accounts, you know.
So there is
people trying to monetize these things through, you know,
selling likes or shares or
-- whatever
-- it's different, right? I mean,
you can create a fake Twitter account.
That's not hard to do.
No.
But if it's easy to hijack an account,
you can grab real accounts that have established credit and history.
I see what you're saying.
You know, it's like Reddit, right? I have a nine year old account at Reddit.
I mean, same thing has happened with DNS now, right.
One of the, one of the good predictors for DNS shenanigans is,
how fresh is this domain,
right? Like,
you know, with DNS domain names, the, you know,
if a domain name is like more than a decade old, chances are,
it's probably not involved in too many, you know,
shenanigans or not naughty things,
you know, same thing with like a linkedin or Facebook account.
You know, it's, if it's 10 or 20 years old, either, you know,
these bad guys are playing the Long Con which
generally speaking from what I've seen they don't bother with,
you know, these guys want immediate returns.
Yeah, there's, there's no money in the long Con. Let's face it.
It's you, when you're doing crime, you need to get in and get out.
I mean, that's, that's the return on investment there.
It's just like this random generator on the slot machine.
Like they, no, this scam won't last forever.
And in fact,
I would imagine Vegas is paying attention to this and as soon
as they have a machine that the payout isn't quite right.
It's gone. Right. They're gonna, they're gonna yank it off.
The floor immediately and they're gonna replace it with something
else and they're gonna start paying attention to this because,
I mean, it is what it is. Right.
And I,
I guess ironically they have the big data to back
this up and so they will know when something isn't.
Right.
I'm guessing what has happened in the past is security consultants have had,
have said, oh, you know, we're not 100% certain about this random number generator.
In theory somebody could xy and Z but,
you know, unless you pay me like 100,000 bucks to spend the time actually doing it.
I, I'm not gonna say yes or no conclusively.
Well, somebody in Russia did it for them.
Like I remember all the times where, you know, oh, this flaw isn't exploitable.
And then, you know, a week later somebody comes up with a
melo module.
I remember being one of those people that was quite happy
to assure the world something wasn't exploitable and that it was.
And so now in my old age,
I've become smart enough to never say something is impossible
because it always is, man. It just takes a smart person long enough to get you there.
All right. I think it's time, Kurt.
We should wrap this one up for those of you listening.
You can go to open source Security podcast.com and get links to
all of the exciting and bizarre things we've talked about today.
You can find a link there to our Twitter
handles. So, Kurt and I love feedback by all means, send it to us.
You can find a link to we have a Facebook group.
You're welcome to join and have various
discussions with other like minded individuals.
There are obviously past shows and all the other fun things as well.
And
I guess I have nothing else to say, Kurt.
I would like you to have a fantastic rest of the day.
And thanks for listening, everybody.
-- Yeah. And, uh, well, we look forward to seeing you at RS A
-- Absolutely.
Yeah, if you're going to Rs A, let us know and we could, you know,
maybe catch up and have a chat or something.
And I guess given the topic of the show, shall we leave on a random number?
Six,
1717, everybody.
-- That's a good random number. Sure.
-- It is. It is a good random number.
All, all random numbers are good, Kurt.
There are no such thing as bad random numbers. Only bad random number generators.
Two is a pretty bad random number.
Have a good day, Kurt.
You too.