Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner and not trying to boil the ocean. Josh Bresser,
I lack the ability to boil the ocean, but I would totally do it if I could
not. If you keep driving a car,
I
just realized using that expression.
I'm like, because every year now is the hottest year on record
so far for like the last five years.
But no, in this case,
we're actually talking about uh like sort of
the metaphorical boiling of the information security ocean
and how there are just,
there are certain classes of problems where
you just kind of have to get everybody on board.
I mean,
it's all going to do it for sure. And it's huge.
Yeah.
And
so,
but the good news now is that there are
a couple of entities
that both have the capability of boiling the ocean
and apparently sort of the willingness to do so.
So we're going to go off on a tiny quick tangent first. So
I was just poking around my Google security settings
for Google workspace because I'm trying to audit,
I'm trying to get a list of all our privileged users
to like audit and make sure random people don't have privileges.
They shouldn't.
It seems like a good idea.
Yeah,
it's very difficult to find. But
yeah,
but I ran across a setting that basically says they're going to be blocking access to
insecure apps uh in July of 2024.
So in a few months from the recording of this podcast.
So for those of you who don't know,
you can use your Google account to authenticate to other
stuff using like single sign on O I DC,
all that crap stuff.
But there are,
they used to, well, they still do,
they would allow apps
though where the app needs access to your Google account.
And they would literally let you give that app, your user name and password
so that, that app could like log into your account and like
do stuff
and, and back in the day,
this would have been something like your email client running on your phone.
Sure, fine.
But
nowadays, it's also like a web based third party
plug in that like,
I don't know, spell checks your file names, whatever in Google Drive.
And so they're getting rid of that because obviously there's been some, you know,
it can lead to security problems when you let people hand
out their user name and password and allow it to be used
and don't enforce like two fa or M fa or whatever.
And so
I love that because it's actually going to break applications for people,
especially a lot of old stuff because by definition, the old stuff is what did this
and it's that old stuff that, you know,
finding a replacement for it or whatever is going to be a chore because, you know,
people have been using it for five or 10 years and, well,
if they wanted to find a replacement for it, they would have no.
Right. Like,
like I have Google advanced account protection enabled
on my account because I'm a super admin
and like
the Zoom calendar plug in doesn't work with it last I checked. Oh, interesting.
I didn't know there,
there's a lot of stuff,
there's a lot of stuff you would expect not to work because it's just not very secure,
well written.
And that's actually one of my new tests for when I,
when I check out a cloud vendors will
their stuff work with advanced account protection enabled.
And like Zoom, I can log into Zoom, I can use Zoom,
but I can't use the calendar plug in,
you know, because it, it just does whatever old version of authentication, but
-- it
-- does something it shouldn't do.
Well, it's, it's secure, but when you enable advanced account protection,
it's like everything has to be the most secure protocol in setting,
you know, whatever
it is, what it is.
-- So
-- that's it, it's interesting to me that for example,
like Google closing this loophole is gonna,
it's gonna stop a, a pretty reasonable number of security incidents,
full stop. But what's really fascinating. So, Github,
-- uh just announced a new thing. So why don't you explain to us what it is?
-- Yeah.
So github has something. They're calling artifact at a stations. It's in
public
-- data which whatever that means, it
-- means you can turn it on and use it if you want to,
but you're not like kind of forced into it
or, and it's like you have to kind of go searching for it.
It's not like my understanding is like, remember with the security advisory stuff,
it was in beta and you could turn it on and now it's like, it's kind of in your face in
the interface if you
like, it's kind of like you should turn this on, you don't have to,
but you should turn this on.
OK? Anyway, anyway, that's
not the topic
because
if you don't make people use the stuff, they won't use it.
And that's a good point and we'll definitely touch
on that eventually in this conversation because you're right,
most people won't use it.
It's what is, it?
Didn't like Google do a study and like 4%
of users change defaults or something like that.
-- I would be shocked if it was 4%.
-- It might not be. I mean, it's like
a,
it's like a conversation the other day about Factorio where
you were saying you can turn off the bugs.
I'm like, I've literally never looked at the settings
and I haven't, and I still haven't, I just haven't played Factorio in like a year,
-- but
-- I would literally be shocked if more than one percent of people
actually significantly change a default setting on pretty much anything they use,
be it security or
like
-- dark mode or whatever,
-- for sure,
for sure. Ok. Anyway, so github
has these artifact at of stations And what they're basically doing
is you can add
a workflow. I think it's called a workflow in this context. No.
Yeah, workflow.
So basically what happens is after you build your artifact in the github
Magic
C
-- I system.
-- What is an artifact
-- in the context of
-- this completely undefined?
-- Anything? It's
-- anything,
it could be a tar ball, it could be
anything,
it could be S
bombs, you can, you can sign whatever.
And this is important because it's
so it's, it's literally, it could be text files, could be compiled files, it could be
collated files like a zip file.
And, and the idea is when you generate your releases in the github
Magic C I,
you can also sign it.
Now,
you can create an at a station that uses sig
store in a bunch of sig store magic that then
you can verify the signed thing you have acquired. Downloaded.
Basically is the thing that was built
and these conversations always amuse me because you've got a bunch of people
that think it does something it doesn't do or it creates like,
oh, we can stop XZ with this.
It's like, no, this isn't. No, we can't. Like, not at all.
XZ would have totally been signed by this.
And in fact, they, they're even good about that at the very end of the article,
they basically say that right?
Like
it,
it is, you know,
but it, it says here
they bolded it.
I just noticed and it says it's important to note that provenance
by itself doesn't make your artifact or your build process secure.
That's right.
If you have a backdoor build process, you are now signing your backdoor build.
-- That is what is happening.
-- Well, this is like a perfect example. This is solar winds.
They
had had a
backdoor build process and what I love is they had improperly signed binaries and
they told everybody to just like mash that override button and get her installed.
And so that's, that's another thing is there is a failure
here that is shockingly common, which is I really want to install this software.
I don't care if it's signed improperly or whatever.
That's right. Well, and we've all done it.
This is a good example of where some people do change the default setting,
which is on Mac Os.
You can no longer by default run unsigned
binaries or binaries signed by a third party.
It has to be part of the Apple ecosystem
and that is one of the few settings myself and other people I know,
turn off because I want to install software that I need, I need to do stuff
-- to do stuff like my job.
-- Exactly.
Ok. So, anyway,
github
now has this worker
that
you build your artifact, you add, it's a couple lines to a file basically
that says once my artifact is built,
I want you to sign it
with
cigar
and then,
-- so it's s store on the back end.
-- Correct.
Yeah. Yeah. They're, they're relying on
SAR and they've got, that's weird how they're doing it, but we'll,
we'll get to that in a second.
But basically, then what happens is you can verify the signature
of the thing
and
I, I cannot figure out how to do it without the github
command line tool, the GH tool. It looks like all the instructions.
Everything I found you need that tool
to phone home to
github to get
the at a station content, which is an in total predicate.
It doesn't matter what that is.
But basically the idea is github has added this
ability where you can use sig store to sign things
and then store those signatures for use later, which
on the surface
is not,
I think hugely useful because the reality is if you build something in
github C I and then you host it for release out of github,
the odds of that being back doored in some way
are
miniscule small it's zero.
Basically,
from what I can tell they've effectively recreated the idea of having archive
name dot whatever extension dot A SC with the external uh you know,
ASY
signature of it, like the P GP signature of that thing.
And the only real difference between this and what we were doing 30 years ago
is that now that, that,
that signature is hosted in SIG store and there's some
tooling wrapped around it to make it easier to validate.
That's really all this does.
I think the fact that they're using SIG store, the way they are is very cool
because historically, if you're going to
software, you would have to build it probably on your own machine.
Where else would you build it?
Obviously?
I mean,
well, but here's the thing like today, if you're going to sign software,
let's pretend I have AC I system that works and I'm not using my laptop, right?
I send my software up to the C I system.
There is now a step where I have to go from C I,
the output of C I to somehow getting key material into my process signing the thing
and then publishing the signature as well as the artifact.
And I think in a lot of instances you have people download the artifact from the C I,
they sign it and then they upload it somewhere else, right? And, and
what is protecting that key? Like who knows what's going on?
-- I
-- mean, in my mind,
you might as well just be publishing the shaw 256 sums of that artifact
on a somewhat trustworthy platform and you would essentially get the same thing,
right.
Largely
fascinating to me is like, ok, so, ok, let's be real.
I, I've decided on a new thing which is, this is not in and of itself helpful.
However, it's plumbing and if you want a nice toilet, you need plumbing first,
-- then you can install the toilet
-- and,
and here I think that's the important part of this
whole conversation and that's why because it was funny,
I told Kurt I'm like,
we need to talk about this and Kurt says at a station is boring and I was like, no, not
in the, at a station is boring, but what this means means in big picture is not
-- exactly
-- that you now have a half inch supply line in your bathroom.
Right. And, and I think that's, that's the thing.
Like I,
I cannot stress enough how hard it is to sign
things in a way that isn't just like theater.
It is so hard to do,
ignoring theater,
to sign things in a way that doesn't add a ridiculous
amount of overhead and work and is prone to failure.
Sure. Right.
-- I, I consider all of that part of the theater because most of it doesn't work
-- well,
even at Red Hat,
where they had a dedicated decades old signing infrastructure with you know,
a hardware,
so uh hardware key man module and like software and
they've been using it for a decade or two.
We still had failures, we still had problems.
We still, like, there was every once in a while, like,
they'd have to bug fix the thing because somebody found,
like we did something new or different and it like broke.
And so
that was a major company putting major effort into signing software
-- and it was an unending nightmare. It was,
-- it was very difficult.
I was one of the maintainers of that system and, and it was hard to use.
I know I still blame you for that. That's
fine.
That's fine.
But anyway, well, my point is if Red Hat can't do it sanely,
what possible chance does an open source project with one developer have none.
Absolutely. Yeah, for sure.
And, and this is, but here's part of the story is so Sig Store is
we'll just call it magic signing because for the, the,
-- the purposes of conversation, it's magic
-- and
management. That's the biggest thing. They also do the key management.
And I dare anybody here write down something on a piece of paper and make sure
you keep that piece of paper and that thing's safe for five or 10 years.
-- It's such a chore.
-- Yes. But here's the important thing even to think about Sig Store.
Sig Store supposedly solved a bunch of problems.
How many start ups were created with the intent of doing something with sig store
and aren't doing anything with SIG store anymore and the number is not zero.
I have no idea.
The reality is like sig store solved a bunch of problems,
but it didn't solve enough problems that it was a tool that could be used,
we'll say by the general public.
Well, that's the thing though is we have to, like, we have to get this.
Basically,
your choices are you either build something
that does something useful for somebody,
but it's like standing by itself and it's
very fragile and brittle or you start building
boring infrastructure, pipes, highways, trains, and that is utterly
not usable at all to people until
you build a local road system and tie it together and put in toll roads and
get people to invent good cars. And that's the thing, right
is like right now this stuff is really boring infrastructure,
but nobody should directly use.
And even what github
is doing today is still part of boring infrastructure 100%.
And I applaud them for investing in this sort of thing because here's the thing.
This is beta. People are going to use it, not
a lot of people, but they're going to start learning
about how something like this needs to work. What are the bugs we find?
What are the difficulties sig Stor introduces into this system?
What is the difficulty of people doing verification of some of this stuff? Yeah.
-- What's the failure mode?
-- Right. We don't know, we literally don't know.
-- Remember
-- online certificate. I'm spacing out Os
O CS po online certificate, revocation protocol.
-- Whatever it was the point of
-- CS P
O CS P
Yeah. The, the certificate vendors couldn't run it reliably enough
so that people could use it because it was down so much. If you actually relied on it,
-- you wouldn't be able to surf the web like 10 or 20% of the time
-- I
remember turning it on and it was hilarious.
And so again, that's a perfect example.
Like people forget the, like the US interstate is a perfect example.
The US interstate was built by the military who realized trains are
great until somebody drops a 500 pound bomb on a train line
and like it takes a week to fix.
Whereas a road, you can drive the truck around the hole in the road,
you have to slow down a bit, but
you can keep going.
And so the interstate nice.
But if you've ever driven on the interstate, like, I'm a Canadian.
So we don't have that in Canada,
we have highway one which goes across the country east to west.
And then in Alberta we have highway two which
goes north south from like Edmonton to Calgary.
And that's it. Like those are. And then the 401 in Ontario which we apo
drive for a lot. It's the busiest highway in the world. Straight up.
But,
so I've driven on the interstate.
And what's fascinating to me is number one, the interstate is a,
it's a mesh, it's a net. It's huge. Right.
It's no, but you've got like, five major east west routes
and then you've got multiple north south routes on both coasts and in the middle.
And then you've got amazing gas stations
with, like, all the foods, hot foods. No,
no. Like, like here, if you're driving
you have to plan ahead because there's no gas station for 100 miles or 200 miles.
Yeah, that's definitely not a thing in America.
Like, there's a sign,
there's that famous sign in Ontario basically saying next gas station,
like 300 kilometers,
like, you better have gassed up back there or else
it could be bad.
And that's the thing I thought driving on the interstate
to me is magical because there's not just the interstate,
but there's all the fast food stations, all the gas stations, all the driver,
coffee bars. There's like
the whole ecosystem of stuff that makes it usable and actually kind of pleasant.
-- Well, I, I hate driving but I,
-- I know, but compared to driving on it's, it's
not bad.
That's fair. Like, I've seen worse.
I've lived in Europe, I've been to South America. Trust me.
If you got to drive 500 miles from A to B,
the interstate is one of the better options.
Right.
And that's the thing is stuff like SIG store.
And this is like, well, yeah,
how do we uh a perfect example is we're now rapidly realizing key management means
it should be outsourced to somebody and the developers should never see the
key or basically touch the key other than at the beginning to say like
make a key,
right?
Well, and that's
part of
what makes sig store magic
is most of the keys that end up getting used.
You generate a key, you sign a thing with the key and then you throw the key away,
you never use it to sign another thing ever again,
which is
amazing.
And this is a perfect example of what we've learned
now because remember it used to all be about,
you have to have your key and you have to keep it safe and you have
to feed it and you have to pet it and you have to groom it.
And now it's just like, yeah, no, just make a jillion keys, use them, throw them away
and have a third party that's somewhat trustworthy,
do it and no technical magic just have a trusted third party do it.
One of the things that has me really wondering about this and I don't think
github is going to get us there with this particular offering.
If you sign every artifact you build,
there are a lot of projects that build hundreds
or thousands of artifacts a day or week,
right?
Signing is cheap. Now
signing isn't the problem.
One of the things Sig Store does is they have a public ledger called Recor
and today Recor has 87 million, 88 million give or take.
It was when I looked a couple of hours ago, I think it was 87 million,
like 888,000 something. Was it something?
I bet you github
builds
hundreds of millions of things a week.
Oh, it, it, you know, it always reminds me of this Blockchain where people are like,
oh,
Blockchain does X number of transactions per whatever and
it's like Visa does 300,000 transactions per second during Christmas
like
bro.
And that's kind of where github
is.
It's like add about six or eight zeros to that number and now that's our hourly load,
right?
That's going to be one of the very interesting
problems I suspect is if this was deployed,
let's say github
said every single thing that gets built in github
is now automatically getting a six star signature. They'd probably crash
record.
Like that's just the reality of it.
Well, or you there's ways to shard it and to do bloom filters and to blah, blah,
blah like there's, there's technology solutions to this ultimately.
Will there be a giant
back end
data store thing of a jigger? Well, yeah, but the good news is
like we're good at that.
-- Yes,
-- we can solve it for sure.
We just,
we we're gonna have to scale up the SIG Store project.
That is why Google's getting rid of all the old analytics data.
-- They got to free up disk space for SIG store.
-- Right. There you go. Yeah.
Called it.
Need those tens of gigabytes of, of text.
-- No,
-- it's, it's a lot more than tens of gigabytes.
Yeah. It's
like I've done the math on the napkin and it's shocking how much.
Yeah,
it's horrifying.
Well, you got to remember because Google Analytics
used to keep everything by default and then they
dialed it down to a default two months.
You can extend it to 14 months
and then all of that stuff basically goes away in July and like,
well,
it's gonna also track like mouse movement and all kinds of crazy things.
Every record is several
well uncompressed and everything and duplicated and all that.
-- But every record is like several kilobytes of data.
-- I believe that.
Yeah. Anyway. Ok. Anyway, get up talking about, get up.
But so the thing is it's doable. Like I hate to kind of wave it away but like, yeah,
storing and serving a couple petabytes of data. Sure, whatever. Just
it's a money problem.
It's not even an engineering problem anymore.
Do it?
You have the strength of will to pay for it?
-- And I suspect Microsoft and Google do
-- I?
I think so and, and look, the reality is what they're signing right now.
I don't think it's a particularly high risk artifact.
Right. It's, you're going from the worker to the release.
There's not a lot of
we'll say distance there
that that could be abused.
Well, again, it boils down to just you do this inside of the github
trusted ecosystem and hope that github
is secure
because
let's be real. Github
has more people on their security team than most open source projects have
users,
-- let alone developers.
-- That would not surprise me if that's true.
-- They have,
-- if it's more than 50 it's probably more than 50.
That's true.
Most projects are one person.
Those projects probably don't have tons of users anyway. Anyway. OK.
Well,
but this is part of that changing ecosystem and also that people are even willing
to entertain this because imagine if you said this to security people 20 years ago.
Oh, hey, you know, there's this thing called github.
It's hosted G
or what's G? Oh, it's like CV S OK?
Cool. That sounds nice.
Like that sounds, you know, we had hosted CV S sort of kind of,
but they're going to do like all your key management
and signing and everything and people would be like,
heck, no, because like I remember, I used to not trust, I laugh.
Now, I used to not trust Amazon
to host my SSL certificates.
I would like, register them myself, upload them onto an Amazon Ec2 server. Anyways.
Now I just outsource all that to cloud flare, you know, and,
and that's that shifting mentality 20 years ago, I was like, oh,
you have to keep your own keys and have to keep them secure.
Now, it's like,
I'm smart enough to realize no, Amazon and Github
will do a far better job than I ever can.
And this speaks to the whole evolution of tools and process
where
cars, for example,
how many people maintain and manage their own cars
and change the oil on their own cars.
Now.
1 to 10% maybe it's very low.
The majority of us just go to Jiffy Lube or whatever,
every 3 to 6 months when the little light goes on.
For sure. You know, I actually own like uh the little connector, diagnostic.
I'm spacing out. What is that D
bus?
No, what's
Linux?
You know, the,
the little connector that plugs into your car and scans the
can bus and it'll tell you what the error codes are,
what they're called
O DB M.
OK.
Uh Anyways, like I own one of those and like,
I'm not going to actually fix my car.
I just kind of want to know what's wrong with it and it costs like 30 bucks.
And that's the thing with the software engineering. Do you want a software engineer
building and maintaining infrastructure or do you want them building
-- software? Like, do we want
-- to look? OK.
No, that's an invalid question and an invalid point.
And I don't like the t
anyway, so here's the thing.
No, one is doing it and they're never going to, no one is going to run their own site
infrastructure.
-- Not just because it's too hard, but because it gives them no value.
-- Right.
-- Well, some do and still do like open BS D and
-- like, ok,
-- whatever the functionally the number
-- is zero, but that's the point is,
they're like fringe lunatics.
-- Now, the number
-- is zero. K,
like,
statistically speaking, it is zero.
Now, here's the thing when someone like github
creates this sort of infrastructure
and they give us the ability to start doing things like sending.
I mean, this is TLS certificates are a great example.
Remember when people were like, we don't really need HTTP S on our site
and there were a variety of reasons for that.
And then eventually Google was like, if you're not HTTP S we're not, you know,
we're not tracking your site and everyone's like, oh, very important.
Now all of a sudden,
and the thing is
we know someday some standard or, or compliance or whatever is going to say
you need the ability to basically track.
Where did these artifacts come from back to some source?
Well,
it's already being written into the memos from the
White House on everything coming out of them,
whatever.
Every, no, but that's all BS everyone says that, but it can't be done
-- well.
-- No, no,
but that's the start of it. It
-- is the start of it. That
-- Yeah. Well, how much funding is behind that.
-- Right. No dollars.
-- It starts as a memo and then 10 years later it's a ni standard.
No, the memo is pointless memos need, they need funding.
But regardless, even if, even if N
said
everyone has to
sign
and verify signatures on all software they use, we'd be like, ha ha. Sure. Ok.
We're going to raise the price of your software by 300% NIST.
-- And they'd be like,
-- ironically the mobile space would be fine.
Sure.
Well, not like, seriously,
-- like Apple enforces this because they want their 30%.
-- That's true.
They, they have, well, they have an incentive
and that's the thing.
No one has incentives, but the reality is it's not just incentives.
We can't even do it today. We can't
do, like, correct at a station like the, the plumbing and the,
the just tooling doesn't,
it's not reliable enough. Like, right now
I have a house, I have water coming into the house from Epcor.
I don't have a backup water system
and you
have electricity. Exactly. Because Epcor is so damn reliable.
You don't even, it's not that you don't have a backup.
You don't even really think about it
and attestation and all of this signing stuff is still
at the point of here's a pile of rusty,
random sharp tools.
Build me a house. Sure. Sure.
And like, you're going to get Tetanus and die trying to do it
and we're slowly starting starting to
get slightly less horrifyingly dangerous tools
like this thing here where I can now actually sign an artifact.
I don't have to do key management.
I don't have to build any software.
I literally just have to like, like you said,
like tweak a couple of lines in one config file and, and run an extra step.
That's actually something that can be done. Now, will people do it? No
0.1 of a percent of people will consider it.
And like eight people, half of whom we probably know
will actually use this thing.
And that's OK. That's ok because this is how we start
like model T fords, you had to crank them and if you didn't crank it right,
it could break your arm
-- and now we have push button, start on cars
-- and I think it is,
it will not surprise anyone
that the logical conclusion of this is github
is just going to sign everything that gets built in their C I system like that is the,
the obvious output of this particular learning experience.
Well, I think the thing is you can only, you can really only
kind of like TLS,
you can really only kind of rely on it if it is done as close to 100% as possible.
Yes, I, I agree with that. And, and I think
-- this is similar.
-- So if you go to Pi Pie
and you go to publish a package,
they now have trusted publishers
which are github,
Git lab and a couple others. I forget it's all the usual suspects.
But the point is with pie pie, for example,
it basically ties itself directly into your github
repo.
And so I don't have that step of like I do the stuff in github,
export it and import it to pi pie.
It just pi pie talks to github for example and just gks the software down, right?
And
this is the kind of thing where now, oh, wait,
this attestation thing combined with that right now.
It's starting now we're starting to talk about
something that's uh for the sake of argument,
there'll be a green check mark on my pie pie package because it's signed and attested
or whatever. And, but today it's a green check mark and tomorrow it's
remember when software browsers used to say, hey, it's a secure site. Yeah.
And now this site is unsecure and now they give you hideously large
screens and make you click three or four things to get at the,
you know, like whenever I want to go to my local Bittorrent server web interface, I,
oh,
it's such a chore because I gotta like click through
all these things to get at the http thing.
You know,
you could just post your own certificate. It's
anyway, yes,
that makes it even angrier.
Anyway.
Well, no, you whatever. I'm not. No. OK.
So anyway, yes,
everything you have said I think is the logical conclusion
of all of this where we have all of these pieces
that can start working together.
I mean, a good example is github and N PM are both under the Microsoft umbrella.
That is an easy win right there to say
that
if you're going to publish N PM things, they need to carry a signature.
And obviously, in the case of github,
it's like you can use our stuff and we give you an easy button now to do that.
And, and it's also from the perspective of a tool like github,
this is, I mean,
I don't want to call it vendor lock in,
but it's kind of going to be vendor lock in just
because I don't know how easy this will be anywhere else.
It's also one of those things where
it
is effectively vendor locking and I'm saying,
effectively vendor locking because the reality is again the time and effort,
even if there's an open source project that provides this and it works well,
the effort to set it up and configure it is
nontrivial and the effort to keep it running and working
non-trivial
because you and I have done this,
this kind of work and it is
super difficult because the problem is
if you start signing stuff, it's like if you use TLS,
you can't stop one day.
No, I'm serious, like, and especially with hsts and, and pre loads and stuff.
Like if you basically say people look we're going to sign the software.
You are now doing something that you basically have to do
until the end of time because if you stop doing it,
is it an attack or is it just like, what is it?
And so that's the thing is once you start doing these kind of security behaviors,
you have to do them.
Yeah. I mean, this is true of like, you can't,
uh, the toothpaste can't go back in the tube, right?
There's so many apt examples of that and for sure,
I think this sort of behavior is one of them.
Absolutely.
Now, there's also the, there's, I think it's going to be very interesting.
You can imagine a, a build system for like something like open source or N PM or,
or whatever where
every dependency you download is going to have the at of station checked.
You're going to have these chains to say like I can verify the thing
I'm working with came from that repository over there and it came through,
you know, three layers of, of packages and three layers of builds from other people.
And it's kind of a wild idea when you really think about it.
Right. It's, it's not something we've really done before.
I know we've talked about it.
There are tons of supply chain people that have been going on and on about,
you know, being able to trace provenance and all this.
But we've, we've never had anything close to the technology to do it
also.
What, what's funny to me is we're,
we're solving a problem that existed 2530
years ago but doesn't really exist anymore.
Which is,
it used to be, you would build
software somewhere and then it would, like, end up on sun site and on Slack Word
F
TV,
distributed by third parties all over the place.
Because, well, a if you try to run it on a server and like it,
it would just crash because like if more than seven people tried to download it,
it would die. That world again, kind of doesn't exist anymore. Like you get software
largely, I'm gonna say from the source. Like you,
you don't,
I know there's third party, there's Debian packages and all that stuff.
But by and large that problem of I have to get my software
from mirrors because where else am I going to get it from?
Like,
I always downloaded my software from Sunset U Alberta because it was local to me.
It was so damn fast compared to all the other mirrors, you know,
-- I mean,
-- that was the point, right?
Like we didn't have cloud flare, we had local mirrors,
you know, even now, like I,
I have a machine with a two terabyte
nvme drive that does 1.1 million, right? Iops per second to 1.2 million read.
Like that's unimaginable to me.
So, but back to this,
what is interesting is once you have this full signing and this full chain of depth,
for example, my Debian packages, they're signed by Debian.
That's nice.
But they consumed signed stuff
which consumes signed stuff.
And it starts to basically,
it doesn't really solve any problems that
we currently have anymore because people aren't,
you know,
attacking third party mirror sites and injecting stuff. They're like,
they're going to the source and getting involved in the pack project and, you know,
doing it right before this would ever be detected.
But the point is now we're at a point where in theory, if this all happens,
the moment that that thing got built in github
and then distributed,
we know from then on it's secure and so
now we can focus on the developer security part.
Yes, that, yes, that is exactly the point.
And that was where I was wanted to bring this to like finish this one up
is
we don't know how to fix a XZ problem today.
Oh, no, it's easy.
-- You just don't allow any new contributors,
-- obviously, obviously that
and we just have to make sure the original contributor doesn't
turn evil or get his account hacked or whatever anyway.
But
that's the thing, right?
You do background checks on all these people.
It's fine. It's very easy to do. Yes, it should be. No problem. Like
it probably legal in at least six countries, at
least in America. It is
our total lack of information
and security law anyway.
But here's the thing,
once we start putting this plumbing into place, this is kind of like what you,
I'm gonna bring this back to your interstate example, even though I test driving is
you couldn't have like those gas stations, those restaurants,
all of those things that exist next to interstates,
by definition,
the interstate had to be built first right before that infrastructure could exist.
That is how it works
by creating
an environment where we have the ability to quickly and easily sign artifacts
by itself.
This probably won't increase security in a noticeable way for anyone because
I can't name a single attack in the last probably 10 plus years
that this sort of thing would have stopped.
-- But
-- there was one where somebody replaced a package on a mirror site.
They, they that used to happen
all the time
like 20 years ago. But I can't think, I, I can't think of it happening recently.
I'm sure it has and I just haven't noticed, but you get the idea right? Where
once we have this infrastructure built now,
we can start thinking about what clever things
can we do with an environment like this?
Like if I have a github runner that I can
arbitrarily sign anything
with,
what else can I do? Like they have an example in here actually of signing an S
bomb
as one of the artifacts
that, that you distribute or whatever, right?
These are the sort of things that make me excited,
like not specifically signing packages because I don't think that's
particularly interesting or is going to necessarily solve any problems.
But I am excited but having the ability to sign
anything I want in a reliable and trustworthy way,
which has never existed before
in a reasonable manner.
Well, let me give you a concrete example until we had widespread TLS.
We couldn't have H TT uh,
-- DNS over http S
-- that's probably a bad example because lots of people hate that.
But
-- also a lot of people hated TLS.
-- Uh, probably,
oh,
no, I wrote articles about it and people, like, some people were like,
this is a terrible idea.
Why would you want to encrypt? You should only encrypt.
What absolutely has to be encrypt.
Like, look at the standard itself like you can downgrade and upgrade encryption,
-- including to none
-- in the old days.
You can't do any of that anymore. They fixed it all.
No, but the point is the people that even built this were like, yeah,
you might have a TLS encrypt or not even TLS SSL encryption.
But you might want to downgrade to nothing to like,
-- save on computer time or something like
-- that could be.
Actually, I remember back in the day you could,
you could make ssh not encrypt and I would use that
for transferring files between machines on a local network because the,
the encryption
overhead was so huge
on these old machines. And, and now it's all magic CPU stuff.
-- But,
-- well, I mean,
I wrote security documentation where one of the first things
you do with Apache is turn off the non encryption,
right?
Like disabled des,
you know,
maybe even disabled three des, if you're feeling frisky
got a
lot of
power
-- the days anyway. Ok. I, we need to land this plane, but
-- that's the thing like
10 years ago,
if you had said TLS everywhere, basically hsts and preload is kind of the,
the default in the sense of how things are expected to work.
I would have been like, yeah, no, that, that, that can't work.
-- We don't have the infrastructure for it and now we
-- do
and we needed, let's encrypt to exist right before we can do that.
We needed that infrastructure.
And so that's, that's the thing, right?
People forget it's not just one thing like you don't just build the interstate,
you also need new, better road surfaces, you need better road paint,
you need better cars, you need better tires, you need better gas stations,
you need better payment systems,
you need fast food so people can eat in five or 10 minutes, like go watch the founder.
You know about the mcdonald's story,
like seriously stuff like that enabled the interstate.
You know,
like one of the biggest problems I have with electric vehicles is
if I want to go on a road trip,
I don't want to spend two hours waiting for my car to recharge.
Assuming that there's a supercharger even available.
Right. Whereas with a gasoline powered car as terrible as they are,
I can reliably go from like
an empty tank to a full tank in like 3 to 4 minutes.
-- But so many places, but
-- again,
electric cars are solving these problems. It is getting better,
-- it's getting
-- there, it's not instantaneous. And that, that is how we should end it.
Is the electric car example, right, like a decade ago,
electric cars suck beyond reason.
And now there's still very early adopter stage, I'd say,
and they're not ready for like mass consumption, but they are improving.
And
in the next 5 to 10 years,
they're probably going to end up in a place where anyone can
have one and use it and not have to worry about.
-- Is there a charger where I'm going to pull off
-- unless you park on the street,
in which case?
-- Good luck.
-- Well, today, today that is a problem.
-- Absolutely because, well, in a cold place,
-- well, I,
I would say it's even better than that.
There are now use cases for which electric cars are clearly better,
cheaper and more effective.
Like, so there are actual
realistic use cases where it is a better option
and it's slowly that s curve of adoption, it's, it's getting better
so that there will be, you know, more complicated use cases where it's like, oh no,
it, it can do that
and then five years from now it'll be like, no, it actually does it better than the,
than the regular car.
That, that is it. That is the point. It can do that. Like
we can
sign things.
It's just feats of heroic.
We need it
very simple and very default.
Well, I think it needs to be like LS and Crypt where it's just,
-- it's just enabled by default when you download Apache, pretty much
-- for sure.
All right, I'm calling this one. This was fun. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for listening. Go up on social security podcast.com. Head up the show,
Not Susy Pound
to this podcast. Hashtag and Mastodon Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.