Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
Hey, Kurt,
I'm super excited. We have a guest today.
We have Dan Lawrence,
software engineer at Google who's doing if you
aren't paying attention to open source supply chain,
anything,
there is no way you've not crossed paths with Dan before.
-- So Dan, hello, welcome to the show.
-- Thank you so much for having me.
So give us, give us an intro. Who are you and why are you here?
Sure. I'm a software here at Google where I've been for
eight or nine years now.
And for the past couple of years,
I've been doing open source security and specifically supply chain security.
I kind of backed into this space just because I noticed so many
problems as I switched from doing internal stuff at Google and our,
you know, weird mono
repo set up to a bunch of our
open source cloud technologies and everybody was building
things on Jenkins machines on Mac minis under
desks all over the world and everything.
Just kind of
kept getting increasingly horrified at what I found in trying to fix it all. So
I haven't fixed much yet, but I've spent a while poking at things.
That's how I got here today.
That's an interesting tangent because I've
noticed a lot of people accidentally end
up in security when they notice a problem and start fixing it.
And then, well, I get through the security guy now.
-- Yeah, I guess
-- that's basically what happened.
I kept poking around saying there's got to be a better way to do
this and everybody looked at me crazy and thought this was all fine until maybe
a year ago. People started to take it a little bit more seriously. And then
December January when solar winds happened,
uh all of a sudden everybody started panicking about this,
you know, obvious problem that had been lying around for a long, long time.
Totally. Totally.
Ok.
So
I would say from my understanding and you can correct me if, if, if you like is
Google has been taking a lot of this stuff seriously for years now.
Whereas many of us will say have not been,
will be my,
my polite description.
But I'm, I'm curious,
what, what can you tell us about?
Kind of what,
what Google's been doing because I know there's some really
cool work that Google does with kind of their internal
ii, I forget what it's called, but you're like repository of trusted open source
that then is usable by, by engineers and things like that, which is I mean,
you've been doing it for a long time.
I know and it's way ahead of the curve for sure.
Yeah,
we can talk about that a little bit.
Yeah. Trusted open source is a little, a little strong for what it is. Um
But yeah, so Google, um
you know,
Google is pretty famous for having a giant mono
repo or all of our code
is in one huge repository. It's all kind of virtualized and fast.
So you can build across it all
you really quickly on all of your machines without downloading, you know,
terabytes of source code, all of this stuff.
What happens though with something like this is you get dependency sprawl really,
really quickly because it's super easy for, you know,
one package over here and one P A
an organization to import a bunch of other stuff.
It's awesome because you can reuse code
but it means the dependency graphs get really, really hairy.
Yep.
So early on as we were, you know,
importing third party code had to get pulled into here.
People had to switch the build system over to our internal one.
You know, we don't use bash scripts and make files and auto
FT and all that stuff.
We have this uh internal version of basil if you've heard of that.
Um
They kind of does all these declarative hermetic builds for performance.
Um And
yeah, at some point uh because of that, um you know,
the dependencies probably started to run into, you know,
the diamond dependency issues where you have multiple versions of things.
Uh you know, the same dependency imported a bunch of times
and you start to get crazy build breakages.
Uh Because of that or you know,
some team changed something that had nothing to do with your code.
But now you can't build anymore because you have two conflicting versions of some,
you know, c dependency.
So because of that, we have a pretty strict one version rule now where you know,
there's one version of every open source dependency that's put in there, you know,
mostly for build performance,
build stability and just keeping builds working at all.
Uh which has some nice side effects when it
comes to supply chain security where things get imported.
Once the DS get reviewed, we try to do it pretty quickly.
Um So again, I think
sort of where we started uh the security aspects of it came later.
Um You know, it wasn't really part of the initial design.
Sorry, quick question, you say one version of everything. So you're saying like
Google has one version of, of G zip in their mono
repo that all the projects that use GZ I have to use that one version.
That's
awesome,
isn't it?
Because like we worked at Red Hat and that was not the case necessarily always.
And I,
that blows my mind like,
-- yeah, it's nice in some ways.
-- How do you make stuff, not break.
Um, yeah. So, I mean, it doesn't break if you don't touch it. Right.
You know, that's the, if it doesn't break, don't touch it, uh, issue.
Which, which is nice when you have huge things that are dependent on and, you know,
teams actively maintaining them.
Uh, the trade off there though is not,
everything gets as actively maintained or not,
everything gets as actively updated because, you know,
the person that originally imported,
it might have moved on and not be on the project anymore.
And now 35 other teams depend on it and can't find the right person to update it
and now nobody can update it without breaking 300 other people.
So it has good and bad effects. I guess I would say it's, it's a whole set of trade offs.
Um, I don't know that I would really recommend it as a great policy for everyone,
but if you do get there, you know, it's a, it does have a bunch of benefits.
Right. Right. Ok. So I don't, I don't want to dwell on
Google's internals too much here.
But now from what I gathered, you've taken a great deal of that knowledge
and kind of, you're bringing it to the outside world now to a degree.
Yeah, we kind of have to because, you know, the mono
repo is great for where you can use it.
But as we start to get more into, you know, the cloud space and open source space.
And, you know, it matters how we build our software and we're taking, you know,
these applications that are published on github
and building them directly from github
to put them into products and things like this, the, you know, the mono
repo and the one version rule don't really work and they don't really
anymore.
You know, if you have to support five versions of my sequel in a product,
then you've got to have five versions of my sequel, you know, stuff like this.
So there's a lot of technology that's shifting to
kind of this more open source uh smaller repo
package manager world uh which is a whole bunch of stuff backwards from this,
you know, kind of hermetic perfectly declared reproducible build, set up
um that a lot of teams were used to before. So we're trying to figure out ways to
get those same security guarantees and build
performance aspects we're able to have.
Uh but outside of, you know, the
Mote repub and custom tooling world.
Awesome.
Awesome
one question.
Uh And this isn't necessarily specific to Google,
but like in my experience of open source,
outside of a few projects,
the majority of open source seems to be consumed as well as source code, right?
Like red hat. Download source code builds it, ships it,
I back in the day, you know, download the newest version of bind, build it locally,
install it, run it
and I know, for some larger projects like say Firefox. Well, obviously you,
you know,
Mozilla does a build and you download the build
because building Firefox is a nightmare and a half
is this sort of aimed at
the world where the expectation is that people are more,
are still downloading the source code and building it or
is it more aimed at the world of binaries?
-- It's both
-- and you get a bunch of weird hybrid cases too.
Um You know, it's interesting.
You said the majority of source code is uh
majority of open source is consumed as source code.
Um I don't know that that's been
experience, I think, you know, maybe depending on how I
could be wrong,
I
wish that was the case, right?
You know, the old days of just going, grabbing stuff and building it yourself.
Um But, you know, especially as you move outside of like the ce C++ world, um,
a lot of stuff starts to get packaged up into package managers and sort of semi
compiled.
Um And maybe depending on how you squint and draw that line,
like is a Python Wheel file source code just because it's a whole
bunch of pies that are in a zip and arranged a strange way.
Maybe, maybe not.
There's a bunch of,
maybe there's binary blobs in there too and
you don't really know where they came from.
But one of the big challenges we've seen actually is that
most people aren't consuming stuff directly from the source code repository.
Even if they are taking source code,
you're taking a zip archive that somebody uploaded somewhere and
you don't actually know what commit that came from and you
don't know what stuff got stripped out and you don't
actually know this hasn't been tampered with along the way.
Pause when you say the word package because traditionally,
when I think of a package, I think of you have a source code in you know CV S or now
get,
then you have Tar Balls of releases
and then
possibly you have,
well Tar Balls, let's say of of binary files with the help files, the man pages,
the config files or whatever
you're saying from your perspective,
you count the source code like cutting a Tar Ball as a release as a package,
basically.
No, no, no, I'm saying most people aren't consuming stuff that way, right?
Most people are consuming the wheel file that you
uploaded to PP I or the gem that somebody
published
to Ruby.
And so there's source in there kind of because these are interpreted languages.
Um but it's not really,
you know a source release uh philosophically, right? It's
somebody did a bunch of packaging steps first to
turn it into something that you're installing directly.
See the same in Java, right?
People grab jars from Maven Central,
they don't grab the actual Java source and recompile everything.
Uh Every time they do their builds.
So there's usually some kind of transformation stuff that happens between the G
repo or the source code
it's maintained and then the
-- package manager download that someone does. Alright.
-- Alright.
So here's where I think it starts to get more interesting is
what is the problem between say me having a
github
repo
and you doing an N PM install?
Yeah,
the problem there is you have no way to verify if
that N PM package you just installed actually came from that Get
repo.
Um That's the simplest one, right?
When you look at, you know, N PM, there's a little link that says here's the Get repo,
this came from
uh anybody can go create an N PM package and put anything they want in that field,
you're trusting people kind of blindly.
And I mean, this is true of every
kind of package repo that exists,
right?
So
now
tell me about Sig Store, which is one of the plans you have to help make this better.
And, and II, I must say I want to add to, for, for anyone who kind of listens
Dan is all over the place.
It is fascinating to see because you're working on sig store, you're working on
uh the, the salsa stuff which, which we'll get to
and, and there's what I forget what else there is. There's a bunch of stuff though.
It's like it's ridiculous to me every time I see you doing something different.
It's amazing.
But anyway, Sigs
Zor
first.
Yeah, it's not just me, we've got an awesome team helping out with all of this stuff.
Um, but,
yeah,
so we'll start with Sigs Store and I'll kind of use an analogy from that N PM example.
We just talk through, um, the one that I like to talk about is, you know,
if you find a USB drive on the ground,
you pick this up. Right.
Everybody know you don't bring that inside and plug that
into your computer and I hope everybody knows that.
-- No,
-- you plug it into someone else's computer. Right.
Yeah. Yeah, you definitely do not plug that into your own computer. Right.
Everybody's it, department. Everybody's security department
has hopefully scared them out of doing that,
but real attacks actually happen that way. Um,
you know,
to companies targeted attacks or we will just drop a
bunch of these outside and somebody eventually brings it in.
So this is terrifying. You're not supposed to do that.
But when you go type N PM, install foo,
um, for some reason, nobody thinks twice about that.
Even though it's doing the exact same thing, except in many ways,
it's worse because you're taking that code.
You've never looked at,
you have no idea who wrote it and you're shipping that off to production,
it's not just the laptop you're plugging it into.
So, trying to think about how to solve that. Right. I mean, to make that safe
and the real problem
there is you have no idea where that source code came from.
Even if everybody did the right thing,
the developers reviewed all the code and they made sure there
are no vulnerabilities that they could find in there anyway.
Um, they published stuff the right way using, you know, the right build scripts,
nothing got tampered with.
You don't have any way to find those breadcrumbs and to follow them back
and, you know, this isn't a technology problem. Really? Right.
We have technology for doing stuff like this.
We've had, you know, cryptographic signatures and asymmetric key,
cryptography
and ways to sign packages of source code and binaries forever,
but nobody's really doing it today.
Um So we kept looking into that did a bunch of research,
talked to a bunch of open source maintainers.
Um And it seemed like it was just
too inconvenient, too hard, too expensive.
The, the analogy we started to copy was let's encrypt
people remember what browsing the internet was like, you know,
even four or five years ago,
half or more of the websites had the chrome red danger icon up
because they weren't using certificates even though
they've been available since the nineties.
Um It was really just an annoyance, right?
You had to pay some C A, you had to find one, you had to give them your credit card,
you had to email them this weird certificate request,
they would send you one back over email
you'd figure out how to drop that next to Apache in the right
directory. And then Chrome would light up correctly.
I just, I laughed because I actually had to buy my first secure web server.
No, because there weren't open source ones available at that time.
I mean, even the server itself, not just the certificate. Yeah.
Yeah, I had to buy Red Hat Stronghold server.
Yeah. Crazy.
Um, so lets encrypt came along and said,
let's make that free and automatic and uh build tooling around it.
So they set up a free C A that anybody could get
just by installing a little automated tool to keep refreshing your certificates.
Now, if you're using Kubernetes or some fancy platform as a service,
you just set a Boolean that's like secure.
True when you automatically get a certificate provision because
let's encrypt automated it and made that all free.
So we said,
hey, can we figure out how to do that?
But for code signing certificates because those exist and they're still kind of
stuck in the nineties where you pay somebody 500 bucks and they,
you know, do a background check on you and check your business address,
verify it and then they send you the certificate that's valid for three years
and then you can't rotate it and you can't figure out
what to do if you lose it and all these problems.
Uh So that was just going through this with BMI and it's uh
it's like three steps backwards.
Yeah, it's, it's fun.
Um And you know, so many of the edge cases still are handled to around,
what do you like?
There's no revocation and there's no rotation and all this stuff built in.
So if you lose that or get it tampered with like,
you know, Microsoft accidentally signed a malware driver a couple of months ago.
Remember that? And,
you know,
there was a great solar Rs blog post about how they had to spend
three months um finding all of the old versions of their source code or
of their products that were distributed and
resigning them with their new certificate before
they could revoke the old one because
otherwise things would just stop working overnight.
Um Yeah, so we started a couple of different projects to address that.
Um we have a free certificate authority for open source code signing.
We've got a whole bunch of cool transparency logs to make it
all work and make it all auditable just like certificate transparency.
Um and just kind of trying to copy the lots of
playbook and then translate it to code signing uh instead of, you know TLS and
uh web encryption.
And, and I will say, I think the important thing
that I see cigar
doing
is
it's not very human focused
in the context of read this horrible how to and then run these 700 esoteric commands,
which I think is a huge deal.
Yeah.
It's, it's again, yeah, we can make it free, you know,
we can do all the security stuff, but it's got to be easy.
It's got to be automatic and people have to not even think about it.
Otherwise they're not going to do it,
you know, just this morning.
I was thrilled to see you when I woke up to Go Releaser,
which is this awesome tool for automatically publishing, go
BNA, you know, on a million different platforms and package managers,
just integrated SIG store.
Um And so you can start signing any go
binary that people are already releasing on github,
github
actions with just like a little bullying.
Um So that's the type of integration we need.
Otherwise we're just not going to get people to care enough to do it.
OK, cool.
So you just kind of,
I think led us into one of the topics I wanted to bring up with you because
uh you reached out to me on Twitter because I think I
was whining about some supply chain thing a couple of days ago.
And
so you, you talk about making it easy,
but also an important part of this is integrating it together.
One of the things that I I is terrifying me about the world of supply chains,
especially open source supply chains is
if we rewind the clock a decade or more,
there was this kind of attitude among application security.
People of security is special, you need to listen to us,
you need to do all this weird stuff to be secure.
And I think saying we failed is a polite description of, of what happened.
And I think we're still dealing with fall out of that even now.
And I feel like a lot of this supply chain stuff I see is, is in that,
in that wheelhouse of this is security supply chain, right?
But I, I feel like it needs to be part of a bigger picture and I I'm terrified
we're screwing that up.
Convince me I'm wrong.
Yeah,
I was wondering which uh which supply chain thing you were whining about there.
You didn't quite say you just said it was all terrible but there's so many, you know,
every week there's another one,
there's right.
And so in all seriousness, I mean,
this is part of what concerns me is
supply chains are cool right now and fricking everyone
is hitching their wagon to supply chains and, and it, it just,
it feels like it did before of like, oh my goodness, what are we doing again?
Do you have any s bombs for me? Yeah,
that's exactly what's happening. Um
because it's seeing so much attention now at the
national and international level like we have an executive
order about this
part of that story is is that everyone wants to shake the money tree, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean,
it's crazy seeing an executive order about something that nobody even understood,
you know, a year ago
but
-- no one
-- understands now.
You know what? No, no, I think it's worse than that.
It's not even that they don't understand it again.
It goes back to, they didn't even know this existed. Right.
No. Right. I,
I've met so many people that are
what's in your software. What do you mean? Well,
you know, I see these BSD strings in your software.
Could you tell me what's in there?
-- You know,
-- I
-- don't
-- want to rat hole.
I
want Dan to convince me I'm wrong because I still want to be wrong.
No, it's good. I love a lot of what you said there.
I was listening to one of the other podcasts you had
and you said something great that you just reminded me of.
You said it's not that there's cracks in the foundation or something,
but there's a whole basement down there that people don't know about,
right? And so,
yeah, a lot of what I've seen in the last year, you know,
hasn't really led to improvements, but it's been, you know,
better insights into what is actually in uh dependency trees.
Eal is kind of a part of that. It's kind of like the end result.
But stuff like, you know, the github
dependency graph and having depend a bot nag you by
sending you a million updates constantly when you turn that on
is showing people how big of a basement there is
under there that they don't understand that they don't realize.
Um, and then,
yeah, it's
who we get to, how, how we're gonna make this easy and everything in a second.
I'm just gonna go off a little bit more of a tangent on what you just started with.
And you said the BS D strings, right? Um,
because we're not starting from scratch here. Uh There has been some work done
in standing dependency graphs and it did come out of these licenses, right.
Um You know,
decades ago when open source uh cases were being tried all the time
and everybody was suing everybody over breaching
different licenses and copyright uh clauses.
Um Everybody started to, you know,
annotate their source code with licenses because they were scared of getting sued.
Right.
Um So now we're seeing the same thing again, except instead of getting sued,
it's getting attacked or getting attacked.
And so it's, you know, what's scarier lawyers or Attackers.
Um You know, they're both pretty scary.
Um, the licensing stuff did a great job,
but I think the level of granularity they did in a lot of these
cases is a little bit wrong for what we need to do here.
Packages don't change their license every day.
You know, they don't have, there's 12 commits a day,
but people don't change their license more often than every couple of years,
hopefully.
Um And so we have to take a lot of that work and kind of move it down to the commit level,
make it more fine grained.
So we can actually say not just these 35
packages but the exact commits of these 35 packages.
Um So then we can join them with more interesting vulnerability databases,
which I know you've done a great deal of work on
trying to automate the way vulnerabilities get ingested and add
more metadata so that we can figure out exactly,
you know, which commit introduced it, which commit fixed it
because we have all this data around.
We just don't have it in ways we can query and do automation with.
Um so I think there's a bunch of different pieces all coming together. And I think,
you know,
there are people of course trying to profit off of all of
this and come up with ways to sell the secure supply chain.
Uh But I think getting it to be automatic,
getting it to be default and getting all this to be, you know,
the right and easiest way to build software is where we need to go.
And I don't think that's too hard, right?
You know, the story I told earlier about, you know, Google getting to this world by,
you know, by accident almost,
right?
Knowing what you're building is great for other reasons than security, right?
It lets your build to be faster.
Um It lets you update dependencies easier,
it lets you know your binaries be smaller, it can improve performance.
Um
So there are all these other reasons
you might want to build things. Uh you know,
in ways that aren't bash files and curl pipe to sh and
um you know,
tar balls being g zipped and piped around without any integrity checking.
So, you know,
knowing what's running in production and knowing uh what commits
it came from is important for so many different reasons.
Ok. I'm not convinced yet.
Let's, let's, let's
let me narrow it. OK. I'm gonna, I'll pick on your salsa which is
SLS A, what does it stand for? I forget
uh
-- security levels for software artifacts, something like that. Yeah. OK.
-- That
sounds, that sounds right.
Maybe swap two VSS. I can't remember.
It's probably fine.
So I, I've, I've read this
and I feel like
it has,
well, I shouldn't say I feel like it does.
It has a very security focus to it and, and that's obviously the intent.
But when I read this, I, I, my immediate thought was this is part of a larger ecosystem
and I think we are doing a disservice to the developers
and ourselves by trying to single this into security instead of saying
this is a larger problem and security is part of it.
-- What would you describe that larger problem as
-- just
I would say the whole world of building and maintaining
II,
I hesitate to even use the word software necessarily because I
think software is also just part of a larger ecosystem of,
you know, you might, for example, let's say, in the case of Google,
Google has a variety of products and software is what drives that.
But you still have like, you know,
humans interacting with a thing and then the thing does something and
security is an aspect of this, but you also have usability, you have quality,
you have the developers that have to
features, right?
There's, there's so many other things and security is just a narrow sliver of it.
I'm, I'm concerned
that by
trying to address just security,
we're going to miss the bigger picture and it's going to turn back into the, oh,
the security nerds are at it again.
So you're saying the whole software industry is broken and
we need to throw it all out and start again,
wouldn't we all love that?
But you know what I mean?
It's,
and I'm not saying that that any of this work is
for naught because obviously you have to start somewhere and,
and build into that.
But at the same time, I, I just,
I remember the early two thousands and how adversarial the
relationship was between security and development and I'm like,
I'm, I'm terrified, we're going to do that again.
Yeah, I think it's a big risk. I think so. Yeah, let's talk about salsa a little bit.
Um And how some of that interplay here, I think, you know, the,
there's an initial set of levels in there,
your criteria that you're supposed to meet to get to salsa level 1234,
that kind of thing.
Uh you know, for the most part,
if you actually read through and think about what you have to do to get something,
you know, to one of those levels,
most of the work is actually done on the
side of whoever is operating the build system.
And I think,
you know, so as an open source developer, as somebody like that, I don't, you know,
most of the work really is not yours uh to know about,
you just kind of have to pick a build system that cares about security
and you have to not, you know, build on a Jenkins machine in a closet somewhere,
right?
Um
And we've known about this forever.
This is one of my, my favorite rants, you know, it's uh we've locked down production,
we buy all this expensive intrusion detection and, you know,
cis call monitoring and everything like that.
But then, yeah,
we build on somebody's random laptop and push that and we
have no idea what security is happening in the build environment.
So I think, yeah, the principle is like, you know,
the build system has to be at least as secure as the, you know,
environment you're deploying that stuff into.
Well, I mean, I think solar winds told us maybe more secure, right?
Yeah,
I would actually take a step back and say you just,
you even need to know what your build system is because I've
literally found production RP MS where the build host is workstation.
Like that was the DNS name of it,
you know.
Yeah, people should not be building from their individual machines, you know,
you should be doing this from secured
systems with monitoring and everything like that.
I guess it's sort of, I guess my,
my thought is even taking a step back and
going back to the like the inventory level of,
yeah, what build system is actually building this? Right?
I'm not gonna even assume it's a build system to start with.
Yeah, that's basically, I,
I did a couple of tweets yesterday trying to explain the levels in like one sentence.
And yeah, level one is like use a build system,
don't build from your laptop and that's a huge, you know,
huge security improvement if everybody did that.
Um And then, you know, number two is, you know, use a build system that, you know,
secures some metadata so you can actually trace stuff back and you know,
it it builds from there.
But the first one really is use a build system.
Um it creates a single point of failure that worries a lot of people.
Like if everybody's on github
actions and github
actions gets compromised.
Uh But at the same time, I think,
you know, the supply chain is
so distributed that um
you know,
it's having one central thing to protect is a lot easier than having
a million things all over the world that then feed into each other.
Right.
Um, you get into one dependency, you're eventually going to make it everywhere. So,
um, yeah,
I think getting stuff onto a small set of well operated production grade build
environments is going to be one of the biggest improvements we can make.
And I don't think people even need to do that for security right there.
Other reasons to do it, you know, for productivity,
nobody wants to be doing these builds on their laptop.
-- It's just been so hard to set up and,
-- and that, that's just it. Right.
I feel like the other reasons are way bigger
and, and again, if I'm the security nerd talking about security things,
I'm going to get ignored.
But if I have a story to tell that's way bigger than just security.
I, I think people are going to listen.
Exactly.
Yeah, I completely agree.
-- Well, but
-- also I,
one thing I've noticed is we'll fix this security problem that may or may
not be a problem versus we'll fix this problem where let's face it.
Building on Josh's laptop will be a problem someday soon when
Josh goes on vacation and we need to do a build.
Right. I, I've encountered that right now. I'm trying to rebuild a website with N PM.
It's some N PM build thing
and it's just, it's not behaving itself and of course,
the person who originally set this up is gone and
yeah, I'm staring at this thing trying to figure out how to make an update.
-- You
-- just need their laptop and then if you log in as them, I'm sure.
Well, and, and no,
the worst is I found the jerk me left a build script for
Mac Os but not how to get that Mac Os stood up properly to
do it all.
Yeah, I think leading with a lot of those benefits, you know, can really help.
One example, I like to show people is, you know, with uh you know, the Google, the mono
repo and stuff we have internally and everything is built from source and
there's just one number that increases as all the changes go in.
Um
you can actually
go type in a, you know, commit hash or whatever.
Um They're slightly different in our system is based on per force.
So they're just numbers that go up, but you can type in a, you know,
commit into the system and then see every single binary
in production right now that has that in it.
Um Which is awesome for like is my change in prod yet?
You know, how many hours have you wasted debugging code?
Because you thought you had the wrong version
checked out from what was actually happening.
Oh,
even simpler.
How much time did me and Josh spend looking to see which
versions of our back port of packages were affected or not.
-- Yeah.
-- Just like, why isn't my print statement getting hit?
And you're like, oh, it's because I still haven't deployed or, you know,
it's still a Q A and I'm looking at, you know, the proud stuff.
So there's,
there's so many of these things that I think do
resonate with people that don't understand or for some reason,
don't think they need to care about security yet.
Um, that you can build up just by having
some semblance of understanding on what's running where.
Yeah, I mean, look, I, I think let's encrypt is a great example of that, right? Where
most people I think aren't using, let's encrypt for the security aspect,
they're using it because it makes the little red stop sign go away in the web browser.
Right.
Yeah. And these are gradual cultural changes too, right?
You know, chrome and other browsers had,
had turned off http websites, you know, 10 years
that wouldn't have worked. You can't do that. It's gradual.
You need to get people to start caring where they are and then eventually, you know,
and I hope in five or 10 years people are going to look at, you know,
random binary packages they downloaded that don't
have any metadata associated with them as,
you know,
as scary as a USB drive you found on the sidewalk.
I think you just hit on the most valuable thing and, and,
and it even reminded me because
we often expect rapid change
and it's never rapid and especially in security and unfortunately,
if we try to push it too fast,
we become the enemy.
And
I know I'm guilty of that from the past. And so I'm always very, very
aware
of what I'm asking of developers because I know if you ask too much,
you, you
just, it's over
-- change,
-- fatigue,
right? Like alarm fatigue. It's a real thing. I mean,
I,
I know people working for various organizations
that through the pandemic have made,
you know, enormous changes to their workflows and
like on a weekly basis and people are just burning out.
Um And I, I imagine developers are humans as well.
I'm not entirely sure of that, but it seems to fit my theory of people,
most of them are,
-- there are a few strange ones.
-- The other thing I, I also wonder about is sort of,
I look at, you know, most things are a nice curve of adoption.
You have early adopters, then you have the bulk and then you have the stragglers.
But it seems to me, I think part of the
challenge with open source is we have such a diverse,
like when you say a build system,
my mind immediately goes to like there's 30 of them,
like which one? You know what I mean?
There's, there's almost too much choice sometimes, which is wonderful. But also,
you know, how, how do we get 30 different
user or 30 different build systems with completely disparate cultures and users
to agree on something like,
like build security.
-- Yeah,
-- it's slow and, you know,
that's my biggest worry is that we forget about this in a year or two.
and move on to something else.
History, especially with all this political pressure happening.
But I think, you know,
I think the Attackers probably won't let us forget
about it and they're going to keep coming.
-- Um
-- So, I mean,
no, I, I think if, if we forget about it, it's because there's no demand for it.
I don't think it would be because
it, we need it and we're not doing it.
I think it would just be because for some reason we've kind of solved this problem,
you know.
Yeah, or the other aspect, you know,
where you get standards and regulations written that say you have to
do X and X isn't exactly what you need for security.
And, you know, we get all these cases where, you know,
compliance is slightly different from security and people end up
making worse decisions in order to get a check box.
But I think we can, you know, come up,
hopefully come up with something good where we stay out of that debacle.
Let us, let us hope so.
Um Now, now at the same time though, like, so,
so one of my complaints about a lot of things
and I'll pick on salsa again for this is
like, I like the idea of salsa
but
like, where are the references? Where are the things that say?
Like this is why we're doing this, right?
I, I feel like today and this might, it's where it starts, I understand to a degree.
But like,
how do you prove what you want to do? Make sense?
And the example I always use is the NIST
password guidance
where, right?
Like NIST literally just made some crap up and then someone did research,
you're like, oh, wait, this is actually bad.
That's exactly what I was hinting at with the regulations being bad. But
yeah, like, I mean, that, that's the, that's the,
that's going to be the poster child forever of, of terrible regulation, right?
Because like a guy made some crap up instead of doing research and
like this is one of my concerns about all the supply chain stuff is
if, if it's people making crap up and not doing research,
it could be worse than nothing. Be it regulations from NIST, be it
something from the Linux Foundation,
be it something from the Cloud Security Alliance?
Right? Like, it doesn't matter where it comes from.
If it's just, if it's not backed by data and research,
you run the risk of being worse than nothing.
Right.
Yeah, I think, um,
yeah, it's a great risk.
I think a lot of this stuff is a little bit simpler than, you know,
say the password guidance.
Well,
-- some of it. Yes, I will agree.
-- Even password guidance to be fair.
It seemed like, you know, at, at a, at a first blush does seem like a good idea.
Um,
of course, rotate your passwords, um, until you realize what that leads to,
you know, the second order effects of it.
Yeah.
I mean, there's always a risk,
some of the stuff we come up with is going to be wrong and, you know,
we can't really do that research until we try
and people start trying a lot of this stuff.
Um I think the the way that a lot of the recommendations and the
levels in this first draft came up was kind of one high level principle,
which was
how can we ensure that at least two people looked at everything, right?
No one person uh preventing unilateral access or preventing unilateral changes.
Um and that applies to source code, right?
Most people know that source code review is good where you can do it.
Um There even are some compliance uh things that, you know, take that into.
You can't prevent one person from, from force,
pushing to proud and then you kind of carry that along.
You know, two people should publish an artifact,
two people should change the BUILD script
or BUILD system that publishes that artifact
all the way out to like the BUILD system itself should
be operated in this way where nobody can change the BUILD,
the running BUILD system.
The infrastructure, all this stuff is on
that also leads to some second order effects like you need hermetic builds for
this because if even if two people reviewed every single line of code,
but one of the lines of code was curl
PPE to bash.
So a hermetic build is something you know where there are no outside effects,
it's sealed off from the outside world.
You can't make random network requests to download code, right?
And so if you've got a build script that, you know,
that script could have been reviewed, but it's hitting some random URL on github,
then anybody can change.
That's right. You've got unilateral access again.
Um And so figuring out how to prevent all the different examples of
all the different places we could think of throughout the life of,
you know, published artifact, uh you know, from source to production
all the places where one person had an opportunity to change. That
um is kind of the,
the guiding principle for how a lot of these recommendations came out.
Um The weird part is a lot of this doesn't make sense in open source.
So we've got to figure that out where, you know,
tons of projects have zero or one maintainers.
You know, you're lucky with one person looking at stuff
who's going to review that.
-- Exactly.
-- So that's, that's the struggle insert
-- the XK CD
-- comic,
-- right?
And I mean, and that might be something valuable to do.
Is with this BUILD system, you know, just to point out, hey, this
uh
like I remember was it XML? Hash do.
And, you know, it was a couple of things were affected
and literally the one person was,
I have a weekend free in about three months and I'll, I'll fix it then.
And Red Hat was like, we'd like to help you get it fixed now,
you know, and this might be,
I think this is part of it is we need to identify those critical projects and maybe
go well, this one doesn't have a lot of support.
So if you depend on it, you might want to help out.
Yeah, we could talk for another hour about this.
Um, because that is such a hard problem to do.
Um, you know, all the different cases of,
uh pretend you have a blank check and go try to improve open source.
It is not as easy as it sounds.
I
mean, now if someone wanted to though, I will take that blank check and,
and we'll have a hell of a party.
Yeah. No, we could, we could get into some real stories here.
Um You know, some people, some people don't want the money.
Some people have full time jobs.
You know,
the worst is when somebody has a popular open source project and then all of a sudden
they get a super high paying job where they're not allowed to work on it anymore.
I mean, something similar happened to Lo Dash
actually recently where that's literally what happened and then
it was a, they, they had no good way to basically
fix it.
Right. And it took months
to,
before they could sort out like who had ownership
of the package and who is owning the github
repo and like it was, it was wild.
Yeah, you can always fork the code but you can't always, you know,
get access to the N PM package or
on a lot of these registries. Yeah. So name spaces are important too
and low dash is if you look at N PM, everything uses a lo dash.
It's like it's literally in everything. It's
it's terrifying to think about sometimes.
Yeah. And so, you know, I I
completely agree and you know, I've listened to a lot of your podcasts,
open source owes you nothing, right?
Just because somebody put code out there, you know, it's this code comes with no,
this code comes with no warranty, use it at your own risk.
But then once it ends up as like a third level dependency
down your tree and you literally don't have permission to switch that
your fork,
you're kind of stuck too.
And I think that's where tooling has to come in and make it easier to swap, you know,
things out for their forks where relevant and start maintaining patches.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Yeah, totally. Alright. Alright. I'm gonna, I'm gonna cut us off.
I feel like I could talk to you for like, six more hours.
I won't,
I won't subject you or, or the audience to me for that long. Ok.
So Dan, I want to give you the last word
and then, and then we'll wrap it all up.
What is your, what is your advice for, about open source supply chain security?
Yeah, I would say, uh, be patient. Right? You know, this is a huge change.
We have to make software
now.
I know software doesn't get rewritten overnight though, right?
We have to change the way software gets written,
which means we have to wait for software to get rewritten.
Um But hopefully we'll get it right.
You know, this next time, thankfully, software doesn't live forever though.
And I think we're making good progress and people care about it now.
So we'll start to see improvements.
I, I truly hope so.
I will say you've given me a,
a sliver of optimism compared to where I may have been prior to speaking to you.
So I thank you for that and
I, I am hopeful. I truly am.
All right.
So thank you everyone. Thank you so much, Dan.
You can go to open source security, podcast.com head up our
show
notes, Suzy Podos
Podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Curt and Dan have marvelous rest of your days. Thanks
-- for having me.
-- Thanks
-- everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye,
the